These five Brahmans are
none other than
the princes of Hastinapur
the sons of Emperor Pandu.
And he's Arjun.
The one you dreamt of getting
Draupadi married to.
They are the Pandavas?
Disguised as Brahmans?
Impossible!
That's impossible!
- Your Highness
I assure you
welcoming them is your duty.
This is how I welcome them.
If they really are the Pandavas
they should be punished
for sure, Vasudev!
I'm sure these princes
of Hastinapur
hadn't come to Panchal
to get married.
They had come with a plan
to humiliate Panchal.
My daughter put the garland
around Arjun's neck
in full faith.
And in exchange he gave
Draupadi a reason
to shed tears all her life.
I believed, Vasudev
that they understand the
meaning of righteousness
and this is what they did.
God has made them do this,
King Drupad.
It's doesn't matter whether or
not they are innocent.
Because of them my daughter's
life has become miserable.
Whether she marries all five
of them or remains unmarried
she will face humiliation
all her life.
Because of them, Vasudev.
All because of them!
Not because of them,
Your Highness.
Because of you.
What future had you wanted
for Draupadi when she was born?
Try to recollect, Your Highness.
'I ask that my daughter suffer
all her life.'
'May she be bestowed with
all the impurities of the world'
'but still be considered pure.'
'Can you give me such
a daughter?'
'May that girl endure injustice
time and again.'
The consequences of the
deeds of parents
has to be borne by
their children.
Now, Draupadi too will get
all the sorrow
you had asked for her.
As you sow so shall you reap
King Drupad.
But, it's reassuring
that Draupadi will overcome
all her sorrow
and find a place among the
great women of the Aryans.
In the future, Draupadi will
be worshipped, Your Highness.
Now you should welcome
your five sons-in-law.
Vasudev Krishna is here,
princess.
Draupadi...
Are you happy with your
decision, dear?
Calm down, Draupadi.
Govind, what have I done?
How could I make such
a decision?
How could I have even thought
of this abomination?
How can a woman marry
five men?
This is immoral, Govind.
Absolutely immoral.
Why did you take such
an immoral decision, Draupadi?
What else could I have done?
How could I have allowed
mother Kunti's four sons
to become ascetics?
The mere thought would have
broken her heart.
But for my happiness
she didn't shed even a tear.
How could I be selfish
and think only about myself?
And Prince Arjun...
I have seen the disappointment
on his face.
How could I have
any desires, then?
How could I have let the four
princes make such a sacrifice
for my happiness?
And the whole community has
expectations from their princes.
How could I have disappointed
the whole community?
That's why I was forced to
be unrighteous.
I couldn't find any other way.
After considering the happiness
of so many people
you arrived at this decision,
Draupadi.
How could it be immoral?
After considering the happiness
of so many people
you arrived at this decision,
Draupadi.
How could it be immoral?
When a tiny pebble enters
a shell in the ocean
the shell turns it
into a pearl.
You, too, have turned
this immorality
into righteousness.
I am proud of you, Draupadi.
Govind...
The gift you gave me.
The five stones.
The five pillars of
righteousness.
When I saw them
I felt as if
you were ordering me to
marry the five Pandavas.
Govind...
Do you really consider
this to be moral?
No...
Never.
I cannot call this righteous
and fill the hearts of all
the women in the world
with sorrow.
It is immoral.
And it will always be immoral.
But...
Your compassion has made
you do this.
And compassion is the basis
of righteousness.
I don't understand, Govind.
The gift of five stones
that I gave you
was advice about righteousness.
Righteousness cannot
be demanded.
But you gave the five pillars
of righteousness
a place in your heart.
Knowledge calms the intellect.
Patience calms the mind.
Love soothes the heart.
And devotion
calms physical needs
and soothes the body.
And justice...
Justice calms the soul.
The mind, intellect, the heart,
the body and the soul
when these five pillars of
righteousness
are calm and steady
a human being is full
of compassion.
That is called righteousness.
And on the basis of
this righteousness
you have made this decision,
Draupadi.
And thus for you
and only you
it isn't a sin.
How will I live
with five husbands, Govind?
How will I be able to be
fair to all of them?
How will I fulfill my duties?
And the society...
How will I bear the taunts
of society?
The kind of thoughts people
would have about me, Govind!
Those who are righteous
are worshipped by God Himself.
You were born from fire.
And fire is also known
as the purifier.
It purifies everyone.
It destroys bad elements.
I believe
all those who come close
to you will be purified.
Don't worry, dear.
Whenever you need
any kind of help in life
then I
your friend
Vasudev Krishna
will come to you.
I promise you.
You only have to carry
the five pillars of
righteousness.
The throne of Hastinapur
awaits you.