Nakul, hold on to its string!
How did you come up with the
idea of making kites, Govind?
Upon observing human beings.
The hearts of human beings
also keep soaring like kites
in the winds of desire.
If the string of control
is lost or cut
the heart
gets bruised and broken
in the harsh winds of desire.
It goes insane.
Look at Nakul's kite over there!
Sometimes human beings
lose control over themselves
because of other people.
Govind!
Your hand is bleeding!
Till the string keeps
the kite in control
it does not hurt oneself
but when the kite
starts pulling the string
one ends up cutting one's hand.
Sometimes
the actions of others
leave the heart frazzled
and one is on the verge
of losing control
but at times like these,
staying composed
and keeping
one's heart under control
becomes quite essential.
Is something like this
going to happen to us, Govind?
Can you not see the future?
No, friend.
I had told you
that I can observe
the temperament of a person
and estimate his future actions.
However
after seeing the success
of the Pandavas
the sons of Dhritarashtra must
certainly be up to something
and at a time like this
if you know what is
most precious to you
and safeguard it
you will indeed see the ray of
joy in the darkness of sorrow.
Will you not
stand by us, Govind?
I must leave to protect Dwaraka.
I have got the news
that King Shalv
has left with his army
and is headed towards Dwaraka
to attack it
but I am
always with you.
The string of control
that you had lost
must once again
be in your hands, friend.
Do not lose heart.
I reside in the hearts
of all of you.
If you lose heart
then your Govind
your Krishna
will be lost as well.
The Pandavas!
Three.
All hail His Highness!
Minister Vidur
seeks permission to enter.
Allow him in.
Welcome!
Welcome, my darling
younger brother Vidur!
Greetings.
Greetings,
brother Dhritarashtra.
Your heart will soar
with joy today
when I give you
this piece of news.
I am all ears,
brother.
What happened in the court
of the sons of Pandu
between Duryodhan and them
and how the daughter of Drupad
had to interfere
in the matters of state
was not at all correct
for which both Duryodhan
and I are very sorry.
That is why, inviting Draupadi
to Hastinapur and welcoming her
is what I suggest.
Besides
after Draupadi's marriage
she was not
received warmly by us, Vidur.
That is why, I have
taken the decision, Vidur
that by burying the hatchet
the Pandavas and Draupadi will
be invited to Hastinapur by us.
Draupadi must get the much
deserved respect and welcome
and we will ensure
that she gets it, Vidur.
The great Guru Drona
and his son Ashwatthama
will also be cordially
invited to Hastinapur.
The sons of Pandu and Draupadi
will be invited to Hastinapur
personally by you,
Vidur.
But sister-in-law is not
present here, brother.
What do you mean?
It has been
my experience, brother
that while delivering a news
whenever sister-in-law
is present with you
that news always brings joy.
Minister!
Yes, Your Highness.
Will the Pandavas
be a part of a friendly duel
in this gathering?
No, uncle.
Duels of all sorts
require weapons
and you are
well aware of the natures
of brother Bheem and me.
If there are weapons involved...
No one will use
any weapon, Duryodhan!
That is an order!
The sons of Pandu will be
welcomed warmly by you
and you better not forget that!
Vidur
along with the knowledge
of the 'shastras' and weapons
a game of dice is also
a part of us 'Kshatriyas.'
That is why, along with
strength and knowledge
it is essential for a King
to have control over
his fortune as well.
And fortune can be tested
with gambling,
can it not?
That is why,
my son Duryodhan
will organize a game of dice.
Let us see
how much control
one has over one's fortune.
Let us see
how much control
one has over one's fortune.
Go on
and send them the invite.
As you say,
Your Highness.
Uncle, go ahead and play.
Here goes.
Go on...
Twelve.
Look!
I won.
But Your Highness,
you turned the die yourself.
So what?
If we can roll them
with our hands
then why can we not turn them?
Once you roll the dice,
you cannot turn them.
You do not know
how to play this.
You may go.
I will play with My Lord.
My Lord.
My Lord...
Prince Arjun.
What happened,
Subhadra?
Please play 'chausar' with me.
This is the least you can do
for your wife who is with child.
Do you know,
Subhadra?
The actions of a mother
become the values
of the unborn child.
Do you wish to give my child the
values of the game of 'chausar?'
My child ought to
learn the values
of love and warfare
and not those
of gambling and drinking.
You will not be able to
teach him the value of love.
That is because,
you do not know it yourself.
You may teach him
warfare instead.
I hope, you will
not fall asleep.
If it is interesting
then I will not.
A labyrinth of this nature
either has five, seven
or nine circles
and each circle has a specialty
that it can be navigated
only in a particular way.
This is a labyrinth
of seven circles.
This is how a warrior navigates
through the seven circles
and enters the middle
of the labyrinth.
The warrior must navigate
through the seven circles again
to come out of the labyrinth.
A different kind of strategy
is used for this.
I hope, you are
listening, Subhadra.
Subhadra...
She fell asleep.
I knew that she would.
She heard how to
navigate into a labyrinth
but
failed to hear the strategy
to come out of it.
She fell asleep before that.
Greetings, Prince.
Minister Vidur of Hastinapur
is here.
His Highness has called you
to the court at once.
Uncle!
What brings uncle here
without informing us earlier?
'The fishes shown in this scene'
'were generated
using computer graphics.'
May Emperor Yudhishthir
have undying glory.
May Empress Draupadi
have eternal happiness.
Your Highness,
on behalf of Hastinapur
I have brought these presents.
For this gesture of goodwill
by Hastinapur
a grand temple will be built
in its honour, Minister
because uncle Dhritarashtra
is revered by all of us.
Your Highness,
Hastinapur is organizing
a humble ceremony
to honour you.
It is being held to honour
especially Empress Draupadi.
I have approached you
and Empress Draupadi
to invite both of you
to that ceremony personally.
Various events will be held
there for your entertainment
and at the end of the ceremony
Crown Prince Duryodhan
will
play a game of dice with you.
Before one accepts
such an invitation
the ministers of the court
and the experienced elders
are always consulted with
Minister.
Certainly.
You may certainly
consult with them
Prince Arjun.
What do you suggest,
uncle?
Should we accept
this invitation?
My suggestion!
Soldier!
Leave!
Greetings, uncle!
Bless you!
When a hunter sprinkles
grains on the ground
one must understand
at once, dear
that the hunter has set a trap.
Under no circumstance should
this invitation be accepted.
Under the garb of a ceremony,
that Shakuni
must certainly be weaving
a web of treachery.