Mahadev, help us.
Parashuram's celestial axe and
Bheesma's 'Brahmastra'
if the weapons
collide then it will be
catastrophic for
the entire universe, my Lord.
Mahadev.
Stop, Parashuram.
Bheeshma has passed your test.
If the two of you
keep fighting each other
the entire universe
will be annihilated.
But I have not yet
got justice, Mahadev.
Then how can you
stop this battle?
Lord Parashuram is bound
by his promise, Mahadev.
Until my mind is not at rest
Lord Parashuram
must continue this battle.
My Lord,
fulfill this wish of mine.
I wish to see him dead, Mahadev.
I wish to be
the cause of his death.
As it is a plea to
Lord Parashuram
I must fulfill your wish.
But I cannot foster
the negative feeling
of vengeance.
Aiming at a higher goal
or noble deed
when you wish
the death of Bheeshma
you will surely become
the cause of his death.
Then I do not wish to live.
But I shall be reborn
to have my vengeance.
Expunge your heart of this
bitterness, Princess Amba.
I promise you...
When the day ordained
by Lord Shiva arrives
I shall lay down my weapons
when I confront you.
I do not require
your generosity, Bheeshma.
I shall not forgive you.
Even after 25 years
I shall be born with the resolve
to kill you.
The throne of Hastinapur for
which you have ruined my life
you will strive day and night
for that very throne.
The throne will never allow you
to sleep peacefully at night.
You will run
and the throne will
make you run your whole life
and when your soul
will be aged and fatigued
I shall come then
as your doom.
'Panchal
Town of Kampawa.'
'25 Years Later.'
Shakti is finally born
in the kingdom of Panchal.
Royal Astrologer,
I am quite certain
that Drupada's queen must have
given birth to a daughter.
I have been awaiting
the birth of this girl
for the past 25 years.
Ever since I have known
that a woman will be the cause
Bheeshma's death.
I have been praying to the Lord
for that girl to be born
in our family.
A daughter is born, father.
All hail Goddess Mahakali!
My wish has been fulfilled,
Drupada.
Bheeshma had insulted me
and our entire kingdom.
'Do not make the mistake
of instigating me'
'otherwise the whole of Panchal
will burn the way Lanka did!'
This girl will avenge the insult.
There is nothing more beautiful
than revenge
in this entire world.
The birth of this girl child
has brought all the beauty
of the world to me.
And that is why,
this girl shall be
called Shikhandini
Royal Astrologer
what do the stars say
about my granddaughter?
It was 12:07 PM today
when this girl child was born.
Rahu has a great influence
on her fate.
This girl will surely be
successful in carrying out
all the duties of her life.
But only after a great struggle
Struggle is the best teacher.
I will poison
this girl against Bheeshma!
I firmly believe
that this girl will be the
cause of Bheeshma's death.
To ruminate over
the death of Bheeshma
will be the sole purpose
of Shikhandini.
The wishes and ambitions
of ancestors
and also their anger,
enmity and revenge
become the legacy
of the future generations.
Parents try their best
to give their children
all the happiness of the world
but end up giving them
their agony as wealth.
They intend to give them love
but end up filling them
with hate.
Think about it.
What have you
taught your children?
You must have given them
love, knowledge and wealth
but did you not fill their
hearts with hate as well.
Did you not impart to them
the preconceived notions of
good and bad?
Does the struggle of one man
with another
that of one society with another
and that of a nation
with another
not get decided by these
preconceived notions?
Do murder, death and bloodshed
not arise from these
preconceived notions?
In other words
parents give their children
life as well as death.
They give them the light of love
as well as the darkness of hate
and darkness may reside
in the mind of one
or may even be a real one
but the only result of it
is fear.
Only fear.
Think about it.
'Hastinapur.'
'Sindh.'
'Adra.'
'Gandhar.'
Kshubbha!
Princess Gandhari,
I am right here.
Aghuna, Kaarya,
quit staring at me
and go and bring
an earthen lamp.
Princess, please calm down.
All the lamps will be lit soon.
The breeze extinguished them.
Please calm down.
Aghuna, the two of you
were ordered
to be in this chamber with lamps
in your hands the whole night!
Then how could the lamps
get extinguished?
Do you not know how scared
Princess Gandhari
is of the dark?
Why am I so afraid of the dark?
Not just you, Princess Gandhari
everyone is afraid of the dark
because our eyes are
our windows to the world.
If one has vision,
one has everything.
But one feels completely
lost in the dark.
The whole world vanishes.
That is why we are
afraid of the dark.
But now, you need not fear it.
You should go back to sleep now.
Such a big army!
I must inform King Subal
about this right away.
A huge army
great strength
and a kingdom which is
wealthier than Lord Kuber
is where my daughter
will be married, sir.
And her husband
will be so good looking
that he will give tough
competition to even Gods.
He will be stronger than
the God of wind
and will have more qualities
than Lord Indra himself.
Any disability
or the slightest flaw
then my Gandhari will not
be married to such a man.
Our daughter is remarkable, sir.
After all, Lord Shiva has given
her the boon to have 100 sons.
'Princess Gandhari.'
What is the matter, sir?
While reading Gandhari's horoscope
why have you become so grave?
Pardon me, your Majesty.
The stars in her...
- Your Highness
General Shatashwa requests
permission to meet the king.
As this hour?
But the king
is occupied right now.
Your Highness,
pardon my intrusion
but the news is such
that I must converse
with the king right away.
What news do you have,
Shatashwa?
Whom does the army belong to?
We have sent our messengers
to find out, my lord.
The soldier
who delivered this news
had not seen
the flag of the army.
How much time will it
take them to reach here?
About six to nine hours,
your Majesty.
Where is Prince Shakuni?
- He is on a journey
for some special purpose.
Someone has dared to attack
the kingdom of Gandhar!
And to attack without
prior notice
is against the Indian rules
of warfare, your Majesty.
Then I shall punish them
for disregarding the rules
of our nation, Lohit!
I will annihilate that army!
This is Gandhar!
Each soldier here has the
strength of a hundred elephants.
Each one of them is like
a brave lion.
But your Majesty,
we have a very small army.
It's courage that brings victory
not weapons, Lohit.
My soldiers will tear apart
the armour of the enemies
and rip their hearts out!
Shatashwa.
- Yes, your Majesty.
Prepare the army.
Tell all the soldiers
to bid goodbye to their families.
Order every citizen
to pick up a weapon.
This will be a terrible battle!