I'm sure Shakuni is
concocting a plot
on the pretext of celebrations.
I suggest that
we go to Hastinapur.
The one who is plotting
would get a hard blow
of my fist.
He would tremble in fear then.
Dices can be an answer
in the game of gambling.
We won't be able to resort
to a fight there.
But when uncle has
suggested us
not to accept the invitation
why should we go to Hastinapur
and fight with them.
A King can never refuse
for a fight and its initiation.
A ruling King can always express
his helplessness, Yudhisthir.
Tell them,
that you don't have time.
No, uncle.
Uncle Dhritarashtra
is a father figure for me.
His invitation
is an order for me.
But, My King
the way to an unknown domain
is all the more difficult.
When we don't know about
the plans of King of Gandhar
how are we going
to counter it?
Plans?
What can be his plan, Panchali?
Maybe, his eyes are
set on our property.
Maybe, he wants to
reign our kingdom.
He can take it all
if that's what he wants.
Do we give up on our rights
just because someone's
plotting against us?
Do we give up on our kingdom
which we have built after
much hard work?
This isn't just, brother.
Bheem, no one has
actual rights on this land
and we are no exception.
Just the way
a fish inhales water
and then exhales it.
Neither does it accepts
water into its system
nor does it reject it.
In the same way, human beings
own a piece of land while alive
but eventually,
have to leave it behind.
We were born in the jungle
and are now,
ruling this kingdom.
Maybe, in future,
we go back to the jungle.
This kingdom isn't ours
for a lifetime
but our pride is
and so is our self-confidence.
We can't let go of our pride
and self-confidence
in the wake of a battle.
It's not just about
the kingdom, My King.
I fear
that if in this game
we play to protect our honour
we will lose our piousness.
And if we protect our piousness
we will lose everything
that we have.
If we protect our piousness,
Panchali
we will be able to get back
all that we lose.
Even if we lose this kingdom
we will build a new kingdom
somewhere else.
But I can't refuse
uncle Dhritarashtra's order.
Uncle
I will definitely go
to Hastinapur.
And if uncle Dhritashtra
orders me
I will surely gamble.
They have entered this place
just the way a fawn
enters the mouth of a python.
They have come with their pride
just to have it
squashed by us.
Their arrival was inevitable,
my child.
When you make the right move
you can compel others
to give
in to your wish.
Let's go and welcome them.
While welcoming the
sovereign king, Yudhisthir
don't forget
to be humble
to him.
For the last time.
May you be happy always.
It's a tradition
that wherever
a sovereign king goes
his wish should be asked for,
firstly.
So tell me,
what your wish is.
King"
I just have one wish, uncle.
For a moment, forget that
I'm a sovereign king
and let me take
your blessings.
No, dear.
A sovereign king
never seeks anyone's blessings.
A coconut tree,
though, is important
it's the coconut
that comes to use
and used in prayers.
In the same way,
neither a father
nor an uncle
is as important as
a sovereign king.
In more than 500 years,
none of the kings from
Kuru dynasty could get
the title of a sovereign king.
I'm really proud of you, dear.
But, today just let me be a
happy and a proud uncle.
I seek your blessings, King.
May you be happy,
brother Duryodhan.
'Order brother-in-law Duryodhan
to drop his weapons.'
'To take away weapons
from a warrior'
'is deemed
a fitting punishment.'
'Confiscate brother Duryodhan,
brother Dushyashan'
'and King of Anga's weapons.'
I seek your blessings, Queen.
May God bless you,
Prince Duryodhan.
The court of Hastinapur
may be inferior
when compared to your
pride and rights.
Do we need to spruce up
Hastinapur's court for you or...
Or?
Or
do we need to apologise
to you
if something lacks
in our hospitality?
King!
Please come in,
if you wish to.
We have arranged a grand
welcome for you
at the court of Hastinapur.
Shall we, dear?
Let's go, uncle.
Welcome.
Queen...
If you wish, we can first
visit the family deity's temple.
After which, you can
enter the court.
As you say,
Queen mother.
Is the snake letting go
of its venom
or is it the venom that's
forsaking the snake?
Why are we being given
so much respect?
A sacrificial lamb is fed well
before it could be sacrificed.
We should stay alert, brother.
Don't worry, Nakul.
As long as Grand Sire
Bhishma is with us
he won't let any harm
befall us.
Let's proceed.
What happened, Sahdev?
I'm getting
a sense of foreboding.
Today, this court is going
to witness an injustice
that has never taken place
in the history of mankind.
Don't worry, Sahdev.
Grand Sire, Sir Drona,
uncle Dhritarashtra
and uncle Vidur are here.
Queen mother's here
and so is our mother.
On seeing an injustice
taking place
they won't remain silent.
Brother Arjun
adversity is when
the rope you hold
for your support
actually turns out
to be a snake.
I fear
that everyone's going
to be a silent spectator today.
Brother Arjun
adversity is when
the rope you hold
for your support
actually turns out
to be a snake.
I fear
that everyone's going
to be a silent spectator today.
Grand Sire, you look worried.
Yes, Vidur.
I'm worried about the fact
that in this game of gambling
Shakuni is surely
going to cheat.
Looking at the splendour
of Indraprastha
Duryodhan is envious.
He wants
the kingdom of Pandavas
by hook or crook.
The reason for my worry
is the same, Grand Sire.
Grand Sire
please try and stop this game
of gambling from taking place.
My rights and my powers
have been subdued, Vidur.
A throne made of sand
remains intact
until someone sits on it.
But Pandavas
with their hard work
have built Indraprastha.
And I...
I won't let anyone deprive
them of their rights.
I must speak to Duryodhan.
The final say should
be ours today, uncle.
I'm sure it will be, my child.
The Pandavas would
be defeated so badly
that they would never be able
to come to terms with it.
Their kingdom, their army
their property...
Take it all
away from them, uncle.
Is that it?
My children
I'm going to
crush their pride.
Those who don't
have a reason
to be proud of themselves
are actually
the ones who are defeated.
How are we going
to do that, uncle?
We will make them
your servants.
That won't suffice, uncle.
We will make their wife
our handmaiden.
She made us part with our
weapons in their court
we are going to unclothe her
in our court, before all.