Grandsire.
What's the penalty for going
against a king's order?
Who has committed the of fence
is also significant
to be considered.
What's the significance
in that, grandsire?
It's enough to know
that the of fence
has been committed!
Tell me!
What's the punishment
for opposing a king's order?
Sometimes,
to save a person's life
the physician amputates
that person's limb.
But that doesn't make him
an enemy.
He is not punished.
Instead, he is rewarded.
What Kunti did
at the entrance
was correct.
She stopped the rise
of a protest in the kingdom.
I've heard the discussions
amongst the subjects
in the kingdom,
grandsire!
Everyone was saying,
if the king's command
was very difficult to follow
then seek refuge
with the mother queen.
Father, now
no one's afraid of the king.
So, what's inefficient
about it, son?
The king's duty is not to spread
fear among his subjects.
His duty is to protect
his subjects
from all their fear in life.
Then, why is father
crowned the king, mother?
Let Lady Kunti sit
on the throne.
Lady Kunti will rule the kingdom
taking advice from her sons.
This means, even Hastinapur
will now be ruled
as per
brother Yudishthir's wish.
Then how does division
of kingdoms hold good?
What do you wish, dear?
I want Lady Kunti
to be rightly punished.
That would be sheer foolishness,
son.
The Pandavas will avenge
their mother's insult.
Do you wish to see a war?
They can never
fight a battle, mother.
They don't have the liberty
to fight a battle.
Their flag isn't going to be
hoisted in that kingdom, mother.
Only Hastinapur's flag
will fly high.
How will they fight a battle?
Grandsire,
please take the decision.
I...
I serve this kingdom.
The king will take
the decision, Your Ladyship.
I have only one boon
that my father had given me.
The boon to decide
the time of my death.
I don't have any other boon,
Your Ladyship.
Grandsire.
Grandsire, please don't
speak sorrowfully.
I accept your advice.
Kunti won't be punished, son.
But, Gandhari,
it's also necessary
to stop the subjects
of Hastinapur
from setting
towards Indraprastha.
Hence, I've decided
that not just the subjects
but even the royal family
shall not take part
in the inaugural ceremony
of the kingdom.
Inform Kunti
regarding the same.
Dear!
Dear
you cannot be unjust.
A mother lives with only
one hope in life.
To see her sons
obtain happiness and success.
Today when Kunti's sons
are going to achieve
such a huge success
how can we snatch away
this opportunity to witness
this success from Kunti?
I know that, Gandhari.
I'm extremely contrite
about it.
But the thread
that holds the pearls together
has to remain hidden as it is
the base of those pearls.
Similarly, a sacrifice
has to be made
by the royal family first.
Because it is the base
of the subjects.
Kunti shall not
go to Indraprastha.
This is my firm decision.
God bless you!
God bless you,
King of Anga.
You're a generous
and capable Arya.
I'm not a generous person, sage.
I give alms only because
my father has said
that there's nothing superior
than giving alms.
Giving alms purifies the soul.
Unfortunately
certain events
keep occurring in my life
that makes my soul impure.
God bless you!
Vrushali.
You're here!
Accept my apology,
Your Majesty.
I'm here to make a request
to you.
There was a time when my house
was adjacent to yours.
Considering that relationship
if you can be kind enough...
- Yes, continue.
What is it?
Ask the crown prince to allow me
to meet my father.
The crown prince is your friend,
isn't he?
But aren't you going
to Indraprastha
with Queen Mother?
The king has prohibited
Queen Mother
from going to Indraprastha.
She can't attend the inaugural
ceremony of Indraprastha.
That's impossible!
Such grave unrighteousness!
The crown prince can't
be so immoral.
I...
I must talk to him.
You may go, Vrushali.
Don't worry.
You shall definitely go
to Indraprastha.
Very soon.
This is my promise to you.
Victory!
Karna, my friend!
Welcome, dear friend.
You've displayed
great resolve and capability
in front of the subjects today.
I'm extremely elated.
If I weren't the reason
for your happiness today
I would have been
very happy, friend.
To get
the credit of unrighteousness
is not a matter to rejoice.
Unrighteousness?
What's the reason behind
your statement?
Which unrighteousness
has taken place today?
To hold someone's mother
as captive
and to avenge her sons
is unrighteousness, my friend.
To hold someone's mother
as captive
and to avenge her sons
is unrighteousness, my friend.
That unrighteousness
is visible to you, friend.
But didn't you see
the immorality
that was inflicted upon me?
- Definitely, yes.
I'm ready to fight
with the entire world for that.
But, friend, even when the king
mounts an elephant
he mounts on its back,
not on its head.
The elephant's head
is always virtuous
because it's similar to Lord Ganesh's* head.
*Ganesha is widely revered as the remover of obstacles, the patron of arts and sciences and the deva of intellect and wisdom.
The enemy's mother
is equally virtuous, my friend.
I understand
your predicament, friend.
But this is politics.
We build castles for protection,
don't we?
Consider Lady Kunti
as one of the castles, friend.
The bricks used to build castles
don't have a heart.
A mother's heart weeps.
And the fire that arises
from this faintheartedness
burns all the happiness
to ashes, friend.
You had attempted to burn
Lady Kunti alive in Varnavrat.
That was highly iniquitous.
Fortunately, she was alive.
Now
don't separate Lady Kunti
from her sons, friend.
My friend
why are you advocating
on behalf of the enemies today?
It's because enmity
is sustained with warriors.
May the woman, child, cow
or a rustic farm
belong to any country.
Causing harm to them
is considered unacceptable.
Whose side are you on, Karna?
Did you forget that I had
made you the king of Anga?
When you were being insulted
in front of everyone
it was me who had given you
the respect and right.
I remember that, my friend.
Therefore, I've taken the oath
to protect you all my life.
P rote ct!
Is this how you
will protect me?
I'm trying to protect you
from being wrongful, friend.
I sense unfaithfulness
in your words, Karna.
I have a feeling
that even you wish to reside
in Indraprastha now.
You are inferior before Arjun.
So, now you wish to establish
your glory in the world
with his support.
You've hurled such a grave
accusation on me, friend!
Since you have doubts
on my intentions
I shall take an oath today
that however the situation
pertains to be
I shall never plead
with Arjun for my life.
Neither shall I provide him
the gift of life.
Now, do you believe
my faithfulness?
Kindly release Lady Kunti
from captivity.
Impossible!
Children!
King of Anga...
Dear King!
A kingdom can't be ruled
only on the basis of the
principles of righteousness.
You're a king.
You must support
unrighteous deeds at times
as well as
be unrighteous at times.
If that's how it is...
If that's how it is
then please permit to remove
this crown, Prince.
Prince, today I feel
that you're avenging
the injustice done to you
by committing
this act of immorality.
You have the right to do so.
But if I support you in this act
then, perhaps
it's the greed for this crown
that would make me do it.
But, I...
I'll not be able to survive
under this burden.
I...
I don't wish to become
the king of Anga.
I want to become
a commoner, friend.
Please forgive me.
Are you giving me this
in return of my favours?
Charioteer's son!
Please don't be indignant,
my friend.
I shall forever be your armour.
At your single command
I shall accept
a hundred deaths.
But to serve you
it's not important for me
to remain a king.
I'm not contended
with your answer.
I'm contended.
I'm contended with the answer.
My dear,
if Karna doesn't wish
it's not right
to forcefully stop him.
Not the king of Anga
but the great charioteer, Karna.
You're just tied
to the bond of friendship.
You're free from the burden
of ruling the kingdom.
I'm grateful to you
for your kindness.
King of Gandhar.
May I make a request
for one last time?
Of course,
the great charioteer Karna!
Kindly allow Vrushali
to go to Indraprastha.
I had promised her
depending on my friendship.
And that promise would certainly
be fulfilled, Karna.
The girl is free to go,
charioteer.
I shall take the king's fury.
You may go.
Greetings!
- Greetings!
Uncle!
- My dear
the sword is sharpened
before the battle.
Everyday,
if you sharpen the sword
it will become so brittle
that it will break
during the battle.
If your friend continued
to preach about unrighteousness
he shall very soon
lose his capability as well.