'After 15 months.'
Greetings.
What message have you
brought, Ayurvati?
There are no signs of labour,
Your Highness.
How is that possible,
Ayurvati?
A woman should bear
a child in nine months.
And Gandhari has been
pregnant for 15 months now.
Why has she not gone
into labour yet?
Disperse all!
Gandhari
you have been pregnant for
more than a year.
Then why haven't you
gone into labour yet?
Why has my son not taken
birth yet?
The one who had given you
the blessing of a 100 sons...
Ask of the same God!
Forget about 100 sons
my first son hasn't been
able to take birth yet!
Why?
I have been asking the same
question to Lord Shiva.
Like the future
even He is silent.
- That's the problem, Gandhari!
Not the solution!
I am interested only
in the solution.
What do I do, my lord?
One can only wait for
the sun to rise
not try to make it happen.
In the same way
we have to wait for the
happiness fated...
I am not interested in these
lessons of yours.
I need a son.
I need my heir.
Find a solution to that.
Seek a solution to that!
Or I'll have to get a son from
another woman, Gandhari.
My lord...
- To bear a son for her husband
is the foremost responsibility
of a princess.
The reason I married you
is this boon.
And if you cannot bear a son
then this marriage is a
deception! A betrayal!
My heart now questions
me, Gandhari
if the Lord has even given
you any such boon.
Or in order to get
you married
your father spread this
false story.
Remember, Gandhari
if the wife cannot
bear a son
then the king does not feel
any affection for her.
Because to give the kingdom
its heir
is the duty of a king.
Hence, you can observe fasts,
perform rituals!
For this!
The penance that you had
gone through
in order to get this boon.
Go through a more strenuous
penance...
Your brother is secretly
overhearing us!
Let him know too
that between a king
and his wife
love can exist
only when that love
is linked to a progeny.
A child...
Lord!
There is a message from
Hastinapur.
Why does the minister
always send a riddle
instead of a message?
This is not a riddle.
To maintain the confidentiality
such language is used.
Lord, only you can
read his message.
Here it is.
What happened, Lord?
Is it any troubling news?
What kind of a trouble
is this, Lord?
Did you give me a boon or
a curse to have 100 sons?
You gave me the lamp
then why don't You
give me the light?
If You have given me the path
then why not the pace?
What kind of kindness is this
which has become
the trouble to my happiness!
Lord, rid me of this pain.
Help my husband
in quelling his unrest.
Until I deliver my husband's son
I'll keep meditating
in this temple, God.
I'll keep meditating.
Lord, is it true that the love
between a king and a queen
is connected to their baby?
Why such a question, Kunti?
I am worried for
sister-in-law, Lord.
After a lot of difficulties,
she got brother-in-law's love.
What if... - You are getting
worried unnecessarily, Kunti.
A baby is the fruit of love.
Not the reason to fall in love.
I can't give you and Madri
any progeny
then has your
love reduced for me?
No, Lord.
Not even in my dreams.
Then don't worry
about sister-in-law.
This is an unfortunate time
for the whole Kuru lineage.
Even these times will
certainly pass away.
The shedding of the leaves is
not the end of the tree.
The spring certainly ushers
in new leaves, Kunti.
Kunti, God would have
certainly planned something
even for the Kuru lineage.
Lord, you are so patient
and tolerant.
Because the Kuru lineage
has witnessed
such unfortunate time
even before.
During the death of my father
Vichitravirya's
there was no successor.
Then grandsire
and Queen Mother
requested sage Vedvyas
for surrogacy.
What does that mean, Lord?
Yes.
When a capable sage
without any selfishness
only for the welfare
of the people
helps a women to get a son
the process is called 'Niyoga'.
The baby that's born
in such a situation
is considered to be
her husband's baby.
That baby is pure as the babies
born by the power of mantras.
But if the husband is alive
then the scriptures
don't permit this method.
'I, sage Durvasa will
give you a mantra'
'by which you can call
upon any God'
'and by invoking that God'
'and can beget a son like
the same God.'
'The power of mantra
does not go in vain.'
'As soon as I disappear'
'a portion of my aura'
'will stay with you as a son.'
You have a son, Lord.
My son is your son
because he's born with
the power of mantras.
He is pure.
Lord, you would surely ask me
as to why didn't I
tell this to you before.
But, Lord, in my heart
I used to feel
that wishing for a son
and becoming a mother
would be my selfishness.
To suffer the curse
upon you
is my foremost responsibility.
That's why, I kept quiet.
Which fact, Kunti?
Lord
Sage Durvasa had blessed me
with a boon.
He had given me a mantra
by which I could
invoke any God
and be blessed with a son
of His characteristics.
Is that really so, Kunti?
Yes, Lord.
Without conception
I can beget a son.
And Lord
I... - You are a beholder of such
a great boon, Kunti.
I can't believe
on my good fortune!
On our good fortune!
You have a solution
to the problem of Hastinapur.
Through you,
the struggle of Kuru lineage
can be overcome forever, Kunti.
But, please...
Hear me out, Lord...
- I've heard you, Kunti.
The king and the Kuru lineage
will be gratified by you.
Beget such a son
who is a scholar
of righteousness
knowledgeable of justice
future of the Kuru kingdom
the one who can be enthroned as
a ruler next to my elder brother
and the one who can be the
fruit of our marriage, Kunti.
The one, whom the entire world
accepts as my son
which would enhance my respect
all over.
Invoke the God of righteousness,
Lord Yama
and seek his blessings
in the form of a son for me.
I'll enquire a saint,
about the auspicious moment
to beget a son
and be right back.
What is the prediction according
to the planets
Master Jaimini?
Why isn't Gandhari
going into labour?
According to the horoscope,
I can assure you
that it's time for Hastinapur
to be blessed shortly
with its heir, His Highness.
At this time, the position of
the planets is really propitious
and the son born will be
a follower of righteousness
intellectual and will be
a believer of justice.
On one side, you say that a son
will be born in our lineage soon
and on the other side,
you're not able to give a reason
of why Gandhari's
not going into labour.
If you are an astrologer,
then please tell me
the reason of this incidence.
My master Vedvyas often says
just like the way a horse runs
on his feet
but his speed and direction are
controlled by the horse rider
similarly, the direction
and movement of humans' lives
are controlled by the Almighty.
If the expecting child is not
born before 1 month and 12 days
then the child would
bear demonic traits.
He shall be aware of
righteousness
but shan't follow that.
He shall bring disgrace to the
throne of Hastinapur, Highness.
Disgrace to the throne
of Hastinapur!
Kunti
I have appeared, being pleased
with your invocation.
You have invoked me
by chanting this mantra
so you must be having a desire
of obtaining a child.
Not just a child, Lord.
I want a son instilled with Your
characteristics in him.
We want a son
who shall be determined
in righteousness
one who can be mentor
to the kingdom of Hastinapur
who can be a reason of gladness
for my ancestors.
You both are really noble
that you think of righteousness
even before any kind of worldly
power and riches.
Righteousness stems from
mercy which comes from justice
and justice from patience.
In all the battles, struggles
and movements of life
the one who is calm and composed
the one who doesn't care for
relationships and self-benefit
before taking a decision
for righteousness
can have righteousness
in his heart.
Your son shall definitely be
somebody of this capability.
My son!
Kunti, Kuru lineage will always
be obliged to you.
My son will symbolise
the God of righteousness.
He'll always be patient during
battles.
My son
will be called Yudishthir.*
*Steady in war.