In reality a human isn't
bound by his deeds.
The expectations linked to
those deeds bind him.
How so, Krishna?
If you hope to be victorious
in this war
then you shall feel
immense sorrow upon defeat.
And that sorrow shall compel you
to do something else
for which you need to
be born again.
If you are victorious
your arrogance shall grow.
And that arrogance
shall drive you towards
worldly triumph.
It shall make you kill
and the sin ought to it
shall bind you.
Think about it!
If in this battle
you have no desire to win
and have no fear of losing
would you feel bliss or sorrow
at the end of this war?
Neither bliss, Krishna
nor sorrow.
Therefore your bliss, sorrow
hopelessness, disappointment,
arrogance
aren't due to the war.
The expectations that you have
from the war
shall cause them.
Is it not true, Arjun?
Therefore, holding joys
and sorrows as equals
without thinking of
gain, loss, victory or defeat
if you engage in battle,
O' son of Kunti
you shall not bear any sins.
This is called 'Karma Yoga'.
The one who attains
the knowledge of 'Saankhya'
realises the fact
that he isn't a body
but a mere soul.
That the bliss and experiences of
the body are only until death.
And therefore, aren't real,
but just illusions.
For him becoming a 'Karma Yogi'
becomes easier.
But, Krishna
if deeds are meant to restrain
isn't it wise to renounce
the world
and embrace sainthood?
Such thinking is the sole reason
for this war today, Arjun!
Ponder over it.
When the ones possessing 'Gunas'
and the ones who know justice
give up deeds
then the ones full of injustice
run the world.
Had Grandsire Bhishma
not renounced the world
injustice wouldn't have
grown so vast today.
And had your father
not gone on an exile
brother Yudishtir would be
reigning in peace today
and would be teaching
his subjects
about justice and righteousness.
But Arjun, the sad truth is
that only the virtuous ones
can benefit the world.
But they are the ones
who often think of sainthood.
Just as water drifts away
as steam
and did keeps lying
right there, similarly
the virtuous and learned ones
give up the world
and unjust ones possessed by
'Tamas' function in the world.
Ought to this very reason sins
and injustice grow in the world.
But 'Karma Yoga'
protects this world
from this bizarre situation!
A 'karma Yogi' gives up
expectations of an outcome
but not the deeds themselves.
He stays in this very world
like a saint.
He performs all actions
but doesn't lose himself in one.
A 'Karma Yogi' expects nothing
from his children,
from his dear ones
and even his subjects at all.
He himself reaps the benefits
of sainthood.
But he benefits the world
like a familial head.
A human toils for the well being
of his off-springs.
How can he not expect joy
from his own off-springs?
Whatever a human does
for his children
is it a transaction
or an act of love?
Love, Krishna.
Then why expect an outcome
for his deeds, Arjun?
Future gains are measured
in a transaction
and not in love.
The human who moulds
his children's character well
and bestows the virtues of
love and justice upon them
his children shall surely give
him love and protection.
The deeds of one's children
and the behaviour of dear ones
reflect one's own deeds, Arjun.
And when one has no rights
upon their deeds
what is the use of having hopes
and expectations from them?
If you think deeply, Arjun,
you shall realise soon
that there is no deed in life
to which linking hopes
and expectations is inevitable.
When the creation is God
and human is a fragment of God
all actions are caused
by God himself.
A human does nothing on his own.
This is the base principle
of 'Karma Yoga', Arjun.
Hence it is necessary
that you become a 'Karma Yogi'
and fight this battle, Arjun.
By giving up three 'Gunas'
be free of them, Arjun.
Be free of this dilemma!
Always think for 'Sattva'
which is the Lord himself
and continue with your duties.
The desire to achieve something
and the thought of defending
something that was achieved
must be given up, Arjun
and liberate your soul.
Remember, Arjun.
Your right is only
to commit deeds.
The outcome relies on the Lord.
Therefore neither is it right
to run from deeds
nor is it right to expect
a return for your deeds.
The one who gives up
on outcomes
but does not give up deeds
how can such a 'Karma Yogi'
be recognised, Krishna?
Look, Arjun?
The one who gives up food
just to escape its taste
in reality the craving for taste
never leaves his mind.
He faces a twofold loss.
For one he becomes weak
due to which the inevitable
effort of attaining the Lord
cannot be done by him.
And secondly
his mind is always full
of craving for taste.
Hence rather than giving up food
one better gives up
the craving for taste itself.
A 'Karma Yogi' draws out
all cravings in his mind.
He accepts life as his duty
and does function.
But he is never in harmony
with his actions.
And Arjun
the one who has no hopes and
expectations from his actions
are the one whose motives
are fulfilled.
The one whose mind doesn't
falter even after one failure
The one who doesn't think he is
most superior after one success
such a person is called
a 'Karma Yogi'.
And such a person succeeds
in life repeatedly.
Wishes arise out of expectations
of outcome.
And it is a characteristic of
wishes to stay unfulfilled.
Unfulfilment gives rise
to anger.
And anger gives rise to desire.
Due to desire a person
forgets the knowledge
of behaviour and interaction.
Loss of knowledge causes
loss of virtue.
Inappropriate actions
take place.
And the society becomes
an enemy of such a person.
And in the end such a person
meets complete downfall.
Like for brother Duryodhan
his Commander-in-chief
Grandsire
is his enemy
and he blessed you
to emerge victorious.
Arjun
dutifulness is the second step
towards the divine knowledge.
Strengthen your faith
in the Almighty.
Know your own self.
Break free from the shackles
of bondage.
Sacrifice the desire of the
outcome and do only your duty.
By strengthening my faith
in the Almighty
how can I become dutiful?
Arjun, due to 'Sankhya Yoga'
a human keeps reminiscing
the Almighty.
Reminiscing the Almighty
gives birth to a sense
of submission.
And this sense is called
devotion.
Devotion enlightens a human
about what is right and wrong.
And that knowledge gives him
a glimpse of the Almighty.
The one who gets a glimpse
of the Almighty
he becomes the most Dutiful.
He is freed from the circle of
rebirth and attains salvation.
That is the ultimate aim
of all souls
and the pinnacle
of righteousness.
But how will I submit
without a glimpse
of the Almighty, Madhav?
To get a glimpse of the Almighty
get rid of
greed, pride, anger
and prejudice.
If a person sitting in
a dark room says
that he wants to see the Sun
what will you suggest him?
Won't you tell him to come out
of the room
and stand under an open sky?
Sun is already present there!
Similarly, Arjun, this universe
is the Almighty.
The Almighty is everything.
Nothing else other from Him.
The one who sees his soul
sees the Almighty.
Like the taste of
a single granule of salt
is indifferent from
the taste of the ocean
similarly
a soul is indifferent
from the Supreme Soul.
That means, Madhav
are you the Almighty?
Yes, Arjun.
I am the Almighty.
Just like you are.
But you aren't enlightened
about it
unlike me.
So, Madhav
why isn't submission before you
regarded submission before God?
Absolutely.
Submission before me is
submission before the Almighty.
Sacrifice everything
and seek my refuge, Arjun.
I am the universe.
I am present in every aspect
of the universe.
I am the Sun and I am the moon.
I am present in all the
constellations and planets.
I am more ancient than the Sun
and as new as
a blossoming flower.
I am the human race.
I am the power that creates
heaven and hell.
I am Duryodhan.
And I am Arjun too.
How is that possible, Madhav?
People have witnessed
your birth.
Your mother is still alive.
You took birth from her womb.
How can you be, both,
ancient and modern?
You are seeing the body
and I talk of the soul.
I have been born innumerable
times, Arjun.
I have many avatars.
I have taken up many forms
and have died right here!
And I will take many births
in the future, as well.
Whenever righteousness is harmed
whenever the
evil raises its hood
in order to rescue the righteous
to annihilate the evil
and to re-establish
righteousness, I'll take birth.
This has happened in every age
and will continue to happen
in future, as well.
I am the Almighty!
I was the Matsya avatar*
*The fish that kills Damanaka to save the vedas and also saves Manu from a great flood that submerges the entire Earth.
and the Vamana avatar.*
*The dwarf that grows into a giant to save the world from King Bali.
I am Parashurama and
I was Lord Rama!
I am Brahma, Vishnu and Mahesh (Shiva)!
And I am Saraswati, Kali
and Lakshmi, as well.
I am neither male nor female
nor a transgender.
I am neither the body
nor its parts.
I am knowledge, creation
reason and eternal.
I am everything!
Yet, I am nothing!
This has happened in every age
and will happen in future,
as well.