But brother Arjun
if you leave the city
then there will be
no Rajsuya 'Yajna.'
Sahadev
if the cows are
not brought back safely
then there will be
no reverence of the city.
We need those one lakh cows
for the reverence of the city.
But brother, think
about the future as well.
How will you live by yourself
for so many years?
And in the meantime,
without your protection
what will become
of Indraprastha, brother?
Duties build the future,
Sahadev
and not the other way around.
And how can you be worried about
the future of Indraprastha?
You can see the future,
can you not?
No one can ever see
the future clearly, brother.
But I have a bad feeling
that Indraprastha is
far from attaining peace.
Something disastrous
is going to happen here.
And at a time like this
if the city is
not protected by you then...
Please let me go get the cows!
Sahadev!
Takshak is an
illusory being, Sahadev.
You do not even have the weapons
bestowed by the Gods.
You will not be able
to defeat Takshak.
I have to do this.
We need to conduct the
reverence of the city soon.
We must ensure that brother
Yudhishthir becomes King soon!
But think about his situation
as well, brother.
When he finds out
that you have made such a
big sacrifice to make him King
what will his state
of mind be, brother?
Had we been five
this would have been
my sacrifice for him.
But we are one,
Sahadev.
I am making
this sacrifice for myself.
Let me go, Sahadev.
- No, brother.
I can go to Panchali's chamber
and get the Gandiva for you.
I shall perform this penance.
Wise men say that when
one is altruistic with food
and selfish with penance
only then does
one's body and soul
stay healthy.
Let me be selfish today.
What could have happened
that My Lord had to
break his oath?
What happened,
Sahadev?
Brother Yudhishthir
Takshak stole the cows
coming here from Hastinapur.
Brother Arjun
has gone after him.
Nakul, the venom needs to be
drawn out of the soldiers.
Go and wake the serpents up.
Brother Bheem,
brother Arjun has said that you
must make arrangements
to protect the city.
Let's go, Nakul.
Bheem, I shall come with you.
'The serpents
shown in this scene'
'were generated
using computer graphics.'
No serpent can ever escape
the circle of fire, Takshak.
If you are willing
to take my refuge
then I shall
extinguish the fire.
Take your refuge!
The refuge of a human?
No.
Shoot me with your arrow,
son of Pandu.
Kill me.
I cannot do that.
I have taken the oath
of not killing serpents.
But until you give into fatigue
and accept your defeat
I shall fight you.
I accept my defeat at the moment
son of Pandu.
Take your cows with you.
But our enmity
has not ended yet.
Today, if
you do not kill me
then do remember
that I
shall certainly be back
to have my revenge.
Certainly.
I shall be waiting.
We had taken an oath,
brother Yudhishthir.
I had entered
Panchali's chamber
without her permission.
I must resort to asceticism now
and perform an austere penance.
Arjun
I am the eldest son
of King Pandu.
Yet, history shall deem you
the hero amongst the Pandavas.
Give me your blessings,
brother Yudhishthir
to have appreciation
in my penance.
May your penance
experience
knowledge and competence
always meet with
appreciation, Arjun.
Bless you!
If you do go southward
then you must certainly go to Saurasen's kingdom.*
*Surasena, present-day Braj region in Uttar Pradesh.
I have heard that the food there
is the tastiest in the
entire Aryan region!
Brother Bheem
I am going to perform a penance.
I will consume bland food
and lead a controlled life.
Do not say that, brother.
I will start crying.
How can food
hamper one's penance?
We shall meet very soon, friend.
Where will you go
to perform the penance?
Manipur* in the East
*A state in northeastern India, with the city of Imphal as its capital.
and even Pragjyotishpur* are quite famous places.
*Pragjyotishpura, now Guwahati.
I wish to see those regions.
You may certainly go there.
But after you are
done travelling
you must come
to the city near Dwaraka
to perform your penance in the Somnath Temple.*
*Located in the Prabhas Kshetra, western coast of Gujarat, is one of the twelve Jyotirlinga shrines of the god Shiva.
Chandra* had been blessed with a new life there.
*The Lunar deity Soma (lit. "juice"), the juice of sap in the plants and thus makes the Moon the lord of plants and vegetation.
Possibly
you might just
find something there.
And that may complete
your penance.
As you say, Madhav.
Pardon me, Panchali.
Before taking
such a major decision
I could not seek
your permission.
You have taken the correct
decision, My Lord.
Your experience
will benefit our kingdom.
And I...
And I shall benefit from
the lesson of patience.
May there be appreciation
in your penance, My Lord.
Handmaidens.
'This life, this world'
'are all games
of time and tide.'
'What is bound to happen,
happens'
'and by its rules
we must abide.'
'Time is the strongest
in the world.'
'Joy and sorrow
are parts of life.'
'Only that happens
what is destined.'
'Time is the strongest
in the world.'
'Duties are more
important than life.'
'Actions are more important
than the amenities of life.'
'It is impossible to know
what fate has decided.'
'Once again, life
in the woods lies ahead.'
'The blissful life of a palace'
'must once again be sacrificed.'
'Time is the strongest
in the world.'
If I am a dedicated
and faithful wife
then no stone
or pebble in your path
will ever hurt you.