Is it a fist of arrogance
or a cupped palm of sacrifice
that you have assumed?
Can you digest this fact?
What is this world, Arjun?
Humans, demons, animals, birds
parasites, insects,
fishes, trees.
How are all these created?
What substance
are they created from?
How do they function
and how do they survive?
How do they die?
And what happens after death?
Ponder upon this secret.
A human body is made from dirt,
Krishna.
Water flows through it
as blood and other humours.
Fire gives the body heat.
And the blank voids in the body
consist of space.
Therefore, earth, wind, water,
fire and space...
The body is created from
these five base elements.
Therefore, Grandsire Bhishma,
Master Drona
are nothing more than earth,
water, wind
fire and space.
Even the learned scholars are
comprised of five base elements
and so are the tyrants.
So, what are you pining for,
Arjun?
For dirt?
But Krishna, it is through this
body made of dirt
that humans assume
their identities.
All bonds are rooted
in this body made of dirt.
No, Arjun!
If this were true
then why is one's body
destroyed post death?
In reality
neither is one's
identity from his body
nor are his relationships
rooted in his body.
One's behaviour and his nature
and his deeds are his identity.
How are behaviour, nature
and deeds even created?
Comprehend that, Arjun!
A human life
is a mere harmony of visible
and invisible entities, Arjun.
Yet every human's nature
and his deeds
seem to vary vastly.
The reason for it is the three 'Gunas'* of nature.
*Operational principles or tendencies.
'Tamas',* 'Rajas'** and 'Sattva'***.
*Negative, lethargic, dull, or slow. **Change, movement or dynamism. ***Balance, order, or purity.
What are these three properties,
Krishna?
'Tamas' means darkness.
Spending one's life without
presuming about good or bad
is said to be 'Tamas' oriented
behaviour.
Just as birds and animals live
solely to fulfill
their bodily cravings.
'Sattva' means
the light of knowledge.
When a person,
in every circumstance
thinks about justice, truth
and tradition before acting
then it is termed as
'Sattva' oriented way of life.
Amidst these two
is such a person
who does possess knowledge
but he is also tethered to
the desires of body and mind.
Such a person lives
with an arrogant
which means, 'Rajas' oriented
mindset.
By the very balance
of 'Tamas', 'Rajas'
and 'Sattva' 'Gunas'
a man's nature is determined.
Look ahead, Arjun!
What 'Gunas' do you see
in all of them?
Prince Duryodhan
knows what is just
but he never acts upon them.
His life revolves around
arrogance.
Therefore, he possesses
less of 'Tamas'.
He possesses more of 'Rajas'
and 'Sattva' is totally absent.
And over there
is Prince Dushyasan.
He has always obeyed
his elder brother's orders
without any forethought.
Therefore, he possesses
only 'Tamas'.
Look at Grandsire Bhishma
as well, Arjun.
He possesses balanced amounts
of 'Sattva' and 'Tamas'.
He harbours no arrogance.
But he is bound by outdated
thoughts and old traditions.
Even when the need arises
he cannot break his oath.
Look at
Master Drona!
He possesses both knowledge
and arrogance.
Knowledge liberates a human.
But his arrogance
won't let him attain liberation.
But Krishna
if a human's nature is the union
of these three 'Gunas'
is a human's actions
predestined?
That a lion shall
devour a gazelle
and a gazelle is bound to
fear a lion.
Then why is justice vital?
Why do crimes need
to be punished?
What is the purpose of that?
A brilliant question, Arjun!
But first comprehend what
a human being is!
A human isn't just the union
of the five base elements.
Not just five entities.
Five 'Gyanendriyas',* five 'Karmendriyas'**
*Sensory organs: Akshi (The Eyes), Karna (The Ears), Nasika (The Nostrils), Jihwa (The Tongue), Twacha (The Skin). **
and three 'Gunas'...
Not even just the union
of 23 such entities.
In order for a human
to walk around function
he needs energy.
And energy is termed as 'Chetana'.*
*Chaitanya: 'consciousness' or 'universal CHUT' or 'spirit' or 'intelligence' or 'sensation'.
So, Krishna, is a human
comprised of 'Chetana'?
No, Arjuna!
Along with a human's 'Chetana'
the union of those 23 entities
is creation.
Residing in this device called
human made of 24 entities
is a 'man', which means
a fragment of God.
That is termed the soul.
When the creation and man
become one
which means,
when a fragment of God
resides in one's body as a soul
that is when a human
comes to life.
What is a soul, Krishna?
And what is the means
of comprehending it?
Just as a human uses a chariot
similarly the soul uses
this device called a body.
Through the medium of a body
it experiences the joys
and sorrows of the body.
But the soul is not the body,
Arjun.
The body can be destroyed.
But a soul cannot be destroyed.
"Nainam chhindanti shastrani,
nainam dahati pavakah"
"na chamam kkadayanti apo,
na sosayati marutah."
A soul can neither be pierced
by weapons
nor can it be burnt with fire.
Nor can water render it weak,
nor can the wind dry it.
Even though a soul resides
in the body
it is immortal!
"Na hanyak: hanyamane sharire."
Arjun, a body can be killed
but the soul cannot
be killed!
A soul is omnipresent,
intangible, stable.
It is eternal.
Just as a man discards
old garments and wears new ones
similarly the soul leaves
an old body
and assumes a new body
time and again.
But, Krishna
I experience the world
through my body.
Without understanding
my very body
how can I understand my soul?
Knowing oneself
in the form of a soul
isn't impossible either,
Arjun.
Even the blind ones live.
Even the mute ones live.
Those who do not have
hands or legs live too.
It is clear that the body
is not what makes a human.
The ones who loses his energy
or loses his consciousness
lives as well.
Therefore it is clear
that a man's unconscious form
isn't the body either.
The one who explores within
himself in this way...
'I am neither the 'Indriyas'*, nor the body'
*Indriyadhisthana: the prime location of sensory perception (gayanendriyas).
'nor the feelings,
nor the thoughts'
'nor am I the thoughts.'
The one who understands this
finally understands himself
in the form of a soul.
What is the purpose of a soul,
Krishna?
When the creation
was partitioned
and when man and nature
were created
then the man, that is the
fragment of God became a soul
and dwelled within every
entity of creation.
That soul was surrounded
by desire and darkness, Arjun.
Awakening from that
slumber of desire
and understanding oneself
as the fragment of God
is the duty, purpose and
the goal of a soul.
But Krishna, if every soul
is a fragment of God
are progress and hindrance
controlled by God himself?
Just as a jewel lying in dirt
does not shimmer
similarly
the soul that is surrounded by
creation's 24 entities learns
that it is the fragment of God.
Very often souls assume that
their bodies are everything.
That they are different
from the body itself
is never known to them.
The joy, sorrow, smell, taste,
etcetera that the body senses
they assume them
to be their experiences
and they never strive
for change.
The souIs that do not
strive towards change
and are constantly
committing injustice
punishing them to awaken them
is inevitable.
You better comprehend this
as well, Arjun
that you are not a body
but a mere soul.
Every warrior seen
in this battlefield
isn't what you think he is.
They have all dwelt within
a body for a time period.
Their bodies shall die
But they are all immortal!
They shall assume new bodies
again.
Until they do not know
themselves as pure souls
until they give up injustice and
imbibe justice into themselves
they shall continue to be born
and die.
This is the first lesson of 'Bramha Vidya',* Arjun!
*Knowledge of the mantra/absolute.
The one who is born
shall surely die.
And the one who dies
shall surely be born again.
This great knowledge is called 'Sankya yoga'!*
*Samkhya philosophy regards the universe as consisting of two realities; Purusa (consciousness) and prakriti (phenomenal realm of matter). Jiva is that state in which purusa is bonded to prakriti through the glue of desire, and the end of this bondage is moksha.
What are justice and injustice,
Krishna?
The path treading which a man
sees himself as a soul
and knows himself
to be a fragment of God...
That path is called justice.
When a man and knows himself
to be a fragment of God
he has an epiphany
that creation is God
and God is creation.
There is no difference
between creation and God!
The human who comprehends this
isn't cruel and harsh towards
other humans and animals.
He knows that amputating
an organ causes pain
not just to that organ.
The pain is experienced
by the entire body.
Similarly, when one human
feels pain
the entire world
experiences that pain.
As long as even a single human
is suffering in this world
no one can feel true pleasure
to the fullest until then.
When upon knowing this
a human mind
is filled with compassion
it is called justice.
When one is under the influence
of 'Tamas' 'Guna'
he becomes harsh, cruel and
selfish towards others!
Just for the sake of his
perceived pleasure
he inflicts sorrow upon others.
He cannot grow closer
towards God.
Therefore
injustice is the path that
leads away from God.
Therefore, injustice is another
name for ignorance.
So, one needs to feel pity
towards an ignorant one.
What is the purpose
of punishment?
When an ignorant one
is unwilling
to know the value of knowledge
and is unwilling to even glance
at knowledge
then punishment is compassion
even towards him
and towards others as well.
For the creation's progress
to be always towards God
is inevitable!
But at times situations arise
when ignorance, desire
and injustice grow
and justice in the world
is at the brink of extinction
and the world is devoid
of justice
compassion and truth
are both destroyed.
In order for the forthcoming
generations to get justice
slaying unjust ones today
and re-establishing justice
is inevitable!
Today is a similar situation,
Arjun!
And the duty to establish
justice is yours!
Hence overcome your weakness
and prepare for this battle!
But murders shall occur
at my hands, Krishna!
If lives are ended by me
won't that destroy
the compassion within me?
And if compassion
is the basis of justice
won't my soul become unjust?
The limit of justice
is surely created.
But the limit of actions
isn't created, Arjun.
The difference between
actions and deeds
is necessary to be understood.
All deeds are actions,
but all actions aren't deeds.
A deed is an action
for which an outcome
is expected.
When one carries out a deed
expecting pleasure,
wealth and praise
he is bound by the outcome
of that action.
When a deed is performed with
an expectation of an outcome
it is called 'Sakam Karma Yoga'.*
*Self-centred action.
And when a deed is carried out
without expecting an outcome
it is called 'Nishkaam Karma Yoga'.*
*Self-less or desireless action: action performed without any expectation of fruits or results, and the central tenet of Karma Yoga path to Liberation.
This is the very reason
he has to be born repeatedly.
In reality a man isn't
bound by a deed.
The expectations linked to
that deed is what bounds him.