I did not get the opportunity
to meet brother Arjun again.
And I also could not seek
the blessings of Mother Kunti.
Rukmini, look behind you.
What do you see?
Our footprints, My Lord.
Look.
Those prints got washed away
by the waves, Rukmini.
Footprints not being visible
does not mean
that the ones who made them
are also not present.
Does this mean
the Pandavas are alive?
I do not know
but if they are alive
then I need to meet them soon.
But why do you not answer me
whether they are alive or not?
A definite answer?
Its definite answer is, Rukmini
that it is time for
the entire society to change.
Look from Magadha to Matsya
and from Kuru to Vidarbha.
Subjects...
Subjects toil in the fields.
They enter the mines to dig out
iron, gold and precious gems.
They break down rocks
to construct buildings.
In other words, subjects yield
the entire wealth.
But what do they get in return?
They get hunger, poverty
and injustice in return.
And the Kings, Rulers
and Emperors get wealthier.
Have you ever seen a King who is
concerned for his subjects?
A King who is concerned
for their happiness.
for their welfare.
No, correct?
And this is what God
calls unrighteousness.
When such unrighteousness
gets out of hand
in order to salvage the world,
God gives birth to people
who have
a righteous heart.
Until things change
until subjects of a kingdom
gain true happiness
those great men sent by God
do not die, Rukmini.
I have complete faith
that they are alive.
And I shall meet them very soon
in Panchal.
Why in Panchal?
We shall meet in Panchal,
Rukmini
because there in the mud
of unrighteousness
the lotus of righteousness
is about to be born.
Such a power is about
to be born there
that will change the future
of the entire Aryan region.
And I have to go there
to protect this power.
From who?
From the one who is going
to give birth to that power.
In other words
from the King of Panchal,
Drupad.
'Panchal
- the City of Kampilya.'
W-Water...
With whose permission are you
giving him water, Shikhandini?
If they do not get water,
they will die.
And we will commit the sin
of killing a sage, father.
Fool!
They are fated to die.
He is not a sage
but a charlatan!
All of them are charlatans!
If the water of a river
is unfit for drinking
it is best for that river
to dry up.
If your rigourous meditation
cannot give me a son
then why
should I allow you to live?
But you are destined
to have a daughter,
Your Highness.
You shall not have a son.
Stop, King Drupad.
King Drupad,
by killing these sages
you are paving your way to hell.
We shall fulfill your wish.
The great sages Yaja
and Upayaja,*
*Two sage brothers that lived on the banks of the Ganga.
when I had approached you
you had no intention of
performing a 'yajna' for me.
Are you scared now
that you will die at my hands?
We do not fear for our lives
but for that of
thousands of sages.
So, in order to save the lives
of a handful of sages
you are going to perform
a charade of a 'yajna?'
Or in order to
bless me with a son
you wish to perform the 'yajna'
great sage Yaja?
Tell me the truth.
You shall indeed have a son
from the 'yajna.'
But King Drupad
you are destined
to have a daughter.
And when you
accept your daughter
only then will you get your son
from the Gods.
And when you
accept your daughter
only then will you get your son
from the Gods.
- Daughter!
I have got nothing
to do with a daughter!
She cannot defend
the honour of her father!
She cannot take revenge
for the insult he faced!
This Shikhandini...
At the time of her birth,
everyone had said
that Bhishma will die
at her hands!
He had insulted my father!
She was supposed to
take revenge for that!
With that hope in his heart
my father passed away!
But she did nothing.
In order to have a son
if I need to accept a daughter
then so be it!
She can stay in a corner
of my palace!
But I
want a son.
Your words reflect ignorance,
Your Highness.
In this world
it is the greatest honour
to have a daughter.
Do not forget that he had
given birth only to daughters
yet we call Daksh* as Prajapati.**
*"Competent", a great king, he had 89 daughters from his wife Prasuti and another 116 from his wife Panchajani (Virini).
**"Lord of creatures".
It was through his daughters
that life sprang in all spheres.
King Drupad
understand this truth real well.
The maiden born from the 'yajna'
will fulfill
all your hopes and desires.
She will gain fame
in the entire Aryan region
for the re-establishment
of righteousness.
That maiden
will change
the course of history
and will mould
the future.
You have brought us
our meal, Arjun.
Come on.
We'll finish all this later.
Duryodhan may snatch
a palace from me
but not my teeth and stomach.
No matter how hard
he tries to cause me pain
but as long as I can eat
nothing can pain me.
Mother
do serve us our meal.
Do begin.
Stop, mother.
Looking at this meal
has reminded me of something.
When we were dining
for the first time in Hastinapur
grandsire had told us
to eat without folding our arms.
Can you show us how to do so?
Without folding the arm?
Mother
as long as we are together
you will not shed tears.
As long as we are together
neither do we
need to fold our arms
nor bow our heads before anyone.
But all of us must take turns
to feed brother Bheem.
I cannot feed him every day.