I will not let this 'yajna'
get completed at any cost.
Krishna's plan will fail.
And if you are able to do that,
Crown Prince Shishupal
then I shall use my mace
to protect you.
I give you my word.
Weak and foolish people like you
are of no use to me,
Duryodhan.
I can be slain
only by the person
who had taken my additional arms
and third eye from me.
In other words,
Krishna.
But he will not kill me
because my mother
had made him promise
that he will pardon
100 misdeeds of mine.
Nevertheless, knowing that
you are on my side
has left me exceedingly pleased.
'The fishes shown in this scene'
'have been generated
using computer graphics.'
The ritual is now complete.
You may be seated
on the throne now
and then distribute
the offertory to the guests.
After you are done with it
we will proceed
to the next phase
in which four
representative Kings
will build a canopy
on your throne.
Only then will you be declared
the supreme Emperor.
Bless you!
Revered guests
our mother had taken the oath
that only after the city
of her sons becomes independent
will she enter Indraprastha.
Hence, we were compelled
to engage in labour
and demonstrate our valour.
Because of the teachings
of our revered grandsire Bhishma
we have been successful
in this endeavour.
Only after seeking the blessings
of both these people
will I have the right
to be seated on the throne.
I welcome mother and grandsire
to this gathering!
All hail His Excellency Bhishma!
All hail Queen Mother Kunti!
May you live long!
Greetings, grandsire.
Bless you all!
Seeing this city of yours
has made me very proud.
Give your mother Kunti
a grand welcome
and have her seated at
the highest place in the court.
I have been a witness
to her struggles.
All of you
are reaping the rewards
of her struggles.
Bless you!
Get up,
Yudhishthir.
Apart from the Almighty
a King does not prostrate
before anyone else.
If you do not allow me
to break this tradition, mother
then I will not be able
to sit on the throne.
Go on,
son.
Be seated on your throne
and grace this court.
All hail the supreme
Emperor Yudhishthir!
All hail Empress Draupadi!
The 'yajna' is almost complete,
Crown Prince Shishupal
but you have
not yet tarnished it.
A few rituals are
yet to be completed
Crown Prince Duryodhan.
First, Yudhishthir
will sit on the throne
then he will be crowned
and finally,
he will distribute
the offertory to the sages
and the Kings.
However, if the Rajsuya 'Yajna'
is interrupted before he does so
it will be deemed unsuccessful,
Crown Prince Duryodhan.
And there are bound to be
a few lapses
in such a grand ceremony.
I am looking for that lapse,
Crown Prince.
But where is the throne?
Despite being an Emperor
how can he sit on the ground?!
All hail the supreme
Emperor Yudhishthir!
All hail Empress Draupadi!
All hail the supreme
Emperor Yudhishthir!
All hail Empress Draupadi!
Dear Yudhishthir
the way Surya Dev
graces the entire sky
by spreading his brilliant rays
and dispels the fear
of darkness in men
similarly
the Kings, who have
accepted your status
as the supreme Emperor
need to be sprinkled
with water on their heads
by you to rid them of fear.
This is the duty
of a supreme Emperor.
As you say,
Sage Vyas-
But dear,
Surya Dev himself
is under the authority
of Lord Vishnu in the heavens.
A supreme King
accepting the authority
of another person
is deemed correct
by the 'shastras.'
A person
who can guide
the Emperor to righteousness.
Upon whose advice
the supreme Emperor
would engage in a battle
or call a truce.
Seeking the blessings
of such a person
and giving him the offertory
first is a tradition.
This tradition
is also called 'pudovas'
or 'prathamarghya.'
Who will you offer
the 'pudovas', dear?
Guide me in this,
Sage Vyas.
Either His Excellency Bhishma
or Vasudev Krishna
can be chosen for this ritual.
No, dear.
A person who is surrounded
by selfishness and greed
or there is a doubt to his
status of a righteous man
or is bound by the orders
of another person
does not have
the right to the
'prathamarghya.'
I am the General of Hastinapur.
Obeying the orders
of King Dhritarashtra
is my prime duty.
That is why,
dear
I cannot accept
this 'prathamarghya.'
I think
Vasudev Krishna
rightfully deserves
the 'prathamarghya.'
Revered guests
righteousness,
freedom and selflessness
are three virtues
mentioned by grandsire
all of which reside in Vasudev.
We brothers have been guided
several times by Vasudev.
He has the knowledge of the soul
the beauty of the mind
the agility of thoughts
and the strength
of determination.
Vasudev
do accept the 'prathamarghya'
being offered to you.
Sahadev
cleanse the feet of Vasudev
and demonstrate the dedication
of us brothers towards him.
Did you see that?!
That was utterly foolish
of Yudhishthir!
Now, under no circumstance
will I let this 'yajna'
get completed.
Stop, Emperor Yudhishthir!
So many great Kings have
displayed their
dedication to you.
By choosing
a deceitful and cunning cowherd
to offer the 'prathamarghya'
you cannot insult us!
Our supreme Emperor
being under
the authority of a fool
is not something we will
accept, King Yudhishthir!
Crown Prince of Chedi
who is more deserving
than Vasudev in this court?
Righteousness
and unrighteousness
this world and the other
the soul and the Almighty
the truth and the lies
are known best
by no one but Vasudev.
All that is a lie!
Kings present here
if you look carefully
at the life of that Yadava
then you will know quite easily
that all he has ever done
is deceive and cheat people!
The milk and butter
that rightfully belonged
to King Kansa
was stolen by him
during his childhood!
That person
would instigate people
to revolt against King Kansa!
He led to the untimely deaths of
various friends of King Kansa.
Putana,
Bakasura
Chanun
Mushtik...
The list is endless,
Kings!
He is the one who stopped people
from worshipping Lord Indra.
That person
is not only a thief
but also an unrighteous man.
He is a rebel!
He is a liar!
Can the one who heeds his advice
ever work towards the welfare
of the Aryan region?
Tell me, Kings!
How can he work towards it?!
Be quiet,
Crown Prince of Chedi!
Your rambling on about Vasudev
is intolerable to me!
So, will you kill me?
Bheem, is only
your exterior that big
or do you have
any intelligence as well?
Just look at that
Vrikodar Bheem, Kings!
Just look!
He married a female ogre.
Now, tell me, Kings...
How can the dog that eats
the leftovers of people
ever be allowed to take
part in a veneration?!
But such an unrighteous Vrikodar
is deemed highly of
by that treacherous Krishna!
But such an unrighteous Vrikodar
is deemed highly of
by that treacherous Krishna!
Shishupal!
I will behead you!
Calm down,
Bheem!
Until His Highness
awards him a punishment
you cannot lay a finger on him
in this court.
Crown Prince of Chedi
do not cross your limits
in this court of mine.
Kings, this Yudhishthir...
He...
He is preaching to me
about crossing my limits
while he gave a runaway cowherd
the highest honour
in this court!
Yudhishthir
did your father
not teach you what is correct
and what is not?
But how could he?!
Pandu himself
had committed the unrighteous
deed of killing a sage.
Crown Prince of Chedi!
If you
have a problem with
our Rajsuya 'Yajna'
then return to your kingdom
and wait to confront our army!
I promise you
that until you die
a canopy will not be built above
brother Yudhishthir's throne!
But do not resort
to verbal abuses
and diminish your respect.
You better be quiet,
Arjun.
By having the right thumb
of the poor Ekalavya cut
you have learnt
the art of archery.
You are the most treacherous
and lying low-life
I have ever seen!
Go
and drown yourself somewhere!
So, Kings!
The father of that Krishna
was a criminal!
That is why,
King Kansa
had imprisoned
Vasudev and Devaki.
Now, tell me! What is a person
born in a prison cell
called, Kings?!
What is he?!
A criminal.
Krishna is a criminal!
A criminal!
Crown Prince Shishupal
if you do not leave
my court this instant
then I will have to
sentence you to death.
I do not fear anyone.
Get up, Kings!
Get up!
These cowardly Pandavas
have no competence!
If they had any,
Emperor Jarasandha
would never have been
killed deceitfully!
In order to prove himself
as the most powerful man
in the entire Aryan region
that treacherous Krishna
has weaved a web of deception.