The Lord has ordered
you to get married
tomorrow at dawn
to Princess Hidimha.
And after that, we will
make a sacrifice
and worship the
new King and Queen.
Let's leave, mother.
Brother Yudhishthir,
let's leave.
Why is King Vrikodar so angry?
Did we make a mistake?
No, you have made no mistake.
We chanced upon this place
during our journey.
We did not come here with the
intention of ruling this place.
If that was the case then
why did you kill our King?
It is our tradition that the one
who kills the King
becomes the next King
and marries the daughter
or sister of the former King.
If this does not happen,
we will have no King at all.
There will be petty
conflicts amongst us
and our youth
will become misguided.
Be it humans or ogres
traditions are
the basis of society.
You have no right to toy
with our traditions.
Since you have
created this problem
you must also come up
with a solution.
Dear
you need not worry.
My son Yudhishthir
is a very intelligent
and righteous man.
He will never allow anything bad
to happen to your subjects.
But what will become
of me, My Lady?
What about our tradition?
I have accepted your son
whole-heartedly as the King
and as my husband.
The complexion and behaviour
of us ogres
may be different
from that of humans
but the heart
and the love within it
is same for all beings, My Lady.
But dear
the marriage of an ogre
and a human...
How is that possible?
The great sage Vishwashrava had
also married the ogre Kaikasi.
And they had a son like Ravan.
But they also had
Vibhishan, My Lady.
I promise you
that I will raise my sons
to be like Vibhishan.
Try to understand
my love, My Lady.
Is receiving clarified butter
either as sacrament or alms
not worthy of acceptance?
Accepting what is pure
has always been deemed correct.
So say the religious texts
of humans beings.
My love is also pure, My Lady.
Please accept me as your
daughter-in-law.
You are not only
a woman, Hidimba
but also the Queen after
the demise of your brother.
How will you
renounce your subjects?
And my son...
How can he spend
his remaining life
living amongst ogres?
Hidimba
it would be best
if you forget my son.
Appoint a worthy ogre
as the new King
and work for the welfare
of your subjects.
For a little while, My Lady!
If I can be the wife of
your son for a little while
then I shall spend my whole life
with those memories.
For a little while, My Lady.
Until our first child is born.
That child will become
the King of the Ogres.
I promise you, My Lady!
That after that child is born
I will not ask any of you
to stay even a day longer.
I promise you this.
You shall earn the merit
of giving alms to a beggar.
You shall earn the merit...
You shall earn the merit
of giving alms to a beggar.
You shall earn the merit...
Get up, dear.
My daughter-in-law
can never ask for alms.
Bring the garlands.
King Vrikodar
place the garland around
the neck of the Princess.
She will refuse
to wear the garland
but if you succeed in doing so
then you shall receive
the blessings of the Lord.
You shall get
only three attempts.
So, go ahead.
This is the first wedding
of the Kuru dynasty.
Had we received
uncle's blessings
I would have felt contented.
Is this marriage
correct, brother Yudhishthir?
Mother's decision
is always correct.
But
the marriage of an ogre
and a human...
Hidimba's love is pure, son.
Using shackles like complexion,
creed and correctness
to enslave love
is not correct.
Mother is correct.
Look at Hidimba's face.
It is glowing with happiness.
The look of happiness on
brother Bheem's face is no less.
I was just jesting, mother.
Go on.
All hail King Vrikodar!
Bless you.
'Hastinapur.'
'A while later.'
'The priest from
the kingdom of Panchal'
seeks permission
to meet His Highness.
May the Lord
bless His Highness
Dhritarashtra.
The King of Panchal has sent
you a present, Your Highness.
What is it, Duryodhan?
It is an earthen pot, father.
Since when did the King of
Panchal become so impoverished
that instead of a gold pot
he has sent an earthen one?
What is inside it?
Only an earthen pot can
hold fire, Your Highness.
The Prince ought to know this.
There is a letter for you.
- What does it say?
Nothing is written
on it, father.
Duryodhan
hold this letter above
the fire in that pot.
The message will appear.
Then do it yourself, Minister.
Your Highness
a 'swayamvar' for the
Princess of Panchal, Draupadi
is being held
and this is its invite.
What is the meaning of sending
an invite in this manner, Vidur?
Our Princess was born
from the fire, Your Highness.
And this magical pot has
the power to bear fire in it.
If there is such a
Crown Prince in the kingdom
then he is invited to take part
in the competition, My Lord.
Was that an invitation
or an insult, father?
It is just like fire, beloved.
Just like fire.
If one can control it
it gives life
but if one cannot
it leads to death.
The truth is that this letter
is an invite
and also an insult.
Is there a Crown Prince
in Hastinapur
who can be sent
to this 'swayamvar?'
Certainly.
I am the heir to this kingdom.
But my beloved
you have not yet been
declared the Crown Prince.
And the invitation is only
for the Crown Prince.
Whether you are
the Crown Prince or not
can be clarified
only by His Highness.
Yes.
After hearing this message
I can declare you
the Crown Prince, son.
Then it is time for me
to go and talk to grandsire
himself, father.