And
what about
the five sons of mine?
Govind!
Will they...
Will they d-die as well?
Govind
I beg of you!
Please give me
a definite answer this time.
Tell me, Govind!
What will be
the outcome of the war?
I want to know, Govind!
Tell me.
A war always brings
destruction, Panchali.
Nothing but agony and suffering
are born in the battlefield.
How could you think, there
would be joy for you in it?
Yes.
Apart from the five
husbands of yours
the entire lineage
of King Shantanu
will be destroyed.
The entire dynasty will be
annihilated in this war.
Govind
will King Pandu's entire dynasty
be sacrificed in this war?
My children...
During times of struggle
their mere thought would
give us the strength we needed.
Their birth had given us...
Had given us a new life.
Will they die?
In other words
the war we are preparing for
with such zeal
and fervour, Govind
is like a preparation...
Like a preparation
for sending our children to die?
There is not a moment
in a man's life
when he is not walking
towards death, friend.
The truth is,
are all his activities
not aimed at dying?
Is each leaf born during spring
not meant to fall off
during the fall?
Is its birth
absorbing the rays of the sun
and producing a melody
while swaying in the wind
utterly worthless?
When a tornado shakes up a tree
each leaf of that tree
tries its very best
to hold onto it.
And when the leaves turn yellow
they fall off gladly.
The creation is also
like a great tree, friend.
And every human being,
flora and fauna is a leaf
which grows and then falls off
that tree.
Their falling off is certain
but until they are on the tree
it is vital for them
to experience both
struggle and peace.
I see no upside to this,
Govind.
Because you are bound
by attachment, friend.
Yes!
I am bound by attachment,
Govind.
And even if we emerge
victorious in this war
it will give me no joy.
When did I say that you would
get joy out of this war, friend?
When did I advise you to fight
to seek revenge,
respect and property?
This war
is for the joy
of the society, friend.
In order to put an end
to unrighteousness
and to establish
righteousness again
we must fight this war,
friend.
Why should such a big sacrifice
be made by us,
Govind?
Why?
Listen, friend.
In a society, man must abide by
rules, ideals and righteousness.
These three entities are like
sand castles
built on the sea-shore.
The waves of time
keep breaking them constantly.
They need to be
built time and again
otherwise
rules, ideals and righteousness
get annihilated.
The Almighty gives
very few the strength
needed to establish
righteousness again.
And even after sacrificing
everything they have
the people who have
this strength
end up struggling
for righteousness.
Be it Lord Ram
Lord Parashuram
or the Vaman Avatar of Vishnu
this world reveres only those
who struggle towards
establishing righteousness.
You must understand,
friend
that struggling
for righteousness
is not a duty
but a decision
and a vow.
Similarly, for you,
this war
is not a duty.
It is a vow
taken for the society.
You may break this vow
whenever you want.
You might
just be blessed with the joy
of children, husbands
and grandchildren
but like millions of people
you too will be lost
in the sands of time, friend.
Your life will become worthless.
Because of you
no one will benefit anything.
The Almighty who has
given you special powers
will lose His faith in you.
The decision
is yours, friend.
Sister-in-law!
Come here.
Sister-in-law
here we have a coconut, a hair
ornament and a wedding dress.
We need to present
all this to Uttara.
Let's go.
Sister-in-law
please come.
place your hand on this.
'Apart from the five
husbands of yours'
'the entire lineage
of King Shantanu'
'will be destroyed.'
'The entire dynasty will be
annihilated in this war.'
Sons
can someone tell me
how these 'laddoos'
can be consumed
without folding the arm?
Our sons have reminded us
of our childhood.
You are correct,
brother Bheem.
And after a few years
their children will remind them
of their childhood.
In other words, our sons
have immortalised us.
Mother Draupadi...
Mother Draupadi.
Mother?
Please tell us
how we can eat
without folding our arms.
Please tell us, mother.
Please come.
Come with me.
Come.
Be seated.
Tell us,
Mother Draupadi.
How do we eat
without folding our arms?
What decision
have you taken, friend?
Govind
a sapling planted by a person
cannot be pulled out by him.
How will I be able
to see my sons die?
In the court of Hastinapur,
a woman was insulted
but she tolerated it.
But a mother will not be able to
tolerate her sons getting slain
Govind.
A wife tolerated
the loss of property
of her husbands
but a mother will not be able to
tolerate the death of her sons
Govind.
No.
I am willing
to forget all the insults,
Govind.
This property,
the empire...
I am willing to give up
all of it, Govind.
But no...
I cannot send my sons
to the battlefield.
No.
No, Govind.
I do not want a war.