'Om Namah Shivaya.'
'Om Namah Shivaya.
Om Namah Shivaya.'
'Om Namah Shivaya.'
Greetings, grandsire.
Greetings.
- Grandsire
I want to ask you a question.
You have unfathomable
knowledge of correctness.
It is said that a kingdom
devoid of a Crown Prince
is a one devoid of
the grace of the Gods.
Then why are you
keeping Hastinapur away
from the grace of the Gods?
Somewhere in Hastinapur
or in the Kuru kingdom
was there a scant amount of rain
leading to a drought?
Or are humans and cattle dying
without any apparent reason
in the kingdom?
Then how can you deem
that we do not have
the grace of the Gods?
How could you deem
that Hastinapur is
devoid of a Crown Prince?
Who is the Crown Prince?
Brother Yudhishthir
has passed away
and I have
not been anointed yet.
Nevertheless
the Gods have not kept us
away from their grace.
What is it that I am holding?
A piece of sandalwood.
Even after being abraded,
it continues emitting fragrance.
Same is the case with
being a Crown Prince.
Whether the throne is occupied
by a Crown Prince or not
the Gods know whether a Crown
Prince is present in the kingdom
or not.
Does this mean, the Gods
know that I am the Crown Prince?
Then why am I not
being anointed as one?
Then the Kings of the
Aryan region will know
that I am the Crown Prince
of Hastinapur.
What the Gods know is the truth.
What the Kings of
the Aryan region know
changes every day.
And that is why
them knowing of it
has no value.
However, for your
contentment, if
you wish to convey
this to those Kings
then who am I to stop you?
You have been exceedingly
gracious, grandsire.
Let me go tell
father about this.
Greetings.
Greetings, uncle.
Greetings, Vidur.
You
gave Duryodhan the permission
to be anointed, uncle?
Yes.
When a Crown Prince
is already present
then even if other people
bathe in milk every day
they do not become
the Crown Prince.
Let the anointment take place.
When Yudhishthir
will return
this anointment will
get nullified on its own.
But our spies have not yet
found the Pandavas, uncle.
Who knows when they will return.
And until then, will Duryodhan
not get himself anointed?
That will not happen.
The sons of Pandu
will return soon.
I have got the news of
where they are.
But how, uncle?
Did you not hear
that a while ago,
the King of the Ogres
Hidimb was killed?
Apart from Bheem,
who else can achieve this?
Bheem
you have become a father!
Today, your ancestors must be
showering their blessings on you
from the heavens.
Hidimba has
given birth to a son!
You ought to jubilate
and worship your King Vrikodar!
Your future King has been born!
My love, this day has brought
the greatest joy for me.
But along with this joy
there is also a great sorrow.
A great sorrow.
Congratulations, brother Bheem!
You have become a father.
You have to become serious now.
If we laugh at you now,
you cannot get angry.
Anoint him with
your blood, Vrikodar.
When a father anoints his
ogre sons with his blood
they become adults.
Vrikodar
give your son a name.
Me?
What should I name him?
Bheem, any name
that you like.
My son's bald head
is shining like a pot.
I name him Ghatotkacha.*
*"Bald Pot".
Son
this is your grandmother
and these are your uncles.
Go on.
Touch their feet
to seek their blessings.
Bless you!
May you live long.
May you be patient.
May you be victorious.
May you be powerful.
Son
your father, King Vrikodar
is returning to the realm
of humans today.
Bid him goodbye
and seek his blessings.
We can stay here
a while longer, dear...
If you want us to.
I wish to keep all of you
here for life, mother-in-law
but I had promised you
that after the birth
of our first child
I will not ask any of you
to stay here even a day longer.
Then how can
your daughter-in-law
break her promise,
mother-in-law?
You are the ideal woman,
Hidimba.
In the future
not only ogres
but also humans will
derive motivation from you.
People will deem you a Goddess
and worship you.
Bless you, dear!
Father, whenever
you take my name thrice
I shall appear before you
to be at your service.
All hail Prince Duryodhan!
Friend Kama
do you know the importance
of this day?
Until now, my life was filled
with the darkness of the night
and unfulfilled dreams.
But henceforth, I shall
have the light of the day
and all my dreams
will be fulfilled.