Soldiers!
Take the cavalry and fortify
the entrance gates.
Archers, assume
your posts at the
top of the gates
with fire arrows.
All infantry units, keep vigil
within the fort.
And the cavalry, outside
the fort, behind the hillock.
Close the fort's gate.
What is the news, Madan?
- It's a vast army, commander.
It flows like the tides
of the river Sindhu.
Infantry, cavalry and chariots
are endless in numbers.
Their heavy marching is
kicking up the dirt, sky high.
They have rations and water for
the soldiers too, your majesty.
They seem to have prepared
for a lengthy conquest.
Whose army is it, soldier?
I couldn't see their banner,
your majesty.
But I could see the chariot
at their forefront.
It's a chariot of white horses
like that of the
Sun-God himself.
There's a white flag on the
chariot too, your majesty.
And on the flag is a golden
emblem of a Banyan tree.
That great man resembled
the blazing Sun-God himself.
He had an ornate armour
upon his body.
His arms are like
pillars of iron.
Eyes, intense as two fireballs.
And the seal of the moon
adorns his forehead.
Your highness, this warrior is
none else but the very son
of the great King Shantanu
and mother Ganga.
Bheeshma.
Mother, what is happening
around here?
Did you not hear?
Hastinapur has attacked.
What shall happen now,
mother?
Gandhar's army stands no chance
before Hastinapur's forces.
Streams of blood shall flow.
Within a matter of days
the fort of Gandhar shall
be reduced to rubble.
Accepting defeat even before
the battle isn't wise, Aarshi.
I beg your pardon,
your highness.
But Gandhar hasn't waged war
since many years.
So you aren't aware.
Demolishing defeated cities,
burning the homeless.
Killing the innocent and
violating the honor of women.
All these are unavoidable
in a war, Gandhari.
What shall we do now,
sister-in-law?
What all the other women
do during battle.
Wait here for our
ultimate doom.
And then..
Sister-in-law.
Pick up a weapon.
I shall participate in the
battle alongside father.
Gandhari!
- Yes, mother.
This war terrifies me
as much as darkness does.
Sister-in-law, the great
teacher had taught us
that there is just one way
to overcome your fears.
Embrace that fear.
If death is inevitable
then I shall die
in the battlefield.
Fear always roots itself
within the human heart.
Sometimes, the fear
of losing wealth.
of humiliation.
Sometimes, the fear of being
separated from your loved ones.
Hence
presence of fear
seems normal to all.
Have you ever thought?
Is it that the situation
or the object that causes fear
is also the origin
of grief?
No.
There is no rule as such.
And everyone's experience
in fact tells
that being scared does not
solve problems in the future.
Fear is only the imagination
of the grief to come.
It has no relationship
with reality whatsoever.
Despite knowing that
fear is nothing but imagination
is it difficult to be free from
it and live fearlessly?
Think about it.
What are the orders,
your majesty?
It is time to respond to
the siege, your majesty.
The white banner of surrender
or the red banner of war!
Humiliation or death..
Never did these two colours
seem so dark, Shatasva.
But, your majesty.
We have to wave
one of these two banners.
The army has stopped
marching, your majesty.
Surprising indeed.
They're waving the yellow banner
of friendship, your majesty.
Open the gates of the fort.
If he wanted a dialogue,
why did he bring his army along?
Must be, to flaunt his power
before us.
But why?
Gandhar has done nothing
to cause insult to Hastinapur.
Hastinapur's throne has been
vacant for so long now.
After the death of
Emperor Vichitravirya
the kingdom has no king
for the past 25 years.
Yet, we never tried to
attack them.
We never allied with
any of their enemies.
Then, what was the need to
flaunt power before an ally?
Your majesty, Power is flaunted
before an ally
when one has some
demands to make.
What could a veteran such as
Bheeshma want from me?
A king should join hands
only before the Gods.
To embrace his allies and
to punish his foes
is what truly befits him,
king Subal.
Your heroic deeds aren't lesser
than that of a God,
Son of Ganges.
But I'm not a king. l'm just
a royal servant of Hastinapur.
My status isn't higher
than yours, your majesty.
Although you may
not be a king
your calibre is greater than
any emperor, son of Ganges.
Calibre comes into picture
only during a siege.
And I'm here,
to visit my friend's home.
To strengthen our friendship.
And to play host
to a friend like you
is the good fortune of
Gandhar, son of Ganges.
All hail Bheeshma,
the son of Ganges.
Sister-in-law.
Sister-in-law, Bheeshma
has arrived only to befriend us.
I heard so, princess.
A great calamity in Gandhar
has been averted.
What is your opinion,
sister-in-law?
Could he be masking
his intentions of war
behind the facade
of an alliance?
I've heard that Bheeshma
never lies, princess.
I've heard there is none
more powerful than him
among the Aryas.
Yes, Sugdha.
Even Parshuram
couldn't defeat him.
A powerful man is always calm
and composed.
Let's see for ourselves.
It shall be proved whether he is
truly powerful
or is it all just tall tales.
- I can't help but wonder
what the powerful Bheeshma could
possibly demand from Gandhar.
Retire.
Looking at such a grand welcome
and vast affection
my heart is truly
overwhelmed.
I hope you have imbued
the same elegance and discipline
into your daughter
and daughter-in law too
Son of ganges, What could our
miniscule Gandhar offer
to the glorious and powerful
Kuru empire?
A future.
And the prospect of
happiness in that future.
Your majesty, you are aware that
no king has attacked you so far.
Because you have the protection
of the Kuru empire.
If the subjects of the
Kuru empire and Gandhar unite
then both the kingdoms shall
become incredibly powerful.
Think about it,
your majesty.
An alliance is formed between
two equally powerful kings.
Gandhar is a mere servant
to Hastinapur, son of Ganges.
Your majesty. Hence, l put forth
not an alliance, but a proposal.
A wedding proposal.
The whole Arya clan talks highly
of the beauty and virtues
of your daughter,
princess Gandhari.
I put forth a wedding proposal
for princess Gandhari.
Do not disappoint me.
But haven't you sworn yourself
to celibacy, son of ganges?
Princess Gandhari's proposal
is for a Kuru prince.
Not myself.
I consider Gandhari to
be my daughter.
I am in agreement
to this.
Who can be a better groom
than prince Pandu?
Prince Pandu's competence
and prowess are known to all.
Dhritarashtra.
Prince Dhritarashtra.
From where did prince Pandu
crop into the picture?
He is the younger son.
Prince Dhritarashtra
is the elder son.
Your majesty.
I am talking about
Prince Dhritarashtra.
Think it over, your majesty.
A hundred sons can be borne
even by a sculptor's wife.
They may build
a colossal house too.
But, not an entire kingdom.
The number of offsprings
is not important.
What matters
is the clan whose virtues and
upbringing they imbibe within.
Not every woman has the
good fortune to
bear a hundred sons
of the Kuru dynasty.
Oh, great one.
Gandhari is the most beautiful
princess in the world.
She is well versed
in many disciplines
and well trained
in combat too.
But prince Dhritarashtra
you know about him.
Prince Dhritarashtra
is capable in every aspect.
And there's no denying it.
You are not aware of
Dhritarashtra's brilliance
Queen Sudarbha.
Dhritarashtra's arms are so
powerful that with a single blow
he can knock down
many elephants at once.
Being crowned as Dhritarashtra's
queen, princess Gandhari
shall be the most fortunate
woman of the Arya race.
Where are you off to, princess?
It isn't the time
to leave us all, yet.
Let her go, Sugdha.
lt's expected of her
to be arrogant now.
There's a proposal for her from
such a huge kingdom, after all.
It's not so, sister-in-law.
Even if it's so, it's
understandable Gandhari.
There's no kingdom
in the entire world
that's more powerful
and wealthy than Hastinapur.
I too have heard great tales
about Hastinapur, princess.
I keep trying to imagine
how would Hastinapur be.
Hastinapur.
Tying this bond with Hastinapur,
you shall turn from king Subal
to emperor Subal.
That means, flaunting your power
you are here for a gain.
Isn't it, o great Bheeshma?
I'm here to induct the royal
family of Gandhar
into our family,
queen Sudarbha.
And within a family,
there is no question of gain.
There's only co-operation.
Gandhar cannot help Hastinapur
profit in any way.
Instead, Gandhar can only gain
from Hastinapur.
It may be a great kingdom
for all I know.
Even our Gandhar isn't
so weak either.
Anyway, a marriage takes place
with a prince, not the kingdom.
Oh!
So our princess is already
dreaming of her husband.
Sister-in-law.
In my opinion, the marriage
of princess Gandhari
and Prince Dhritarashtra is
ordained by the Gods.
Resolutions and options are
games a mind plays, king Subal.
But, I do not mean to
pressurize you in any way.
Only after clearing all your
doubts should you
arrive at a decision,
your majesty.
So, what have you decided,
your majesty?
The prince of Hastinapur seems
like Lord lndra among humans.
The subjects of the Kuru empire
consider their princes as Gods
and worship them
with all their heart.
Sister-in-law,
what is his name?
Why do you want to know
his name, princess?
Anyway, a wife never utters
her husband's name.
Sister-in-law, please tell me.
What is his name?
His name is Dhritarashtra.
Prince Dhritarashtra.