That sounded like the scream
of your eldest brother, My Lord.
That is impossible.
What danger can befall him while
performing the 'Sandhyavandana?'
Maybe a crocodile bit him
or maybe a Yaksha or an ogre
has captured him.
Please go and have
a look, My Lord.
I cannot leave you here
and go, Panchali.
That is the second time he has
screamed for help, My Lord.
Please go and have a look!
You will return soon anyhow.
What can happen in the meantime?
Please go,
My Lord!
But Panchali
today is the last day
of our exile.
Duryodhan must certainly
be up to no good.
That is what we fear.
He must have attacked
My Lord Yudhishthir
finding him by himself.
Please go and have
a look, My Lord!
Until My Lords Bheem
and Sahadev return
I shall protect myself
with this sword, My Lord.
Please go and have a look.
Daughter of Drupad...
Who are you
and why have you come
to my residence?
Me?
I am King Jayadrath of Sindhu
and Dushala's husband.
King of Sindhu!
Greetings!
Welcome!
Pardon me...
- What?
My Lord Yudhishthir has gone
to perform the 'Sandhyavandana.'
I know that.
I
saw everything
while hiding there
and the moment he left
I came here.
Brother Yudhishthir!
Nakul! What are you
doing here?
I heard your scream.
You were screaming for help.
I was performing 'pranayam'* under the water.
*Extension of the praṇa or breath.
This is certainly a part
of a wicked plan, brother.
Panchali...
Panchali is by herself
in the hut, brother Yudhishthir!
Let's go there immediately!
What is this villainy,
King of Sindhu?!
I have come to take you away.
You have already
served five husbands.
Now,
how about
you serve me for a while?
Let me go,
wicked man!
Let's go!
- Let go!
Brother Bheem
I have a feeling that something
bad will happen with Panchali.
We must return
immediately, brother.
Let go!
My Lord!
Let go...
- Panchali!
My Lord!
Let go.
- Stop, King of Sindhu!
My Lord!
Panchali!
- My Lord!
Bheem!
It was Dushala's husband,
brother Yudhishthir!
He has abducted Panchali.
He must certainly be trying
to go to the kingdom of Sindhu.
We must stop him
before he crosses the border!
It is not dusk yet,
uncle.
Even the Pandavas have
not yet reached, my darling.
Look over there.
King of Sindhu is on his way.
Do not worry,
my darling.
No one can stop the sun.
Let go!
Arjun!
- My darling
none of us can attack him.
If we break our promise
then that old geyser
will not get off our case.
Wait until it is sundown.
No one shall attack
until sundown.
How dare you lay even
a finger on Draupadi
King Jayadrath of Sindhu?!
How could you even dream
of defeating
the sons of Pandu?!
How could you even think
that your act of trying
to abduct Panchali
would go unpunished by me?!
Here you go!
Here I am!
And when I stand tall
like a wall
Pavan Dev himself
is unable to go through me!
You are a mere mortal!
We cannot attack him,
uncle
but we can certainly
protect our brother-in-law.
Attack!
Stop!
Where is the King of Sindhu?!
Where did Arjun and Draupadi
disappear?!
We must find them before dusk!
Where did the three
of them disappear?
of them disappear?!
King of Sindhu!
You must be aware of
the punishment awarded
to a person who tries to
abduct a married woman!
Pardon me
but we must slay you!
Then you must
also slay Duryodhan.
I did this because
he asked me to.
Does a piece of wood
thrown into the fire
by someone else not burn,
King of Sindhu?!
Bheem!
Kill King of Sindhu!
All of them must certainly
be present in these woods!
Soldiers!
Jayadrath,
I shall crush your head!
Punish him,
My Lord!
Punish him in a way
that whenever any evil man
looks at a woman with depravity
fear should take him over!
No, brother Bheem!
He is Dushala's husband.
We cannot leave
our sister widowed.
Do not take pity on him,
brother Arjun!
Whoever tries to save a scorpion
from drowning in the water
gets stung by
the scorpion itself.
I hope you know that.
This man will hurt you someday!
We will deal
with it later, Nakul
but
we cannot leave
our sister widowed.
Brother!
I have found the crown
of the King of Sindhu.
They must certainly have
gone in that direction.
It is almost sundown.
Do what you have to
but with haste.
We must punish him
so that even Duryodhan
learns a lesson!
Arjun!
Bring your arrow!
I shall shave his head!
These are five tufts of hair,
King of Sindhu!
Show them to Duryodhan and tell
him that even the five Pandavas
will always be present
on his head
like five lines of tension!
Brothers.
How could they escape
in just a moment?
How could they just vanish?!
The question is not
how they left.
The question is
where they went.
My darling
before a year is over
we must find the Pandavas.
Please be quiet,
uncle.
Your plan
has failed once again.
My plan has not failed,
my darling.
Good fortune was on
the side of the Pandavas
Yet again.
Fortune!
What is fortune,
uncle?!
Good fortune of the enemies
is merely another term
for our weakness.
Karna was correct.
Treachery can be useful
only in winning a game of dice
and not an empire!
Do not forget,
my darling
that for the past twelve years
the glory of being the Emperor
was not acquired by you
in a battlefield.
Treachery
and cheating have
gifted you that.
The competence
to fight the Pandavas
does not reside
within you.
I do not have the competence!
Is Bheem more powerful than me?
When compared to
my friend Karna, is Arjun
a better archer,
uncle?
The individual competence
of each one of you
is something I am not aware of.
However,
in a battle
the basis of victory
is not individual might
but the might of the army.
The number of Kings
on your side in a battle
is more important.
The love the subjects
have for you
is more important.
The blossoming
of a single flower
does not denote
the arrival of spring.
When the entire forest
is filled with flowers
it is spring time then.
Similarly
an empire
is formed with the affection
and trust of all the Kings.
Uncle
your words can
no longer be trusted by me.
My heart desires blood now.
I want a war now!
I want a war now.
- You want a war!
You want a war?!
There will be a war!
Before a year is over
if we do not find the Pandavas
if you
do not see any one of them
and call him by his name
and if their life of anonymity
cannot be rendered
worthless by us
then there will be war.