Son...
Duryodhan?
Greetings, father.
Son.
Did Bheem come
to Praman Koti with you?
No.
He did not come with me.
Dushala said
that she had seen him.
Eldest brother Yudhishthir
was occupied
and so was Arjun.
So, he said that he will
be there with the others.
Then where did Bheem go?
If he was not with Duryodhan
then how would Duryodhan
know about him, sire?
True.
Your majesty!
Your Majesty, have me beheaded!
Have me beheaded, your Majesty!
I truly deserve death,
your Majesty.
I truly deserve death.
After delivering
such a terrible news
I have no right to live,
your Majesty.
I have no right...
What are you rambling about?
Your Majesty.
The fate of Kuntibhoj's daughter
is marked with misfortune.
Such penance
exile
the death of her husband
and now this.
Your Majesty
Your Majesty, grief and agony
are choking my heart.
My heart breaks.
What news do you bring,
Prince of Gandhar?
News?
What news do you bring?
The news, great Bheeshma...
Soldier.
A hunter had gone to the woods
to hunt for game this morning.
There, inside the den of a tiger
he found these ornaments.
I fear
that these ornaments
belong to Prince Bheem!
Bheem!
Bheem... No.
Mother! - Mother!
- Mother!
Mother, what happened?
Mother? - Mother?
- Mother?
My son...
Bheem.
My...
My son cannot die.
Bheem.
Mother!
- Mother! - Mother.
'13 days later.'
Vidur.
I have seen the deaths
of my younger brothers.
First, the death of Pandu,
who was like a son and...
And now
the death of Pandu's son.
What has destiny
in store for me?
What has it decided?
God tests only
the competent, sire
Perhaps, to teach patience
to ordinary people.
The 'Brahmin' children are here,
great Bheeshma.
Sire, for the peace
of Bheem's soul
it is time for
the 'Brahmins' to be fed.
Let us proceed.
Enough of this, Kunti.
Bheem's...
Bheem's death
took place 13 days ago.
And you have been shedding
tears for the past 13 days.
Stop crying, Kunti.
Stopping my tears
cannot stop my weeping,
sister-in-law.
Your Highness, here you go.
One question
will keep agonizing me
for the rest of my life.
Why?
Why did my Bheem
go so far away from me?
Why?
Brother Bheem has
not gone anywhere, mother.
He will always be with us.
He will live in our hearts.
'Brahmins,' for the peace
of Kuru Prince Bheem's soul
do consume the food
that will be served to you
for which we shall be grateful.
Uncle.
- Yes.
What kind of a boy is he?
He eats so much.
I'm perplexed too, dear.
But we have
no other alternative.
Until all the young 'Brahmins'
are satiated
we must serve them food.
Arjun.
In order to serve food
to the 'Brahmins'
we must go to the courtyard.
If I feed
the young 'Brahmins' myself
then I will feel
as though...
As though I am
feeding my Bheem.
Your Highness,
we have a problem.
We are out of food
but there is a young 'Brahmin'
who is not yet satiated.
He is asking for more food.
Mother...
Mother, now I am satiated.
Bheem...
My son.
Where had you gone?
I am Vasuki,
the King of Serpents.
My soldiers told me that you
put up quite a fight with them.
He was biting me.
Upon Pawan Dev's* request I had sent my soldiers to you
*Other name of Vayu, Pavana (the Purifier).
for your protection.
There was poison in your body
and in order
to cancel out its effect
I had sent my soldiers
to bite you.
Only poison can
nullify the effect of poison.
Could he not have told me that
before biting me?
We serpents are
of a furious nature.
But your ancestor, King Shuvasu
had married
the serpent woman Marisha.
The blood of serpents
runs through your veins.
That is why it is natural
for you to get angry.
I am not only short-tempered
but also very strong.
My serpents have experienced
your strength.
I am extremely pleased
with your courage and bravery.
No poison shall ever harm you.
Here you go.
Consume this.
With the help
of this special concoction
you will be blessed with
the strength of 100 elephants.
My blessings are with you.