I can see that my friend
too, is very angry.
Greetings, Madhav.
Only one with a right
to have a temper can be angry.
I bear no such rights
over you
other than friendship.
I am not the throne, Arjun
whose authority can
be passed on.
My name is Vasudev Krishna.
He who claims his rights
on me
I willingly give him
the rights.
Subhadra's wedding
with Duryodhan...
What's the purpose
of this, Madhav?
His Highness Shakuni
said
that the Kuru
and Yadav clans
need to have an alliance
born of kinship.
How could I oppose
such a noble thought?
It's a conspiracy.
A conspiracy to stop
the Rajsuya Yajna
from taking place
at Indraprastha.
Madhav
it's a tradition.
The royal family
with which an alliance is forged
but isn't bonded together
by kinship
has to be defeated.
That's when the Rajsuya Yajna
can take place.
And we will never come
to defeat Dwarka.
Parth*
*Paartha, "son of Pritha", another name for Kunti.
my purpose wasn't to
break ties with Indraprastha
by getting Subhadra married.
During the Rajsuya Yajna
if Duryodhan attacks
Indraprastha
then you'll have to be
on their side, Madhav.
And we...
We'll have to surrender our
weapons in front of you
Madhav.
You analysed everything
politically, Arjun.
But about
my dear sister Subhadra
you never gave a thought.
I did think of her, Madhav.
You know how unrighteous
Duryodhan is.
How will Subhadra spend
her life with him?
What bliss will she get
at Hastinapur?
You needn't worry
about me.
I will be happy
wherever I go.
No.
Because of me,
my sister eyes
are filled with tears.
Now you will have to defend
me from this problem, Parth.
Me?
- Yes, Parth.
That's the reason
I had told you
that your penance
will be completed
at Somnath.
Brother.
Tell me.
Will you guard me?
Saw that, Prince Arjun
I had told you, that whatever
my brother does
has more than
one interpretation.
But, Madhav, I cannot
marry Subhadra.
It's impossible.
Vikarna
where are uncle
and Dushashan?
I don't know, brother.
I saw them leave
by a chariot.
She has been pledged
to Duryodhan.
So what?
Rukmini too was pledged
to Sishupal.
But Draupadi too was
in this state.
And there were only
two choices then.
Either you brothers would've
fought each other
or any four of you would've
renounced the world.
But Draupadi made way
for the third option.
My friend has done
a lot of favours
for you five brothers.
But here
the circumstances
are different.
And I didn't know that
you were hesitant
to take up arms
against Duryodhan.
Or is the thought of
Duryodhan renouncing the world
breaking your heart?
Call the bride to
the wedding podium.
Go and get Subhadra.
If I abduct Subhadra
then you and brother Balram
will have to fight me.
And I cannot take up arms
against you.
That's true, Parth.
A battle will be announced.
It's a very dreadful
situation.
Subhadra
Parth cannot abduct you.
But, brother, I can
abduct your friend.
Abduct me!
How can you abduct me?
A warrior abducted
by a girl...
This has never happened before.
But, the solution is
an excellent one, Parth.
There's a problem though.
You'll be mocked at.
You will be humiliated.
Give it a thought.
What is your command?
In this world, it is valour that
always abducts love
but I believe
that if love abducts valour
then the world can be
a happier place.
But the final decision
is yours, Parth.
At your behest I had taken up
a woman's guise.
Let me do this too.
Subhadra
you know driving a chariot.
I have kept
the chariot
ready for you.
Brother.
Stay blessed.
Go, Parth.
If the future of the entire
Aryan lineage didn't depend
on this abduction
then I wouldn't have gone
through with this fabrication.
Balram
why is the bride taking
so long to arrive?
I'll send the maids,
Your Highness.
Hurry up, charioteer.
That is Princess Subhadra,
uncle!
Where is she going
with a sage
at this time?
That was Arjun, you fool!
Vasudev Krishna!
You will have to face
the consequences
of this fabrication, Vasudev.
We will have to get
to Dwarka soon.
Prince Balram, it is time
for the wedding ritual.
Get Princess Subhadra to
the wedding podium.
Balram, what's taking long?
Why the delay?
How can she come,
Your Highness?
Because she is far
away from Dwarka.
And unfortunately,
her chariot is running
in the direction
opposite to Dwarka.
King Shakuni!
What are you
trying to say?
Dushashan and I
have seen it ourselves
Prince Balram.
At first, I thought that
the chariot wasn't in control.
But now, Prince Balram,
the question is
if the chariot wasn't in control
or is Princess Subhadra
not in control?
You're forgetting your limits,
King Shakuni.
Um...
And your sister has forgotten
about the honour of Hastinapur.
Keeping the prince of Hastinapur
waiting at the wedding podium
she has renounced Dwarka
and eloped with
someone else.
But why will Subhadra
do such a thing?
Good question.
But you can get the answer
from your younger brother
Vasudev Krishna.
Rudra Yadav, go and see
where Krishna is.
I'm right here, brother.
Ask him, Prince Balram.
Ask him!
Vasudev
at this time,
is Princess Subhadra
in Dwarka?
No, brother.
I have to admit
with great regret
that Subhadra is not in Dwarka
right now.
She isn't in Dwarka!
What do you mean?
Where is she?
When will she return?
Forgive me, Your Highness.
It's a very disgraceful
thing for Dwarka.
I supplicate
and apologise to you
but my sister Subhadra
will now return with her husband
only after her marriage.
She will return after
her marriage!
What are you trying
to attempt, Prince Balram?
To defeat Subhadra's
abductor
and get Subhadra to
the wedding podium
is your responsibility.
You're right, Prince Duryodhan.
Krishna
why isn't the army ready
to attack yet?
I'll get the army ready
right away, brother
but there's a problem.
Who will we fight?
The one who abducted
is without arms
and is a woman.
The warrior who is armed
is the one who
is abducted.
It's a very dreadful situation.
Who has abducted whom?
Reveal this to everyone here
so that everyone is able
to understand
your conspiracy
Vasudev.
- King Shakuni
conspiracy means six kinds
of fabrications.
I have committed only
one fabrication, brother.
I lent my chariot
to my dear sister
so that she could abduct
her husband.
And do you know who she
has chosen as her husband
Your Highness?
Son of Pandu Arjun!
And do you know who she
has chosen as her husband
Your Highness?
Son of Pandu Arjun!
Krishna
because of your plays
I'll have to hide myself
in the womb of the Earth.
Brother, that's certain.
And the place too
is certain.
Prince Balram
the princess had been pledged.
You had given your word
that Duryodhan
and Princess Subhadra's wedding
will be conducted by you.
In a certain sense,
she had been married
then how can she get married
for the second time?
Forgive me, Your Excellency.
If pledging means marriage
then what is the need
for the seven vows?
Pledging means,
the approval of the parents
but a marriage is complete
only after the approval
of the man and the woman.
Pledging cannot be considered
marriage, Your Excellency.
If that's the case
then what is the significance
of giving away the daughter
Vasudev?
The fruit of coconut
falls in the sea
and then the tree renounces its
right on that fruit.
Which bank it will go to
and which land it chooses
to grow as a new tree,
is decided by the fruit
and its fate.
During the giving away ceremony
the parents
renounce their rights
on their daughter.
But who she wants to give
the rights on her
is decided by the girl.
My dear sister Subhadra
also took this decision
and I accepted her decision
on behalf of the Yadavs.
Now you shall only have enmity
with Hastinapur, Vasudev.
Very soon, Hastinapur's army
will attack Dwarka.
Attack!