Gather your weapons and courage
and be prepared to fight a war.
We must improve the security
in Virat for this purpose.
In order to harm
Panchali, Subhadra
or Uttara,
what if that wicked
and evil Duryodhan
sends someone to Virat?
That is not necessary,
My Lord.
We women of the Kuru dynasty
will reside
near the battlefield.
Taking care of the supplies
and tending to the injured
will be the responsibility
of us women.
And when you slay
Duryodhan and his brothers
my presence
will make him realize
that he is being punished
and that he is
not dying as a martyr.
This is how
I shall slay you,
Vasudev!
Friend Duryodhan.
What are you doing here?
Is this what you call
friendship?
When that Vasudev was
insulting me in the court
you had taken his side!
You were scared
at the thought of a war!
You, uncle,
that old geyser
and everyone present there
were left terror-stricken!
Calm down,
friend.
I am not scared,
friend
and neither have I forsaken you.
I shall die before you
and that is an oath of mine.
And I
shall indeed fulfil this oath.
A message has been sent.
We need to proceed
towards the battlefield.
Let’s go, friend.
Victory awaits you.
My darling
we must head westward towards Samanta Panchaka.*
A vast water reservoir in Kurukshetra (region "kshetra", now in Haryana state).
Have faith.
You have unparalleled might
fighting from your side.
Victory
awaits you.
‘I, son of Ganga’
‘swear on the purity
of my mother’
‘that I shall never become
the King of Hastinapur’
‘but spend the rest of my life
as its servant!’
‘I shall ensure that your sons
are made the Kings!’
‘I want you to promise me’
‘that under no circumstance’
‘will you quit being on the side
of my sons and me.’
‘As long as you are
the King of Hastinapur’
‘I shall serve you
and Hastinapur as a servant’
‘and deem every word
of yours an order.’
While fulfilling the promise
I made to my father
I have given rise to internal
conflicts within my family
Vidur.
In order to maintain
the sanctity of that throne
I have strived endlessly.
However, it got tainted
right before my eyes.
I know
that if this throne
did not have my protection
then Duryodhan would never
have dared to wage a war.
Uncle, you have merely
discharged your duties.
When a strong current
pushes a boat
towards the waterfall
the oarsman has
no fault in it, uncle.
You have always
tried to steer
the boat of Hastinapur
in the right direction.
That was not adequate,
Vidur.
I have seen my father
preside over that throne
and govern this kingdom.
I have seen the effects
of his righteous governance.
During his governance
his subjects were happy
and the Gods were pleased.
Righteousness,
knowledge
and justice
were the bases
of the Kuru kingdom.
And I have firm faith
that even Yudhishthir
will govern the Kuru kingdom
in a similar manner.
And righteousness,
justice and knowledge
will merge into one
on that throne.
However...
However what
saddens me is that I
shall not be able to witness it.
Today...
Today, I am standing before
this throne for the last time.
Uncle
why will you die?
You have been blessed with
the boon to die at will, uncle.
Dear Vidur
as long as I have
a weapon in my hands
the sons of Pandu
cannot win this war.
And I must fight in this war
until the reason of my death
appears before my eyes.
I have the boon to die at will
and now
I also wish to die.
I am contented,
dear Vidur
that the power which can end me
lies in the hands
of the Pandavas.
The army is ready
to march now, uncle.
We brothers and Uttar
are awaiting the next order
with our respective troops.
The General will make
the inspection soon, dear.
Only after that will the army
be ordered to march forth.
I hope you have appointed
Crown Prince Bheem
as the General,
Emperor.
No,
Your Highness
Grandsire Bhishma is
the General of Hastinapur.
Our General has to be someone
who can strip grandsire
of his weapons.
All hail Mahadev!
Greetings, father!
Give us your blessings,
father.
I am going to pull out
the thorns
from my heart forever.
What blessing
should I give my sons?
It is said that
where there is hope
there is no fear.
However,
the hope of your victory
and the fear of your defeat
have morphed into such an odd
entity in my heart today, son.
that I do not know myself
what blessing
I should give my sons.
In the battlefield
may your valour be unparalleled.
This is my blessing to you.
It will indeed be so,
father.
Not only will our valour
be unparalleled
but also our victory.
Give us your blessings,
mother.
I turned my back to light
in this life of mine.
I never knew the value of lamps.
That is why
I do not know any way to protect
the hundred lamps of mine.
Vindhan.
Vikarna.
Dusshasan...
My sons!
You must ensure
to protect each other!
Dear Duryodhan
please pardon me.
I took an oath without
thinking about the future.
But today,
I have known
that knowledge and solutions
give rise to contentment in life
and joy in the future.
Intransigence and oaths
are merely the paths to sorrow.
My blessing to you is
that may all of you be blessed!
Goodbye, mother.
Goodbye, father.
Greetings,
Guru Drona.
Your Excellency.
Greetings,
Supreme Emperor Yudhishthir.
I asked all of you
to gather here
so that everyone gets to know
that this place
is an exceedingly sacred one.
When Lord Parashuram had
put an end to sinners here
five lakes of blood were formed.
Hence, this place came to be
known as Samanta Panchaka.
To the north of this place
is the River Saraswati
and to its south
is the River Drishadvati.
The place that lies
between these two rivers
has been blessed by the
ancestors of Lord Parashuram.
This is where righteousness
shall be established.
Lord Indra had
blessed Emperor Kuru
saying that anyone who dies
in a battle in this place
shall get a place in heaven.
For your war of righteousness,
this region of righteousness
is most suitable.
Vasudev
Kurukshetra is a region
of righteousness.
Do tell us what the
appropriate day to gather here
with the intent
of a war will be.
My friend Draupadi has
already decided upon that day.
The day the stars
Kritika and Rohini align
during the ninth lunar month on
the 14th day of the waxing moon
is when the war will begin.
In other words, in three days
from now will begin
the Mahabharat.