A message from
the King of Gandhar?
Purandiri, the King of Gandhar
has sent a message.
We must set the palace
on fire tonight itself.
Then...
Yes, we will have to poison
their meal tonight itself.
If they are alive
they might escape easily when
they see the palace on fire.
Bring the vessel of poison
I gave to you at once.
Certainly, My Lord.
Purochan!
What...
What is it, Prince?
What are all of you doing?
W- We are...
We are preparing tonight's meal.
Y- Yes.
It is way past dinner time.
Are you not done with it yet?
Indeed, Prince. We shall
serve the meal right away.
Do proceed to
the dining chamber.
You do not follow any order
given to you, Purochan.
W- What, Prince?
We had told you to construct a
dining chamber inside the palace
but you have not yet
paid heed to it.
I made a mistake.
I made a mistake, Prince.
I shall have one made
tomorrow without fail.
Brother Bheem, wait.
Let us take some 'kheer'
for Nakul's mouse
otherwise he will bring it
with him to the dining chamber
and mother will be unable
to have her meal.
That's a splendid idea.
Bring a small bowl, Purochan.
Purochan!
Bring a small bowl!
We want some 'kheer...'
T- That...
What is that substance
on the 'kheer?'
Herbs. - Potion...
- Syrup.
In other words
it is a syrup made
from selected flowers.
It has an odd smell.
It is excellent
for digestion, Prince.
That is why, it is used
in preparing 'kheer.'
The meal shall not
have an odd smell, Prince.
Not one bit.
Alright. Make sure the taste
is not compromised.
Certainly.
Brother Bheem
you forgot to take the 'kheer.'
- Oh yes.
Purochan, bring some 'kheer'
in a small bowl.
Certainly, Prince.
Purandiri.
- What?
Certainly.
Here you go.
But father, what if the Pandavas
don't eat the 'kheer' themselves
but feed it to
the mouse instead?
It will die.
What happened?
Why do you seem so tense?
Are you famished like me?
No, brother Bheem.
No other person can ever
have an appetite like yours.
But... But something
ominous is going to happen.
I have such a premonition.
Purochan's wife
prepares the meals.
It is bound to be ominous.
Who knows what she adds
to the meals.
I feel, Purochan's entire
family is ominous.
He has constructed
such a strange palace.
It looks stunning
but the entire palace
reeks of something.
We should ask Purochan about it.
But only after having our meal.
Once I see food,
I cannot control myself.
Go on. Go and call brother
Yudhishthir, Arjun and Nakul.
And if you do not reach on time,
I shall begin eating.
Certainly, brother.
You may begin eating.
Besides, you eat
for three hours.
And we end up
just sitting there with you.
Go on.
Purochan.
What is it, Prince? - If you
keep standing at the door
you will turn into a festoon
hung over doorways.
Come on. Make haste.
Serve the meal.
But Prince, the Crown Prince and
Her Highness are not yet here.
They will be here.
Just serve the meal.
Prince, do pardon me.
How can you begin eating
without Her Highness?
She has ordered me
to begin eating without her.
But Prince, we have prepared
quite a feast today.
If you eat with your family,
it will give us great joy.
Give me that.
I will eat not only with her
but also after she is done.
Place the other vessels
over there. - Certainly, Prince.
Let's go.
Mother!
Brother Yudhishthir!
I am awaiting for all of you!
They ought to begin
eating together, My Lord.
If he begins eating
before the others arrive
the poison will start
showing its effect on him
and our plan will be foiled.
Stop him from eating, My Lord.
But how do I stop him?
How odd!
Every animal feels calm
in my presence
but why is it so restless?
Nakul
maybe your mouse is hungry.
Here is some 'kheer' for it.
Brother Arjun, mother is
awaiting us for the meal.
Why? Will brother Bheem
not wait for us?
Nakul
do come for dinner
after feeding your mouse.
But it refuses to eat.
- How odd!
Where do you wish to go, mouse?
Maybe it is anxious to fulfill
the task it came here for.
Then we will know why
uncle Vidur sent us a mouse.
Nakul, let it go.
Let's see where it goes.
What is it, brother Arjun?
Lac has been used instead
of bricks in the palace.
Why has this palace been
constructed this way, brother?
You may not know this, Nakul
but lac is extremely flammable.
Along with lac,
this palace is made
with dried grass,
clarified butter and cotton.
If this palace catches fire
everything will get burnt
within six hours.
But why?
This is a conspiracy.
Greetings, Her Highness.
Bless you.
Greetings, mother.
- Bless you, Bheem.
Where is Yudhishthir
and the rest of your brothers?
Mother, instead of
having a meal with me
my brothers find feeding
a mouse more interesting.
Bheem, you may begin eating.
I shall await for the rest.
Alright, mother.
Father
the remaining Pandavas
have figured out
that the entire palace
is made of lac.
This is a scheme to burn
us alive in the palace.