How dare you, Vidur?!
Divide the Kuru Kingdom!
How could you even
suggest such a thing?!
Did the mere thought of this
not split your head in two?!
My heart has been split, uncle.
Please pardon me, uncle!
But in a situation like this
this is the only solution
I could think of.
Quit with your rambling, Vidur!
This is not a solution
but a mockery!
A mockery of our ancestors!
Our ancestors
have struggled a lot
and have sacrificed many things
to make our Kuru Kingdom
the most powerful one
in the entire world!
Just look at our ancestors.
They have built
this kingdom of ours.
My revered father Shantanu
made this kingdom powerful.
He augmented the boundaries
of this kingdom
and you wish
to break it, Vidur?!
But brother Yudhishthir
if uncle Vidur has suggested
the kingdom to be divided
then he must have
put some thought into it.
Yes, brother Yudhishthir.
He thought of our happiness.
To keep internal conflicts
from rising in the Kuru kingdom
he thought of this solution.
But how can the division
of our motherland
ever be accepted by us?
But the Great Sage Vyas had said
that we must ask for our rights.
Not for us but the subjects
of our kingdom.
How can asking for one's rights
equate to dividing
the kingdom, Bheem?
My body shall be divided first.
Only then will the kingdom
get divided.
Uncle
oil and water
and never kept
in the same container.
They can never mix.
Then neither of them
is fit for any use.
Uncle
if we wish to make happiness
return to Hastinapur
then dividing the kingdom
is the sole solution.
Impossible!
I have the right to the
entire kingdom, father! Me!
This is my kingdom.
This is my kingdom!
Why should I give half of it
to the sons of Pandu, father?!
No one can even dare to think
of dividing this kingdom.
Had you told me before, son
that you had seen the sons
of Pandu alive in Kampilya
then... - Then what would
you have done, father?
Grandsire and the Minister
have always bound you
in the name of righteousness.
And you become weak before them
every single time.
That is why,
after declaring
brother Duryodhan
as King we were going
to tell you about it.
Father
making you resort to asceticism
was never my intention.
Grandsire and the Minister
are here to serve you.
They can never act
as your master.
And whenever
it concerns my rights
they always render
you weak, father.
Brother Duryodhan
is correct, father.
If you do not realize
the importance of your
status and position
then why would anyone else?
You must use your might to prove
that your decision is ultimate.
Grandsire will be
deeply anguished.
The soul of our father will be
deeply anguished, Bheem.
But brother Yudhishthir
Madhav had said that we
should have our kingdom.
Would refuting his advice
be correct?
Subjects can also be served
without gaining polity.
No, Arjun.
Just to gain hold of polity
we cannot have
the kingdom divided.
I shall approach His Highness
and step down
as the Crown Prince.
Do not forget that
His Highness is mighty
but he is so only because
of Bhishma and the Minister.
Both of them
the Minister and Bhishma
are the armour and weapons
of His Highness.
Till the time the shell
keeps a tortoise covered
it does not know defeat.
However, if the tortoise
falls to the ground shell first
it begins to squirm!
You seem to be forgetting the
might of us 100 brothers, uncle!
The army of Gandhar,
the army of Ashwatthama
and that of King Karna of Anga...
When he is backed
by these entities
why would father
need to be afraid?!
You should demonstrate
your might, father!
What do I do now,
my sons?
What do I do?!
They had taken to arms
in the court, father.
It was an insult to you.
We have a splendid opportunity
to defeat Yudhishthir.
You know quite well, father
that a criminal or culprit
has no right to be
the Crown Prince.
What do you mean?
Just think about
my suggestion, uncle.
Brother Dhritarashtra
too is a righteous man
and I am certain of it.
But if amber is covered
with ashes
then it does not give off light.
At the moment,
brother Dhritarashtra
is surrounded by Duryodhan
and the King of Gandhar.
Hence, he is unable
to think righteously.
I do not agree with you, Vidur.
I have firm faith
that Dhritarashtra
will heed my advice.
I shall remind him of his duties
towards the kingdom.
Great Bhishma
I bring an exceedingly
important news.
His Highness has ordered
the Pandavas
to be taken into custody.
Pardon us, Crown Prince
but His Highness has ordered
to take all of you into custody.
Greetings, great Bhishma.
Where is His Highness?
He is performing
a 'yajna,' sire.
He has given the order
to not permit anyone inside.
Tell him Bhishma
has come to meet him.
I have something important
to discuss with him.
When one's own family
is in a crisis
one cannot earn merit
by performing a 'yajna.'
Go on!
- As you say, sire.
Soldier!
Is this the rope
you have to bind me?!
You cannot be bound even by
iron shackles, Prince Vrikodar
but what can I do?
I am bound by orders.
Even I am bound by them!
An order is far stronger
than even lightning!
Otherwise there is no prison
on this planet
which can imprison
my brothers and me!
Calm down, Bheem.
Do not fret.
If the King has
taken us into custody
then we shall indeed
spend our lives in prison.
If the King has
taken us into custody
then we shall indeed
spend our lives in prison.
Following a King's order
and honouring justice...
If Princes do not abide by them
then how can the subjects
of a kingdom?
Panchali
do ask for this rope
from aunt Gandhari.
It is very strong.
Just look.
Hey!
It broke.
Soldier!
Bring another rope.
- Indeed.
Bring about ten ropes which are
used to bind an elephant.
And do get an order
from the Minister
preventing brother from breaking
the rope while having 'laddoos.'
How will you solve
this situation, My Lord?
There is only one solution,
Panchali.
We can apologize
to His Highness.
Even mother will
suggest the same.
What do you suggest,
Panchali?
I do not covet any land,
My Lord.
If I have to serve all of you
even in the woods
then I am ready to do so.
But...
But what, Panchali?
Panchali
do you think, we should
not apologize to the King?
Yes, My Lord.
If you are guilty
then face the punishment.
But if not, then protest
against this injustice.
What is the point
in apologizing?
Does apologizing have
no value, Panchali?
You are wise enough, My Lord.
How can I dispense
advice to you?
Nevertheless
in my opinion
if one apologizes to someone
inferior to him
then it is called valour.
But if someone
is stronger than you
then apologizing to him
is called cowardice.
You are correct,
Panchali.
Do not worry.
We will not apologize.
Let's go, soldier.
Panchali
if we will be imprisoned
then Hastinapur may not be
safe for you.
You should get ready
to leave for Kampilya.
Maybe this is the end
of your journey with us.
Pardon me,
great Bhishma!
His Highness has said that
until the 'yajna' is complete
he will not see anyone.