Mother.
I'm still hungry.
Uh!
But, hadn't I given you
'laddoos'?
Arjun, Nakul and Sahadev
ate all those 'laddoos'.
Did they eat all the 'laddoos'?
Not all, but most of them.
They ate four of those
'laddoos'.
Wait.
I had kept this 'laddoo'
for Madhavi.
Here. You may have this 'laddoo'
as well.
I don't know why, mother.
But when you feed me
with your hands
I am satiated instantly.
Because I'm content at heart and
it passes over to your stomach.
And my biggest contentment lies
in feeding all five of my sons
with my own hands.
Come on. You all better come in
and have your lunch too.
Else, his contentment lasts
only for a few moments. Come.
Mother!
'If I marry your father,
I shall only bear misfortune.'
'Your son shall be
your successor as the king.'
'But what shall be the fate
of my sons?'
'King Shantanu may have just
one of these two pleasures.'
'The pleasure of living in
the royal palace with his son.'
'Or the pleasure of living with
his wife in this humble home.'
'No, mother.'
'My father shall have
both these pleasures'
'at once.'
'I, the son of Ganga,
swear upon
the sanctity of my mother.'
'I shall spend my life
not as a king'
'but as a servant
of Hastinapur.'
'I will not have a family
of my won.'
'I swear to a life of celibacy.'
On these banks of yours,
your son had taken an oath.
If only you had
stopped him then.
If you had stopped him then
so many lives wouldn't
have been lost.
Why didn't you stop him?
Why?
Every day, hundreds of humans
come to my banks, Satyavati.
They take various oaths
and make many promises.
If I keep stopping everyone
how will nature work, Satyavati?
It isn't my duty
to hinder one's oaths.
But Bheeshma is your son,
0' Bhagirathi.*
*One of the two headstreams of the Ganges.
For twenty five years you have
imparted him with morals.
You made him capable
of being a king.
But when he renounced royalty,
did it not pierce your heart?
Who isn't my son.
Every human who visits my banks
is my son.
And I always impart sanctity
and morals to everyone.
Therefore, isn't Bheeshma
significant to you?
He is...
Bheeshma is significant.
But that significance
lies in his heart.
Not in how I perceive him.
Satyavati.
The bad state that Hastinapur
and the Kuru clan is in today
you are the one solely
responsible for it.
Because your vision has the gift
of foresight, nof mine.
I am a mere moral.
I am not immortal as yourself.
Every moment, the fear of death
torments the human heart.
That is why he seeks protection.
I, too, was just seeking
protection.
So, did you find protection?
What did you get?
A lifetime of struggle?
And humiliation at this old age?
Curses and distrust
of millions of subjects?
To add sugar or salt to an urn
of water, is your decision.
But once you take a decision it
cannot be reverted, Satyavati.
I know, 0' Bhagirathi.
It was my fault indeed.
But, I didn't possess the power
of foresight then.
And a human's life is a
consequence of his deference.
I know.
It was my fault.
But now...
Now I must strengthen the future
of the Kuru dynasty
and the Kuru empire.
Please suggest a way
to do it, Ganga.
Please, show me the path.
You had made the first decision
on your own.
You hadn't sought anyone's
advice.
Now it's time to take
the second decision.
You have to decide by yourself,
Satyavati.
Everyone wants to make decisions
about today, for a bright future
To have a happy and safe future.
To take such decisions today is
what everyone attempts to do.
Consider your life for example.
Aren't most of your decisions
backed by thoughts for future?
And why shouldn't they be?
Everyone has the right to make
their life simple and happy.
But no one knows the future.
It can only be imagined.
So we make all crucial
decisions of life
based on imagination.
Could there be a third possible
way to reach a decision?
Think about it.
The basis of all pleasures
is a sense of duty.
And the sense of duty resides
within the human heart.
So before coming to any decision
do ask your heart the question
whether this decision
is result of selfishness
or out of your sense of duty?
Isn't it reasonable?
So, won't thinking about your
duty instead of the future
make the future
far more joyous?
Think for yourself.
Salutations, Queen Mother!
Bless you, son!
Vidur.
Arrange for travel.
I need to leave at dawn's break.
Are you leaving for somewhere?
To fulfill my duties, Bheeshma.
I should have done it years ago.
But then, my selfishness
hindered me from
being aware of my duties.
Fortunately, it didn't hinder me
my entire life.
But now, I must bring about
a change of circumstances.
What do you mean, Queen Mother?
Vidur.
It was my duty to pay
a wise son as yourself
the respect you truly deserve.
But I never did so.
I always perceived your advice
as inappropriate.
But today...
Today I have realized
my mistake, Vidur.
Hence I...
I am here to take you along,
on my journey.
The two of us shall go to Pandu.
I shall reason with him...
Convince him.
I shall remind him
of his duties.
And at any cost,
I shall bring Pandu back
to manage the throne
of Hastinapur.
Welcome, Your Highness.
What ritual have you organized,
elder brother?
It is to take a pledge,
dear Gandhari.
Have a seat.
- No, brother.
Until I don't know the outcome
of this ritual
I shall not participate
in the ritual.
Dear Gandhari.
Your elder brother's heart
wishes for nothing but joy
for you and your family.
Don't you trust your brother?
My family doesn't end at just
my husband and my children.
The descendants of
king Shantanu are my family.
Uh!
Then it is a dispute between you
and your spouse.
If instead of Duryodhan,
one of Pandu's sons gets
the throne of Hastinapur
and that's acceptable to you
then you may discuss the matter
with your husband.
Why would that happen, Shakuni?
My successor can be none other
than my son, Duryodhan.
What do you have to say,
Gandhari?
I have faith in Grandsire.
I have faith in Queen Mother
and Vidur as well.
They will see to it that
no injustice is done.
Once, a pond was drying up.
The frogs there had to go
to another pond.
A stork said...
'Trust me. I shall take
you to the other pond'.
'Sit within my beak'.
Did you understand anything,
dear Gandhari?
Those frogs who trusted the
stork didn't reach the pond.
They reached the stork's
intestines instead.
Today, after fifteen years
why did Queen Mother
remember Pandu all of a sudden?
Did you ever give it a thought,
Your Highness?
Indeed!
I have been thinking of the same
since many days now, Shakuni.
If out of affection,
Queen Mother indeed embarked
upon this journey, why did
she take Vidur along?
She has definitely gone there
to help King Pandu
complete his penance,
Your Highness.
Come, Your Highness.
Have a seat.
Let us take a pledge.
What oath do you want us
to take, elder brother?
To break the Kuru dynasty
into pieces?
No, sister.
Why would I want your clan
to be divided?
Why would I violate
His Highness's trust?
All I want is that
His Highness's offspring
be called 'Kaurav'.
The 'Pandavas' should
not be included.
Before the return of
Queen Mother and the minister
Prince Duryodhan should
be declared
the crown prince of Hastinapur.
If my words seem appropriate
then have a seat.
How far can this arrow be shot,
father?
It can be shot all the way
out of this forest.
I can throw it that far
with my hands.
What is the need of a bow
for that?
It's not about throwing it,
brother Bheem.
It's a matter of piercing
the target.
At how far can a target be shot,
father?
The strength of a bow
depends on a man.
It is not the other way around,
son.
A weapon is only as handy
as the wielder's inner strength.
Just as a skill is only as
beneficial as one's will power.
I do not understand, father.
What is will power?
When the wind blows at a high
speed, it can uproot trees.
The tree that get uprooted,
becomes firewood.
But the tree that stands firm,
blooms new leaves and flowers
after a certain time.
And that is termed as
the will power of the tree.
Even when the odds are
against him
a human should not abandon
his duties, son.
And what is inner strength?
When pests and termites
from beneath the ground
start biting and devouring
a tree, some trees die.
But there are some trees,
that the pests cannot devour.
That is the tree's
inner strength.
When evil afflicts
the human heart
and tries to consume it
from within
then he should not give in
to the affliction within.
That means, will power protects
against unfavourable
circumstances outside.
And against the inner conflicts,
inner strength protects us.
Brilliant, my son.
I am proud of you.
Some day you shall be the most
deserving king of Hastinapur.
Queen Mother.
Arrangements for your meals
and rest have been made here.
And your seat has been arranged
upon that river bank.
I have no need for rest, Vidur.
But the soldiers and
the horsemen need to rest.
For many years
I have lived
in the comfort of the palace.
But not even for a single moment
did I feel rested at all.
Maybe, as my mind keeps working,
my body gets tired too.
But today...
Today, it is as if
this single right decision
erased all traces of tiredness
and pain within my body.
You had enthroned King Pandu
even before this, Queen Mother.
But it was a twist of fate...
- No, Vidur!
It isn't the fault of fate.
If my decisions were
inappropriate
I could have forgiven myself.
But the reasons behind
my decisions
were always inappropriate.
There was affection
within my mind.
But I had restrained that
affection out of selfishness.
Do you see that river, Vidur?
It flows between the banks...
But its water...
But its water goes underground
and reaches far, to those
trees within that forest.
A Queen Mother's life is
somewhat similar, Vidur.
She lives with her family.
But if her affection and respect
does not reach across the nation
then her life is futile.
Her reign is incompetent.
So, will brother Pandu heed
your words, Queen Mother?
Will he abandon his penance?
He will heed.
Pandu will surely heed my words.
I shall convince him.
This nature,
the flowers bloomed in spring
these leaves, the bark of trees,
the excitement of the birds...
I shall show him all of it.
I shall tell him
that if we wish such a spring to
bloom within our subjects' lives
he must give up his oath.
And Vidur...
In the spring, even Lord Shiva's
penance was broken for a moment.
Pandu's penance shall be
surely broken too.
Mother!
Sahadev!
What happened, son?
I don't know why, mother.
But my heart is quivering.
Surely some mishap has occurred
with father.