Engage in a grappling combat
with me, Krishna!
If I die in this combat
my guard will slay your parents.
If you die
your parents will be spared.
Now, tell me,
Krishna.
Do you still wish
to engage in a combat
or in order to save your parents
you are prepared
to embrace death.
I took an oath to save millions
of parents of the Aryan region.
That is why, I am here,
uncle Kansa.
How many parents will you
be able to kill?
Engage in a combat with me, uncle!
All hail Shri Krishna!
All hail uncle Shri Krishna!
Uncle, did the possibility
of death of your parents
not rob you of your strength?
How could you gather
courage at that moment?
How were you able
to keep your mind calm?
Dear
where there is affection
there is always the possibility
of being agitated.
Being the reason of death
of the people who gave you life
is as agonizing
as being the reason
of death of your children.
But there is a truth
that man seldom remembers...
That every particle
of the creation
is a part of the Almighty.
That is why, they always
remain connected.
The way a flower
spreads fragrance
in the entire chamber
and an odoriferous object
spreads a foul smell in it
similarly
the joys and sorrows of man
influence the entire world.
One's joy
makes
everyone experience
a little joy.
One's sorrow makes
everyone experience
a little sorrow.
In other words, joy and sorrow
are alike in the world?
That is correct,
dear
Such is the creation
of the Almighty.
And when
unrighteousness escalates
this balance gets disrupted.
Because of Kansa,
the entire Yadava society
was filled with sorrow.
Because of Jarasandha,
the entire Aryan region
had to witness the destruction
of righteousness.
And now
because of Duryodhan
the entire Kuru kingdom
is unhappy.
The subjects are being
exploited and tortured.
When unhappiness
escalates in the world
very few people experience joy
while the majority
experience sorrow.
As a result, the society
falls prey to illness.
At a time like this,
treating that illness
becomes mandatory.
Sacrificing oneself
in order to put an end
to the unrighteous
becomes mandatory.
At a time like this,
relationships
and love hold no meaning.
Neither does selfishness
hold any value
nor does one hope for joy.
This is the situation
that lies ahead of you now.
The entire family of King Pandu
must either make a sacrifice
or accept the unrighteousness of
the sons of King Dhritarashtra.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
The decision
rests with all of you.
A tree does not know
the taste of its fruit.
Similarly
none of you will derive
the benefit of this sacrifice.
Look within your hearts.
Do you have
the required compassion?
Does your soul have
the required righteousness
to take the decision
to sacrifice yourself
for the welfare of the society?
All of you need to
meditate over this.
Give me your blessings,
uncle
to aid me pacify the burning
hearts of the sons of Pandu
so that they can pardon
Duryodhan and his brothers.
May the daughter of Drupad,
daughter-in-law Draupadi
give up the thought
of waging a war.
People who lead a righteous life
have the capacity within them
to pardon others, Vidur.
But I
have a suspicion on Shakuni.
What could have made him propose
the idea of avoiding a war?
How could he...
How could he make
Duryodhan and Dusshasan
accept this proposal?
He must certainly have
a plan behind all this.
It will certainly
get foiled, uncle.
Each plan of the King of Gandhar
will get foiled.
Uncle,
the sons of Pandu
have Vasudev with them.
The competence to foil
even the most treacherous plan
lies with Vasudev Krishna,
uncle.
Allow me to leave.
Goodbye.
May your journey be fruitful.
Let's proceed,
charioteer.
Minister Vidur
is proceeding towards the city of Virat.
Splendid.
Marvellous,
my darling.
Before the war
the obstacle lying in
your path needs to be
taken care of by me.
His Excellency Bhishma
Great Guru Drona
Maharathi Jayadrath
and Great Archer Karna are
the great warriors on our side.
We must provide them
with the opportunity
to demonstrate their greatness.
That is why
I must look for a way
to tackle that treacherous
Vasudev Krishna
and that too,
quite soon.
What is the plan,
uncle?
My darling
as the envoy of peace
on behalf of the Pandavas
Krishna will certainly come here
because we have sent Sanjay
with the message
that
it is mandatory
for Vasudev Krishna
to be here.
My darling
you need to make
a strong and illusory rope
which cannot be
broken even by Airavat,*
*Airavata, a white elephant.
Lord Indra's mount.
The court of Hastinapur
shall witness
Just watch
how Vasudev Krishna
gets captured by us.
This tie
shall go beyond
the physical realm
and become a tie
between your souls.
Bless you,
son!
My blessing to you is
that may your wife
become your motivation
and not your limit.
And may your husband...
May your husband
become your pride
and not your tie.
Bless you!
May you live long!
'Struggling for righteousness'
'is not a duty'
'but a decision'
'and a vow.'
'Similarly, for you,
this war'
'is not a duty.'
'It is a vow'
'taken for the society.'
Give me your blessings,
Mother Draupadi.
May I be able to serve you
for the rest of my life.
'Apart from the five
husbands of yours'
'the entire lineage
of King Shantanu'
'will be destroyed.'
'The entire dynasty will be
annihilated in this war.'
'Look within your hearts.'
'Do you have
the required compassion'
'to take the decision'
'to sacrifice yourself
for the welfare of the society?'
My blessings...
I bless you to...
Bless him to have
a long life, dear.
The blessing to a long life
is the right of a person
during times of peace
but during war-time
it is merely a hope.