Hastinapur can only be your
enemy henceforth, Vasudev!
Very soon, the army of
Hastinapur will attack Dwaraka!
We are outside the borders
of Dwaraka now, My Lord.
You should rest for a while
after which you can take
the reins of the chariot.
You and your brother
can never be fully
understood by me.
If your head cannot aid you
in understanding someone
then you should give
your heart to that person.
I must look for a 'Brahmin'
and get married to you soon
otherwise your brother Balaram
may come and take you away.
Marriage!
In the woods!
No, My Lord.
I will not get married
in the woods.
I wish to get married
only in a 'mandap.'
How can I build a 'mandap'
in these woods?
You need not
build one, My Lord.
You are still not well
acquainted with my brother.
When a 'mandap' was
being built in Dwaraka
brother pointed to it and said
'Subhadra, look.'
'You will get married
in that 'mandap.'
So, I will certainly
get married there.
You are not well acquainted
with King Shakuni of Gandhar.
Something major troubles me
at the moment.
King Shakuni of Gandhar
will certainly
make Hastinapur and Dwaraka
fight each other.
And even Indraprastha
is not yet independent.
I too shall be ordered
to fight Madhav with my Gandiva.
And not only the army of
Hastinapur, Vasudev Krishna
but also that of Indraprastha
shall take part in this battle!
You seem to be forgetting
that Indraprastha
is not yet independent.
The person for whom
you have insulted our King
that very person
will come to fight you with
his Gandiva outside Dwaraka
Vasudev!
Aunt
my beloved sister is your
daughter-in-law now.
Hastinapur and Dwaraka
may have become enemies
but I am certain that you will
not punish my sister for it.
Even the person who chops
a tree down and burns it
keeps the fruits
of that tree safely.
This is tradition.
I cannot welcome Subhadra, dear.
The property
may have been divided
but not the rights.
The right to welcome a new
daughter-in-law lies solely
with the King and the Queen.
This is a major problem.
His Excellency
if Hastinapur does not
welcome Arjun's wife
then it would mean
that Hastinapur has
accepted Indraprastha
as an independent state.
King Dhritarashtra
you must welcome Arjun's wife
and deem Dwaraka
a part of family
otherwise
you must declare the sons
of Pandu independent.
What do you suggest
His Excellency Bhishma?
Dear Dhritarashtra
you must welcome Arjun.
My darling
Vasudev is no longer your enemy.
He is my enemy now.
I will crush the Yadavas
even if the entire Aryan region
is set ablaze with
the fire of a war.
Greetings, mother!
Arjun!
Son
heat of a fire turns
gold ores into pure gold.
Similarly
after every struggle
my sons become more glorious.
I am very proud of you, son.
When a mother has the capability
of challenging her own self
her sons are bound to be
powerful, mother.
While deciding not to
come to Indraprastha
your heart must have broken
into a thousand pieces.
I can only imagine what you
must have gone through.
I can only imagine it.
Do not worry for me, son.
In order to find a pearl
its shell is bound to be broken.
No, mother.
We will not let that happen.
We will not.
As you had instructed
we will become independent
and Indraprastha
shall be sanctified
by your presence.
Let's go, son.
Krishna has said that your
penance is now over.
You must now get married
return to Indraprastha soon
and perform the Rajsuya 'Yajna.'
Indraprastha awaits you, son.
Her Highness
Prince Bheem has
sent this 'laddoo.'
My Lord Bheem knows
that My Lord Arjun has
the right to me this year.
So, I too shall spend this year
engrossed in a penance.
I consume only two
food items every day.
He knows this quite well
and hence, has sent
only one 'laddoo'
for you to taste.
He has made this himself.
He has said that if black gram
is soaked overnight...
- That is enough.
I will not be able to understand
his culinary skills.
Place the 'laddoo'
on the plantain leaf
and take away
this bowl of 'kheer.'
Will you
eat just this much,
Her Highness?
Yes.
This is a penance.
My Lord Arjun
must also have been
doing the same for years.
'Panchali, as ordered by
righteousness and tradition'
'I am going to marry again.'
'With this marriage,
my dedication to you'
'will indeed magnify.'
'I promise you this.'
'I hope I have
your permission for this.'
'May this wife of mine'
'have your love and protection.'
Give us your blessings, uncle.
Bless you.
Dear Subhadra
welcome to the Kuru dynasty.
Now, you and Arjun need not
come to Hastinapur
to seek our blessings.
You may go to Indraprastha.
On behalf of the
Kuru dynasty, the present
will be sent over to you
in Indraprastha.
Let's go, Gandhari
Vikarna.
Queen Mother
your daughter-in-law
seeks your blessings.
May you be blessed with a son.
Bless you.
Greetings, grandsire.
Stop, dear.
Do not touch my feet.
I will not be able to
give you my blessings.
A blessing is an expression
of one's emotions.
The one who dips
his hand in a reservoir
is bound to get water.
The reservoir has
no say in this.
Similarly
people who seek the
blessings of their elders
are bound to receive it.
A reservoir that has dried up
no longer yields
any water, Vasudev.
Upon seeing this
unrighteous deed
my heart too has dried up.
Which unrighteous deed,
Your Excellency?
The Kuru dynasty has been
insulted in this 'mandap' today!
A maiden meant to marry someone
cannot be married to
someone else, Vasudev.
So, do the feelings
of the maiden
have no importance?
If you had given your word
after asking the maiden
then it would have been correct.
But disregarding tradition
in this manner is incorrect.
A human being can trust another
only when traditions
are adhered to.
Traditions...
Traditions
are like mangoes.
When they are born,
they taste bitter.
After a while,
they taste sour.
Only the ones
who like the sour taste
accept them readily.
And after some more time
they taste sweet.
They become
everyone's favourite.
But after a point of time
they turn to mush.
They begin to reek,
Your Excellency.
The person who
consumes them falls ill.
And in the end, all that
is left are the dried up pits
which are of no use to anyone.
I have nothing against
traditions, Your Excellency
but when they become
a tool of exploitation
and begin to give
sorrow instead of joy
they should be
buried in the earth
in order to give rise
to newer ones.
Who gets to decide
which tradition is decaying?
You, Vasudev?
No
time will decide that
and everyone must obey the
rules of time, Your Excellency.
For the entire Aryan region
this is the time of 'sankranti.'*
*Transmigration of the Sun from one zodiac to the next.
The way Surya Dev changes
his course in a 'sankranti'
similarly
the entire Aryan region
is about to change its course.
Old traditions will break
old empires will crumble to dust
new definitions of righteousness
will be written
and a new era will be ushered,
Maharathi Bhishma!
And in this cycle of time,
you must decide
on which side you wish to be
because everyone will be caught
in this vortex of time.
People who have chosen
the path of unrighteousness
will usher this change
and the ones who have
chosen that of righteousness
will establish the new era.
This is pre-decided.