If your daughter was born
to become a queen
then she might just
turn a 'Brahmin'
into a King.
Kings and spectators
present here
not all dreams are realised
in this world.
But a resolution never fails.
If a person makes a resolution
then in some form
or through a medium
it certainly gets realized.
To have my daughter
married to the
most competent warrior
of the world
is my resolution
and it shall
indeed be fulfilled!
I address the 'Brahmins'
present here
and if there is a competent
person amongst them
then he must come forth.
Did you see...
Did you see that, Pateshwar?
I came here and the King
opened this competition
to the 'Brahmins.'
This is certainly a sign.
Be quiet, Batukeshwar.
Just because Lord Parashuram
is a 'Brahmin'
it does not mean that
all 'Brahmins' are like him.
How can 'Brahmins' win
such a difficult competition?
We will be insulted.
Pateshwar, there is
no insult in trying.
You five brothers seem mighty.
One of you should go there
and give it a try.
Brother Yudhishthir
it is not right for us
to stay here.
The gaze of all the spectators
is upon the 'Brahmins.'
If brother Duryodhan
recognizes us then...
We should go from here,
brother Yudhishthir.
You are correct, Arjun.
Let's go.
What is this foolishness
being exhibited
by King Drupad?
When we mighty 'Kshatriyas'
could not achieve this task
then how can these 'Brahmins'
achieve the same?
Where are you going,
young 'Brahmins?'
Despite having the capability
to win the competition
leaving the gathering must also
be termed competence!
But such competence
is of no use to anyone.
Turning one's back to actions
must also be termed excellence.
But does such excellence
help the world gain
anything, 'Brahmins?'
To think only of one's joy,
sorrow and oath
and not of one's duty
towards the world
is utter selfishness.
But a truly competent person
can never be selfish.
Even when a lion is done
devouring its prey
it leaves a good amount of it
for other carnivores.
Is such altruistic behaviour
not the basis of
righteousness, 'Brahmins?'
Think about it.
If you have true competence
then come forth.
The welfare of the world is
connected to this competition
and possibly
your welfare may also
be connected to it.
Your friend Vasudev
not only invoked but also
assured you, Arjun.
You cannot back out now.
If Krishna has said it
then it must be correct.
Go on, Arjun.
May you be victorious.
Even seekers of alms
have been filled with the zeal
to display their might.
When such people only know
how to hold a bowl for alms
then how can they lift a bow?
Go back, 'Brahmin.'
If you try to lift the bow
then you will lose even
the last drop of your dignity.
Think of Lord Parashuram
and move forth!
The gurus who teach people
the art of weaponry
are 'Brahmins.'
Then you need not be scared,
young man. Move forth.
Our blessings are with you.
May you be victorious.
You are indeed Prince Arjun.
Lord Shiva has given me the sign
that this competition
is solely for you, Prince.
You will indeed be successful.
King Drupad, do accept
my greetings.
Vasudev Krishna
do accept my greetings.
Princess Shikhandini
and Princes Draupadi
I bow before you.
Look! He is bowing before
Princess Draupadi!
Every woman
is a form of Goddess Durga.
One who does not respect women
has no competence.
If you accidentally get married
to the Princess, 'Brahmin'
then what will you do?
Will you accept the Princess
as your wife
or establish her in a temple?
Every home is a temple,
Crown Prince Rukmi.
And the wife...
The wife is the deity
of the temple.
I assure you
that I bow before
your sister Rukmini
every single day.
Move forth, young 'Brahmin.'
Let's see if the values
imparted to you
have given you the
adequate strength or not.
All hail the great 'Brahmin!'
King Drupad
I, Patukeshwar Sharma,
hail from Panchapuri
and I brought them
to the'swayamvar.'
Now, you must reward me
handsomely, King Drupad.
They are my friends.
My friends.
A 'Brahmin' won!
He won!
All hail Mahadev!
Princess, place the garland
around his neck this instant
otherwise I shall have my
granddaughter married to him.
Arjun.