He too has a heart.
I've closely
watched him
strive over the years.
He knows
that the path
he's headed on
isn't just or right.
If we succeed in persuading him
then we could awaken
his conscience.
No, aunt.
No.
Only once
he experiences awakening
we'll be able to persuade him.
And
you'll have to do it.
Me!
How would I do it?
I tried to tell him
a lot of times
that he's my son.
I either couldn't find
propitious time
or a circumstance to express it.
How would I face him now?
How will I
persuade him?
Krishna
you're omniscient.
You are compassionate
towards everyone.
Only you can forgive me.
And...
Ask for forgiveness
on my behalf.
Once...
For once, request
him to do what is right.
Just once.
One who favours righteousness
is always favoured.
I can only remind
Karna of what's right, aunt.
Since you've asked me
I'll certainly make a request.
Greetings!
Karna is addressed as Radheya
by the whole of Arya clan
because of you.
I salute you for inculcating
righteousness in Karna.
I've failed
since my son's endorsing
the ones who are unjust.
My son was a pure soul.
I don't know
why is he defending the evil.
Perhaps he isn't aware
as to who he is.
You're here to meet Karna
but he doesn't stay here.
He stays in the palace, Krishna.
I know.
I also know
that he'll certainly
come here today.
Like a bird seeks shelter
in a tree
to find solace
away from the Sun.
If he's tired of standing
by injustice
he'd come here.
His family has treasured
righteousness as legacy for him.
Karna, your destiny
is an accumulation
of all your decisions.
One decision
can alter your destiny.
It can transform the future.
Decisions are derived
out of human perspective.
Altering perspective
is a herculean task.
The thoughts
a human has been harbouring
all his life
influence him.
When one's thoughts
can't be altered
one's decision too
can't be altered.
Hence, the future remains
uncertain as ever.
Prince Duryodhan too
could've set things right
for himself.
But he can't do anything
about it now.
It's ones experience
that influences
his thoughts, Krishna.
One who's experienced
injustice all his life
considers everyone around him
as an enemy.
What's wrong with it?
My friend deserves the throne.
How can you say that?
His father's the King.
A King's son
is crowned as a King.
Do you mean one's birth
determines what one deserves?
And not his capabilities!
You're trying to talk me
into things.
All I desire is respect.
I've never desired for power.
For I know
one's birth
determines ones rights
and one has to earn respect.
Then you only have
the right
to be a charioteer, Karna.
Don't you want
to be a part of this war?
When everyone around me
mocked at my capabilities
my friend, Duryodhan
rewarded it with what
it rightfully deserved.
I'll have to support him now.
I don't consider it
a war at all, Krishna.
I am just here
to carry out my duties.
If you were born to a King
and you rightfully deserved
to be a King.
You weren't being favoured.
Would you still call
this war a duty?
It's baseless to reason
on this, Krishna.
For I wasn't born to a King.
I don't have the right
to be a King.
For one's birth
determines one's rights.
If you ask me
one who's capable
deserves the throne.
And respect...
Self-respect is the optimal
form of respect.
For one who expects
to be respected
is never sated
with the amount
of respect one gets.
Like you're
so lost
in your quest for respect
that you aren't able
to differentiate
between the right
and the wrong.
I don't think
Duryodhan's wrong, Krishna.
Because you're looking
at the truth in fragments.
I'd told you
that one's decision
carves out one's destiny.
One decision of yours
can alter your destiny.
Assume
if Kunti was your mother.
How can I assume that?
I am Adhiratha and Radha's son
who's indebted to
Duryodhan for eternity.
No, Karna.
You don't know
whom you were born to.
You owe your capabilities
to the Sun God.
You are
Lord Suryanarayana's* boon.
*The Supreme Light.
How do you say that?
Karna
you weren't born
to Adhiratha and Radha.
They found you floating
on the Ganges.
So...
Who was I born to, Krishna?
You were born
to Kunti, the Queen.
Your father is
Lord Suryanarayana.
Hence you were born
with earrings and a shield.
You may ask Adhiratha about it.
You may ask
Lord Suryanarayana too.
Then
you may alter your perspective
and decide.
It's a request.
Mother!
Where are you, mother?
Karna, my son!
I was cooking up
a meal for you.
Mother...
- What is it, son?
What did Krishna say?
Krishna is evil, mother.
He's vicious.
Duryodhan was right.
What did he say?
- Answer me, mother.
I...
I am your son, right?
Right?
You certainly are my son.
You definitely are!
That evil Krishna has been
trying to delude me.
He wants to talk me into
things by deceiving me.
The King of Gandhar said
that he'd definitely make
an effort to deceive me.
But how can one
deceive me this way, mother.
He said
that my entire life is a lie.
He tried to make me believe
that I've been living a lie
all my life.
He deluded me
to such an extent
that he questioned my existence.
He said
that you're not my mother.
That's what he did, mother.
No one can separate us, son.
You are my son.
My son.
Who told you that you weren't
born to me and Adhiratha?
How greedy can one be
to utter such a lie?
I've always been drawn
to the Lord Suryanarayana
since I was a child.
I can look into the eye
of the scorching Sun
that people stay away from.
No matter how heavy I feel
whenever I happen to see the Sun
I feel at ease at once.
My heart's filled with joy,
mother.
But...
But that doesn't mean
that I was a boon
from Lord Suryanarayana.
Isn't it, mother?
But that doesn't mean
that I was a boon
from Lord Suryanarayana.
No, son.
Try to recall.
Try to recall, son.
When you were a kid
and I'd go to fetch water...
I used to pay attention
to you as you'd cry even
when I stood near the well.
Yes.
If you weren't my son
how could I hear you cry.
I am your mother, child.
How can he say
that you aren't my son?
How can he say that?
I am your son, mother.
I am your son.
You certainly are my son.
During your childhood,
when you were to save a kid
and you slipped off
the chariot.
I almost died.
Only a mother would be
so concerned, right?
Yes.
- And... And come here.
Look at this, son.
Look at this.
I've served you food.
How would I know
what you'd like to eat
if I wasn't your mother?
I might not have given birth
to you.
But I was the one
who raised you.