Your majesty. Please remove
the blindfold at least for once
and look at your sons.
Even my Lord hasn't seen
his sons, Sugadha.
And they shall look as good in
vision as they do through touch.
Gandhari!
Gandhari! Dear sister.
Have all your sons taken birth?
- Yes, elder brother.
Only, my daughter is yet
to be born.
That shall happen too.
Her birth isn't significant.
It is the hundred sons
that are important.
Brother!
I mean, she is important too...
Absolutely important.
Your daughter is significant
only to you.
But for the throne of Hastinapur
and to defeat Pandu's sons
your hundred sons have
a higher significance.
It seems, Shakuni
that you have prepared
for battle already.
It's possible that...
- Indeed, your majesty.
It is possible.
'Possibility' is another name
for the cycle of creation.
How can I forget that?
But your majesty,
a race to the throne
and a race between two chariots,
are similar.
In both, there is a possibility
that victory comes easy.
But capability...
Competence.
Knowing one's capability
is always beneficial,
your majesty.
'15 years later.'
Come on, charioteer.
Faster!
Faster, faster...
What are you waiting for? The
chariot is stuck. Pull it out.
Be quick, charioteer.
Is he...
- He's my son, your majesty.
Karna.
How did that armour and
earrings appear on him?
It's God gifted, your majesty.
He bears them since birth.
Faster, faster...
Who are you?
A 'Kshatriya' or a 'Suta'?*
Traditional Hindu varna/social rank: 1. Brahmins, 2. Kshatriyas, 3. Vaishyas, 4. Shudras.
Stop!
My people. Today's contest
is devoid of any result.
None of the warriors succeeded
in toppling the flag.
It is a huge shame
on the entire Kuru clan.
The way a tree looks bare
upon all its leaves being shed
that is how our
empire looks today.
Devoid of bravery
bereft of glory.
Today, only one youth impressed
me with his prodigal skill.
My charioteer
Sushen's son, Karna.
My boy...
Come here.
Your skill in riding a chariot
has truly pleased me, Karna.
I have immense faith
that you shall be a charioteer
for a prince of the Kuru clan
and perform a victory march
on these very grounds.
Chariot riding skills!
On behalf of the nation,
charioteer Sushen's son, Karna
shall be granted a reward of
a hundred gold coins
for displaying exceptional
skills in chariot riding.
Karna.
Collect the reward
that his majesty has granted.
His majesty has protected you,
charioteer.
Or else,
for committing the crime
of displaying archery skills
despite being a 'Suta'
you would have lost your life.
Do not try to rise above
your social status ever.
If the root which is bound to
be buried underneath the ground
rises above the surface,
it withers away.
Looking at your son's skills
as an archer
my mind is filled with
sadness and wonder, Sushen.*
*Adhiratha and Radha named Karna, Vasusena also known as Radheya (the son of Radha).
Forgive him, your majesty.
The society of Hastinapur
shall not forgive him.
The 'Kshatriya' soldiers and
warriors here won't forgive him.
If one keeps 'Ghee'* in a raw earthen pot
*A class of clarified butter.
the pot itself absorbs it.
Neither is that 'Ghee' useful,
nor is the earthen pot.
Skills beyond one's status
are of no use.
That is the fact, Sushen.
I have told him many a times,
your majesty
to give up his fondness
towards archery.
But...
But I...
I assure you, your majesty
that henceforth he shall
never touch a bow ever.
No, Sushen.
Archery skills are ingrained
within his soul.
Skills and craftsmanship
are a gift of god.
They cannot be repressed.
When a pearl attains full form,
the oyster opens itself.
You son's archery skills shall
surely surface as well.
And he is capable too.
But the society here won't
respect him for his skills.
It will punish him instead.
That is what I fear.
Here he shall have to
lay down his bow.
In the eastern regions,
the religion is liberal.
There, even other social classes
are allowed to pick up arms.
Tell your son that if he wishes
to learn Archery
he should settle down
in Magadha.
He must let go of his parents
and his homeland.
It saddens me, Sushen.
It is a tradition here, in the
'Kuru' and 'Panchal' regions
that apart from a 'Kshatriya',
no one else has the right
to acquire combat and weapon
skills.
Tradition is the religion,
Sushen.
And religion always asks for
sacrifice and penance.
Religion resides
within tradition.
And it is true that traditions
maintain religion.
But is religion solely
due to tradition?
Think about it.
The truth is that as there is
a sculpture hidden within a rock
there is religion within
the traditions.
There is a sculpture
within this stone.
This stone is not a sculpture
itself.
To bring out the sculpture,
it needs to be broken.
The unnecessary portions
need to be chiselled off.
Similarly
religion must be
sought within the traditions.
If the tradition of Indra's
veneration hadn't been broken
to start the tradition of
Govardhan's* veneration
*The day Krishna defeated Indra.
the Yadavas wouldn't have found
the way to their salvation.
Thus, the one who leaves
tradition unchanged
shall be deprived of religion.
And the one who blindly follows
tradition too
cannot acquire a religion.
They say that a swan has a
wisdom for distinguishing.
It leaves out the water
in the milk
and consumes only the milk.
Then, to acquire a true religion
is it crucial to possess wisdom
arising out of knowledge?
And without such a wisdom,
it is possible that one accepts
a religion, which is not
a true religion at all.
Think about it.
Oh, prince!
What are you doing?
No! Forgive me, prince!
Run!
This is unfair.
No!
No, prince.
Please do not take away
my fish.
He tried to attack you with
a weapon, Dushasan.*
*Tough ruler/punisher.
How dare you try to attack me?
- No! No, prince!
Prince Dushasan,
a fisherman's boy
can never assault a prince.
He made a mistake, prince.
Forgive him.
I shall take his life.
I am the prince, Dushasan.
And I shall be the one
to dispense justice.
Step forward, lad.
Do you wish to say anything?
My prince, I was just protecting
my fish.
I did not lift my sickle.
A prince would never lie.
You have committed the crime of
raising a weapon
against a prince
and for that, you are
sentenced to death.
My prince. You may arrest him
and take him to the minister.
But I beg you,
not to take his life.
Yes, my prince.
After all, we fishermen are
your distant relatives.
The Queen mother hails
from our clan.
Please, don't be so harsh.
Forgive him.
Forgive him, prince. This boy
has no father as well.
Bring the boy forward.
Bring him here.
He must accept the punishment.
How dare you!
Break everybody's hands.
Prince..
- Break them!
Forgive us, prince.
Forgive us.
Break their hands!
Stop!
Duryodhan..
Dushasan.
- Uncle.
These fishermen have
insulted us.
They have raised their weapons
against us.
And I shall punish them.
Only the justice council
has the right to do justice.
Or perhaps,
the king himself.
Soldiers, arrest them all.
Duryodhan.
Come on.
Uncle, you say that I must
mould myself to become the king.
But when I try to do justice,
you won't let me.
You had started a war
back there.
Does anyone start a war, within
a city of their own kingdom?
They were up in arms, uncle.
Do not argue.
A rock can break a rock.
It cannot break water.
Power can defeat those,
who are powerful.
Those who have nothing,
cannot be defeated.
And water drowns the rock.
Angry and dissatisfied subjects
can knock a king off his throne.
It breaks a kingdom.
Don't you understand that?
So do the subjects have a right
to insult a prince?
My dear child.
When will you learn to
be diplomatic?
You mustn't let arise
a situation
that would lead to your
insult in the first place.
Now, if that old hag
pardons these fishermen
then word shall spread
throughout the kingdom
that Duryodhan
has no say
within his own royal family.
Whom do you mean by old hag?
That fisherwoman.
The Queen mother of Hastinapur.
Now we have to get the
the fishermen punished.
Uncle!
Don't let the bleeding stop.
This is a reward for your
foolishness.