Whoever raises his weapon
againts Hastinaour
shall have to pay the price for it!
You are right, Grandsire!
It isn't your skills that are
being displayed in this battle
but it is your weakness that is exposed.
If you were capable indeed
instead of taking the lives
of your heirs and descendants
you would lay down your own life!
I...
am bound by my duty, Khrisna!
Duties grant liberation!
What duty is this that blinds you instead?
Surely this isn't your duty
but a snare!
A shackle!
Do not question my sense of duty, Khrisna!
In my entire life never for a moment
have I commited injustice!
In order to fulfill the promise I made to
my father I only did what was necessary!
Just for the sake of your duty
you are plunging the whole world into peril!
I do not consider this
the strength of character.
A character is which strives towards
everyone's well being, every moment.
Your character is tainted
and so is your duty!
Khrisna!
You are crossing your limit!
I respect you very much!
But you have no rights
to call one's duties tainted!
My duty is truth!
And therefore, no one can defeat me!
- No one!
- I can defeat you!
I can defeat you this very moment,
Grandsire Bheeshma!
Do not fan the flames of my anger!
There is no such metal
that does not meal in my fire!
And there is no oath, no curse or no blessing
that I cannot violate!
You are being a hindrance to worldly
well being and the course of destiny.
If you do not lay down
your weapons now
I shall surely slay you!
[MUSIC]
I do not even need a weapon to slay you!
I can slay you even
with the wheel of this chariot!
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
Khrisna!
Why aren't my arrows able to reach you, Khrisna?
I am not Vasudeva Khrisna!
I am not a Yadava!
I am not even human!
I am the most supreme God, Grandsire!
I am truth, knowledge and justice!
You are fighting only with my permission!
You are alive only with my consent.
And it is with my consent
that you may acquire death!
Please forgive me, Khrisna!
I was unaware of your true form.
You are indeed capable of slaying me.
But in order to slay me,
you are willing to violate you oath.
I must indeed be largely at fault!
What is my fault, Khrisna?
Please tell me!
Your fault is ignorance, Grandsire!
You never tried to comprehend
the true form of justice!
Until the roof of compassion
spans the entire world
until then justice in society
stays incomplete.
But you only thought about your family.
You never thought about worldly well being!
Therefore even your sacrifice
is a form of selfishness.
I renounced royalty for the sake of my father!
I swore to a lifetime of celibacy.
There were no selfish motives for these, Khrisna!
The oath to celibacy and renouncement
of royalty were indeed great deeds!
But why did you give up your responsibility
towards the society, Grandsire?
In order to avoid mutual conflict
within the Kuru clan
and to avoid war in Hastinapur for the throne
and to protect the subjects of
Kuru dynasty from pain.
I took up this oath, Khrisna.
Look all around you, Grandsire?
What is going on here?
Your oath did not avoid
this catastrophe, this war!
Ponder over it, Grandsire!
You treated your oath as your duty!
If it indeed were just
why would this great war occur?
In reality, justice isn't a name
of a forgotten thought.
It isn't the name of any tradition either.
Justice is the name of life!
And life changes constantly!
Changes is the characteristic of life!
And a human must commit deeds
for the sake of change!
Yet you give up on deeds, Grandsire?
But I have acted only appropriately
at every step of life, Khrisna.
No, Grandsire!
In this birth of yours
in order to keep yourself from the ties of actions
you have not truly engaged
in any significant action.
The meaning of actions is taking decisions
and accepting the consequences of one's actions.
But when did you take any decision,
Your Excellency?
Was crowning King Pandu your decision?
'A person who is blind since birth'
'is unworthy of becoming the King.'
'That is why I suggest'
'brother Pandu to be crowned the King.'
Was having King Dhirtarashtra
and Queen Gandahari married your decision?
'On the auspicious occasion of Akshay Tritiya'*
*Hindu holy day, believed to bring good luck and success.
'Prince Dhritarashtra shall be married
to Gandahari the Princess of Gandhar.'
Why did you not try to stop King Dhritarashtra
from committing unrighteous deed, Your Excellency?
'Prince Duryodhan was attacked by these people
and you need to punish them.'
'That is atrocious.'
'Just do as I say!'
The decision of hosting the game of dice
and that of not stopping the
humalliation of Panchali there...
'Grandsire, the whole of the Aryan
region resonates of your glory.'
'You are the son of Goddess Ganga Herself.'
'Then despite witnessing such depravity.'
'How can you even remain quite?!'
The decision of waging this war...
'To establish righteousness
in the Aryan region again'
'it is mandatory to wage a war.'
In order to stop all these unrighteous deeds not
only did you have the competence but also power.
But you could not take a decision,
Your Excellency.
You remained bound to your oath and vow!
'I...'
'shall live my life as a servant!'
The truth is that under the garb of duties
you kept running away
from the responsibilty of taking decisions!
Does taking decisions not forge new ties, Vasudev?
In order to free yourself from various tie and you
tried to understand the principle of selfness acts
then your life would have been filled
with righousness, Your Excellency.
In order to free yourself from ties,
why did you renouce actions altogether?
You could have renounced
the fruits of those actions.
Instead of deeming someone's order to be a duty
you could have deemed your action to be so.
That would have rid you of your ties as well.
You had taken that oath a very long time ago.
Did you know what the future
had in store back then?
Circumstances changed, Your Excellency.
Times changed.
But did you not break your oath.
And neither did you accept any change.
As a result of all that
this war is being waged today.
Then does an oath hold no value?
It indeed does.
An oath that benefits the
entire society indeed holds value.
However, the moment
the oath of a person and his decision
begins to affect the society adversely
then that very instant
it becomes mandatory
to break that oath, Your Excellency.
If fighting from the side of Pandavas
is the decision you cannot take today.
Then at least give up your weapons.
And accept your death.
Today being on the side of the Pandavas
if you cannot take the decision
to engage in battle
at least lay down your weapons
and accept your death!
I accept, Khrisna!
If I had acquired the knowledge
imparted by you earlier
a lot of injustice could be avoided.
But...
even if not in life
at least in death the knowledge
imparted by you will surely be useful.
Death at your hands shall be
a great honour to me.
End me!
I am ready!
As you wish, Grandsire!
No, Khrisna!
You have sworn not to engage in battle!
It is the time to break my oath now, Arjun!
That is why I am breaking my oath!
But, Khrisna, the entire world
shall condemn you then!
Then I shall accept it!
Either way, after this battle
I have to bear may insults
and curse and you are not aware of it.
But I would not feel glad or sad about it!
At this moment, Grandsire's death in inevitable!
No, Khrisna!
Give me an opportunity!
I shall give up all my affection
and defeat Grandsire under
my circumstances!
But Khrisna do not commit
such a grave sin due to me.
If it happens so because of me
that very moment
I shall die, Khrisna!
Give me an opportunity!
Please heed to my plea!
My death
is pre-ordained at the hands
of Princess Amba of Kashi.
And ought to that reason
Princess Amba is born as Shikhandini!
Let only her have the privilege
of slaying me, Khrisna!
I promise!
I promise, Khrisna.
I shall wait for her!
And the day when she faces me
on the battlefield
I shall lay down all my weapons!
Until then
I shall surely protect the soldiers of Hastinapur!
But none of your soldiers
shall die at my hands!
This is neither my duty
nor anyone's orders!
This is my decision, Khrisna!