Before beginning the competition
I welcome such a guest
whom my old eyes deem
of having the potential
of becoming the man
of the millennium
and ushering a righteous era.
Welcome, Vasudev Krishna!
The great Yadava,
Vasudev Krishna.
He is the only person
whom an intelligent person
befriends for life.
Why so, uncle?
Because in the whole of
the Aryan region, he is the one
with whom having any enmity
cannot be afforded by us.
He is way more intelligent
and cunning than me.
Vasudev
I always had
the desire to see you
in my heart.
Greetings, uncle.
You deem me your uncle, Vasudev?
You are the uncle
of my brother Duryodhan.
Hence, I must address you
as my uncle.
No, Vasudev.
No.
I fear in becoming your uncle.
Fear.
Why so, uncle?
I had salvaged my uncle Kansa.*
He imprisoned his own father, Ugrasena (King of Mathura), to usurp the throne; and later imprisoned his sister, Devaki (Krishna's mother) along with Krishna's father, Vasudeva.
I liberated him of his sins.
Greetings, brother Duryodhan.
Bless you, Krishna.
Greetings, Vasudev.
- Bless you, Dusshasan.
And you...
You must certainly be
King Karna of Anga.
By looking at the radiance
on your face
anyone can know
of your competence.
Greetings.
Greetings, Vasudev.
Meeting you is my good fortune.
The whole of the Aryan region
resonates of your righteousness.
Righteousness is such a topic,
King Karna of Anga
that everyone discusses it
but
not everyone can know it.
Then you tell us
what is the path to know
what righteousness is.
Righteousness gives respect,
King of Anga.
If one gets disrespect in
one's life, one must deem
that he did not lead
a righteous life.
And the one
who has got nothing
but disrespect since birth...
What should he do, Vasudev?
He should struggle for respect
but not side
with unrighteousness.
He must certainly
fight for his rights
but not desire something
over which he has no right.
What do you mean?
It means, King of Anga
that even the biggest
of mountains
must not desire a small river.
The mountain which
tries to stop a river
ends up breaking.
The right to a river
resides only with the ocean.
Are you talking about
the strength of the ocean
or the weakness
of the mountain, Vasudev?
I am talking about the fate
of the river, King of Anga.
Hear all!
The most beautiful
and serendipitous
Yajnaseni,* Princess Draupadi is making her entrance!
*Daughter of fire.
'When I'
'like the light'
'am surrounded by
the joy of knowledge'
'and everything is novel
all around me'
'when should I play'
'oh childhood?'
'Novel are the pictures'
'and the light
of bright colours.'
'Fire is my'
'fate.'
'I am Draupadi, who'
'never experienced childhood.'
'I am Draupadi, whose'
'fate is fire.'
Bless you.
Such a beautiful woman
ought to become
the Queen of Hastinapur, uncle.
Certainly, my dear.
Certainly.
Truly
she has unparalleled beauty.
Do have a look, King of Anga.
Admiring the beauty
of someone else's wife to be
is inappropriate, Dusshasan.
Besides
if the Princess will be
married to friend Duryodhan
she will have the status
of your mother.
You are correct.
Greetings.
No, friend.
Govind
will Prince Arjun
come to the 'swayamvar?'
Govind
will Prince Arjun
come to the 'swayamvar?'
I have a feeling, Draupadi
that if he does arrive
you shall know about it
before I do.
Splendid!
Instead of giving alms
everyone has gone
to receive charity.
If you do not get any food
what will become of you,
brother Bheem?
I can even eat
the leaves of a tree
because poison
has no effect on me.
What will become of you, Nakul?
Let's proceed to Kampilya then.
If we stay cautious
no one will recognize us.
No, Sahadev.
There must be another village
here. We should go there.
We must not go to Kampilya.
We have no business being
at the 'swayamvar' there.
Let's proceed.
Hear all!
The son of King Vradyakshen
Susharma, is making his entrance
for the competition!
Hear all!
The son of King Samudrasen
Chandrasen,
is making his entrance
for the competition!
I have firm faith
that there is indeed
a village in this direction.
I see some sages over there.
We should go ask them.
What do you think,
brother Yudhishthir?
L-Let me ask them.
Let me do it.
Greetings, sages.
- Bless you!
In which direction are you
headed, young 'Brahmins?'
We are proceeding
towards Naimisharanya
but before we proceed further
we wish to seek some alms.
That is why, we are
searching for a village.
When the King himself
has engaged in charity
then why do all of you need to
seek alms from the villagers?
Let's proceed towards
the city of Kampilya.
One will be rid of
one's poverty for life.
Let's proceed.
Do come with us.
Revered ones,
we are grateful to you
but we..
- Let all this be
and come with us.
Revered ones
do lead the way
and we shall follow.
Alright. As you wish.
- Alright.
Let's proceed in this direction.
Hear all!
The King of Ushneer, Shivi
is making his entrance
for the competition!
Even that King
got defeated, Vasudev.
I have firm faith
that the capability
to win this competition
lies solely with Arjun.
In the entire Aryan region,
this competition can be won
by two people, Your Highness.
The son of Pandu, Arjun
and
the King of Anga, Karna.
But Vasudev
he is the son of a charioteer.
I never oppose any caste
or creed, King Drupad.
The right to respect
belongs to every
competent person.
I am certainly worried that
he is with unrighteous people
but
we cannot stop him from
taking part in this competition.
However...
if marrying Karna
is not what Draupadi wants
then she can
certainly say no to it.