I command you,
grandfather
to follow Yudhishthir
and protect Hastinapur.
As soon as you
get an opportunity
slay Yudhishthir.
Charioteer, proceed
towards Hastinapur.
Friend
it's time to take
the third step.
It is time to extract
your brother Duryodhan
from Guru Drona's protection.
Of course, Madhav.
Commander Dhrishtadyumna
is busy with that task.
Release the spheres of fire!
Attack the unit
releasing the spheres of fire!
Attack!
Soldiers, get ready to attack.
Attack only once Guru Drona
reaches us.
Guru Drona has started attacking
Commander Dhrishtadyumna.
And Commander Dhrishtadyumna
will be able to stop
Guru Drona,
only for a short while.
Friend
we need to bring Guru Drona
towards you.
This is the fourth step
towards victory.
Guru Drona's only weakness
is his son.
Once I attack Ashwatthama
Guru Drona will come to me
voluntarily, Madhav.
And then
no one will be there
to protect Prince Duryodhan.
Neither His Excellency Bhishma
nor Guru Drona.
Nakul and Sahadev will clear
brother Bheem's path
to Prince Duryodhan.
The last stage of our victory
will be completed
when brother Bheem
kills Prince Duryodhan.
Kill?
Kill my Duryodhan!
No.
What kind of a plan is this,
Sanjay?
I... Anyhow, I need to send
this message to Duryodhan.
Yes!
We are very far away
from the battlefield
Your Highness.
- But...
But my son's life
is in danger, Sanjay.
I am feeling
very restless.
Do something, Sanjay.
Do something quickly.
The great sage Ved Vyas
blessed me with divine sight.
The pain born as a result
of that divine sight
will have to be borne by us,
Your Highness.
But how will I bear the pain
of my son's death?
Tell me what is happening
on the battlefield.
Who is there near him,
to protect him?
Tell me.
King Dhrupad
Guru Drona's son Ashwatthama
has always dreamt
of defeating me.
He should get an opportunity
to fulfil his wish.
I challenge you!
Select the weapon
of your choice, Ashwatthama.
Yudhishthir
you would be committing a sin
by attacking
the fort of Hastinapur.
And you must have
enough faith in me
to know that I never sin.
Then are you going
on a pilgrimage
by leaving Kurukshetra?
Catching a glimpse of you
is akin to going
on a pilgrimage, for me.
Today, this is my place
of pilgrimage, grandsire.
I was not going
to attack Hastinapur.
I am only proceeding
towards Hastinapur
as per Vasudev's strategy.
But I have received news
that you plan to attack.
You never lie.
When did I lie?
That I am proceeding
towards Hastinapur
to mount an attack...
This false news was circulated
by Vasudev.
I never said so, grandsire.
Vasudev must have been aware
that Duryodhan would get scared
and surely
command me to proceed
towards Hastinapur.
Yes, grandsire.
This is what is Vasudev's
strange strategy.
And now, you will have
to fight me and my army.
I will not be able to emerge
victorious against you
but I will surely fight you.
Guru Drona!
Your son Ashwatthama's life
is in danger.
He is battling Prince Arjun.
None of the students
of Guru Drona
are capable enough
to defeat him.
And as long as I am alive
my son's life
can never be in danger.
Guru Drona!
Friend...
the longer
you keep
Guru Drona occupied...
The longer brother Yudhishthir
keeps His Excellency Bhishma
away from the battlefield...
The better the chances
of brother Bheem
defeating Prince Duryodhan.
The final stage of our strategy
and our final step
towards victory
now depend on you,
brother Bheem
and brother Yudhishthir.
Just keep him occupied.
Get brother Bheem
as much time
as you can.
Duryodhan!
Have you become a coward
or have you lost
your self-confidence?
Come on! Fight me!
MY child!
My child
do not act foolishly.
Do not be a fool
by rising to his bait.
A smart warrior does not just
accept a challenge.
He does so at the right time.
Uncle
I shall crush this worm.
Possible, but not inevitable.
And his Excellency Bhishma
is absent from the battlefield
at this moment.
In this situation,
you should not
accept this challenge.
Soldiers, attack!
Duryodhan!
If you are really strong
face me on the battlefield.
Think about the prestige
of your clan.
You are shaming
all our ancestors
and our descendents.
Our ancestors in heaven
are hiding their faces in shame.
They are ridiculing
your parents!
Father
this is Vasudev's strategy.
I need to leave
at the earliest
to protect my friend
Duryodhan.
None of your strategies
will be successful, Arjun.
You cannot leave
without completing the fight.
What sort of a eunuch
has your mother
given birth to?
- Bheem!
Why did you declare war
when you fear death?
Come on, Duryodhan!
Rub your head on my feet.
Are you a Kshatriya
or a eunuch?
Bheem!