Pardon me, dear
but if the Kauravas win
then the entire society
will meet with misfortune
and establishing righteousness
will become impossible.
And
in the path to defeating
the Kauravas
you are acting as a fortress.
If you take an oath
to back out from this war
then I can release you
from the promise you made.
The decision is yours.
Either back out from this war
or give up the protection
of your armour.
Do accept the charity,
Lord Indra.
For the sake
of your son's victory
you had to engage
in such a grave deception
with me, Lord Indra.
The mere sight of this
gives me the joy of victory.
What have you done,
Lord Indra?!
You asked for the armour and
ear-rings of King Karna of Anga!
Yes, Arjun.
Now, there will be no obstacle
in the path to your victory.
But how could you act
so unjustly, father?!
By rendering my enemy weak
you have rendered me
weak as well.
If there is no challenge
then how can there be
an increase in one's strength?
The trees that grow on rocks
are very strong, Lord Indra.
But the stem of a lotus
growing in a pond
is not strong.
Today, you have tainted
my reputation, Lord Indra.
The severed thumb of Ekalavya
weighs my spirit down
even to this day.
Even today, whenever someone
appreciates my archery
I am reminded of Ekalavya.
I begin to doubt
that had Ekalavya
not sacrificed his thumb
would he have been
stronger than me?
Because of
Ekalavya's severed thumb
my competence has been
gravely tainted, father.
By asking for the armour and
ear-rings of King Karna of Anga
you have tainted
my reputation further, father.
Because of me
you inflicted such agony
on the King of Anga.
Did
you not have faith
in the competence of your son?
Did you not have faith
in his Gandiva?
Or did you not have faith
in your own blessing, father?
The question is not about
your competence, Arjun.
Karna's armour
was not a celestial weapon
bestowed by a God.
It was a part
of Surya Dev himself.
After his birth
Karna was Messed with it.
It was necessary
to have it removed.
In a war of humans
no part of a God
can ever take part in it.
Neither for protection
nor attack.
That is why, Lord Hanuman
shall be present on your flag
and not in your chariot.
But you have cursed me,
father!
I could have slain
King Karna of Anga
with the presence of his
armour and ear-rings.
However,
as I have taken an oath
I will still slay
King Karna of Anga!
However
by asking for the armour and
ear-rings of the King of Anga
you...
You have snatched the joy
of victory from me, father.
People will say
that only because of
the weakness of my enemy
did I gain victory.
My victory
has been turned into
an insult by you, father.
Now, please have
mercy on your son
and return the King of Anga
his armour and ear-rings!
That is impossible,
Arjun.
King Karna of Anga
will never take back anything
he gave away as charity.
However, I am willing
to give you a boon.
Go ahead,
dear Karna.
Ask me for a boon.
I have engaged in charity,
Lord Indra.
I have not engaged
in a business dealing.
If I grace someone
with my presence
and give him nothing in return
then it would taint
my reputation.
Go ahead.
Ask for anything you like,
dear
To a warrior,
the greatest boon
is his weapon.
If you are so intent on giving
then give me a weapon.
An unfailing weapon
which, when released in the
name of a particular person
slays that very person.
So be it!
Do remember, dear.
You can use this weapon
only once
and that too
when the enemy is right before
your eyes in the battlefield.
I accept it, Lord Indra.
Arjun
you will indeed die at my hands.
I will use the very weapon
given by your father
to slay you
very soon...
Karna!
Son!
Karna...
Karna!
Son!
Be careful,
King of Gandhar.
The war begins tomorrow
but you are already staggering!
Before embarking on
an enterprise of this magnitude
it is quite natural to stagger,
Vasudev.
When man becomes presumptuous
he also becomes heedless.
And when it is time
for man to stagger
the entire creation
compels him to become heedless.
Various situations arise
which are bound to make man
presumptuous.
And what are
the various situations
you are going to give rise to
Vasudev?
When did I ever give rise
to a situation?
Man's actions
give rise to various situations.
And our reactions
in those situations
bind us to them.
His Excellency
had your sister married
to a blind man
and that gave rise
to a situation where revenge
was born in your heart.
And by taking an oath
to aid your sister
and her sons have the throne
you have bound yourself
to that situation.
Tomorrow's war
is the result of that oath.