On behalf of Hastinapur
I have arrived with a message
from King Dhritarashtra
O sons of Pandu!
Before plunging the entire Arya
clan down the path of battle
it is necessary that both sides
ruminate over their thoughts.
This is a request
by his Majesty.
The battle had begun
that very day, Sanjay...
When Draupadi was dragged
into the royal court
unnecessarily...
When that brute laid hands
upon Draupadis drapes...
The royal court where
Draupadis drapes were yanked
represented the Arya clan.
It represented humanity.
It symbolised the faith
of all women in the world.
So, justice shall be done
for that.
The time to ruminate
was before the royal courts
incident, Sire Sanjay.
Go tell your King
to rather ruminate
over his battle strategies.
There are two perspectives to
every incident, sons of Pandu.
If you put forth one perspective
the sons of Dhritarashtra
will put forth the other.
It is futile to debate over an
incident of the past, Pandavas.
Demise and insult
can never be the past!
A persons demise,
that is, his death
can affect all the lives
affiliated to his own.
A persons insult
affect his present life!
You speak the truth
revered Sanjay.
There are two perspectives
to an incident.
And when a battle is fought
when the perspectives conflict
only then can it be decided
as to whose perspective is true.
I approve of your anger,
King Dhrupad.
But this battle shall have
dire consequences.
You know, My Lord
that youths are sacrificed
in a battle
and what is left behind
are children and aged ones.
The old ones,
who have no direction
and children,
who have no one to guide them.
By the screams of widows
this world will be rendered
poisonous, My Lord.
If the atrocious ones
come into power
the potential of the youth
is destroyed.
The future of the children
The aged ones perish.
The honour of women is violated.
Penance, justice, customs
and practices are destroyed.
Whatever losses are
caused by this battle
seem greater than that
in peace to me.
Justice can be established
even without a war, O Pandavas!
Put forth a proposal
before King Dhritarashtra
that establishes justice and
causes no destruction either.
Even King Dhritarasthra's mind
is worried by the possibility
of battle, O Princes.
He shall agree to any choice
to gain your approval
and restore your honour.
Now, if this clan
faces destruction
his wisened heart
will suffer immense pain.
If you do not approve
of this proposal
then...
Then you may continue
with the battle.
But peace should be
given a chance, O Princes.
Before the declaration of a war
attempting to call for a truce
once
is a royal obligation.
Lord Krishna,
what is your
opinion about this topic?
I have no opinion whatsoever,
revered minister.
A person may have his eyes
open or closed
when the sun rises
even with his eyes closed
he perceives light.
Similarly, one may
follow his duties or not
he surely is aware
of his duties.
I am confident
that brother Yudishtir
is aware of his duties.
What have you all decided?
Draupadi, attempting for a truce
before a battle
is a royal obligation.
And we cannot overlook
our obligations.
What does Krishna have to say?
Eldest brother has
requested Krishna
to visit Hastinapur
with a peace proposal.
And Krishna is of the belief
that one may follow
his duties or not
he is always aware
of his duties.
We must fight this battle
to vanquish the tyrants
and establish justice.
Apart from your five husbands
all the descendants
of King Shantanu may perish! [WOMAN SING]
The entire family of King Pandu
must make sacrifices
or accept the tyranny of
the sons of King Dhritarashtra!
[MUSIC STOPS]
A Peace proposal?
We cannot send
a peace proposal, My Lord!
How can we forget
our honour and our duty?
The one who ill-treats a woman
must be punished by death!
This isn't a war,
but an attempt to reformation.
This is a revolution!
And a revolution has no peace,
O Arya Princes!
Krishna cannot go ahead
with this peace proposal!
Where is Krishna?
[HORSE NEIGHING]
Krishna!
I ruminated upon your words!
I strengthened my heart.
I accepted all pains.
In spite of so many difficulties
when I swore to make a sacrifice
you have decided
against all of it?
Attempting at peace before a war
is inevitable, Draupadi.
And what if the proposal
is accepted
won't there be a war, Krishna?
This is the decision
of the sons of Pandu.
They have no rights to make
such a decision, Krishna.
I was the one who was
humiliated in the courtroom.
dishonored, Krishna.
If the entire Arya clan
mocks someone
it is me.
My sons have to suffer the pain
of my mockery, Krishna.
Therefore only I shall decide
whether to fight a war
or not to.
No, Draupadi!
The decision for war
cannot be made
either for revenge
or to prove ones sanctity
to others.
The decision for war
can be made only for justice.
Only I have the rights
to demand justice, Krishna.
Indeed!
If you demand for justice
you will indeed get it.
This is my word.
- But how, Krishna?
You are going there
to have talks of peace.
How will you make it
culminate into battle?
Have faith, Draupadi.
Not just in me
but also in Duryodhan.
There shall indeed be a war!
Will we be able to
capture Krishna, uncle?
Why this doubt, my lad?
I have heard many tales
about him, uncle.
He is a sorcerer,
an illusionist.
Some even behold him
as an incarnation of God.
All those are futile talks.
Accepting fear as God
is human nature.
And the nature of fear is
one fear gives
rise
to another fear.
In reality
Krishna is
a mere human.
He is far more powerful
and his wisdom
sometimes even baffles me.
But a God...
is something he is not.
Fear giving rise to fears
is happening in your mind,
uncle.
I do not fear Krishna at all!
He had the army of Narayana
which is now with me!
He is unarmed.
So what harm could he cause?
The scriptures say
one wrestler is mightier
than two scholars.
Because he can land a blow
on each scholars head
and teach them of
the path to heaven. [LAUGHING]
My lad!
Do not be so haughtily proud
of your might.
It is difficult even
to breach close to a clever man
If Krishna has sided
with the Pandavas
even my deceit cannot help you
attain victory.
Remember!
Even the most skilled warriors
on your side
are all influenced by Krishna.
Your friend, the armored Karna
respects Krishna.
That old Bhairav
considers Krishna to be great.
Kripacharya, Dronacharya,
Vidur, all of them
fear Krishna.
If Krishna
enters the battlefield
representing the Pandavas
the might of all of
your skilled warriors
will be cleaved in halves.
Therefore
capturing Krishna
and imprisoning him
is a good move.
[LAUGHING]
I shall capture him.
In front of the entire
royal court
I shall capture him.
Everyone shall know
whether the greatness of Krishna
is true
or a mere legend.
[LAUGHING]
By the end of the meeting
all of them shall be laughing
at Krishna, uncle.
His respect will be reduced
to mockery
when he is in prison.
Be quiet, my lad!
He might overhear us.
Will he hear us
from so far, uncle?
I suspect that this person
overhears everything.
Greetings, Your Highness!
Bless you, Krishna!
I am here with a message
from the sons of Pandu.
O the supreme Yadava!
A flute just transforms
gusts of air into tunes.
But the ability to transform
Pandavas message into knowledge
can be possessed only by you.
My Lord, listening to
the tunes of my flute
the cows of Brindavan
yielded more milk.
But donkeys used to bray
tunes of their own.
The importance of tunes
lies with the listener, My Lord!
Greetings to the Queen!
Welcome to Hastinapur, Krishna!
The conflicting turn
that the Kuru clan stands at
only you can guide it
towards the path of peace.
There is only one path
to life, O Queen!
The travelers mind makes it
either a path of peace
or that of conflict.
But I assure you
that I shall sincerely try
to avoid any conflict.