I am the truth! I am complete!
I am life and I am God!
I am prime alphabet!
I am "Shamveda (melody knowledge)" among "Vedas"! I am
"lndra" among Gods!
I am the consciousness in animals! I
am "Kubers ( the Lord of Wealth, the god-king of the semi-divine Yakshas)" among the "Yakshas (benevolent nature-spirits)"!
I am "Shanker (Shiva)" among the "Rudras (Shiva's followers)"!
I am "Fire" among Demi-Gods!
I am "Summeru (a sacred mountain with five peaks, the center of all universes)" among mountains! And
I am "Brighu (one of the seven great sages)" among saints!
I am "Omkar (mantra)" among sounds! I am the
chant in "Yagyas (yajna, ritual of offerings)"!
I am the holy "Peepul (Ficus religiosa, sacred fig)" amoong trees!
I am the memory of intelligence!
I am intellect, constancy and
patience!
I am glow!
I am "Chitrarath (king of gandharvas)" among "Gandharvas (distinct heavenly beings)"!
I am "Narad (a Vedic sage)" among divine saints!
I am "Kapil (the founders of the Samkhya school of philosophy)" among sages!
I am "Uccheshawa" among horses! I am
"Airavat (a mythological white elephant who carries the Hindu god Indra)" among elephants!
And I am the lion among animals!
I am the eagle among birds and the
King among humans
and the "Vajra (diamond)" among armours!
I am "Kamdhenu (a divine bovine-goddess)" among cows!
I am "Vasuki (a naga, one of the King serpents)" among serpents!
I am "Sheshnag (a mythical snake with 5 heads)"! I am "Yamraj (lord of death)"!
I am the Rain God and the Wind God
as well!
I am Lord Ram! I am Holy Ganga!
I am the origin, sustenance and end
of creation!
I am "Bramha's" knowledge! I am
"Mahakaal (lord of destruction)"
and "Bramha', effect, victory,
nutrient
and decision.
I am punishment, power, strategy,
silence
and "Tattva ('thatness', 'principle', 'reality' or 'truth')" knowledge as well.
I am Vasudev, Arjun, Ved-Vyas!
There is nothing that is not me!
There is no place where I am not
present!
I am time
and I am life and death, Arjun!
I stand here as the death of all
humans present here!
Even if you do not raise your weapons
I shall slay them all!
Therefore overcome your desire
and comprehend your duties!
Shoulder the burden of justice!
Raise your "Gandiva" bow and
commence the battle!
Engage in battle, Arjun!
Engage in battle!
O' Madhava! O' Madhusudan*!
*Slayer Of Demon Madhu.
Today, all my doubts have been
obliterated!
Kindly return to your human form!
I shall obey every order of yours!
"Karishye vachanam Tava (thy will be done)!"
Krishna, with his "Yogic" illusion,
has imparted the entire “Bramhic“
knowledge
into Arjun's mind in a single moment,
Your Majesty!
Even I have attained sanctity by
this knowledge.
I indeed feel so!
There is not doubt anymore
that Arjun, with his great power and
resilience
has raised his "Gandiva" bow Your
Majesty!
What else is happening at
"Kurukshetra", Sanjay?
Continue describing everything to me
in detail.
The Pandava army is gathering for
its first day of formation.
The five Pandavas, are heading east
upon their horses, Your Majesty!
At the foremost position of the formation all five
Pandavas are upon their chariots, Your Majesty!
Because they have smaller army
on their side,
they have assumed such a formation
by which they can penetrate into our
formation
and reach Prince Duryodhan at the
earliest!
What could be such a formation,
Sanjay.
Which has the capability to pierce
through an entire army?
The biggest strength of commanders-
in-chief
whose formation is immensely
difficult
and to control which is equally
difficult!
The one which is terrifying as the
armour of God Indra!
The "Vajra" formation!
The Pandavas have assumed the
"Vajra" pattern, Grandsire!
Order our soldiers to assume our
formation!
No formation shall be assumed at
this time, Prince!
There shall only be a retaliation to
their attack!
Soldiers!
Attack!
Uncle Shalya.
Uncle.
Is that weapon in your hand called
as "delusionist" too?
- Or else, it won't work.
- No, dear.
This weapon is called "your death".
Grandsire, I hope you remember your
vow.
You must fight the war with all
your power.
You must destroy their entire army
today
and get me to Yudhistir.
I want victory today, Grandsire.
Today.
As long as I'm alive
I won't let you get defeafed,
Duryodhan.
But as long as the Pandavas are
together
your victory is impossible.
Grandsire.
Ask them to form a squared planning.
We don't have time to build anything
now.
Let them get over with their
wreckage.
Arjun.
Ride the chariot towards Duryodhan.
At your command.
Madhav.
Grandsire. That eagle will eat our
army.
Why don't you say something?
What delusion are you in?
Prince Arjun, with much quickness
has destroyed the foremost part our
army's formation, My King.
All five brothers
are at a close proximity to Prince
Duryodhan!
They shall soon be facing Prince
What!
But why isn't Grandsire coming up with a
counter attack for protecting my sons, Sanjay?
Grandsire Bhishma!
The Pandavas are smashing through
our army!
If we do not counter them
they shall soon reach my dear lad
Duryodhan!
Why aren't you assuming a better
formation to counter them?
A crocodile always keeps it's mouth
open
until the fish fully enters into its
mouth with confidence!
I was awaiting Grandsire's blessings!
I have it now!
Now I shall duel with Grandsire!
Proceed, Krishna!
The time has come for the crocodile
to shut its jaws!
Untill all five Pandavas are together
we cannot reach Yudishtir!
Now, it is time to separate the
Pandavas!
Bheem, Arjun, Nakul, Sahadev...
We must stay together at all times!