All hail Prince Duryodhan!
Friend Kama
do you know the importance
of this day?
Until now, my life was filled
with the darkness of the night
and unfulfilled dreams.
But henceforth, I shall have
the light of the day
and all my dreams
will be fulfilled.
And when it comes
to fulfilling your dreams
I shall always be
a step ahead of you.
Greetings, father.
Bless you, son!
Today, the dream
in these blind eyes
will be fulfilled, son.
The blind can only see dreams
and not the world.
That is why
the attachment to one's dream
cannot be seen
by people with vision.
The truth is
I am very happy today
and I feel as though I can see.
Truly.
Go on, son.
Go on.
Greetings, grandsire.
- Bless you.
Those who see only dreams
and not the world
are called blind.
Today, your dream
will be fulfilled.
I have firm faith that you too
shall be blessed with vision.
My dear!
My dear
what one needs to see and not
can be discussed later.
You must seek the blessings
of your mother now.
Greetings, mother.
Greetings, brother.
- Bless you, son.
Duryodhan
when old clothes are adorned
with new embroidery
it is done only on
the existing patterns.
That adds beauty to old clothes.
You must glorify the memories
of your brother Yudhishthir
when you become
the Crown Prince.
When old walls are painted with
a fresh coat of paint, mother
the old paint gets covered.
People will forget
my elder brother
because I will be
that good a ruler.
All hail Crown Prince Duryodhan!
- Greetings, father.
May you live long, son.
'This wound will remind me
of how Gandhari'
'has met with grave injustice.'
'It is in the best interest
of His Highness'
'to have Duryodhan anointed'
'as the Crown Prince.'
'Until the sons of Pandu return'
'no one will be anointed
as the Crown Prince.'
Uncle
the 'swayamvar' of
the Princess of Panchal
awaits me now.
Princess Draupadi herself
is awaiting none but you,
my darling!
Sons, you should rest
for a while now.
You must be tired from lifting
my weight all this while.
One who considers
his mother to be a weight
indeed gets tired.
You need not worry, mother.
When they get tired,
I shall lift you.
I had told them earlier
that I am capable of lifting
the palanquin by myself
but they refused
to listen to me.
We too must get the opportunity
to serve mother, brother Bheem.
But why do you not
help us lift the palanquin?
Have you seen how tall I am?
If I hold the palanquin
from one side
mother will have to sit
in a crooked manner.
Besides, this is probably the way to Naimisharanya.*
*Naimisha Forest lay on the banks of the Gomati River (in Uttar Pradesh now), between the Panchala Kingdom and the Kosala Kingdom.
We shall come across a village
or hermitage on this path soon.
Someone will guide us then.
Oh, Lord!
Oh, Lord! - I can see
people over there.
Wait right here.
Let me go check.
Oh, Lord!
May you live long.
Have a long life.
All hail Lord Vedvyas!
Go on, villagers.
One serpent had bitten him.
Do not take your anger out
on all the serpents.
Now, I am expecting some guests
whom I had been
awaiting for a while.
Go on.
Come over here.
I have been awaiting you in
this forest for three days now.
What is your name?
How can you expect the people
whose names you do not know?
Names are not the only mode
to get to know people, Bheem.
How did you know
that my name is Bheem?
I had heard that only you
can ask such questions.
Where is your mother Kunti
and the four brothers of yours?
Call them here as well.
My disciples have arranged
for you to rest and dine here.
Stay here for the night
and leave at dawn.
The great sage Vedvyas!
Greetings!
- May you live long.
May you live long.
Be seated. Lifting the palanquin
must have left all of you tired.
I knew
that the fire in Varnavrat
could never burn
the sons of Pandu.
But My Lord, it is our wish
that the world deems us dead.
My Lord
did we take
an appropriate decision?
Man has the delusion
that he takes all decisions
on his own
but one who lives by clouding
his vision with emotions
cannot take a decision
on his own, Kunti.
The truth is
those decisions
are taken by fate.
The decision you have
taken is appropriate
but very soon it will
become inappropriate.
What do you mean?
I believe, you shall
get your answers
in Kampilya,
the city of King Drupad.
When you leave tomorrow at dawn
while proceeding towards
Naimisharanya
all of you must take rest
in the city of Kampilya.
Kampilya?
Draupadi
to compete for your
hand in marriage
every King and Prince
of the Aryan region
is quite eager.
107 noble men
have come here with the
intention of marrying you.
It is quite evident from the
presents sent by the Kings
that your marriage holds
great political value.
I have understood the value
of my marriage, sister.
But what is my value
in this marriage?
Why are you asking
such a question, Draupadi?
I feel restless, sister.
Despite being served
in a gold platter
food does not become tastier.
Will the Prince
who wins the competition
be able to win me over?
The day of the 'swayamvar'
I will certainly have
107 questions before me
but will there be
a single answer
to my questions?
Princess...
Princess!
Princess, take a look
at what I have brought for you.
What is that, Malini?
It is for you.
I have brought it for you.
The city of King Drupad
Kampilya, lies
right before us, mother.
We must look for
a place to rest here.
There must be an inn somewhere.
Who is he, sister?
He is Arjun.
Greetings.
King Drupad has sent
many such paintings to the spies
in every corner
of the Aryan region
to look for Arjun
and to invite him
to the 'swayamvar'
so that he comes to the event
and gets married to you.
This is what King Drupad wants.
And what do you want, Govind?