Alright, child.
Do this.
There is a person
at the stables
who goes by the name of Dhamgranthi.*
*"Abode of a relater/narrator/chanter."
Go and give this 'laddoo' to him.
Go and give it to him.
Go on.
Dhamgranthi.
Are you Dhamgranthi?
He is.
But Tantripal told me
that Dhamgranthi is a person.
Tantripal has sent
a gram flour 'laddoo'.
Wonderful!
I was wondering
when the 'laddoo' will arrive.
You may have it.
- Won't you have it?
If I have it,
I will gain weight
and become ugly like you.
Have it.
Even Minister Kank
loves these sweets.
Has chef Ballav
sent him 'laddoo'?
How would I know that?
Your Highness, we have brought
food for you.
Gram flour 'laddoo'!
Who had the audacity
to send me these sweets?
Your Highness,
if you permit me
may I have the 'laddoo'?
I am reminded of my childhood
while having them.
Of course.
You have made my kingdom
prosper so much.
Not just a portion
of my food
you may even ask for a portion
of my kingdom.
Attendant, keep the food here.
We will have it later.
Your Highness
you seem to be distracted today.
Minister Kank
my subjects are very upset
over General Keechak's conduct.
But he is the Queen's brother.
Hence, I can't control him.
General Keechak is the strength
of our kingdom.
The basis of our protection.
A tortoise's shell becomes
a burden for its whole body
because
its shell is its
only protection.
Meaning?
Your Highness
a wise king does not depend
on a single source of protection
for his kingdom.
He divides the responsibilities
among several people.
Even you need to do that.
Attendant
has the same food been sent
to the Queen's chamber?
Yes, sire.
Enough. I cannot dance any more, Brihannala.*
*"Large reed" or "having a reed."
I am tired.
You got tired so soon,
Uttara!
How will you grow strong
by learning to dance?
Train yourself in warfare.
Only then
will you become strong.
Alright, Uttar.
If you are that strong
prove it by dancing.
I am a warrior.
I don't dance.
Knowledge of dance
even helps in warfare, Prince.
Dance in warfare!
Definitely.
Raise your sword
and try to injure me.
Then, watch the miracle
called dancing.
Prince
in life, dance is equally
important in times
of struggle and peace.
Remember.
If the joyful 'Tandav'* of Lord Shiva gives life
*Divine dance performed by Shiva.
then the terrible 'Tandav'
takes it away as well.
Gram flour 'laddoo'?
Why do we have these sweets
for our meals repeatedly?
Take them away.
Your Highness
if you permit me
I wish to visit the town
for a while.
Of course.
Princess Uttara
will rest now.
Malini*
*"Having a garland."
have you finished
adorning my hair?
Yes, Your Highness.
Where are you going?
Your Highness
Today I am observing a fast called 'Yaksh Poojan'.*
*Worship of Yaksh/benevolent nature spirits.
And the sun is about to set.
If you permit me..
May I offer the prayers?
Wait for a while.
First, take this vessel
containing liquor
to my elder brother's house.
Forgive me, Your Highness.
But
But I am an expert maid.
My duty is to style your hair.
I can't undertake the task
meant for servants.
No one refuses to obey General
Keechak's order in Kingdom of Matsya.
You are under the protection
of Minister Kank.
And for some reason,
the King is very fond of him.
I am aware of that as well.
But if my brother
gets angry with you
he will have you burnt alive.
No one will be able
to protect you.
Take this and deliver it
to his house.
Right now.
Brother Bheem
is there any reason
behind sending the 'laddoo'?
I was very eager
to see your ugly face.
But, brother Bheem
elder brother had told us
that unless
it is something serious
you should not send any message
through 'laddoo'.
But there is a serious problem.
Your waist has become
very narrow, Brihannala.
Eat the food that I prepare
and become strong
as one needs to be strong enough
to face a battle.
Did Panchali not receive
my message, Arjun?
She is the only one
who is yet to arrive.
We had seen the gram flour
'laddoo' together brother Bheem.
But I think
the Queen stopped her
and gave her some task.
Bring that vessel here.
Forgive me.
I might stumble in the dark.
Let me light up the chamber.
Now, remove this veil,
expert maid.
Otherwise, you will get burnt.
I have already told you,
General Keechak.
I am under the protection
of the immortal Gandharvas.
Fire, poison or weapons
cannot harm me.
But yes.
You should definitely
worry about your well being.
Words spoken behind a veil
echo
and I hear those words
several times.
The results of your sins
will be such
that you will be punished
several times over.
Who are you?
You seem to be from
some royal family.
Such beauty
can be found only among royalty.
Beauty and character are not
bound by any caste or creed.
They can be found anywhere.
And I never lift my veil.
You have not seen
my beauty at all.
I have.
Once, at Sudeshna's palace
I had seen your
beautiful face.
I am enchanted
by your beauty.
I am even ready
to marry you.
I am already married,
General Keechak.
If your husband is alive
then why do you
leave your hair untied?
My husband has taken a vow
of extreme penance
to finish all the sinners
in this world.
I leave my hair untied
at his orders.
Move out of my way.
Foolish maid
if you reject
General Keechak's love
then I will force you
to surrender to me.
The one who touched my clothes
will die a horrific death.
God Himself has granted
this boon to me.
You have made
a very big mistake
by touching my clothes.
Then call your protectors
and save yourself.
I had told you
that I am under the protection
of five immortal Gandharvas.
No one can touch me
against my will.
Listen to me.
While you are under the protection
of the great King Virat
don't indulge in such sins,
Keechak.
Before the serpents residing
under the ground
the ones clinging to the
sandalwood trees have to die.
You will have to die,
in the same manner.
I am grateful to Queen Sudeshna
for giving me food and shelter.
Hence, I am forgiving you
this time.
Very soon, I'll uncover
your secret.
And that day
you will voluntarily
have to come to me,
for protection.
Yes!