You cannot slay my father.
You will have to slay me first.
You are wonderful, Draupadi.
In order to re-establish
righteousness
I shall require two weapons.
You are one of them
and the other is Arjun.
What happened, Arjun?
Mother, I can hear
a woman crying.
Brother Bheem's stomach
must be growling
because of hunger.
My stomach's growling does not
sound like a woman crying.
It sounds like a lion's roar.
Brother Bheem!
Arjun...
Arjun!
Stop!
Who are you?
And what are you doing in this
illusory forest, alone?
Are you...
Are you an ogre or a human?
A human.
Had I been an ogre
I would have asked you
whether I should fry
or roast you for my meal.
Show yourself
and tell me who you are.
These ogres devoured
my entire family.
I managed to escape
from there somehow
but now, I cannot find
a way out of this forest.
Come with me.
Four brothers of mine and
our mother are resting nearby.
We shall protect you.
Yudhishthir...
Son, where has Arjun
gone, all alone?
That too in this
illusory forest.
I am very worried about him.
Mother, you need not worry.
We shall find him.
I shall go look for him.
- No, Bheem.
Now, no one will go
anywhere, alone.
All of us will go together.
Arjun had gone
in that direction.
But even his footprints
are not visible.
I shall rip out all the trees
of this forest, mother!
We will find Arjun.
Brother Bheem
you may put the tree down.
Arjun
who is...
Mother, this maiden was crying.
Her
parents were slain by the ogres.
She is terrified.
That is why, I have
brought her to your refuge.
You need not worry, dear.
My sons will protect you.
Brother Bheem will protect you.
Right, brother Bheem?
- What! Yes.
Since it is mother's order,
I shall certainly protect her.
Why won't I?
What is your name, dear?
How did your family end up
in this terrifying forest?
We were on a pilgrimage.
We lost our way
and entered this forest
and...
And in this forest
the ogres...
The ogres devoured my family...
Calm down, dear.
No need to be afraid now.
We should leave now.
Yes.
But will you be able to walk
or do you need
to rest for a while?
She shall indeed
be able to walk, mother.
When I saw her,
she was sitting and crying.
She was not engaged
in any physical labour.
Arjun!
It is not right to laugh
at another's plight.
Pardon me, brother Bheem.
Mother asked if you will
be able to walk or not.
Yes, I am alright.
Let's go.
In which direction are we
proceeding, brother Yudhishthir?
Even the sky is not
visible here.
How will we find our way out?
During this season
the wind always blows
from East to West Nakul.
That is why, we are
headed towards West.
This is West.
It smells of meat from here.
This forest reeks
from all directions.
But that is the smell of food...
In other words,
it is the meal of the ogres.
And some of this smell
is also from the fruits that
have fallen from the trees.
I have become familiar
with that smell now.
Can you tell us from this smell
from where we can find
some fruits to eat?
Certainly. There must be
some fruit trees ahead.
The smell of fruits
is coming from there.
Wonderful!
How strange!
The fruit trees are so near.
However, brother Bheem has
not gone to pluck them yet.
The way you have conquered sleep
similarly, brother Bheem
has conquered hunger.
Then we need to conquer
hunger as well
because I do not think
that brother Bheem
will go to pluck fruits for us.
Arjun, be quiet.
Bheem.
Son, go and get the fruits.
As you say, mother.
Brother's hunger got quelled
even though mother
didn't feed him.
Many people transform pride
into their life's goal.
They toil away recklessly
to add a feather to
their existing pride.
But, what is pride in reality?
Have you ever thought
about that, King Drupad?
No.
If you ever had,
you would've realized that
a person blinded by pride
begs for respect.
He wants everyone to praise him.
He always craves to hear
about his glorious past.
It implies that he expects others
to acknowledge his strengths.
He never has faith upon himself
whatsoever.
He lives in fear
of being a weakling.
He never has any sort of power.
It means
the one filled with pride is
also surrounded by fear.
Your Highness.
Isn't pride just another name
for fear?
Think about it, Your Highness.
Your Highness.
Fear chains your heart
and pride is a link
in that chain.
Take yourself for instance.
A man drowned in pride can
never appreciate love.
You have earned enmity
of your friends.
And your children...
Your children are no more than
weapons of assault for you.