Stop!
What are you doing,
Dhritarashtra?
Who permitted you
to make Duryodhan King?!
Permission!
Does the King of Hastinapur
seek permission before
taking decisions, Your Highness?
Be quiet, King of Gandhar!
I, son of Shantanu,
Devavrat Bhishma
always walk ahead
the King of Hastinapur!
This is my oath!
By walking ahead
on the righteous path
I guide and protect
the King of Hastinapur!
And as he is on
an unrighteous path
I am blocking his way
and protesting against him!
That is why...
That is why, seeking
my permission is mandatory.
But great Bhishma
how can you obstruct
an action of the King?
You have taken an oath
of not going against Hastinapur
and taking to arms.
I have taken the oath
to make sure that
the throne of Hastinapur
is presided over by a competent
and righteous King.
And if I see an unrighteous King
on the throne of Hastinapur
then I shall
indeed take to arms!
And this
does not break my oath.
Does anyone have the competence
to stand up against me?!
Pardon me, great Bhishma
but if I am ordered
by the King of Hastinapur
then I shall indeed
demonstrate my competence.
I do not know
if I will be victorious
on my friend's behalf or not
but in order to protect him
I am prepared to sacrifice
even my life.
Dhritarashtra!
Before the anointment ceremony
order the King of Anga
to take to arms!
And let Prince Duryodhan know
that when it is time
to crush unrighteousness
how fiercely I,
Devavrat Bhishma, fight!
No, uncle!
No!
There was no intention
to insult you.
But uncle
I wish to transfer the duties
of the kingdom to my son
and resort to asceticism.
You may certainly do so.
You are the Acting King
and you may make
your son the same.
But you cannot make him King.
Why can he not do so,
great Bhishma?
There must be a reason.
When he has already been
made the Crown Prince
then what can be the problem
in declaring him the King?
Duryodhan's coronation
as the Prince holds no value.
How can it not hold
any value, grandsire?
You had permitted me
to be coronated as the Prince.
But the first one to be
coronated as the Prince
was Yudhishthir.
The five brothers have died
in Varnavrat, grandsire.
When the first Crown Prince
is not alive
then I am next in line
to be the Crown Prince.
The first Crown Prince
is alive.
Are
you telling the truth, uncle?
The sons of Pandu are alive?
The 'swayamvar' of the daughter
of the King of Panchal
was witnessed
by Duryodhan himself.
Was it not
a difficult competition?
Can the winner
of that competition
be an ordinary 'Brahmin?'
That was indeed Arjun.
And if Arjun is alive
then so is Yudhishthir.
Do you believe now,
Dhritarashtra
that making Duryodhan King
is unrighteous?
Now, if
Yudhishthir is alive
then making Duryodhan King
is no longer possible.
Then where are the sons
of Pandu, great Bhishma?
If the sons of Pandu are alive
then do bring them here.
Vidur has gone to Kampilya
to bring them here.
How can we believe
that the Minister
has gone to Kampilya?
He did not seek the permission
of His Highness before leaving.
And even the timpani
were not heard
as a sign of a message
being received.
They shall indeed return.
Soon.
How many days?
How many years?
His Highness
there must certainly
be a time limit.
Yes!
There must be
a time limit, uncle.
Two days, three days, a week?
If the sons of Pandu
do not return within a week
or if there is no news of them
then Duryodhan will certainly
be made the King, uncle.
And at that time
you too must accept
this decision, uncle.
Not a week...
Not even a day, Your Highness.
Listen.
The welcome ceremony
of Crown Prince Yudhishthir
has already begun.
The Pandavas have
reached Hastinapur.
Righteousness is returning
to Hastinapur.
Greetings, His Highness.
Bless you, dear.
Greetings, Her Highness.
Bless you!
Dear Yudhishthir
if all of you were alive
then why did you not return?
Aunt
when something seems righteous
I try my best
to fulfill it with
complete devotion.
Then why did you
change your mind now, dear?
Uncle
during the monsoons
the same plant first
gives birth to new leaves
then to flowers,
to fruits
and in the end, to seeds.
A plant judiciously follows
the schedule of seasons
and a righteous person
follows the path of truth.
Greetings, grandsire.
May you live long!
I have protected
the throne of Hastinapur
so that righteousness
may preside over it
in your form.
Greetings, His Highness.
Bless you, dear!
During the exile,
Lord Ram
had adopted the lifestyle
and mentality of his subjects.
That is why,
he proved to be a fine King.
That is why, we decided
that if brother Yudhishthir
stays in the woods as a common
man amongst the subjects
then he too will prove to be
a fine King in the future.
Greetings, uncle.
Arjun
I have heard that a competition
which could be won only by you,
was organized in Kampilya.
And because of your blessings
I could augment the honour
of Hastinapur, uncle.
Greetings.
Bless you!
Where is Kuru dynasty's
first daughter-in-law, Arjun?
Not the first, Her Highness.
Second daughter-in-law.
During the exile,
brother Bheem
had married
the sister of Hidimb.
And sister-in-law Hidimba
has also given birth to a son.
In other words,
brother Bheem
married an ogre?
Hastinapur, peculiar
is your morality
where Princes marry ogres.
Till the time Hidimba
resides in the woods
you may deem her your wife.
I shall
not deem her son a part
of the Kuru dynasty.
But I can
certainly deem him
my great grandson.
Congratulations!
Greetings, sister-in-law.
Where is Kuru dynasty's
second daughter-in-law
of the next generation?
Where is Kuru dynasty's
second daughter-in-law
of the next generation?
This is the Princess of Panchal
Panchali.
Greetings, Her Highness.
Bless you!
I cannot see you
but your beauty must match
the competence of my Arjun
and I am certain of that.
Arjun.
Come forward, dear.
A newly married couple
is always welcomed together.
Her Highness
all five of us
need to be welcomed.
The five of us have got married.
Where are the rest
of the daughters-in-law?
Uncle
we five brothers
have married Draupadi.