How dare you snatch
the prince's weapon?
Dushasan, you fool!
It isn't courage,
it is training.
Even if the teacher's son
is younger to us
it's right to consider
him as an elder brother.
Our uncle had said so.
But he is elder to us in age.
Accept my greetings, friend.
You seem cultured.
I was afraid
that I may have to force
the princes of Hastinapur
to change their attitude.
What is the pearl on
your forehead?
It is the center of my sharp
brains and limitless powers.
It's the fruit of the penance
I did in my previous birth.
Due to this
I will never fall sick
or grow old.
Then being friends with a great
Brahman like you
will be a blessing to the
future king of Hastinapur.
My uncle has made all
these arrangements for me.
Hereafter, you will have equal
rights on all these things
as much as I have.
A lamp burning with
perfumed oil?
Such great facilities!
Life at the palace is
actually very comfortable.
This is nothing.
The day you become the Royal
teacher of Hastinapur
there will be abundance
of facilities.
Your friend promises you.
Food can be served
on a golden plate
but one cannot cook in it.
No facilities are allowed
for the students
of this hermitage.
It's human nature
that he wants himself,
his family and his children
to get all the happiness.
That's why we always
stay away from
hard work and problems.
We try to increase our
comforts and facilities.
Think about your life.
Isn't it true
that we always provide
our children
with comforts and facilities?
But have you ever thought?
How would comforts benefit them?
The ones who are provided
with comforts and facilities
how would their lives be!
Hard work makes the body
healthier.
When our brains encounter
tough challenges
it becomes more radiant.
We have experienced it.
But we tend to forget
that when our heart and
soul experience difficulties
even they become stronger.
It means
whenever we try to keep
our children away
from hard work and sorrow
aren't we actually shutting the
door to happiness for them?
Think about it.
Ashwathama.
Ashwathama!
Son.
These lovely clothes and gold
why are you putting them
in the fire?
I am following my
father's orders.
Did your father
ask you to burn all the gifts
received from Hastinapur?
But your father had decided
to renounce poverty
for your sake, son.
But not from his heart, mother.
Poverty is still very
dear to him.
I think he wants
me to be miserable and
lead my life begging for alms.
Why is that, mother?
What is the pride in assuming
liquid flour to be milk?
Why does father hate prosperity?
Today, I was being friends with
the prince of Hastinapur.
The prince would be the future
king of Hastinapur.
Beings friends with him
could have filled my life with
all the comforts and facilities.
But father
shut the door of that
friendship for me.
Son, there are four
types of friendship.
The best form of friendship is
where everyone together
with knowledge, devotion
and principles
work hard for the welfare
of one's soul.
The second best form of
friendship is when
all the friends together
think about their families,
dynasty
the society and the
welfare of the nation.
The third is the
friendship of business
where efforts are put
to earn wealth
together.
The last is the friendship
of vices
where attempts are made
only to enjoy.
What kind of a friendship do
you share with the Kuru prince?
What benefits would you derive
from such a friendship?
What have I derived
in life until now
that I can chose?
- Ashwathama!
Don't you talk like that
to your father.
Let him speak, Kripi.
I understand his feelings.
But son, you must remember
he is being friends with you now
because you are
his Guru's son.
I trusted such a friendship and
had a bitter experience in life.
You had a bitter experience
because you had huge
expectations, lord.
Ashwathama is only...
- Only?
Are you using the word only?
What does he want?!
The best clothing?
Gold ornaments?
Or does he want to be
served a grand feast every day?
Would he be satisfied with that?
You seem to forget
he is the grandson of
the great sage Bharadwaj
and the son of the disciple
of the great Parshuram.
He has to become great.
He has a right to the throne.
The throne of Panchal.
I will crown you
king of Panchal.
This is your father's
promise, son.
It's a promise.
Until I do not crown you
king of Panchal
I won't be able to forget
the humiliation I'd endured.
How would that happen?
Among all the Kuru princes
who is capable of doing this?
Wake up.
Wake up!
- Go away, servant.
Not now.
We will wake up
after four hours.
The rats didn't let us sleep
throughout the night.
Go away.
Wake up!
- Sire!
Wake up, elder brother.
The teacher is here.
Let me sleep. I haven't
completed my sleep yet.
Wake up!
- Sire!
The one who can sleep like a dog
and wake up immediately
is called a student.
Everyone should assemble
in the garden. Quickly!
Students.
A new life begins for
all of you today.
Nothing is more important in
life than getting an education.
The first day of acquiring
knowledge is more important
than any other day in your life.
Today, it will be decided
what will all of your learn
in the coming years
and how much knowledge
you will gain.
There on the branch of the tree
a wooden bird has been placed.
It's eye has to be pierced
with your arrow.
Yudhistir, you are
the eldest of them all
so step forward.
Aim at your target.
What do you see?
I can see a tree, Sire.
The branch on the tree
and I can see the bird
sitting on the branch.
There are other branches
which has a birds nest on it.
I have to be careful when
I shoot the arrow
that the nest should not fall.
If the branch falls along
with the bird
there is an ant hill down there.
It may break.
I have to be careful
about it too.
That's amazing, dear.
You can see so many
things at a time.
This is the first quality
needed in a good ruler
which is naturally
inculcated in you.
But you cannot become an archer.
Place the bow down
and go back to your place.
Bheem!
Step forward.
Aim at the target.
What do you see?
The elder brother has created
a problem for me, Sire.
Whatever brother had seen,
I see the same things.
And
many fruits.
You could see so many things
but you couldn't see whether
the string on your bow is tied.
Should I tie it?
- Of course.
Go around the entire hermitage
a hundred times.
And then tie the string.
Hurry up!
Duryodhan, step forward.
Aim at your target.
What do you see?
I can only see the bird
and the branch of the
tree, Sire.
What should I drop?
The bird or the branch?
The eye of the bird
placed on the branch
has to be pierced in a way
that the bird doesn't
fall from the tree.
How is that possible, Sire?
An attack will surely
have an aftermath.
Until there is no control
on the aftermath
until there is no control on
the level of the aftermath
a warrior doesn't attack.
Place the bow down.
Go back to your place.
That's surprising.
There is no one among
the Kuru princes
who can pierce the bird's eye.
Father had taught
that to me first.
Arjun.
Aim at the target.
What do you see?
I can only see
the bird's eye, Sire.
Shoot the arrow.