Their powers had been snatched
through treachery in this court.
Return their powers to them.
That will be sufficient.
Yes! Of course!
I return the property
and the kingdom of the Pandavas
right at this moment.
Impossible!
You have no right to give
away my property, father.
Duryodhan...
Keep quiet,
foolish Prince!
Have mercy on Hastinapur.
Stay quiet.
Stay quiet!
I would have surely done so.
Let us assume
that the entire game
was based on dishonesty
and deceit.
You must also admit
that you have quietly
allowed this dishonesty
and deceit to take place.
Even you admit that all of you
are to blame as much as I am.
Admit it!
If this game...
The rules of this game
were drafted
by grandsire Bhishma
and both the parties
had adhered to the rules.
If the game
was unlawful
then, all of you
are the culprits.
If not, then even
I am blameless.
Is there anyone
present at this court
who can say
that this game
was based on dishonesty
and deceit?
Is there any such person?
Silence still reigns
in the court.
Is no one still doubtful
about their conscience?
Do all of you not know
that the silence
of a pious person
is considered a greater crime
that the words
of an evil person?
Remember this,
knowledgeable ones...
Duryodhan will definitely
be punished for his sins.
But before that
all the people
present at this court
will be punished
for staying silent.
This is a curse
by Draupadi, the one born
from a sacrificial fire.
Mankind has always
subjected women
to exploitation, injustice
and humiliation.
Look around yourself.
Look at all of history.
That's all you will see.
Men's jealousy, lust,
pride, enmity...
Women suffer
the consequences
of all these negative emotions.
Men indulge in battle
but the women of the defeated
kingdoms are tormented.
Men lose their property
while drinking and gambling.
And women?
Women are destined to starve.
Men, overcome
by their pride
restrict women's freedom,
ruin their happiness.
Men get defeated
at the hands of life
and give up their families.
And women?
Women keep struggling
to feed
their small children.
Count all the sufferings
in this universe.
It will be very apparent
that compared to men,
women suffer much more.
What kind of a society
have we created?
Wherein, one half of mankind
relentlessly
exploits the other half.
And those exploited women
give birth to the next
generation of mankind.
Look at the nature.
Those seeds which give birth
to new plants
are surrounded by petals.
They are surrounded
by colour and perfume.
The place where the future
is conceived
should be surrounded
only by beauty, happiness
contentment and respect.
Is that not so?
But by making women suffer
the society makes
the future generations suffer.
Torture, exploitation, pain...
After experiencing such torment
how can women give birth
to happy and healthy progeny?
Hence
whenever any woman
is humiliated
exploited
whenever a woman's hair
is pulled
in some form or the other
the seed of a battle is sown.
In some form or the other,
an epic
begins.
Judge for yourselves.
Do so again and again.
Your Highness
your decision to return
the Pandavas' property
their kingdom
their weapons
and their freedom
to them, is right.
But even Duryodhan's objection
is justified, Your Highness.
Thus,
I propose a compromise.
If your courtiers permit me
I will tell you about it.
Well?
Tell me quickly.
What is it?
Your Highness
for 13 years, Duryodhan
can claim ownership
of all that he has won.
As a result of their defeat
the Pandavas will spend 13 years
in exile, in the forest.
And when they return from exile
their property
and their kingdom
will be returned to them,
with due respect.
Uncle!
I am right, my child.
I am right!
If you are still not satisfied
then let us
sentence the Pandavas
to 12 years of exile
and 1 year of hiding.
If the Pandavas
are recognised in the last year
then once again
they will have to go through
12 years of exile
and 1 year of hiding.
Now
do not be too greedy,
my child.
I accept this solution.
If the Pandavas
are recognised
in the last year
then once again
they will have to go through
12 years of exile
and 1 year of hiding.
Now
do not be too greedy,
my child.
I accept this solution.
Wonderful!
What's the opinion
of the Pandavas? - Uncle!
These Pandavas
are still my slaves.
My decision will be
the ultimate one.
Don't you make that mistake,
Duryodhan.
The curse of a tormented soul
never goes in vain.
You might be afraid of that,
grandsire...
You are going to be punished
for your principles.
I am not.
Father!
I will not free my slaves
or return their property.
But if you command me
I am ready to accept
the compromise
proposed by uncle.
Along with Draupadi
these five Pandavas
will have to stay in exile
in the forest, for 12 years.
In these 12 years
they can't become the allies
of any king
enjoy their hospitality
or build an army.
Which means
that in these 12 years,
these Pandavas
won't be free.
At the end of the exile,
all of them
will have to stay
in complete hiding for a year.
If, in that one year
I see any of the five Pandavas
or their wife
then once again,
they will have
to live in exile
for another 12 years.
So, tell me, father.
What is your decision?
Forgive me, sons of Pandu.
But as per the tradition,
you were the ones
who lost yourselves
to Duryodhan.
Thus...
Thus
I have to accept
Duryodhan's proposal.
I command you.
You five brothers,
along with your wife Draupadi
will have to go through
12 years of exile in the forest
and one year of hiding.
You have to accept it.
As you wish, uncle.
Please permit us
to visit Indraprastha
to meet our subjects
and make certain arrangements.
Permission granted.
We are grateful
to all of you, uncle.
We're taking your leave
for the last time.
After 13 years,
when the Pandavas return
we'll snatch
what's rightfully ours.
This court has introduced us
to the power of dishonesty.
We will make
this very court realise
the power of honesty.
Before I leave,
hear my oath, everyone.
I will tear open Dushashan's
chest and drink his blood!
The death of all the sons
of King Dhritarashtra
will be by my hands.
This the beginning of the end,
King Dhritarashtra.
In this court
everyone who witnessed
the deceit we were subjected to
along with Panchali's
humiliation
yet remained silent
will have to die.
Rivers will turn red with blood
there will be mountains
of severed heads
there will be a catastrophe!
There will be a great battle.
The greatest battle
in the history of mankind!