What is your name?
Vrushali!
Even we'll accompany you!
- Even we'll come with you...
Take us along...
- Brother.
Even we'll accompany you,
Your Highness!
Let's take them along.
- Even we'll come...
A city is not just made
of bricks and mortar!
We also need people.
Even my friends
are coming along.
All hail, King Yudhisthir!
I am not at peace, uncle!
Why should I spare them
even a gravel of my land, uncle?
They are taking all
the subjects along with them.
Why worry, my child?
People from the neighbouring
provinces
will settle in Hastinapur.
I'll get people from Gandhar
and settle them here.
People will come
and settle in cities.
Keep your mind calm.
Concentrate on
the future plans, my child.
Think about your benefit!
Khandavprastha is barren!
Any human who ventures
into this land
is killed by
the serpent Takshak!
If Pandavas get killed by it,
then we benefit.
If the Pandavas kill Takshak
and
establish a city there
we'll benefit by that too!
How will that benefit us, uncle?
The cuckoo bird lays its eggs
in the crow's nest.
And when they hatch, the cuckoo
bird takes away the hatchlings.
The crow takes the pain
but the cuckoo stands to gain!
So consider that
Pandavas are toiling
in Khandavprastha for you!
If a city is established there
we'll snatch it
from the Pandavas!
Now even the ageing guardian
has been defeated, my child!
Mother!
I see myself surrounded
by just one question.
What sin have the ancestors
of the Kuru clan committed
which has caused their kingdom
to be bisected mercilessly?
What's the reason for it?
I am sure my question
is flawed, mother.
Else, why aren't you appearing
to eliminate my dilemma?
Tell me, mother.
Tell me!
Whose righteousness
is being slurred today?
Who has been defeated?
Who?
His Excellency Bhishma
will be defeated!
'Who are you?
Who invited you'
'to come here
and manifest your might?'
'I have already accepted
King Shalva as my husband!'
'You have won me by displaying
your might, in the courtroom.'
'Now, I will be wedded
only to Bhishma.'
'But this is impossible.'
'I have vowed to live
a life of celibacy.'
'And I have come here to
get that vow revoked, Bhishma!'
'You will have to bear
a much graver pain'
'than the pain I had to bear
because of you.'
'Whenever you are associated
with a noble task'
'and you wish for
Bhishma's death.'
'You will definitely be
the cause of Bhishma's death.'
'If so, I don't want to live!'
'But I will take a rebirth.'
'And when the vagaries of age'
'would have worn you
and your soul, out'
'then I will come.'
'As your death!'
Or shall I say that
His Excellency Bhishma
is defeated?
The kingdom, for whose greatness
you committed so many sins
today you had to bisect
that very kingdom!
You're repenting for the sins
you committed in your life,
Bhishma!
Had it been so, then I would've
definitely repented, today.
But all my acts in the past
have always stood on the
pedestal of righteousness, Amba.
I gave up my life, in my last
birth, because of you, Bhishma.
During my last moments
I had told you
'The throne of Hastinapur, for
which you ruined my life'
'will make you struggle,
day in and day out!'
'That throne will never
let you be at peace!'
'You will struggle hard!
The throne will make you do so!'
And even today,
you are struggling!
If you haven't sinned, then
why are you being punished?
This is the punishment
for loving my family.
No, Bhishma!
It's the punishment for
disregarding others
for your selfish love.
Your love for your family made
you disregard the whole world!
You forgot, Bhishma.
That a hive becomes
a curse for a queen bee!
It cannot free itself
from the hive!
It dies painfully in a hive
filled with nectar!
You will meet the same fate,
Bhishma!
Your punishment has
just commenced, Bhishma.
Your family will punish you!
Your sins shall strike you
like lethal arrows
and tear you apart, Bhishma!
You will lie on a bed of arrows
and squirm!
And upon seeing the slaughter
around you
you'll yearn for death,
Bhishma!
You'll yearn!
And I will be present there.
Like a predator crushes
its prey in its jaws
and kilIs it, brutally
likewise,
I shall witness death crushing
you mercilessly, Bhishma!
This is Khandavprastha.
Our new kingdom.
How can people
settle down here?
I've heard that
the land of this place
was burnt down
by snake's poison.
No, friend. It is a result of
Lord Indra's fury.
Lord Indra has granted
the snake Takshak a boon
according to which, he won't
cause rainfall on this land.
The rains would be limited
till the woods over there.
I hope we haven't made
a mistake by coming here.
There's no way that we can
return to Hastinapur now.
You all have come here believing
the ability of Pandavas, right?
Why are you upset then?
If Lord Indra is on
Takshak's side
then we have on our side
the godson of Lord Indra
Arjun.
What do you mean?
Everyone knows that each
son of King Pandu
is part of some God.
Kind Pandu was granted
these sons as boon by Gods.
So that the land of the Kurus
can be saved.
Son of Kind Pandu, Arjun
is Lord Indra's blessing.
Hence, do not worry.
This land would certainly turn
out to be fruitful for Pandavas.
Is this the state?
There are more trees even
underneath the sea water.
Those who love land,
are loved back by it.
I firmly believe
that this land will bring about
our glory and prosperity.
Just that we need to
work a little hard for it.
Only the servants
are going to work hard.
What did you just say?
Your Highness,
please forgive me.
I didn't say anything.
Charioteer, please stop.
Why are you afraid,
Vrushali?
Come closer.
I'm not going to punish you.
What's the matter?
Why do you look
so worried and sad?
Your Highness, I...
I wasn't supposed to come here
but since father insisted...
Why weren't you supposed to
come here?
Don't be afraid, Vrushali.
No matter what your concerns
consider me as a friend
and tell me everything.
Actually...
Your Highness...
I like Hastinapur a lot,
Your Highness.
My friends, my home
and the amenities I desire...
Everything is over there.
Forsaking all that,
in this desolate place
why indeed have I come
to struggle for a life?
How would it benefit me?
You are here to contribute
to the making of a great empire.
It will be Duryodhan's reign
in Hastinapur
and here, it will be the Pandav
Yudhisthir's.
That empire will be yours.
Fame is found
only by the rulers.
The common folk
have mere struggles
in their fate, Your Highness.
That won't be the story here.
I assure you of that.
My husband will always be
righteous.
The empire won't be our property
rather it will be ruled as if
it were our heirloom.
All the rulers speak
of righteousness
but their righteousness
is only towards their families.
Speak of common folk
or ordinary people
and their sense of righteousness
becomes very stiff.
Be it the son of Dhritarashtra
or of Pandu
both are well alike,
Your Highness.
Your Highness,
if my words
amount to a death penalty
I would happily oblige.
Why would I sentence you
to death, friend?
Not only will we be fair
towards our subjects
but we'll also honour the right
of the serpents living here.
Just like different flavours
in food have their own place
all our subjects will have
their own rights and place.
Speaking of you...
You've taught me the definition
of an ideal empire.
You will never face any harm
or pain.
Takshak
the Pandavas
and their subjects are here.