It's the opinion of the penal
council, Your Highness
the losses that these people
have incurred
deems justice mandatory.
Council-Head, please ask them of
the impairments.
Their trust has been impaired,
Your Highness!
They trusted the royal family
and the king to protect them.
Their trust was priceless,
Your Highness.
In order to reinstate the trust
let such wealth be bestowed
upon them, grandsire.
That wouldn't suffice alone,
Your Highness.
In my opinion, the princes
should apologise to them.
This deed will strengthen
their trust in justice
and it will serve as a moral
lesson for the princes too.
Your Highness!
Excuse me, Your Highness!
Excuse me...
Your Highness!
There is no need to worry
anymore, Your Highness!
I was aware that on hearing
about Duryodhan
you'd be quite worried,
Your Highness.
Hence, I hurried over here
so soon, Your Highness.
There is nothing to worry about.
I have already spoken to
the physician, Your Highness.
The wound will heal soon,
Your Highness.
In no time.
What are you rambling about,
Shakuni?
What wound?
Whose wound?
Your beloved Duryodhan's life
is out of danger, Your Highness.
What!
Duryo...
Is Duryodhan wounded?
How?
Answer me, Shakuni.
Who dared spill my son's blood!
The revolt that these fishermen
created, Your Highness
counted in every one of them.
Every one of them was attacking
with a weapon, Your Highness.
Who's weapon it was
that injured Duryodhan
will be impossible to find out,
Your Highness.
Son!
Duryodhan!
Your Highness...
For attacking the prince...
I mean, the attackers of
Prince Duryodhan
should have justice, right?
Justice?
The ones who spilled my son's
blood will have but one fate!
Off with all their heads!
But, Your Highness...
- But, Dhritarashtra.
This would be atrocious.
Justice has been dispensed.
Let the orders be followed.
Forgive us, Your Highness.
Please do not take our lives.
Spare us from a death sentence,
Your Highness!
Forgive us, Your Highness!
Spare us from a death sentence,
Your Highness!
Spare us from a death
sentence, Your Highness!
Spare us from a death sentence,
Your Highness!
Dhritarashtra,
what sort of justice is this?
I have inspected
Duryodhan myself.
He is not grievously wounded
at all.
My son's blood has been spilled,
Queen Mother.
Instead of thinking about
the gravity of their crimes
why are you concerned about
the severity of his wounds?
They have tried to revolt.
They have intended for
the death of the Prince.
Do these crimes seem so
trivial to you, Queen Mother?
Even if the accusations
against them are true
they aren't as grave to effect
a death penalty to so many!
I've been reigning for
many years now, Queen Mother.
I've at least become as wise
to not require your advice.
Wait, Dhritarashtra.
Such stoicism
doesn't befit a ruler.
Your father Shantanu
was always a loving
and kind-hearted ruler.
Not one inspiring fear.
Bhishma.
Bhishma, please
say something to Dhritarashtra.
Right after
the coronation
the king's word holds
as good as the law of the God.
I had told you of the same
earlier itself, Queen Mother.
But I can
appeal to His Highness.
I appeal to you too,
Your Highness.
I appeal to you too.
I may not be a citizen
of the kingdom
yet I appeal, Your Highness.
Please heed her advice.
Your Highness,
you must surely recall
that these fishermen are
Mother Queen's kin.
Punishing them makes her heart
writhe in agony, Your Highness.
Mother Queen hasn't forgotten
her childhood yet.
Prince Shakuni, that's an act of
impudence to the Queen Mother.
How can
reminding one of his/her clan
be a crime, Chief Minister?
Your Highness, so what
have you finally decided?
Keeping in mind
the feelings of Mother Queen
I change my decision,
Chief Minister.
The fishermen are hereby
banished from this province.
Nowhere in the entire
Kuru province
do they have permissions
to reside anymore.
Let the orders be followed.
The Queen Mother
or His Highness
aren't questionable
by us.
But you are my sister,
hence I am asking you this.
When the time came to leave
this land of our ancestors
and if you weren't Queen Mother,
rather a member of our family
would your tears have
been sanguine or not?
Just tell me that.
This land and this water
have but our sweat
seeping and flowing in them.
And after death, they have
but assimilated our very bodies.
Then why
are we being banished from here
in vain, Satya?
Queen Mother?
I...
I'm helpless.
- I know.
Everyone is helpless.
The whole province is helpless.
Today if King Pandu
were on that throne
he wouldn't have
sided with his sons'.
Justice would have been
upheld by him.
And probably
King Pandu's sons wouldn't have
been like these princes, Satya.
A fruit has the taste
which the tree imparts to it.
God knows,
where King Pandu is!
Where are his sons!
Arjun!
Sahadev!
I have found brother Bheem.
Where is brother Bheem?
Only Nakul can answer
this question.
Nakul
Sahadev! Brother Bheem
is behind that rock.
Brother.
Sit.
One for Nakul.
And one for Sahadev.
What are you doing?
Say your prayers first.
So, are you done eating?
Now go and play.
Didn't you just eat?
Didn't I offer you both a 'laddoo'* each?
*A ball-shaped sweet.
Didn't I?
You had, brother Bheem.
But as we closed out eyes
to say our prayers
you devoured our 'laddoo'.
Do you mean to say,
I stole it?
Are you accusing your own
elder brother of stealing?
While you eat it so quick
as if it were the first time!
Aren't you ashamed?
We have just seen them.
We never get to eat them.
It is apt, isn't it?
It isn't appropriate
for kids to eat 'laddoos'.
Eating 'laddoos' can cause
you to fatten up!
Go have the 'sattu'* that mother has prepared for father.
*A foodstuff consisting of a mixture of ground pulses and cereals.
Arjun!
That's my 'laddoo'.
Arjun,
I will beat you up.
Hey, my 'laddoos'.
Brother Yudishtir.
Enough of it.
You three will not eat
even a single 'laddoo'.
Let Bheem eat
all those 'laddoos'.
Elder brother, they snatched off
four of my 'laddoos'.
How can I manage with
just these many 'laddoos'?
Aren't you aware?
'Glutton' is my other name.
Have them in peace, Bheem.
Then have some fruits as well.
Here, brother.
We three will eat
half a 'laddoo' each.
If the three of you eat
half a 'laddoo' each
there will still be
half a 'laddoo' left.
Go.
Get that half as well.
Wait, wait.
All three of you
may eat with me.
Sit.
Arjun, Sahadev,
come on.
Brother. Was that love
or an assassination attempt?
I do not understand.
Son Dhritarashtra.
I can tell by your
quivering words
that you are at unrest,
Queen Mother.
But justice isn't necessary to
be as per everyone's comfort.
What you did wasn't justice,
Dhritarashtra.
To be blinded so much
by your love for your son
isn't appropriate.
Are you here to remind me
of my blindness?
No.
I'm here to remind you
that you are a king.
Your foremost responsibility
is towards your subjects.
Whatever happened, wasn't
the subjects' fault at all.
The fault was your son's.
And it wasn't right to punish
the fishermen for his fault.
Return them to their
rightful place. - Queen Mother
I have heard that
the fishes in a pond
love that pond so much
that when the pond dries up,
they die
rather than leave the pond.
But maybe that's
their helplessness.
But what helplessness causes
your life among the fishermen
to be as fresh
in your memories till date?
Haven't you left that past
behind, Queen Mother?
Today I will give you
an advice, Queen Mother.
Please do ponder over it
being in the role you are in.
Not as a fisherman's daughter.