Grandsire will not fight us
in the battlefield.
He knows what his duties are.
But his duty is to serve
the throne of Hastinapur.
Are his principles
more important to him
than serving the throne?
One does not forsake one's
principles for the throne, dear.
Give the sons of Pandu
what is rightfully theirs.
In order to wring clothes
one can apply force
only up to a limit.
One does not apply
excessive force, dear.
You have hurt
the Pandavas enough.
Now, returning their property
with due respect
is the righteous thing to do.
Do not let the patience
of the sons of Pandu cave in
dear Duryodhan.
Arjun has challenged us
to a battle.
Return them their property
and also the throne
of Yudhishthir.
I shall make them agree
to accept the property.
Give them
what is rightfully theirs.
They will never refuse
to what I say.
Are you asking for mercy for
the Pandavas, Your Excellency?
If you are making a request
then we shall return
the Pandavas their property.
However
mercy cannot aid one
get the throne, can it
Minister?
If you are asking
for their rights
then do pardon us,
Your Excellency.
We cannot give them
their rights.
The sons of Pandu are capable
of taking their rights,
King of Gandhar.
The land they attack
with wrath and vengeance
will have to face
utter destruction.
Dear Dhritarashtra
take the correct decision.
End this struggle.
A struggle always has
two sides, uncle.
You must convince the Pandavas
to prove that it was
sundown the other day.
Their rights shall be returned
to them with due respect then.
However,
if they attack us
then we cannot
stay quiet either.
Go and tell the Pandavas
that the right
to attack a kingdom
resides only with another King
and not with forest dwellers.
All hail Emperor Yudhishthir!
All hail Empress Draupadi!
All hail Ballav Maharaj!
Because you gave us refuge
your kingdom was attacked,
Your Highness.
Emperor Yudhishthir
when a piece of gold is shaped,
it transforms into an ornament.
By spending your life
of anonymity in my kingdom
you have sanctified
my entire household.
The army of the Matsya kingdom
is prepared.
The moment you give the order
we shall attack Hastinapur.
You have indebted us
with your love, Your Highness.
A twig within a whirlwind with
the intent of touching the sky
has no competence of its own.
No
the armies will not fight,
Your Highness.
We five brothers took an oath
solely based upon our competence
and we shall use it
to fulfill our vows.
Very soon,
only five chariots
will be standing
at the gates of Hastinapur.
To punish the hundred
sons of King Dhritarashtra!
Not hundred,
Panchali.
Hundred and one,
Have a message
sent to Hastinapur.
The basis of unrighteousness
of Crown Prince Duryodhan
is the competence
of King Karna of Anga.
The sons of Pandu will sacrifice
hundred and one people.
The way
hundred and one fruits
of the Golden Apple Tree
are offered to Lord Shiva
for worship
similarly
tomorrow at dawn
hundred and one severed heads
will be presented to
the Deity of the Battlefield
Kala Bhairav* as an offering.
*The fierce manifestation of Shiva associated with annihilation.
'Tomorrow at dawn,
hundred and one severed heads'
'will be presented to
the Deity of the Battlefield'
'Kala Bhairav as an offering.'
How dare the sons of Pandu
challenge me to a battle?!
I shall render
the people sleepless
who dream of beheading me.
Forever!
Forever.
By accepting the heads
of the Pandavas, Kala Bhairav
will have to be contented,
friend.
Anyone who attacks you
shall be slain by me.
Have faith in my competence.
Why are you getting so excited,
King Karna of Anga?
The right to fight
on behalf of Hastinapur
has not been given to you yet
because
the other term for 'rights'
is 'responsibilities.'
With the grace of the Almighty
this right
resides with the most competent
person of this world
and the most powerful General
His Excellency Bhishma.
Impossible!
The challenge is for the hundred
sons of Dhritarashtra
and not Hastinapur!
Challenge?
Challenge...
This is not a challenge,
Your Excellency Bhishma.
This is a protest.
A protest of slaves!
Do something,
Your Excellency.
Do something.
Whether the life of anonymity
of the Pandavas
was successful or not
has not yet been proved by them
in any manner.
That day,
the sunlight
had not faded,
grandsire.
Even when the sun goes down
and the sunlight is visible
it is still called
dusk,
grandsire
and not night.
When one cannot see the sun
while standing
in a particular place
it is deemed
the end of the day
for that particular place.
Now,
this question
is of righteousness,
Your Excellency Bhishma.
Who is the one
who gets to decide
whether it was night
or day,
Your Excellency?
You?
Yudhishthir?
Me?
Who?
In other words
their challenge and attack
are both acts
of unrighteousness.
Now, you must decide,
Your Excellency Bhishma
whether you
wish to take the side
of righteous people
or that
of that family.
You must leave
bearing righteousness within you
and weapons in your arms
My Lords.
Righteousness is on your side.
Become the weapons
of the Almighty
to slay the sinners!
Uncle, tomorrow at dawn,
the sons of Pandu
will enter Hastinapur.
When Hastinapur will echo
with the sound of a battle cry
we will have to hoist either
of the flags, uncle.
The white flag of peace
or the red flag of war.
Hastinapur has emerged
victorious
for the past
seven generations, uncle.
If the sons of Pandu win
then the honour of Hastinapur
will get annihilated.
However,
if the sons of Pandu lose
then the entire Aryan region
will be robbed of righteousness.
I have taken an oath to protect
the throne of Hastinapur
Vidur.
If the sons of Pandu
lose then my dream will break.
Either way,
I end up being defeated.
Only the sons of Pandu
can safeguard my principles.
However, my principles
cannot safeguard
the sons of Pandu.
Till this old man
continues to stand
in front of the Pandavas
the Pandavas are bound
to be defeated.
Are you here
to fight a battle, son?
In reply
even I have waived
off the red flag.
I am the actual stronghold
of Hastinapur.
If you're competent enough
then try breaking
this bastion.
Lift your weapons,
Pandavas.
In reply of your summon
Hastinapur's defender
is present here before you.
No, grandsire.
I cannot shoot an arrow at you.
- Then accept defeat, Arjun
and return.
I am confined
to the throne of Hastinapur.
If Hastinapur is ever attacked
I will definitely be present
to defend it.
You too raise your weapons.
If Hastinapur is ever attacked
I will definitely be present
do defend it.
You too raise your weapons.
The summon was
for the Kauravas
and not the entire
Hastinapur, grandsire.
There are not courageous enough
to even accept this!
Then based on what powers
did they commit a crime.
Based on my powers,
Bhima.
My powers.
It's very unfortunate
for me
that my righteousness
serves as a shield
to many unrighteous deeds.
We're not here to fight
a battle with you, grandsire.
Hence we sent the summon
only to King
Dhritarashtra's sons
and the king of Anga,
Karna.
Your summon
for a battle
has not been accepted
by Dhritarashtra's sons.
If they do not come
to fight a battle with you
then what will you do?
We will be forced
to break the fort
and that will be considered
an attack on Hastinapur.
Guru Drona and you will
raise your weapons against us
and we will have
to fight you.
This means, grandsire,
that the circumstances are
that either we forget about
our humiliation
forget about our wealth
and reside in the forests.
Or we attack you.
Why this dilemma?
Why this dilemma, grandsire?
You very well know,
grandsire
that we're on the side
of righteousness.
The cruel behaviour that
Kauravas showed towards us
towards your daughter-in-law...
Is it not important
to punish them?
Why are you protecting them?
I have no remedy, son.
The outer cover
of the coconut
cannot sacrifice his stiffness.
Even if the water within
the coconut dries
not even then.
I will have to carry out
my duties.