A father always prays for
the well being of his child.
He worries about
the future of his progeny.
Due to this
he always tries to decide
their future endeavours himself.
The path which the father
has tread himself...
The path whose pitfalls he
is familiar with...
He knows where lies shade and
sunshine of the path
That should be the path
his son should take too.
This is the desire
of every father.
Indeed, it is
a noble intention.
But
we always forget to reflect
upon three questions.
Which questions?
The first question.
Doesn't every path
change with time?
Doesn't time always bring forth
newer challenges?
So, how can experiences from
a time gone by
benefit the new generation?
The second question.
Is every child
an image of his parents?
Yes.
Morals are always taught to
the children by the parents.
But, inner capability.
Inner capability is something
that's God gifted.
So do you believe the path where
the father has found success
is the path where the son shall
find success and bliss too?
Third question.
Aren't the challenges and
strife of life beneficial?
Doesn't every new question
open a portal to a new answer?
So does the act of
depriving children from
new questions, strife
and challenges
qualify as benefiting them
or harming them?
Therefore, just as
it would be best
to develop a child's character
rather than develop his future
similarly, instead of deciding
the path in a child's life
wouldn't empowering them
to face new conflicts
with confidence and knowledge
be more beneficial?
Think about it.
'As long as this thread
is tied across your wrist'
'you must not reveal your past
to your husband.'
No.
What devotion is it,
that nurses a secret within?
And what matrimony is it,
that has no devotion?
I must tell my lord the truth.
Kunti.
For a woman, this broach
symbolises her husband
By wearing this in her mane,
she assigns her husband
the highest position
in her life.
But I do not approve
of that tradition.
I shall adorn your hair
with this broach myself
as a symbol of our love
and trust.
Handling a woman's mane
seems harder
than handling a nation.
When it's about
handling a nation
one takes the help of ministers
and the court, your majesty.
But when it's about
arranging my hair
you shall have to
do it yourself.
May I say something, Kunti?
I wished to say something at
your 'Swayamvar'.
But I never got
the opportunity.
I was spellbound by
the question
you put forth at the
'Swayamvar'.
That very moment
I prayed inwardly
that my answer be the right one.
Your question was very witty.
Even I began praying the moment
I glanced upon you, my lord
that by god's grace, you answer
my question from your heart.
Were you testing my heart
or my intelligence?
Your heart, my lord.
A human tests
what he wishes to acquire.
You are amazing, Kunti.
You tested my heart
with just one question
and acquired it too.
For a king to surrender himself
to one's will so easily
isn't appropriate, my lord.
It is imperative that one
examines the virtues of
the person wanting to acquire
such a special heart.
Do you not trust my choice?
Or are you just flaunting
your caliber again?
No, my lord.
I...
I just want to
tell you something.
You have to pass the verdict.
A man who tests his wife,
is tested himself in turn.
My married friends tell me so.
That means, I have to
undergo another test.
Tell me.
What is the matter?
My lord...
I wanted to say...
What is this?
Whose message has arrived
at this hour?
What happened, my lord?
The beat of the drums
conveys a message.
I'm sure, the matter is grave.
I must head to the royal court.
You cannot go to the battle,
Pandu.
You have just been married.
Forgive me, Queen Mother.
My personal pleasure cannot
hinder my sense of duty.
If the need for battle
has arisen
It is my duty to answer it.
I shall command the charges
during the battle, your majesty.
You shall have plenty of battle
opportunities, your majesty.
For a king,
no war is a final one.
But the first battle is
always the first one.
The subjects always have doubts
about a new king's potential,
grandfather.
Pandu must display his strength
at the earliest opportunity.
I beg your pardon, grandfather
but that is my opinion.
I may be blind.
But I know how to wage war.
I shall go instead.
Brother is right, grandfather.
It is our duty to help
the kingdom of Madra.
Whoever has attacked Madra
has done so under the assumption
that I'm a new king
and I'm just married.
I would have neither
the courage, nor the inclination
to help Madra.
The enemy wishes to gauge me.
And I shall undergo the test
put forth by him.
Have you even thought
about Kunti?
She shall be heartbroken.
What will you tell her?
What happened, my lord?
Is it distressing news?
A news that is pleasurable
to one
is perceived to be distressing
by the other.
A husband and a wife
aren't separate, my lord.
They are one.
What is pleasurable to you,
shall be pleasurable to me too.
Tell me, what is the news?
Someone has attacked
our ally nation.
I must go to battle.
This very moment.
Mother and grandfather insisted
that someone else will
proceed with our army.
But I said that this was
the king's duty.
Hence, I shall go to the battle
myself.
I should have consulted you
before coming to this decision.
But...
- No, my lord.
You have taken a decision
that truly befits a king.
If the ruler of Hastinapur
took any other decision
I would be disappointed.
I am aware that a queen would
be gratified.
But I wish to know what
a wife's heart feels.
If you are angry upon me
you have every right
to do so, Kunti.
The first night of our wedding
has brought us separation.
An eclipse always obscures
a full moon.
But after the eclipse,
that very moon
appears more bright and radiant.
I shall wait for you, my lord.
When shall you commence?
Now.
This very moment.
I could have spent the first
night with you and left by dawn.
But that would be my
weakness, Kunti.
And once a person surrenders
to his weakness
he is weakened forever.
I am here to be your strength,
my lord.
I shall not be your weakness.
I am a queen as well.
You shall be victorious
and return soon.
I am confident.
Do you wish to say
something, Kunti?
If something ails your heart,
you may tell me.
No, my lord.
All that my heart possesses
are prayers for you.
May you be victorious.
May you return with a token
of victory from Madrapur.
I shall be waiting for you.
Soldiers...
Har Har Mahadev!*
Hail Lord Shiva!
Har Har Mahadev!
Proceed.
'A few months later...'
Waiting is something every queen
is destined for, Kunti.
Turn your wait into
penance.
Not a lament.
Forgive me, sister-in-law.
I do not wish to cause all of
you anguish with my behaviour.
So why have you ceased eating?
What else can I do,
sister-in-law?
Earlier, we would get messages
through the beating of drums.
But now we are not getting any
messages from the battlefield.
No messages being conveyed
mean only one thing, Kunti.
That they have no good news
to convey yet.
But at least there
is an assurance
that there is no bad news too.
But my ears
are craving to hear
the drums, sister-in-law.
We will get a message.
And it shall surely be
good news.
I have complete faith
in Pandu.