Will you come
to aid us again, Govind?
Indeed
but
I will not be able
to aid all of you
where you are headed
at the moment.
All of you must succeed in the
life of anonymity on your own.
The time for your life of
anonymity is drawing closer too.
Which place would be appropriate
for our life of anonymity
Vasudev?
Brother Yudhishthir
is the Emperor.
The entire Aryan region
knows him.
Brother
the most difficult task for man
is to remain hidden
because in order to remain so
one must first expunge
oneself of one's arrogance
and forget one's competence
one's respect
one's class
and one's existence.
If family and friends
fuel your arrogance
then none of you
will forget who you are
and if the enemy
challenges your arrogance
then you are bound to get angry
and show yourselves
to the world.
You must choose a place
where no one recognizes you.
A place where you will get love
but not get attached to anyone.
If someone does insult you
you ought to be able
to pardon that person.
Where can such
a place be, Vasudev?
In this vast Aryan region
there must be a King
who you are not acquainted with.
In this vast Aryan region, there
is only one such King, Vasudev.
The person I am
alluding to is King Virat.
Yes.
Only in the Matsya kingdom* of King Virat will all of you
*Matsya ("fish") is located south of the Kurus, and west of the Yamuna river which separated it from the kingdom of Panchalas.
be able to
safely lead a life of anonymity.
Certainly, Vasudev.
The day Arjun returns after
completing his meditation
we shall proceed
towards the Matsya kingdom.
He shall return soon after
succeeding in his endeavour.
Arjun has such
a strong determination
that he can achieve
even the most arduous
of meditations.
'The animal shown in this scene'
'was generated
using computer graphics.'
You seem to be the indigenous tribe of Kirat.*
*The Kirati or Kiranti people in the Himalayas (mid-hills) extending eastward from Nepal into India, Burma and beyond.
Who are you?
I am meditating here.
Let me take my arrow out.
You can take this warthog then.
I shall indeed take it away.
I was hunting it after all.
So, I shall take it away.
Pardon me
but this animal was killed
by my arrow
and not yours.
You may certainly take it away.
He insulted you,
Your Highness!
He said that he
hunted that animal!
Then he must certainly be
stronger than you.
He is a better archer than you.
Since you are the King,
you must demonstrate
that you are the stronger one
and not him!
I am Arjun,
the son of Pandu.
I am more skilled
than a tribal person.
The son of Pandu!
Such arrogance!
Can you see that hollow
on that tree?
You must pierce it.
I had killed this warthog
with such lightning speed.
You must not have
even seen my arrow.
The focus required
to be a great archer
does not reside in you.
Can you fight using a sword?
A true warrior is one
who can use
all weapons proficiently.
Pick up the sword,
Prince.
Do you accept defeat?
Are you not tired yet?
No
I am not tired
but when Lord Shiva
himself is one's opponent
how can a person win?
Being a disciple of guru Drona
no tribal man
can ever withstand
my attacks for so long.
Lord Pinaka*
*Vishwakarma.
had made the first bow known as Pinak*
*Shiva's bow.
and had taught the entire world
the art of archery.
Punish me for
my mistakes, My Lord
and please do appear
in your true form.
Bless you!
Lord Indra requested me
to give his son the knowledge
of Pashupatastra.
However, without testing
your worthiness
I could not give you
the Pashupatastra.
A person who is worthy
knows divinity in a moment.
The truth is
the one who recognizes
the greatness of others
is truly worthy
but My Lord
I could not recognize you.
I must certainly not be worthy.
Lord Indra
your son has
acknowledged himself
that he is not worthy
of acquiring the Pashupatastra.
A person who
deems himself worthy
is not truly so,
My Lord.
Worthiness can be truly known
only by the person
taking the test.
You have the ability to become
truly worthy, son of Kunti.
I am pleased with you.
I shall teach you how to
use the Pashupatastra.
It is not a weapon
but knowledge.
Falling prey to unrighteousness,
when the enemy becomes weak
he can be killed using
ordinary weapons, son of Kunti.
However,
often times
one has to kill an enemy
who is also righteous.
It is impossible to kill such
enemies with ordinary weapons.
The ones who walk
on the righteous path
are blessed with
my refuge after death.
I have made such
a promise to the world.
That is why,
the Pashupatastra brings
the people who have always
walked on the righteous path
to my refuge after death.
You shall receive
the Pashupatastra now.
Bless you!
Twelve years are
almost over, uncle.
Today
before dusk
we must find those Pandavas
and stop them from
leading a life of anonymity.
When the last ray of the sun
fades into darkness
the life of anonymity
of the Pandavas will begin.
When will we abduct
Draupadi, uncle?
My darling, Arjun
has not returned yet.
But I have a feeling,
uncle
that Arjun will return
before dusk today.
I have firm faith
that he will return
but at the moment
the might of the Pandavas
is not that considerable.
Before Arjun returns
we must abduct Draupadi.
But how is that
possible, uncle?
We cannot attack the Pandavas.
We are bound by
our promise, uncle.
We cannot attack them
but
your sister
Dushala's husband
King of Sindhu, Jayadrath,
most certainly can, my darling.
I
have come here
to aid you, Duryodhan.
We cannot attack them
but
your sister
Dushala's husband
King of Sindhu, Jayadrath,
most certainly can, my darling.
I
have come here
to aid you, Duryodhan.
Now...
Now
I have promised your sister
that I shall
indeed aid you.
Welcome,
King of Sindhu.
Be seated.
I am grateful to you
for coming here to aid me
but these four Pandavas
never leave their wife Draupadi
by herself.
One of them
is always present
to protect Draupadi.
Four of them!
I can defeat 400 Pandavas
in one go
and abduct Draupadi.
King of Sindhu
you are Dushala's husband
and the son-in-law
of Hastinapur's royal family.
That is why, I do not
wish to insult you.
However, a frog cannot
inflate its throat
and become the size of a bull.
King of Sindhu
I think the competence
of the Pandavas
is something
you are not aware of.
Duryodhan
you are my brother-in-law.
That is why,
I have
not given you a demonstration
of my competence yet
otherwise...
And
may the Almighty never
give rise to such a situation
King of Sindhu.
You are correct.
You are not only
free to attack them
but also competent enough
but
I have a solution
using which you will not have to
engage in a battle.
Yudhishthir
performs
the 'Sandhyavandana'* every morning
*Salutation to twilight (dawn and dusk) or solar noon.
by going to a river bank.
Bheem
and Sahadev
go to the village
to distribute alms
to the poor.
That leaves Nakul.
Every day,
for 90 minutes
he is given the duty
of protecting Draupadi
all by himself.
If we can
somehow
keep Nakul
away from the hut
then without having to fight
you can abduct Draupadi.