Great-grandsire, please accept
my greetings.
If I meet you at home, I would've
asked for your blessings.
But we meet on the battlefield,
therefore, I ask you to fight me.
Who are you, lad?
Where did you get your ability
and courage to face me?
Who are you, warrior?
I'm son of Pandu's son, Arjun
with Yadava's daughter, Subhadra.
Abhimanyu.
My dear uncle is Krishna.
And today
I'm here on this battlefield
to challenge death.
Why don't you attack me,
Great-grandsire?
No, child.
I can't attack you.
At this age, when you should be
learning knowledge
instead you have to
face us in battle.
This sight saddens me.
In relation with my family tree.
A new, healthy sprout.
Like a golden crown.
The new generation
shines.
That's what my dream is.
But today,
seeing the battlefield,
I feel that our family will soon perish.
I feel my whole life is a waste, child.
A great-grandfather endows knowledge
to his great-grandchildren.
He doesn't punish them.
You are my great-grandson.
I can only love you.
How can I possibly hurt you?
Go, child. Go away.
I, your great-grandson, do not
admit defeat.
I won't go.
I admit my defeat, child.
Even the fact that I have
to fight you,
instead of that, I choose to give in.
A family in which the youth dies,
would be felt lonely like
a ruin of fire
inhabited by elders with
deep guilts.
If only I were not under my oath,
then in this instance,
I would've given up my weapons
and become a hermit.
Go, child.
Don't challenge me. Go.
I'm like an arrow from Arjuna's Gandiva.
Once shot from the bow, it won't
get back to its storage.
Fight me.
Fight me, Great-grandsire!
Your great-grandfather commands you
to go from here.
Go!
I'm sorry, Great-grandsire,
you are my enemy.
I can't follow your orders.
My child,
the sun will soon sets.
Everyone's engaged.
Now. We have to go to Yudishthira.
We won't have a better chance.
He is alone, brother.
Charioteer, let's go.
I ask you, dear.
Go.
- No.
Dushasana, brother Yudishthira holds a spear.
The rule of war is clear.
A warrior can fight other warrior
only if they wield the same weapon.
Either you raise a spear,
or brother Yudishthira has to use a mace.
My dear.
Always use what suits you.
And use weapon,
that you're good at.
Use this brother Yudishthira.
So that you won't taint our name by saying
that we have broken the rule.
Your character is such that
even soiled and defiled,
it doesn't matter.
Unfortunately, Dushasana do not even
worried about his name.
Prince Arjuna, go and protect Emperor Yudishthira.
A warrior has to fight more than
one opponents,
is this not violating the rule, uncle?
You've told us to not worried about
defiling our names.
But it's not about that.
We are now worried about
our advantage.
We have to apologize for this action.
For our various unrighteous actions,
brother Yudishthira
We will apologize for this unrighteous act.
But only after killing you.
Won't you heed an old man
request, dear?
Go back.
Great-grandsire.
Protecting uncle Yudishthira is my duty.
So why do you
advise me otherwise?
Your courage is praiseworty, dear.
When you rule over all Aryan region,
I will be the proudest watcher from heaven.
King Madra, the sun almost sets.
The great Bhisma has returned.
We have to kill Yudishthira.
Attack him.
I can't attack behind his back,
evil Shakuni!
Like a crow, you are used to
disgusting life
but not me.
- A swan that live among crows
is just as disgusting, King Madra.
Not pure as well.
You have promised.
You have pledged loyalty to Duryodhana.
To help Duryodhana emerges victorious,
is you duty.
Attack him.
Throw your spear, King Madra!
Attack him!