Whatever Arjun has got
must be shared equally
among you five brothers.
What happened, son?
What did you say, mother?
I got the daughter of Drupad,
the King of Panchal, as charity.
I got a wife, mother.
Your daughter-in-law.
And
unknowingly, you
ordered us five brothers
to divide her amongst ourselves.
How can
a woman be divided
into five parts, mother?
How?
Draupadi.
Draupadi!
Stop, dear!
But Arjun, why...
Why did you
use the term 'charity'
for a woman?
It is charity, mother.
Giving away one's daughter...
You have taught us
that all forms of charity
in the world
tie down the fortune
of the one engaging in it.
Only giving away one's daughter
opens up one's fortune.
That is why, Nakul had said
that his brother Arjun's
fortune had opened up.
Mother, you could have
at least turned around once.
The ones who have
the right to give orders
do not have the right
to be ignorant.
'Mother, have a look'
'at what I have got as charity.'
'Whatever Arjun has got'
'must be shared equally
among you five brothers.'
'I got the daughter of Drupad,
King of Panchal, as charity.'
'How can'
'a woman be divided
into five parts, mother?'
Draupadi...
Dear
pardon me.
It was my mistake.
But
my sons never planned
to go to your 'swayamvar.'
Never had I imagined
that Arjun...
That Arjun would win
the competition.
Were you that certain
of your plans, Lady Kunti?
Are your sons that competent
that they can circumvent
both fate and destiny
and realize all your plans?
You are correct, Draupadi.
It is my fault.
You have every right
to be angry with me.
I am your offender.
No, lady-
Pardon me.
Blaming you is incorrect.
If the floodwaters of a river
drown a deer
then the river is not at fault.
But even the deer
is not at fault, lady.
What is my fault
in this situation?
You are not at fault.
You are not at fault, dear.
I can understand
your state of mind.
The mere thought
of being divided among men makes
a woman experience hell itself.
But
that will not happen.
The ones who have
the right to give orders
also have the right
to abrogate them.
I...
I will tell my sons
not to follow my orders.
'This life, this world'
'are games of time and tide.'
'What is bound to happen,
happens'
'and by its rules
we must abide.'
'Time is the strongest
in the world.'
'Joy and sorrow
are parts of life'
'Only that happens
what is destined.'
'Time is the strongest
in the world.'
Arjun.
Marry Draupadi
this instant, son.
And right after that
you must go to Kampilya.
Forget the order
I gave you by deeming it
a bad dream, son.
No, mother.
That is not possible now.
Arjun
listen to mother.
When a volcano erupts
birds do not stay on
the trees of the mountain.
They fly away instantly.
If a place involves
a moral dilemma
one must not
stay there for long.
You should go.
After a while
we shall drop mother off
near the kingdom of Panchal.
Drop me off?
What do you mean?
Mother, you may be present
in Arjun's marriage
but we four brothers cannot.
We will never show ourselves
to Princess Draupadi again.
What are you saying, son?
Why will you not be able
to show yourselves?
When I have abrogated my order
then what problem
do you have with it?
Mother, an order
can be abrogated
but not the words
uttered by one.
Words are like seeds
and when they
sink into the heart
they emerge in some form
or the other in the future.
That is why, mother,
wise men say
that the one who utters words
without thinking first
commits a sin.
But son
it was...
It was a mistake.
Shravan being shot
was also a mistake, mother.
But for that
King Dashrath had to
pay very dearly.
It is not that things
done unintentionally
have no consequences, mother.
Unknowingly, you have bound
Princess Draupadi by
your words mother.
You have bound her by your words
and she is obligated
to fulfill them.
Unknowingly, you have
named the relationship between
Princess Draupadi and us.
And the moral dilemma
is that, mother
it cannot be rendered false.
Then what is the solution to it?
Answer me.
Someone please answer me!
What is the solution to it?
Yudhishthir
tell me.
Answer me.
Someone please answer me!
No maiden can be divided
among five men, mother.
The solution to a moral dilemma
always lies in meditation.
All of us have decided that
we will meditate, mother.
It is Arjun's duty
to marry the Princess.
He shall marry her
and we four brothers
shall resort to asceticism.
Princess.
Prince Arjun
is there a solution
to Lady Kunti's order?
It is easy to look for gravel
amidst wheat, Princess.
But when
wheat falls amidst gravel
it is impossible to look for it.
Similarly
finding solutions
to certain situations
is very difficult.
How did this situation
become so difficult, Prince?
My father conducted
the 'swayamvar'
you won the competition
based solely on your competence,
I deemed you my husband.
I did not even question you
about your identity!
I did not ask you your name!
I did not ask about your clan,
dynasty or future plans!
What did I do, Prince
that made
the situation difficult?
You are not at fault, Princess.
Maybe fate is at fault here.
Fate.
Fate can be designed.
It is not definite, Prince.
My Govind says so himself.
That very fate
has been designed by my mother
by dividing you amongst
us five brothers.
Now, even if mother wants to
she cannot go back on her words.
I have
no answers to your
other questions, Princess.
I have only one request.
Please
marry my eldest brother.