My son.
All of us have waited for you
for a long time.
Your father will
be very pleased.
I'll inform him right now.
Lord!
Kripacharya
what do these omens portend?
There's darkness everywhere.
Blood chilling screams
can be heard.
What... What kind of a bad omen
is this, Kripacharya?
Whenever a human being
with evil tendency takes birth
the entire universe feeIs it.
The entire universe
conveys its reaction
through such bad omens,
Your Highness.
In fact, the entire universe
warns of the troubles
we would face in the future.
Amidst all these bad omens
the first child is taking birth.
This child has taken birth
as a threat to Hastinapur.
Are you trying to say that
my son is a demon and is evil?
This is what's written in
the scriptures, Your Highness.
Kids who are a menace
to society are born
in this world every day.
If the scriptures were right
such an atmosphere would
persist forever
isn't it, Kripacharya?
This is no small crisis,
Shakuni.
It would be catastrophic.
Not just for the Kuru clan.
Not just for Hastinapur
and Kurukshetra
but for the entire
Arya empire.
For the well-being of oneself
and for the welfare of the state
the scriptures ordain that such
a cursed child be sacrificed.
This child is a
threat for sure.
He is a threat, but to whom?
Is this a bad omen
for the entire state
or for an individual?
Is this a disaster for
the one
who didn't allow His Highness
to be crowned?
The child His Highness had
been waiting for
how can you even suggest that
the child be killed?
Whether Her Highness
has 100 sons or 99
it won't harm the state much.
But if this child remains alive
it would be devastating
for the entire state
and the entire clan.
I am not in favour of killing
my sister's son, Kripacharya.
Bheeshma, what's your opinion?
The thought of snatching
the right to live, from a child
pains me, Queen mother.
If it's in the interest
of the state
a sacrifice cannot be termed
inappropriate, Sire.
I believe
this decision should be made by
the one who is a king
and a father.
On the basis of dreams
and intuitions
we imagine the joy and
sorrow of the future.
To eliminate the cause of
our sorrow in the future
we make plans today.
But by eliminating the troubles
of the future, right now
do we gain or lose?
We never ask this question.
The truth is
the problem and its solution
evolve together
for a human being
and for nature as well.
Isn't it?
Think about your past.
Look at history.
You will realise immediately
whenever there's trouble
the solution comes
into existence simultaneously.
This is how the world works.
Thus, a crisis is the reason
for the birth of a power.
Whenever a person
gets out of a crisis
he has taken a step ahead
and shines more.
He's full of confidence,
not just for himself
but for the world too.
Isn't that true?
Actually, the birth of a crisis
is the birth of an opportunity
to change oneself
and to develop one's thoughts
to strengthen one's soul
and enlighten it with wisdom.
The one who is able to do so
doesn't face any crisis
but the one who is unable
to do so
is a menace for the world.
Think about it.
'This child has taken birth
as a threat to Hastinapur.'
'The scriptures ordain that such
a cursed child be sacrificed.'
'This decision should be
made by the one'
'who is a king and a father.'
'This child has taken birth
as a threat to Hastinapur.'
'The scriptures ordain that such
a cursed child be sacrificed.'
'This decision should be
made by the one'
'who is a king and a father.'
Mother!
Can my son see me?
Can he see his father?
Yes, my son.
Seeing you has brought
a smile on his face.
My son...
My heir
will be invincible in
this world, mother.
It would be impossible
to fight and defeat him.
My son will be called
Duryodhan!*
*"Unconquerable one".
I am pleased
by your prayers, Kunti.
On Sage Durvasa's command
I've come to bless you
with a son.
I am very grateful to you,
Lord Indra.
The way
you are the greatest demigod
similarly, I want my son
to be the greatest human being.
Your wish
will be fulfilled, Kunti.
Your son will be renowned
among humankind.
The way I am the basis of
heaven's potential
similarly, your son will be
the basis of Earth's potential.
He will be
physically very strong.
He will be the most determined.
His heart will melt
at human misery.
He will be very soft-hearted
And due to his kind-heart
that is, his generosity
the whole world
will know him as Arjun.*
*"Shining or famous like silver."
Madri...
Why are you shedding tears?
I had gone to the forest
to collect wood, Kunti.
There I saw a family
of monkeys.
The old monkey
was having a jovial time
with his wife and kids.
There were all so happy
and at peace.
All their faces reflected
hopes of the arrival of spring.
When I saw them
I became emotional.
Did you get emotional on
seeing them happy, Madri?
No, Sister.
But there I saw
and old female monkey,
away from the entire family
sitting on a branch
all by herself.
She neither had food
nor the warmth of
the family.
Alone
helpless
and miserable.
She would have once been a
part of this happy family.
But she wouldn't have been
able to bear children.
Hence she has been
forgotten.
She is awaiting her death.
Don't you have faith
on these three sons, Madri?
No, Sister.
A new born child has no
preconceived notions.
How can I distrust them?
But when rain water
falls into the sea
it turns bitter too.
Your three sons will definitely
make my condition
like that of the
old female monkey.
Madri
don't say such things
on this auspicious occasion.
This occasion might be
auspicious for you!
Spring hasn't come as
spring for me
but as winter which will
freeze all my desires.
Today your wish has
come true, Sister.
You have defeated me with
the power of your mantras.
You have also made the king
do injustice to me.
I am not as crafty as you.
But remember one thing, Sister...
As you sow so shall you reap.
The one doing injustice has
to carry its burden with him
for his entire life.
Son, the five main parts
of a temple are
The gate pyramids,
the innermost sanctum
The pillars, the canopy
And the spire.
In the same way, a kingdom
is also divided into five parts
The council of ministers
is the canopy of the state...
The citizens are its pyramids.
The army its pillars.
The seat of justice is the
sanctum sanctorum.
And the throne is it's spire.
The Lord's idol is placed
in the sanctum sanctorum.
And a nation's glory
lies in
its seat of justice.
Will you remember this?
Then you will definitely be
the greatest king.
In order to become
Emperor Dhritrashta's heir
you have to work very hard,
Yudhishthir.
Won't you work hard?
I am content today, my son.
Your 104 younger brothers
will spread your glory
worldwide.
My lord...
It is time for the birth of
Yudhishthir's two
younger brothers.
I had the same thought, Kunti.
This time we have to
get the divine sacrament
of the
Ashwinis
the physicians of the Gods.
When Yudhishtir becomes
the king
it's important that his brothers
have the knowledge of health.
Humans, cows
horses, elephants
and other animals.
The ability and knowledge
to understand them
can be given only by
the Ashwinis.
Invite the Ashwinis, Kunti.
Yes, your highness.
But this time
I won't recite the mantra
Madri will.
My lord
even Madri has the right
to bear your children.
You have received
this boon, Kunti.
It is the reward
for your efforts.
Whether there's a crisis
in the family
or accomplishments
everyone has the right
on the proceeds.
If we want to teach this
truth to our children
then first
I will have to learn
to accept this truth.
I will teach Madri
the mantra
with all my heart.
And the mantra
will definitely bear fruit,
my lord.