Then from this moment
this archer is a king.
I declare him king!
All hail Prince Duryodhan!
No, Prince.
I do not covet a kingdom.
I have not come here to ask
for a kingdom in charity.
Respect shown towards my art
is sufficient for me.
I do not wish for anything else.
The entire Kshatriya lineage
has been defamed by you, friend.
So, you ought to get
a chance to compete.
Far away in the west
there is a forested region
beyond Magadha.
That place
is called Ang Pradesh.
Grandfather Bhishma
had triumphed over
the people of that region.
But today,
it is devoid of a king.
I declare you
the King of Ang Pradesh.
How can this be?
No, Prince.
Do not indebt us
with such benevolence
that can crush all our lives.
I have no intention
of being benevolent
Sushena.
I consider all great warriors
to be my friends.
Prince Duryodhan!
Neither do you have
an authority over Hastinapur
nor Ang Pradesh.
The truth is,
even a small amount
of land cannot be donated by
you for you have no authority!
You are correct
but his Highness
has that authority.
Maybe, his Highness
will fulfill his son's wish.
After all, it's about preserving
the honour of the Kuru dynasty
Your Majesty.
I, King of Kuru, Dhritarashtra
from this very moment,
declare this lad
the King of Ang Pradesh!
With my blood, I take the oath
that the charity made
by my father today
will be upheld by me
till the moment I die.
And I shall always defend it.
All hail King
of Ang Pradesh, Karna!
Prince.
I honour the order
of His Highness
and with his blessings,
I take the oath
that henceforth
my property
my kingdom
my competence
and even my life
will forever be
at your service, Prince.
Your friendship
is sufficient for me.
Go on.
Fight.
Now, what are you looking at
your teacher for, son of Pandu?
Now, do you doubt
you being a Kshatriya?
Maybe he is
because everyone has heard
that the five of them
were not born with the blood
of our dynasty.
If Arjun is my son
he will certainly
accept this challenge.
Before letting his father's name
get defamed
he will accept death.
Sanjay!
Who got defeated?
The fight has not yet reached
a conclusion, your Majesty.
Only a few moments
are left until sundown.
The verdict must be in
before sundown!
'The power of the mantra
does not go in vain.'
'After I leave,
a fragment of my power'
'will stay back with you
in the form of a boy child.'
'My son will be invincible,
Kunti.'
'The entire world will know him
by the name of Karna!'
Princess...
Princess, he is...
What happened, Kunti?
T-That lad...
Princess... - Mother Kunti...
- Princess Kunti!
Mother Kunti fainted!
Princess...
Princess?
The competition has ended,
King of Ang Pradesh.
The sun has set.
It seems, you have
Lord Surya's grace upon you.
That is why the Sun God
upheld your honour.
Is darkness the limit
of your art, Prince?
No.
I cannot be unrighteous
in order to be victorious.
Resorting to unrighteousness
while proving one's superiority
is not art but arrogance.
But do not be disappointed,
King of Ang Pradesh.
You are a king now.
You will have more opportunities
to engage in fights.
Son.
Son...
'After I leave,
a fragment of my power'
'will stay back with you
in the form of a boy child.'
Karna!
Princess... - Karna!
- Princess, calm down.
Calm down, Princess, and
do remember as to where you are.
My...
He...
He... He is my son.
Karna!
My...
M-My son Karna.
Karna who?
I know only about the five sons
of yours, Princess.
What...
What are you saying?
I am telling the truth,
Princess.
Even the world knows only
about the five sons of yours
who are the sons of
the late Kuru King Pandu.
And you have no son.
What are you rambling on about?
He is my son.
He is the gift of
the Sun God himself.
Princess.
Only the feathers
attached to a peacock
act as its adornment.
The feathers that fall off it
act as a medium to dust
the seats of saints.
Do not talk like a fool,
Priyamvada.
A peacock feather may also act
as an adornment of a crown.
He is my son, Priyamvada.
He is deserving of the rights.
After so many years
he has come before me...
To have his mother's love.
To garner affection.
To...
To ask...
To ask for his right.
But Princess
he does not even know
that you are his mother.
Man must not feel sad for
something he could never have.
Think of the five sons of yours.
Think of their sorrow.
If the society finds out
that Karna was born to you
out of a wedlock
there will be no appreciation
in his respect.
But the five sons of yours
will certainly be ridiculed.