What has happened to you, sister?
Sister!
Please get up!
Sanjay, now nobody can
stop my son's victory dance.
How much longer to sunset, Sanjay?
Not too long to go,
Your Highness!
This duration of time
will serve as a jolt
to the Pandavas!
Sanjay, Shikhandi's death
is now certain.
It is certain.
My Queen, her heartbeats seems
to have stopped.
I don't think she can survive now.
If Grandsire Bhishma does not die today
we will surely lose this war.
You will have to rise again.
You will have to go to the battlefield.
Rise!
Sister, you must.
Madhav, there is very
little time left for sunset.
Where is Shikhandi?
Arjuna, do not worry about Shikhandi.
He will only cause Grandsire
to lay down his weapons.
You will have to take the
fight to him thereafter.
To bring that great man down
all five of you brothers
will need to work together.
Master, do allow your student
to showcase his skills!
You are sure to die by my hands.
This is sure to happen today.
Charioteer, the Pandavas
are approaching him.
- Take me there.
- Stop right there, Duryodhan!
Do not worry about Grandsire!
Duryodhan, you should be
more concerned about yourself.
Lord Surya!
When Vichitravirya had died
I had called out to you.
Today, I request you.
Please wait a while longer.
After many years,
the possibility of my death
looks possible and near.
Please
let this happen.
May God bless all of you,
my dear.
The sunset is upon us.
Do not wait any longer for
Princess Amba.
Use all your combined powers
and attack me together.
Prince Bhima.
Take your mace and step down from chariot.
We are short on time.
If all five of you attack me together
you will surely be able to kill me.
Do not wait for Princess Amba.
Attack me, dear.
No, Grandsire.
How can all of us attack you together?
If four of my beloved ones lift
my bier during my last moments
and one of you takes the
fire to light the bier
I will consider myself extremely fortunate.
It is time for my departure.
Nakula, Sahadeva, get your weapons.
You have taught us the path of
righteousness, Grandsire.
We cannot do this to you.
I saw the true face of righteousness yesterday.
For the first time ever.
After taking a lesson in
righteousness from Lord Kishna.
I order you...
to attack me together
as that is appropriate.
Do not shed tears.
You are about to bring
salvation upon me.
Arjuna.
Your powers...
don't need Amba's support.
Your powers will inspire millions
of others in times to come.
Take your weapons and attack me.
Dear, your weapons will
not cause me pain.
Instead I will be relieved!
Attack me!
Why are you standing silent?
My child, go and kill Shikhandi.
Hurry up!
Until we live, we will not allow
them to harm you.
Now, it is our responsibility
to take you to Grandsire.
Attack me, Bhima.
Attack me, Bhima!
I command you!
Attack me, Bhima.
Brilliant, Bhima!
You are an excellent mace fighter!
Sahadev, slay me!
Slay me!
These hands have comitted
many sins!
My silence has caused much
injustice in this lifetime!
This life of mine must ends!
This life should ends.
At the hands of you five,
my lads.
Yudhisthir, my lad.
Fight!
Fight with all your might, my lad!
Do not wait for Shikhandi, my lad!
The sun is about to set.
Attack me!
When your soul is plagued by age and exhaustion,
I shall arrive as your death!
Your wait has come to an end,
Grandsire Bheeshma!
Your redemption stands
right before you!
Complete your life's purpose,
Lady Amba!
The cause of your death is present
before you, Bheeshma!
Recall your promise!
I make a promise...
I shall lay down all my weapons
before you.
Grant me redemption, Lady Amba!