Greetings.
May you live long.
Wonderful!
You are way more skilled
in archery than me.
My knowledge of the art can
only improve the hunting skills
of my disciples.
Hunting?
That is not a form of art,
teacher.
I am wandering
around to learn.
I have gone
to numerous hermitages
and tried to become a disciple.
I have scaled the regions
of Kuru and Panchal for it.
I did not do so only
to learn the art of hunting.
But who will teach you
the skills that you seek?
You are well aware
that our community
does not have the right to
learn such higher skills.
Knowledge is made by God
as is water and air.
How can someone
have the right to it?
I do not wish to argue
with you, Karna.
You will gain nothing
from my hermitage.
Near the banks of river Drishadvati*
*"She with many stones", seasonal river estimated at southern boundaries of Kuru.
lies the hermitage
of the revered Drona.
Request him
if he's willing to accept you
as his disciple.
But know this.
To make an enemy of the entire
society only for your sake
is not something people
would either like
or have the capability
of doing so.
That is why accept the clan
you were born into
as your fate
and try to lead a happy life.
'I do not believe in this
discrimination of caste.'
'I shall certainly go to
the revered Dronacharya'
'and learn from him.'
Arjun.
Greetings, Sire.
Who are you?
- I am Karna.
I have come to you for I
have heard of your fame, Sire.
I hope to learn the art
of archery from you.
My father is the charioteer
of the great Bheeshma.
Son of a charioteer?
Then how could you even dream
of learning the art of archery?
Don't you know
that only Kshatriyas have
the right to higher knowledge?
Son of a charioteer...
Indeed!
I am the son of a charioteer!
And Sire, I am not asking for
a kingdom like the Kshatriyas.
I merely wish
to fortify my capabilities.
Then why can I not learn
the art of archery?
To a deserving person,
his capability is his blessing.
In that case, why did
you learn the art of battle?
Why are you teaching
military arts to your son
revered Drona?
Do not argue.
I am unique.
I was not born from
the womb of a woman.
I was born in the drona* vessel of sage Bharadwaj.
*Pitcher, leavepot.
If you also had a divine birth
then prove it.
Otherwise go away.
- Divine?
What do you mean by that, Sire?
The birth of every child
is divine for his parents.
No one has the right
to weigh the love of a mother
and the dreams of a father
in the scales of caste
and creed.
My father's heart
bleeds each time
he tells me to stay away
from archery.
Why does the society
frighten him so?
Why can I not be the reason
of pride and honour for him?
Why must I live
by curbing my capabilities?
Who has made these rules, Sire?
Did my father choose the caste
he would be born into?
Did his ancestors
make this choice?
Then why do such rules exist
that weigh human beings
on the scales of discrimination?
Why?
No.
I do not believe
in such rules, Sire.
I would be honoured to break
such traditions.
A bow belongs to a person
who can tie its string.
And that is acquired by deeds,
not by birth.
Your arrogance is soaring high
but it is worthless.
Higher knowledge belongs only
to Kshatriyas and Brahmins.
Not to people of a lower class.
Ghee* is used to light the
holy fire in a Yagna.
*A class of clarified butter.
But a clay oven is fuelled
with crude oil.
But Lord Parashuram
had used Ghee
to light a clay oven.
Go away.
Go away!
I do not even
wish to see your face.
I am leaving.
I shall go and gain knowledge
from the one
who imparted knowledge to you.
I shall return.
But let me assure you
that I shall return as the most
skilled archer of this nation.
And I shall be better
than all your disciples.
What does superiority mean?
Superiority means, having
more knowledge than others.
In other words, it is immaterial
how much
knowledge you have obtained.
The thing that matters is how
much more knowledge you have
obtained than others.
In other words,
the desire to be superior
makes even obtaining knowledge
a competition.
And when does victory become
decisive in a competition?
It is possible to be superior
for a limited period of time
but no one can be superior forever.
That is when discontent,
agony
and struggle are born.
But, instead
of becoming superior
if one tries to excel
then what would it be like?
To excel means to obtain
all that is worth obtaining.
It is not out of the desire
to gain more than others
but merely for
the contentment of the soul.
On the path of excellence
one does not
compete with others.
It is a competition
with oneself.
In other words, one trying
to excel will sooner or later
gain all the knowledge.
Even without trying,
he becomes superior.
But the one
who tries to be superior
may or may not succeed
but he can never excel.
Do think about it.
With my hair
I renounce the rules
of the society.
The society that has insulted me
shall be the recipient
of my blow.
With my old apparels
I renounce all traditions.
My new form will usher the
beginning of a new tradition.
By smearing the ashes of caste
and creed on my forehead
I pledge that henceforth
my capability is my identity
and my knowledge is my religion.
Greetings.
Are you a Brahmin?
I too, like you
am opposed to the Kshatriyas,
my Lord.
I am not opposed to Kshatriyas
but to the tyranny
of the Kshatriyas.
And even more than that
I am opposed to feeble Brahmins
feeble human beings
and the feeble society.
I have come to you
with the hope
of becoming strong.
I have given up teaching.
And I have donated
all my weapons.
But I
upon seeing
the aura of your face
am filled with the desire
of imparting knowledge to you.
If you are a Brahmin, son
then I shall indeed
impart knowledge to you.
'People of our caste
can become only charioteers'
'and not warriors.'
'A charioteer carrying
weapons
'has no place
in the kingdom of Kuru.'
'Are you the son
of a charioteer?'
'Then how could you even dream
of learning the art of archery?'
'Higher knowledge belongs only
to Kshatriyas and Brahmins.'
'Not to people
of a lower class.'
I am
a Brahmin, my Lord.
Karna, from today, your
training in military arts
shall begin.
You created the sun,
Lord Parashuram?
My dear boy, similarly
the day you are
able to do this
your desire to learn
the art of archery
shall indeed be fulfilled.
'12 Years Later.'