You may speak first, friend.
Vasudev
I did not know
that you would
break your promise.
I am not breaking my promise,
brother Duryodhan.
You most certainly are,
Vasudev.
When I had come here
your eyes were closed.
And my eyes were closed
even when friend had come here.
But he sat in a place
where I could
see him first.
And it is the fault
of the Almighty
because He has placed
the eyes in front of the head.
A person sitting at the back
cannot be said
to have arrived first.
Vasudev
but all the seats
were placed behind your head.
That is not my fault.
If friend wanted
he too could have taken a seat.
Pride seeks to occupy
the highest place
while love seeks to occupy
the correct one.
I am not breaking my promise.
Then coming to you
with the hope of justice
was futile.
I am leaving now,
Vasudev.
Stop,
Crown Prince Duryodhan.
You had come here to ask
for something from Madhav.
You cannot leave
without asking for it.
That would tarnish
Madhav's reputation.
Then what is the reason
that Vasudev has decided
to fulfill your wish first?
Because friend has come
with a request while you
have come with a plan.
Friend has dedication
in his heart while you
have politics in yours.
Friend seeks charity
while you require support.
If one gets the opportunity
to engage in charity
then one seeks
to fulfill it first.
No other task in the world
is more important than charity.
This is partiality,
Vasudev.
No, brother.
I certainly am partial
towards the person
who forsakes the world
and chooses me.
However, I have
my brother's orders.
So, I cannot be partial today.
Before asking for anything
listen to my decision.
In this war,
my army and I
will not fight
from the same side.
My army will stand
against me in the battlefield.
The Narayani Army of Dwaraka
is like no other in this world.
Each soldier of this one 'akshauhini'* army
*An ancient battle formation that consisted of 21,870 chariots (Sanskrit ratha); 21,870 elephants; 65,610 cavalry and 109,350 infantry.
battles like a 'Maharathi.'
He can use all known
weapons of the world.
Defeating this army
is nearly
impossible.
But Vasudev
your competence
is more than that
of your Narayani Army.
You are correct,
brother Duryodhan.
The strength and power
of my Sudarshan 'Chakra'
can be matched
only by Mahadev's Trident
and Indra's 'Vajra.'
Its blow
scares not only humans
but also the Gods.
The strength of my knowledge
the might of my character
and the energy of my soul
reside in this weapon.
The moment I use
the Sudarshan 'Chakra'
there will be annihilation.
Truth-untruth
justice-injustice
weak-powerful...
Everything will be destroyed.
In such a situation
the presence
or the absence of a war
makes no difference,
brother Duryodhan.
That is why,
I have taken the decision
that I shall
not take to arms in this war.
On one hand,
there is
my invincible one 'akshauhini'
Narayani Army
while on the other
there is me.
Alone
and weaponless.
Now, the decision rests
with the two of you.
Tell me,
friend.
What do you wish for?
Make the choice,
friend.
My choice is clear,
Madhav.
However, to save your name from
being tainted with partiality
could you please give
the opportunity
to Crown Prince Duryodhan
to make the choice first?
Tainted!
When I was a child,
Mother Yashoda
used to call me 'Kala'.*
*Kaladeva, the black deity.
How can a dark person
be scared of getting tainted?
And it is quite evident
what brother Duryodhan
seems to have chosen.
The basis of choice
of some human beings
is often
the possibility of a benefit
while the basis of choice
of other human beings
is their nature.
And brother Duryodhan
knows quite well
where his benefits lie.
You do know, do you not,
brother Duryodhan?
I most certainly do.
That is why, I choose...
- No.
The first one to choose
will be friend.
You have earned
this right, friend.
Forsaking one's rights
is not called bravery.
Right?
One has the right
to one's property, Madhav.
Love
knowledge
and truth
have their right
on human beings.
You are the embodiment
of love, knowledge and truth.
You are righteousness yourself.
I cannot choose you.
I can only ask for you,
Madhav
but neither out of
the greed of victory
nor the fear of defeat.
For...
For the sake of righteousness
I ask for you,
Madhav.
You
asked for a person
who has no army
or weapons, Arjun?
Is this generosity
or foolishness?
When the juice of sugarcane
has been extracted
only the juice is of value.
The sugarcane has no value,
Crown Prince Duryodhan.
You are correct,
Arjun.
Vasudev
your one 'akshauhini'
Narayani Army will have to
suffice me now.
Splendid, brother.
Brother had said
that neither him,
me
nor our army will fight
on behalf of the Pandavas.
His words did not go in vain
friend had his wish fulfilled
and even your plan
was successful.
Now,
we must see
who gets what
in this war.
Kunti
you must indeed have heard
that the Yadavas of Dwaraka
have decided to take
Duryodhan's side.
Only the army of Dwaraka
will battle along with that of
Hastinapur, brother-in-law.
Today, I am reminded
of my beloved Pandu.
Brother-in-law,
this is the time
when the heart
becomes agitated with
the uncertainties of the future.
At a time like this
one is reminded of the past.
Yes!
You are correct, Kunti.
My heart is full
of uncertainties.
This reminds me of an incident
from my childhood.
At that time,
Pandu
was about three-years-old.
One day, in order to keep
his gold toy safe
he placed it in my hands.
A person who has vision
has a different world than the
ones who are visionless, Kunti.
Even as a child,
I could not know
what a toy was.
I could not
take care of that toy.
It fell from my hands and broke.
Pandu cried a lot at that time.
Then I...
Then I took the pieces
of that broken toy
in my hands
and etched its shape
in my mind, Kunti.
After working hard all night
I made the exact same toy
out of wood and gave it to him.
His joy knew no bounds
that day, Kunti.
He went to everyone and said
that something
that belonged to him
would stay safe
only in my hands.
His joy and faith
had left me feeling
exceedingly happy, Kunti.
I decided right then
that anything
that belongs to Pandu
will not be harmed
as long as I am alive.
But today,
I feel sad
that despite my presence,
I could not keep Pandu's sons
safe from all this.
That is why,
I request you, Kunti
to explain to your sons
to quit being
intransigent about a war
and dedicate themselves to us.
If they die
then my heart will break,
Kunti.
You need not worry,
brother-in-law.
The Almighty himself
has come up with a plan
to keep my sons safe.
They will not be harmed.
Krishna is with them.
Do you not remember,
brother-in-law?
Your sons had tried
to disrobe Draupadi
in the court.
Krishna had left the entire
court bare on its account.
However
he did not let Draupadi
get disrobed.
Krishna is Narayan himself.
The side he is on
is the one that will
emerge victorious.
Kunti...
But Vasudev has decided
not to take to arms
in the battlefield, Kunti.
In such a situation,
how will he aid your sons?
Krishna does not aid anyone,
brother-in-law.
The side he is on
gets aided by
the entire creation itself.
In the battlefield,
all of Arjun's arrows
will transform into
the 'Brahmastra'
because he will be
aided by Krishna's powers.
Bheem's mace will strike
like the 'Vajra.'
The weapons of Yudhishthir,
Nakul and Sahadev
will wreak havoc on your army
like lighting burns a tree down.
You had once promised
My Lord to keep him safe.
That is why,
today
I have lit these hundred lamps.
I have made an attempt
to keep your sons safe.
When these lamps
almost get extinguished
you will know
that the lives of your sons
are in danger.
Krishna being on their side
will take my sons to victory.