So, Your Highness
which of your brothers
are you going to put at stake?
Impossible!
Prince Duryodhan,
in the game of dice
you can only wager property.
You cannot put humans at stake.
But this game
is not for property,
Prime Minister.
He has himself said
that humans play
for their pride.
And one always puts
his pride at stake
when playing-
Humans are proud of
many things, prince.
Knowledge acquired.
A father's dutifulness.
Mother's purity.
And one's lineage.
But these cannot be
put at stake.
Because humans have no
right over it, grandsire.
Father, mother, teacher and heir
are all God's blessings,
grandsire.
Anything that you have
a right on and you are proud of
can be put at stake
you have said it, grandsire.
This is a pointless
discussion, Duryodhan.
Parents have rights
on their children
but I haven't heard of anyone
having a right on his siblings.
Prime Minister Vidur
you had acceded to
King Pandu's authority
and you also accept
King Dhritarashtra's authority.
Don't you?
Excellent.
Absolutely excellent.
So it's clear
that my dear Duryodhan
has the right on his
younger brother Vikarna
and he is also proud of
him, Your Highness.
So, Prince Duryodhan,
can put his brother Vikarna
at stake.
If His Highness deems it fit
he can abide by the rules.
So tell me,
Your Highness
which of your brothers
will you put at stake?
He will put me at stake.
No, Nakul.
No...
- Nakul
not you.
No, Nakul.
Long live the Empress.
What happened?
Hastinapur's Prince has put
his younger brother Vikarna
at stake.
And Prince Nakul has volunteered
from the emperor's side.
What kind of a game is this?
Are humans and relationships
meant to be put at stake?
Demons and serpents perform
the 'Narmedh Yajna'
where humans are sacrificed.
Is Hastinapur too inculcating
this tradition, Your Highness?
Had Krishna been here
he would have definitely stopped
this game of dice.
But King Shaka has
attacked Dwarka.
Krishna is fighting a battle
to protect Dwarka.
Queen Gandhari...
Queen Gandhari
we have to stop this game,
immediately.
Kunti
when grandsire and Vidur
are unable to stop it
then there must be
an ethical dilemma involved.
How will I be able
to resolve this?
I will resolve this.
Maid
go tell the Emperor
that the five petals of hibiscus
are connected to its stem
not to each other.
He doesn't have the right
to put my husband at stake.
Go right away and tell him.
- As you command, Your Highness.
No, Nakul.
I cannot put you at stake.
Brother, it will be appropriate
for you to put me at stake.
If you lose,
then Arjun's competency
and the strength of
brother Bheem will be with you.
Brother Bheem and brother Arjun
will be able to get me released
but I won't be able
to get them released.
If you are in a dilemma then put
brother Bheem at stake, Emperor!
If you are defeated
then serving me as a slave
will be quite easy for him.
Nakul may die
toiling as a slave.
Pick up your weapon, Dushasana!
Let's decide right away
as to who will die!
Dear Bheem!
This is the game of dice,
not a battlefield.
Challenging a kingdom that has
surrendered to you, for war
is unrighteousness, son.
Calm down.
Calm down, Bheem.
I will put my...
I'll put my younger brother
Nakul... - Greetings, Emperor!
I have a message
from the Empress.
I can't put my younger
brother Nakul at stake.
I am definitely proud of him
but I have no rights over him.
I don't have any rights over
any of my brothers!
We brothers are interconnected
like the petals of hibiscus
but through the medium
of our wife Draupadi.
She has the right over us.
That's why...
This game is over now.
Emperor...
I have a question.
Will you please answer?
Does a branch grow on the
tree, first
or a flower petal?
Emperor...
Empress came much
later into your life.
All five of you
got married to her.
Were you not brothers
before that?
Didn't you share
any relationship?
Prince Nakul, answer me.
Didn't the Emperor
have any rights on you
before marriage?
After getting married
did you give that right
to your wife?
Didn't the Emperor
have any rights on you
before marriage?
After getting married
did you give that right
to your wife?
It means
if the Emperor, upon
seeing a hibiscus flower
quits the game
then it will be violation
of the rules.
And unrighteousness, as well.
I put my younger brother Nakul
at stake.
Emperor, if you get six points
then you shall
win over Duryodhan.
Emperor, Duryodhan's
first pawn has won.
You just need
four points to reach the fort.
Emperor, it is unfortunate.
You just needed four points
but you got five points.
You got one extra point.
Now if Duryodhan's pawn
beats yours
then he will win the bet.
One, two, three, four
five, six, seven.
In order to beat Emperor's pawn
I just need seven points.
Then, Nakul will be my slave.
Come on.
Emperor, rejoice.
You lost your younger brother
Nakul.
The place of a slave
and the footwear
lies at the master's feet.
Nakul
come here.
Come and kneel among
these slaves.
Come here!
My brother is as pious
as Lord Ram's impressions.
I will make sure he dominates
you, brother Duryodhan!
The kind of behaviour I dispense
to my slaves, is none of
Prince Arjun's concern, Emperor!
It is only mine.
Calm down, Arjun.
Calm down.
Slave Nakul, come here!
Come and sit among these slaves.
Come!
Sit down, slave Nakul.