Were you aware that all this
was happening in Dwarka?
Yes, brother!
This has been happening
since a while.
I tried stopping it.
But the subjects of Dwarka
get drawn to the path
of immorality repeatedly.
When a river meets a waterfall
it's speed grows even further.
Even when the society
treads the path of immorality
it gets completely tainted
with injustice.
Yudishtir is the one to be
blamed for all of this.
He gambled his own wife
in that filled courtroom.
And now, all over the Arya clan
people are following
that despicable practice.
No, elder brother!
No!
Neither is brother Yudishtir
to be blamed
nor brother Duryodhan.
It is the righteousness
that is to blame
that gets bound by malice...
That surrenders before malice...
In reality, it is the blindness
of traditions.
There is no such thing
as righteousness.
Please elaborate, brother.
When a man holds on stubbornly
to his oaths and promises
it is great indeed,
elder brother.
But is being stubborn
in every situation
any wise?
The same happened
in that filled courtroom.
Grandsire Bheeshma,
Master Drona
Vidur, the wise one,
and the eldest brother Yudishtir
were all bound by their words
and remained blinded
by tradition.
Just fulfilling their oaths
and promises
seemed like righteousness
to them.
Even if one of them had
broken out of their solemnity
Draupadi would never face
such grave injustice.
What do you mean to say,
Krishna?
Isn't fulfilling of oaths
appropriate?
Righteousness is like a tree,
elder brother.
Oaths and promises
are its branches.
But the roots of the tree are
compassion.
The branches are
significant too.
But not as much as the roots.
If in order to end one's agony
a promise has to be broken
it is appropriate.
But here, at this present time
compassion has been destroyed
all across the Arya clan.
All across the world!
One values his agony
more than that his dear ones.
And the agony of dear ones
matters more than society's...
Compassion has drained out
of this society.
When there is no compassion
in the society
people do not bond
with each other, elder brother.
They just live for
their own comfort.
The plight that Dwarka
is in today
is the plight of
all of Arya clan.
The branches of trees
that snap off the trunk
dry up and become wood.
Similarly, at this time,
righteousness
has grown lifeless.
It is time to revive
righteousness, elder brother!
Once again the society must be
made aware of righteousness.
Our administration will handle
the injustice prevailing
in Dwarka, Krishna.
But I am facing
another grave problem.
That is due to the injustice
prevailing in the Arya clan.
The prospective war between
the Kauravas and Pandavas.
There shall indeed be a war,
elder brother!
When compassion is destroyed
within a society
the society itself
decides a war for itself.
The Kauravas and Pandavas
are mere clans.
A river has banks.
But a flood has no banks.
Even we cannot be mere
spectators in this war, brother.
We have to fight
on someone's behalf.
You are right, Krishna.
But brother, an equally
important truth is
the side to which
you shall incline to
will turn into the just side
by default, Krishna.
Now try proving me false.
What are you doing, son?
Whose heads are you smashing?
That head was supposed
to be yours.
Dear son, Abhimanyu.
If you severe my head
your uncle Bheem shall be angry.
Because the oath to slay
all of us hundred brothers
is your uncle Bheem's.
And you father wants
to slay the armoured Karna.
Then I shall slay your sons,
uncle!
Whoever the blood of
Grandsire Dhritarashtra runs in
shall bleed it all out
on the battlefield!
Son Abhimanyu, there are
two more heads
that you can severe.
Your uncle Krishna
and uncle Balram.
Because your uncle
has chosen our side.
Will you be able to
severe his head?
If an earthen pot has
held poison even once
it has to be smashed,
uncle Duryodhan.
Couldn't you severe the heads?
Because the heads of
both my uncles
can never nurse the thought of
siding with injustice.
Brilliant!
Brilliant indeed, Son Abhimanyu!
You have indeed understood
both your uncles well.
Come.
It is time now for you
to train for mace combat.
Proceed and wait for me.
Bless you!
Forgive me, Balram,
the mighty one!
But you have promised that...
- That...
I shall not fight
on behalf of the Pandavas.
But neither had I assured you,
King of Gandhar
that I would fight
on behalf of the Kauravas.
So how did you arrive
at this conclusion?
I shall not fight on
anyone's side in this battle.
Because after all,
both sides are my family.
And how can I engage
my own family in battle?
Therefore, will Krishna
and his army not participate in
this war either, Master Balram?
You better question him
regarding that decision.
Krishna is Lord Narayana.*
*The Refuge of Everyone.
And all decisions pertaining to
the army of Narayana
will be made by Himself.
Dear Duryodhan,
go and counsel with Krishna.
He has promised me
that he won't be partial.
Whoever approaches him first
he will provide that person
with appropriate help.
But remember.
Victory lies to the side
that Krishna will be on.
Permit me!
My lad, go and meet Krishna
immediately.
Meet him before Arjun does.
Remember.
Under any circumstances,
Krishna, the son of Vasudev
should be on our side.
And also the army
of Lord Narayana.
Meet him at the earliest.
Make haste, my lad!
Make haste!
My Lord!
The eldest one has
sent a message.
He has consented with
Lord Krishna and the Yadav army
with participating
in the battle.
Hurry up, My Lord!
Request brother Krishna
to aid our side with the army
of Lord Narayana.
Krishna has always been
on the side of
truth and justice.
If there is no truthfulness
on our side
there is no use asking him.
You have to ask him, My Lord!
Help is granted without asking.
But blessings...
Blessings must be sought.
And if brother supports you
without asking
brother Duryodhan will claim
that Krishna is being partial.
Krishna has promised
that whoever
approaches him first
he shall surely grant him
whatever he asks for.
Please go soon, My Lord.
You must approach Krishna before
the son of Dhritarashtra does.
Please go soon!
Arjun, why are you
seated on the ground?
A beseecher's place
lies on the ground, Krishna.
You aren't a beseecher, Arjun,
you are my friend.
If I am a friend
how does my position matter?
Even prince Duryodhan
awaits your counsel.
Welcome brother Duryodhan!
I did not spot you
as you were seated above.
Excuse me!
Krishna.
I am not seated higher.
I am seated next to you.
Very well!
Would you like some
refreshments?
The 'ksheer pak'* made from the milk of Dwarka's cows.
*A milk decoction.
You shall not find it even in
the celestial world.
My gratitude, Krishna!
I am not here for refreshments.
I am here to discuss
an important matter.
We shall indeed discuss,
brother Duryodhan.
First, let me hear
Arjun's request.
Go ahead, Arjun.
But, Krishna.
You had promised master Balram
that whoever approaches you
first
you shall join his side.
Impossible.
Brother could never decipher
this meaning from my words.
I had said
whoever appears before me first
I shall surely grant his wish.
You speak first, Arjun.