Tomorrow's war
is the result of that oath.
No, Vasudev.
Tomorrow's war
is the result of
Hastinapur's arrogance.
By displaying its might,
Hastinapur
had covered my
beloved sister's fortune
with a cloth of darkness.
That day
I promised myself
that Hastinapur
will either give
my sister a present
for her sacrifice
or
pay dearly for it.
Getting a present and
paying dearly for a sacrifice!
One who deems sacrifice
a business dealing
certainly experiences agony.
It is such a strange thing!
Your sister made a sacrifice
but it was turned
into a business dealing
by you.
The truth is
under the garb
of exacting revenge
you wished to have opulence
and supreme power.
By calling your actions
a sacrifice
do not deceive yourself,
King of Gandhar.
Deception.
Deception!
Am I deceiving people
or are you
Vasudev?
By calling this war
a righteous one
you are deceiving
the entire Aryan region.
In the entire world
if there is someone
more wily than me
then it is
you, Vasudev.
I have firm faith
that in this war
of righteousness of yours
you will indeed use deceit
to justify
unrighteousness.
This is indeed a war of
righteousness, King of Gandhar.
In this war,
both might
and deceit shall be used.
To establish righteousness,
unrighteousness shall be used.
To safeguard the truth,
lies
will be told.
To champion life,
death shall be welcomed.
To usher the new creation,
the old
shall be annihilated.
Such faith!
Do you have such faith
in the competence
of the Pandavas?
No.
I have such faith
in you
and your deception.
I had told you
that various situations
have arisen and you
have been bound
to them in such a way
that in the end,
every deception of yours
will benefit only the Pandavas.
That is why,
King of Gandhar
you must now engage in deception
only after meditating over it.
From tomorrow,
every deception of yours
every treachery of yours
and every unrighteous deed
of yours shall meet its match.
Do remember that.
You need to remember
Vasudev
that you have taken an oath
of not taking to arms
in this war.
I have taken an oath
of not taking to arms
in this war, King of Gandhar.
However,
my might
is not my weapon.
In this battlefield, I bear
the might of righteousness.
That is my weapon
and also my armour.
And I am
the armour of your
beloved Pandavas.
Look at this battlefield.
The war will begin here at dawn.
Before dusk
there will be
so many corpses here
that even stones will float
in a river of blood.
There will be so much
bloodshed here
that the soil of this land
will remain red for eternity.
And I promise
that whoever dies
in this gruesome war
will indeed realize what
righteousness is at the end.
The purpose of this war
is to establish righteousness
and till the end of time
it shall be known as Mahabharat,
the war of righteousness.
Friend Karna
what have you done?
You gave away your armour
and ear-rings as charity!
They were a part of you,
friend Karna.
How could you chop off a part
of your body and give it away?
Had a treacherous person
asked you for your right arm
would you have
given it away as well?
Why did you act
so foolishly, friend?
Why did you act so foolishly?
What good is duty
if, in the process of
discharging it, might, future
hope and even life
have to sacrificed?
When everything needs
to be sacrificed, friend...
Pardon me,
friend.
Pardon me.
Had I broken one oath of mine
I would have had the thought
of breaking another.
And possibly
in the battlefield
I would not have been able
to discharge my duties, friend.
I
shall heal soon,
friend.
My darling
let's go.
The healer
will take care
of King Karna of Anga.
I had told you,
my darling!
His righteousness is his limit!
And King Karna of Anga
has great pride
in his righteousness!
Do you remember what your guru,
the mighty Balaram had said?
Whenever righteousness
and pride come together
man meets with loss.
This is the reason
why Yudhishthir had accepted
to go on an exile
while he wishes
to exit this world.
This is the reason
why King Karna of Anga
never had my complete trust.
I was alluding
to the armour and ear-rings
of King Karna of Anga.
And now,
they are gone.
Now,
let him go as well.
But uncle...
- This is not the time
for 'ifs' and 'buts,'
my darling!
The holy armour
of King Karna of Anga
is gone!
At a time like this
it is important to augment
our army...
And there is going to be
an addition of
two 'akshauhini' armies
to our existing army.
Karna...
Karna!
Karna.
- Son!
Karna...
- My Lord! - Son!
Healer
why is his breathing
so irregular?
His condition is critical.
Upon cutting out
the holy armour and ear-rings
the resulting wounds
on King Karna of Anga
are not healing
with the traditional herbs.
We cannot do anything for him.
But healer,
my son is in great agony.
Do something.
Radha
Karna will indeed get better.
Have faith.
- Faith?!
On whom?
You?!
The mother of the people who
robbed my son of his divinity
is reassuring me!
Be quiet,
Radha.
No,
My Lord.
I will not be quiet today.
What kind of an enmity made them
snatch my son's divinity
from him?
In order to secure
the victory of your children
you engaged in such treachery!
How can you even call yourself
a righteous person?!
Please believe me,
Radha.
I have engaged
in no such treachery.
Then why did
the father of your son
take away the divinity
of my Radheya?
Did he think that just because
he is the son of a charioteer
he could act treacherously
with him?!
My son was born to be
seated on the throne.
But he
grew up deeming the lap of his
impoverished father a throne.
My son had the capability
of standing tall next to
the greatest of Kings
but his childhood
was spent standing behind
domestic help.
The armour and ear-rings
denoted his divinity
but they were
snatched from him as well!
For safeguarding
the lives of your sons
do accept my greetings,
Queen Mother!
But you have murdered my son!
You have murdered my son...
Do not say that,
Radha.
Karna...
Karna is my son.
No!
Had he been your son
he would never have met
with such treachery!
If you say
that Karna is your son
then please save his life.
Your sons,
Nakul and Sahadev
have been blessed
by the Ashwini Kumaras.
I request you
to alleviate the agony
of my son, Queen Mother!
Alleviate it...
Queen Mother
can Prince Sahadev
and Prince Nakul
heal My Lord,
their elder brother...
Can they deem him
their elder brother
and heal him?
No, Vrushali.
Why would they do that?
My son is their enemy after all.
And who can ever save
the life of one's enemy?
In a battle,
it is a rule
that if the entire army
gets annihilated
or all the soldiers
flee from the battlefield
then the King must surrender.
The King cannot even challenge
the enemy to a duel then.
That is why, in order to sustain
in the battlefield
we require a large army.
We have
a seven 'akshauhini' army
while our enemies have nine.
We must acquire an additional
two 'akshauhini' armies
at any cost.
Ruler of Madra,
King Shalya
the elder brother
of Mother Madri.
Nakul has
requested him to aid us.
The two 'akshauhini' army of his
is just as mighty
as the Narayani Army.
Very soon, uncle Shalya
shall be here with his army.
In other words,
our army
will be as big and mighty
as that of the Kauravas.
We have also arranged
for them to rest on the way
brother Yudhishthir.
Sons...
Mother.
Mother
is there a problem?
There is bound to be a problem,
brother Yudhishthir.
Our mother is residing
in the enemy camp.
She was residing there,
brother Bheem.
Now,
she has come to us.
Greetings, mother.
What is the matter,
mother?
Why do you not seem happy?
Even after meeting your sons
after such a long time
are you not happy?
No, son.
A mother is weeping here
and it is time to wipe away
the tears of that mother.
Whose mother?
The mother
of King Karna of Anga.
Nakul, Sahadev
the two of you need to
come with me this instant.
King Karna of Anga
is in great agony, sons.
What is the matter,
mother?
What agony?
- Son
King Karna of Anga
is gravely wounded.
If...
If he does not receive
the holy herbs from Nakul
and Sahadev soon then...
Then finding a remedy to his
agony will become impossible.
Please pardon me,
Queen Mother Kunti, but
if the soldiers of the Kaurava
army get injured in the war
then will they be treated by
Prince Nakul and Prince Sahadev?
Then there is no point
in waging a war.
The war has not begun yet.
And at a time like this
it is our duty to protect
the life of an injured person.
King Karna of Anga would never
have mercy on your sons, mother.
Had there been kindness
or righteousness in his heart
your daughter-in-law would
not have been subjected
to grave humiliation during
the game of dice, mother.
Man behaves according to
the circumstance he is in, son.
At the moment
the circumstances are different.
How is today's situation
any different, mother?
Sons
the King of Anga...
King Karna of Anga...