Please
marry my eldest brother.
By presiding over
the throne of Hastinapur
please work for the welfare
of its subjects.
Your radiance
and your glory
will illuminate the entire
Aryan region in the future.
What about you, Prince?
We four brothers
will resort to asceticism.
Out of the five brothers,
four must resort to asceticism.
In this strange situation
we five brothers
cannot coexist together.
Is this the solution you
came up with in this situation
Prince Arjun?
In other words, you will give
the fruit of your competence
to someone else as charity.
Did King Karna of Anga
not wish to do the same?
But he was prohibited to do so.
Then how can you
have the right to do so?
And what about
my honour, Prince?
The world will laugh at me
that when I found out
that only the eldest son
has the right to the throne
I decided to deem
someone else my husband.
What am I, Prince?
A woman who loves a man
only for property?
When a tree burns
the climber wrapped around it
also burns to ashes.
It does not change its basis.
Am I inferior
to even that climber?
If you agree with me
then it shall not be deemed
your selfishness
but sacrifice, Princess.
No one will speak ill of you.
Prince even Goddess Sita
was spoken ill of.
Then how can I be spared?
Then answer this question
of mine, Prince.
I will make the sacrifice.
You will make the sacrifice.
Three of your brothers
will make the sacrifice.
Will the burden
of so many sacrifices
let your eldest brother live?
Then, Princess
you should return
to your father.
Invalidate the 'swayamvar.'
You have the right to do so.
- And after that...
Who will marry me?
I have heard the tale of Amba,
the Princess of Kashi, Prince.
Should I also follow her path
and go beg before Kings
and ask for justice?
And in the end
the fire of dejection
will burn me to ashes.
Has the royal family
of Hastinapur
taken an oath to torch
the maidens of the Aryan region
Prince?!
Pardon me, Princess.
If the four brothers of mine
resort to asceticism
because of me
then its burden
will crush our married life.
I see no solution
to this situation.
Pardon us.
'These five stones...'
'These are the fives bases
of righteousness, Draupadi.'
'There are many instances
in one's life, Draupadi'
'when one is unable
to see the path.'
'In order to remind
oneself of righteousness'
'one requires an object.'
'The decision will always
be yours, Draupadi.'
'But taking a decision bearing
righteousness in mind'
'will be easier.'
We cannot let this injustice
happen to Princess Draupadi
mother.
We must face
the punishment for it.
Lady.
Draupadi.
Dear, my sons have found
a way out of this situation.
You will not face
any form of injustice.
You and Arjun will get married.
But before that
the rest of my sons
will resort to asceticism.
Asceticism is the
path of courage, lady.
It is not a refuge when
running away from problems.
Who will benefit from
the asceticism of your sons?
And Prince Bheem is married.
Why should his first wife
be punished so?
There is no other
solution, dear.
When a woman gets married
she enters her new home
with the hope to become
that family's good fortune.
How can I bring misfortune
to King Pandu's
family and his lineage, lady?
Unknowingly, you
have divided me
amongst your five sons.
I deem your mistake
my destiny.
I...
I will marry your five sons.
Impossible.
- Impossible!
What did you say, Draupadi?
Have these 'Brahmins'
planned to divide you?
How did such a terrible thought
stem in their minds?!
Is this the competence
of this 'Brahmin?!'
The divinely fragrant
sandalwood tree
is home to venomous serpents!
I had heard of such a thing!
Today, I have seen it myself!
We have no such plan,
Your Highness.
Pardon us.
Fate worked in such...
- Be quiet, 'Brahmin!'
Otherwise I shall lose the fear
of killing a 'Brahmin.'
The royal family of Panchal
shall protect its Princess.
I do not accept this marriage.
Let's go, daughter.
Father
if a maiden won in a 'swayamvar'
stays with her father
then you will be humiliated.
And so will I.
That will not be humiliation
but the blessing
of Lord Surya himself.
Daughter, one would have
been humiliated
had his daughter not been
welcomed in his home.
How did this happen, sons?
How could I commit
such a grave mistake?
I have ruined a maiden's life
by giving her lifelong insult.
Joy, sorrow, respect, insult
life and death.
If you can give all this, Kunti
then what does the Almighty do?
Lord Vedvyas!
Greetings.
There would come
a time in your lives
when you would not know
what the righteous path is.
I knew of it.
That is why
I have come here
from Kampilya, Kunti.
Lord Vedvyas
greetings.
No one knows more about
righteousness than you
in the entire world.
You have classified the 'Vedas'
into four segments.
Oh Great Sage, answer us.
What would be correct and
appropriate in this situation?
Your name is Yudhishthir.
It means being steady
in testing times.
Being steady in testing times
is in your nature, child.
Then how can you
be so perturbed?
When life is spinning
out of control
it is essential
to calm oneself down.
Let's meditate
over this situation.