Yudhishthir, you truly
are very powerful.
The blood of which dynasty
runs through your veins?
From whom did your characterless
mother conceive you?
Pray tell me.
I cannot fight you
any longer, Duryodhan.
This is a friendly competition.
And there can be no place
for anger in it.
However, you had angered me
for a moment back then.
If I raise my weapon
against you now
it will be unrighteous.
But it is not
unrighteous for me.
All hail Prince Duryodhan!
Your Majesty,
Prince Duryodhan is victorious.
This ovation is the evidence
that my Duryodhan
has returned
as a unique warrior.
Was Duryodhan victorious again?
No.
This time,
only Yudhishthir was defeated.
Had you waited
a few more moments there
you could have defeated him
quite easily. - No.
Had I waited there, I would have
defeated myself quite easily.
You can call Arjun now, son.
What if Bheem defeats Duryodhan?
And the subjects get robbed
of the opportunity to see Arjun.
Bheem will not win, father.
And Arjun?
He will not even reach here.
'Bheem.'
Duryodhan.
While fighting Bheem...
- I need no suggestion
or advice.
The day I get defeated by him
it will be
the last day of my life.
Go on, my dear.
Go on.
Mother, I knew it all along.
Only brother Bheem can compete
against brother Duryodhan.
Now, let's see how brother Bheem
crushes brother Duryodhan's
vanity.
Kunti.
Why is the earth trembling?
Bheem has entered
the arena, sister-in-law.
All hail Prince Bheem!
Your Majesty, among Prince Bheem
and Prince Duryodhan
the former seems more
proficient. - Be quiet, Sanjay!
All hail Prince Bheem!
Your majesty!
This competition will make
a mockery out of us before all.
The fear evident in the princes
is scaring the subjects.
Order this to end right now.
In other words, you mean to say
that without even giving
others the opportunity
Should I declare
Duryodhan the winner?
No, grandsire.
That would be unrighteous.
It is important to give
one chance to all the princes.
The winner will be declared
only at sunset, grandsire.
Your Majesty, Prince Duryodhan's
forehead is bleeding.
Prince Bheem has broken
a rule of the competition
your Majesty.
- Splendid.
Now, it will not be unrighteous
to declare Duryodhan the winner.
Sound the conch shells.
Stop!
Bheem, stop!
Bheem...
Bheem!
You have violated the rules
of the competition.
Who said I was competing,
teacher?
I have been blessed
by the great Vasuki
and I was just giving him
a taste of that boon.
And of the things that will
happen to him in the future
this was just a slice.
The glory of winning
the competition
can be garnered only by Arjun.
The winner of this competition
is Prince Duryodhan!
All hail Prince Duryodhan!
Do not be sad, Bheem.
Someone is bound to lose
in a competition.
I am sad, brother Yudhishthir.
Upon reaching here,
I had the thought
that if I ripped
Duryodhan's head from his neck
then what would have happened.
I'd have been just disqualified
from the competition.
But you are not more intelligent
than me, brother.
Brother, I was just...
'Arjun.'
Premonition.
Did I not tell you, Nakul?
The premonition of victory.
That time has come.
Brother Arjun is on his way.
Now, the next to enter the arena
is Prince Arjun of the Pandavas!
All hail Prince Arjun!
Even a 'gadaa'* is useless before Arjun's arrows.
*Bludgeon.
He is neither hot-headed
like Bheem
nor is he a saint
like Yudhishthir.
The one who scared me
since the beginning
was no one but Arjun.
My dear, that problem
has been taken care of.
'The doorway to the arena
that you shall construct'
'should collapse
at the correct time'
'with just one arrow.'
You wish to drop that structure
of the doorway, do you not, son?
So that the doorway
collapses on Arjun?
Give me that.
Let me do it for you.
My disciple is on his way.
Arjun.
Arjun!
All hail Prince Arjun!
- My son.
Arjun.
- All hail Prince Arjun!
All hail Prince Arjun!
Brother Arjun is victorious even
before engaging in the fight.
You must be wondering, son
how he did not get
crushed under the debris.
He created a canopy
of arrows over his head.
He is Arjun.
All hail Prince Arjun!
We must now resort
to deception, uncle.
When it comes to deception,
it is
successful only when one has
personal limitations, my dear.
But I do not see
his limitations.
Then what do we do now?
If you do not have
the means to win
then it is wise to accept
defeat, my dear.