As long as you are
the King of Hastinapur
I shall serve you and
Hastinapur as a servant
and deem every word
of yours an order.
Every living moment of my life
will be spent in protecting you.
But today...
Today, you must
divide this kingdom.
And declare Yudhishthir King.
Give the sons of Pandu
just one opportunity
to lead a happy life, dear.
Just one opportunity...
As you say,
uncle.
Be seated on your throne.
Division of the Kuru kingdom!
How is that possible?
Maybe it is their way of ousting
the son of Pandu, Yudhishthir
and keeping him from becoming
the King of Hastinapur.
That is why, by giving
him another kingdom
they are driving him
away from the state.
In other words,
Hastinapur will now be ruled
by the sons of Dhritarashtra!
I will leave Hastinapur
and reside in the new city.
But how can we leave?
Our entire world belongs here.
The ones who can leave with
the sons of Pandu are fortunate.
We would truly be fortunate
when we get to see Crown Prince
Yudhishthir become the King.
Hear all!
The son of Pandu and the
Kuru dynasty's daughter-in-law
the daughter of Drupad,
Panchali
are making their entrance!
My dear
I do not see joy on your face.
What should I
rejoice for, uncle?
That old geyser made
Yudhishthir King
and crushed my dreams
of becoming one forever.
When did I ask you
to experience joy?
But you must pretend,
my dear.
If you pretend to be happy
then you will also find
the reason to rejoice.
Greetings,
His Highness!
Son of Pandu,
Yudhishthir
you may present your proposal
to His Highness now.
If those people are given
the fertile region near
the bank of the Ganges, uncle
then I will break
the peace treaty
and attack that region
tomorrow itself.
Calm down, my dear.
Calm down.
I keep telling you...
The ones who walk on
the path of righteousness
are the most susceptible
to unrighteous ploys.
Just wait and watch.
May the Kuru King
be victorious!
Your Highness, I,
the son of Pandu, Yudhishthir
by respecting your wishes
accept a portion
of the Kuru kingdom
as a part of the treaty.
Allow me to be crowned
the King, Your Highness.
You have my permission,
Yudhishthir.
But
before you are crowned the King,
you must tell me
which region of the Kuru kingdom
you wish to have.
Excluding the city of Hastinapur
you may ask for any other region
of the Kuru kingdom
but its expanse...
Its expanse
should not be more than
half of the Kuru kingdom.
Go ahead and ask,
Yudhishthir.
What do you want?
Your Highness
numerous regions
were made prosperous
with your labour
and if I am made the King
of any of those regions
then it would not
denote my valour.
While transferring
his property to his son
a father feels overjoyed
but when a son
earns his property
through hard work and labour
his father is left ecstatic.
You are like my father,
Your Highness.
I wish to inherit your
strength and competence
and not property.
That is why,
Your Highness
we brothers have decided
that with your permission
we would like to go
to Khandavprastha
and build a new city there.
My dear
did you find the reason
to rejoice now?
Dear Yudhishthir
you do not know about
Khandavprastha.
I know,
grandsire.
The Yaduvanshi King
Sudarshan, had his kingdom
there many years ago.
Lord Indra once
cursed that kingdom
which made all the water
there to dry up.
It was even robbed of the rains.
The buildings of that city
were destroyed by the King of
Kashi with Lord Indra's help.
And the region
was left desolate.
We have taken
an oath, grandsire
that we will
salvage that region.
And try our best to augment the
prestige of the Kuru kingdom.
You will not be able to,
Yudhishthir.
The woods near that region
are home to a small clan
of serpent worshippers.
But they are venomous beings.
The beings there
are against humans.
Their leader is an illusory
serpent called Dakshak
and any human who
goes to Khandavprastha
gets killed by him for he
has taken such an oath.
No human will go with you
to reside over there.
You cannot succeed
in this endeavour.
The basis of success
is the blessing of
one's father, grandsire.
If we have
your blessings with us
then we shall certainly
be successful.
That is a foolish decision,
Yudhishthir!
Your Highness
I have selected a few regions
which comprise half
the Kuru kingdom.
Giving the sons of Pandu
those regions would be correct
and just as well.
Impossible,
His Excellency!
Yudhishthir must have thought
about it before making the plea.
And fulfilling his plea
is my duty, Your Excellency.
Dear Yudhishthir
I give you one lakh* gold coins
*100.000.
and one lakh cows
for establishing your city.
In the Kuru kingdom,
whichever subject
is ready to leave with you
out of his own free will
has my permission to do so.
What kind of a decision is that?
Yudhishthir
I declare you the independent
King of Khandavprastha!
But do remember, dear.
There is a tradition
of the Aryan region...
Until more than 100 Kings
accept you as a stronger
ruler than themselves
you will not be deemed
an independent King.
You will be an independent King
only for the sake of it.
Your kingdom will have
no flag of its own.
Any oath of office
in your kingdom
will be taken only in the name
of the throne of Hastinapur.
And all the official documents
will be in the name
of Hastinapur as well.
Revered Kripacharya
do begin the crowning
ceremony of Yudhishthir.
As you say,
Your Highness.
May this gold crown represent
your fame,
Prestige
prosperity,
competence
valour and all your rights.
May it adorn the head of
the King of Khandavprastha
the son of Pandu,
Yudhishthir for ages to come!
All hail King Yudhishthir!
- My darling
just wait and watch
the splendid plan
I came up with
to ensure your safety.
Dear Yudhishthir
your kingdom is now
independent of Hastinapur.
And I have firm faith
that no region of Hastinapur
will be eyed by you any longer.
In order to augment
the boundaries of your kingdom
you will never attack
Hastinapur, dear.
In order to multiply the
property of your kingdom
the property of Hastinapur
will never be snatched by you.
I promise you,
uncle
that I shall always remember
that my uncle Dhritarashtra
aunt Gandhari
uncle Vidur
and beloved Duryodhan
reside in this kingdom.
This is also the residence
of your mother Kunti, dear.
Do not forget that.
What do you mean?
Kunti is the daughter-in-law
of the Kuru dynasty.
After the demise of my
beloved younger brother Pandu
it is my duty
to keep her safe, dear.
Kunti will stay here.
With Gandhari
and in her security.
And this is not an order
of a cruel King
Kunti!
Your brother-in-law
and sister-in-law
are merely making
a humble request.