The Gods have showered their
blessings upon us, King Drupad.
In exchange for our merits
they have blessed you
with a son.
It is now time
to obtain the great blessing
which is a part of your destiny.
For the birth of your daughter
make the sacrifices,
Your Highness!
I am not a fool, great sage.
I wanted a son
and I have got one.
Now, I do not wish
to sacrifice anything.
Let's go, son.
Stop! King Drupad!
The maiden born
from this 'yajna'
is the fate of the Aryan region!
You must accept her!
No woman can ever be
a person's fate, great sage.
A father never obtains
anything from his daughter.
Let's go, son.
You are a fool, Drupad!
One obtains love
from one's daughter!
One obtains respect
One obtains righteousness
from one's daughter!
Do not forget, King Drupad
that a son bestows only
his family with righteousness!
But a daughter blesses
the future generations
and the entire world
with righteousness!
All that is good in the world
is obtained only from
a daughter, Drupad!
The wrath of the Gods
is increasing, Drupad!
Do not be foolish!
Come back for the 'yajna!'
Stop, Drupad!
You will not be able to leave
this 'yajna' incomplete!
And the Gods will not
permit you to leave.
What will the Gods give me
by forcing me
to make a sacrifice?!
What will they give me?!
Then I shall make a sacrifice!
Do the Gods wish to bless
the entire world through me?!
Then I
ask for lifelong struggle
for my daughter!
I ask for pain!
What are you asking for,
Drupad?!
How can you ask for pain
for your own daughter?!
Why not?
With pain and struggles does
the best of character get built!
May her character be as pure and fair as this 'abeer.'*
*A dye (dry powder) from flower extracts.
May she have all the
impurities of the world!
Yet the world
must deem her pure!
Can the Gods give me
such a daughter?!
Like this wheat,
may she have the strength
to give courage to others!
May she keep facing situations
that can damage the morale
of any person.
Yet she must remain courageous
and give courage to others.
Can the Gods give me
such a daughter?!
This 'gulaal'* never changes its colour!
*Colored powder solutions thrown during Holi/the festival of colors or the festival of love.
May she have
such steadfast valour.
Can I get such a daughter?!
Nothing is more beautiful in the world than this 'kumkum'* here.
*Powder used for social and religious markings--made from turmeric or saffron.
Just like this 'kumkum,'
may my daughter
be the most beautiful woman
in this world!
And may she reflect
the beauty of others as well.
Can the Gods give me
such a daughter?!
These flowers here...
When flowers are crushed,
they emit fragrance.
May she face injustice
time and again!
Yet she must spread
the fragrance of justice!
Can the Gods give me
such a daughter?
To carry out the wishes
of the Gods
is why this maiden
has been born, Drupad!
Take good care of her!
You have never had anything
precious like her before
and neither will you ever have!
King Drupad
this maiden will change
the future of the Aryan region.
She will create a new history!
This is your daughter, Drupad!
The Gods have named her Krishna.*
*One of darker complexion.
Since she is born from a 'yajna'
she shall be called Yajnaseni!
The world will remember you
by her name!
She shall be called Draupadi!
Bless you!
With the brilliance
of fire on the face
with the heat of fire
in the breath
and with the purity of fire
in the heart was born
your daughter, father.
I place the boon of the Gods
at your feet.