Here, master
rest your head on my thighs
and continue to rest.
Karna
I am habitual of taking rest
on stones and rocks.
You're habituated, master,
but it's not a necessity.
Give me a chance to serve you.
Please come.
Forgive me, master.
This...
This bug bit me
and I bled
hence your sleep
was disturbed.
Forgive me, master.
Oh, God!
Such a deep cut!
Such severe pain!
Yet you didn't move!
You stayed firm!
No!
Who are you?
I...
I am your disciple, master.
- Impossible!
Only a Brahman can be
my disciple.
And you, undoubtedly,
are not a Brahman.
Had you been a Brahman
such patience
and so much tolerance
wouldn't have been your traits.
Tell me honestly.
Who are you?
I...
I'm not a Brahman, master.
I'm the son of a Suta.
But you had told me
that you're a Brahman.
You lied to me?
You cheated me!
The truth has always
humiliated me, master.
Had I told you
that I'm not a Brahman
but a Suta
then I'd have returned
disappointed again.
You fool
you have committed
a very big mistake.
If you had shared your
pain with me
then I would have definitely
sent you to a qualified teacher.
Karna
I am not
an opposer of caste
or lineage.
I had
sworn to teach only Brahmans.
My grandfather sage Rucheeka,
all his life
taught people of all lineages
the veneration of Lord Shiva.
If you had said
the truth, dear...
If you had taken
the path of truth
then you would have
definitely been benefitted.
Karna
how could you forget
that lies
are synonymous
with a weak nous?
And no form of education
in the world
gives results
to weaklings, dear.
Not at all!
Just like the leaves of
some trees
do sway in
the warmth of the sun
but wither off during
the winters...
Karna
in the same manner
a weak person's knowledge
gets destroyed at
the time of a test.
It is of no use to him.
This is not a curse, dear.
It is a reality!
The truth of life!
Go, Karna!
There will be a point
in your life
when it will be the moment of
the biggest test in your life
and at that very
moment
your knowledge
will leave your side.
It will disappear.
It will not be of
any use to you.
Lord Parashuram
I regret being unaware
of your generosity.
God does not differentiate
unlike the common man
and I couldn't comprehend it.
I weighed God against
the common man.
It was my mistake.
These words, that are a
result of your disappointment...
I accept them as your
sacrament, master.
Won't you
bless your disciple, Lord?
Your struggle
and your mistake
both in the times to come
will guide many a youth.
This is my blessing, dear.
May you have a long life.
'Near Hastinapur.'
'Before the princes' return
from the seminary.'
Go tell the king of
Gandhar Shakuni
that Guru Drona's son
Ashwatthama has come.
With the message of
Prince Duryodhan.
Your Highness
Guru Drona's son is here.
He wishes to meet you.
Greetings to Shakuni,
the King of Gandhar.
Marvellous!
You have applied ashes
on your body
and carry weapons too.
My past is that of a Brahman,
and my future that of a king.
Hence I prepare myself for
protecting both
my body and my soul.
This means, master Dronacharya
has conspired to shake off
the political condition of
the Arya dynasty.
Which state is it?
With time, even that shall be
revealed, Your Highness.
But right now, the question
is not about me
but my friend, Duryodhan.
Duryodhan said
'You had promised the throne
of Hastinapur, uncle.'
'Do you remember that or...'
My child!
I remember as well as
am determined for it.
Hence I have left Gandhar
and come here.
To Hastinapur.
For 12 years, one question
wouldn't let me sleep
that Guru Drona, when
starting his seminary
instead of imparting education
to the entire Arya dynasty
why did he find it appropriate
to educate
the princes of
only one lineage?
This complication is now
being resolved.
Only the Kuru princes will
get you a kingdom.
Which means your friendship
is not with Duryodhan
but with the throne
of Hastinapur.
Then I would have had
affection for Arjun.
My father too says that Arjun
will get me a kingdom.
Yes.
I have heard
that Arjun has become
a great archer.
But, Ashwatthama
the one who can get
you the kingdom
can snatch away
the kingdom too.
Hence in your heart
there should not be affection
towards Arjun but fear.
Don't you have faith on
my friendship?
I do.
But in order to make your and
dear Duryodhan's friendship
even more stronger
I am coating it with
greed and fear, both.
See, Ashwatthama
the biggest political setup
of the Aryan dynasty
is going to begin
here at Hastinapur.
Hence it is necessary that
everyone knows their roles.
Tomorrow, if your father
begins to have affection
for the Pandavas
or if he talks
about righteousness
then at that time, it will
be beneficial for you
to teach your father
the lesson of greed.
But for that, we will first have
to make Duryodhan the king.
You just mind your own business.
Leave the rest to me.
Duryodhan's enthronement
will definitely take place.
At any cost.
At any cost!
Time had once defeated
me in my life.
Since then
I have always walked
ahead of the times.
How will I be able to recognise
the footsteps of my son
My lord?
When our sons had gone
to the seminary
they were children.
I have never seen
their faces.
Yet I could recognise
their every step.
Whenever Duryodhan
would enter the room
I could say whether he is
happy or sad.
Duryodhan would have
changed a lot, right?
Of course!
Definitely my Duryodhan would
have changed, Gandhari.
Now
his walk shall have
the dignity of a king.
And when one walks
with prestige
the earth recognises
that glorious footfall
and produces a sound
deserving of him.
Shakuni!
But there's only one question,
Your Highness.
Does the earth know
that the footsteps
that lay on it
are those that exude authority
or ambition?
In order to welcome Duryodhan
the sound that needs to be...
What if the earth
emanates the same upon
Yudhishthir's arrival?
Since the time of the return
of my dear nephews
is getting closer
I also came here.
Greetings, Your Highness.
I did not understand
the meaning
of your question.
The meaning of my question
remains the same
as it was 12 years ago,
Your Highness.
Capability!
The time to test capability is
getting closer, Your Highness.
And in order to prove dear
Duryodhan incapable...
There are many people
sitting alert
in Hastinapur's palace,
Your Highness.
Brother!
Don't make the arrival of
princes a political affair.
Politics!
I won't, dear sister.
But tell the same thing to
His Excellency Bhishm
and Chief Minister Vidur.
Because, definitely
by now
they would have begun to make
this a political affair.
Before the arrival
of the princes
Guru Drona will arrive to
meet His Highness.
Definitely,
His Excellency Bhishm
and Chief Minister Vidur
will ask him questions
on capability.
What is the solution?
There's only one solution,
Your Highness.
You yourself make capability
an important issue.
Attention!
King Dhritarashtra
is arriving!
Long live King Dhritarashtra!
Welcome to Hastinapur,
King of Gandhar.
On having met
you again
my heart feels at peace
Chief Minister.
Please have a seat.
'Are you'
'exiling me from
Hastinapur, Your Excellency?'
'It is considered appropriate'
'that a king stays
in his kingdom.'
'And the courage
to disobey my orders'
'does not lie
in Gandhar.'
'Leave!'