This is 'Lakshagraha.'
A 'yajna' will be
conducted there. A 'yajna!'
And in that 'yajna'
that palace will be used
as the sacrifice, friend.
And my enemies
will burn to ashes
in that 'yajna!'
Not only your enemies,
Prince Duryodhan
but also the competence
of this friend of yours
your respect,
the glory of your ancestors
and even the righteousness
of Hastinapur
will burn to ashes.
What are you saying, friend?
Why are you unhappy
on this joyous occasion?
Pardon me, Prince Duryodhan
but it will be a truly
joyous occasion for me
when my arrows will crush
the head of my enemy
and my enemy's arrows will
cut right through my chest.
Beheading an enemy
who is sleeping
is like chopping down the tree
of righteousness, friend.
This is the difference between
a murderer and a hero.
Righteousness?
Righteousness!
Do not ramble on about
righteousness, King of Anga.
There is only one form of
righteousness in the world...
Victory!
Because only victors
create history.
And the traditions
mentioned in history
assume the form of righteousness
down the road.
Lie!
Righteousness is something
that nurtures the possibilities
and capabilities of a person.
Any task that weakens
the soul of man
cannot be righteousness, friend.
In other words, do you have
a soft corner for the Pandavas
now, King of Anga?
King of Anga, did you forget
who made you King?
Foolish Dusshasan!
Be quiet!
My friend
is correct.
If any task of mine
is hurting my friend
then I shall not perform it.
Have Purochan
informed right away!
The plan has been cancelled!
Brother Duryodhan...
- No more arguments!
The plan has been cancelled.
Friend Karna
your happiness is more
valuable to me.
If you do not want me
to become the Crown Prince
and the King in the future
then I shall
renounce my royal life.
I desire to make you a glorious
emperor, Prince Duryodhan.
I am against deception.
I am not against a battle.
Battle? With whom shall
I engage in a battle?
With my father?
With my grandsire?
With my uncle Vidur?
Even if I win in that situation
it will be deemed
my defeat, friend.
In the battle,
will I behead my father
or will he behead me, friend?
Just answer this question
of mine, friend.
They have deceived us.
They are the unrighteous ones,
friend Karna.
They have given rise
to such a situation, friend
where I will have to either
resort to unrighteousness
OT
Give up my right.
Friend Karna
the way a person who
snatches the right of another
is sentenced to a life in hell
similarly, falling prey
to weakness
a person who gives up
his right is also
sentenced to a life
in hell, friend.
Pertaining to the topic
of Duryodhan's right
if you have any doubt,
King of Anga
then do speak up now.
No.
I do not doubt it.
Then do show me the way, friend.
Show me the middle path.
Do come back soon, Kunti.
I shall await you.
Certainly, sister-in-law.
Goodbye, brother-in-law.
Bless you.
Goodbye, Her Highness.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, uncle.
- May you live long.
May you live long.
Yudhishthir
one must never impede
the journey of a pilgrim.
That is why,
I am not stopping you.
But the decision of
staying out of Hastinapur
is not a very wise one
at the moment.
All of you
need to be back soon.
Certainly, grandsire.
Staying away from Hastinapur
for too long
will not be easy for us either.
My concern for this place
will keep me wide awake.
Your departure
will rob Hastinapur
of its prosperity, My Lady.
Goodbye, brother.
You need not worry
one bit for Hastinapur.
No, Duryodhan.
I am not worried
about Hastinapur.
The Almighty himself chalks out
the happiness of subjects.
One needs to worry about people
because the Almighty
protects a person only when
he upholds righteousness.
In other words
we are worried about you,
Duryodhan.
Very soon
the reason of your worry
will come to an end,
brother Bheem.
Be happy.
May glory be yours.
King of Anga
may you never deter from
the path of righteousness.
This is the only blessing
I can give you.
Unrighteousness is like mercury
that robs gold of its lustre.
'Dwaraka.'
In such a short time span
I have acquired so much
from you, Madhav.
The one who has the
mental state to grasp things
only he can acquire
something, friend.
You will come across the
Triveni Confluence on your way.
Do bathe in it.
There
lies the Lost River Saraswati.
While bathing
do think of the tale of
Goddess Saraswati getting lost
in that river.
But I have not
heard of this tale.
It is said that
Goddess Saraswati
could not walk on earth bearing
the holy fire on her palm.
That is why
she began migrating
into the earth.
If you think of this tale
while bathing
you will earn
good fortune, friend.
As you say.