Brother Balaram!*
*Krishna's older brother, and so Arjun's cousin.
Aren't you Arjun?
Greetings, Bahrain!
Bless you.
Charioteer,
proceed in that direction!
Arjun!
Don't stop Rukmi.
Let him realize his destiny.
Faster!
Krishna!
Stop!
Stop fleeing like a thief!
Stop and fight me!
Welcome!
Welcome, brother-in-law Rukmi
and do accept my greetings
for the second time.
You scoundrel! Rukmini was
to marry Prince Shishupal!
Aren't you ashamed to run away
with someone else's property?
Goddess Lakshmi blesses
people with property
but she isn't
a property herself.
Similarly, every woman is the
embodiment of Goddess Lakshmi.
A woman has the power to
bless people with property.
Quit rambling, Krishna!
Pick up your weapon!
Why do you wish
to be defeated, Rukmi?
Go back and convey
to the King of Vidarbha
that his daughter and son-in-law
have sent their greetings.
Rukmini!
I order you to
get in my chariot!
No, brother. Henceforth,
all the roads of my life
lead to Dwaraka.
Pardon me, brother.
- Rukmini!
If you don't come along with me,
I will take your corpse with me!
Brother, I am now
in the shelter of Krishna.
Now, Lord Yama* himself cannot kill me.
*God of death.
Quit being stubborn
and go back, brother.
Listen to your sister, Rukmi.
Go back.
- Rukmini
you have insulted your brother
because of that man.
But he shall not
be with you forever!
You and he will be separated!
Do remember! You shall
certainly get separated!
Did you feel nothing
in your heart
while uttering such harsh
words about your sister?
I shall kill you for this
impudence of yours!
No, My Lord!
He is my brother.
Please don't kill him, My Lord.
But I shall
certainly punish him.
Greetings, Madhav.
What do you plan to do next?
- Plan?
My plan is quite simple, friend.
On the coast of Saurashtra
lies the city of Madhavpur
where Rukmini and I
are to be married.
We shall get married there
and after that...
After that, righteousness
will be re-established in India
unrighteous people will be slain
and the entire Aryan region
will be gifted with happiness.
That's it.
And will your marriage
accomplish all this, Madhav?
If not mine but yours might
just accomplish it, friend.
But you should be
prepared for it.
The course of time
can change because of you.