There should indeed be a war,
Grandsire.
I do not approve of this war.
Grandsire Bheeshma
is right indeed.
Nothing can be more unfortunate
than war, my lad.
Uncle!
- But...
A clever human is the one
who always strives to ensure
there is no war in his yard.
If today there is no war
in Virat's yard
in future,
in the yard
of Hastinapur
there shall be an epic battle.
Grandsire Bheeshma.
At that time, you shall be
the commander in chief.
And at the blade of your sword
shall lie the heads
of the Pandavas.
Are you here to destroy
Hastinapur,
Lord of Gandhar?
Me?
Do you think I am here
to destroy?
I am here
just to
fulfill your word,
Grandsire Bheeshma.
You had arrived to Gandhar.
You had my beloved sister
betrothed
with a promise
that you shall make her
the empress of Hastinapur
and that her hundred sons
will be the rulers
of Hastinapur.
That you shall make them
the sovereign rulers.
How badly could the promise
made by you fail
Grandsire Bheeshma.
If an elephant's foot
comes into a crocodile's grasp
it causes a huge dilemma
to the crocodile
Grandsire Bheeshma.
It can neither devour
the colossal elephant
nor can it spare the elephant.
Now, it is my request to you
Grandsire Bheeshma.
Either crown my dear lad
Duryodhan
as the sovereign ruler
or, because of you
Hastinapur shall face
annihilation.
Please come forth,
revered commander in chief.
The fortress of Virat
awaits to be destroyed
by your hands.
'Bahika'.*
*Madra was a part of the Bahika/Vahika or Madra was Vahika country, at current central parts of Punjab — between river Chenab and Ravi.
Your majesty.
A vast army has laid siege
to the northern gate.
All our forces must go
for the defence of Virat.
I shall lead the charge.
- Your Majesty!
Even I will participate.
My Lord, please do not
participate in the battle yet.
If I feel I am losing the battle
I shall send you a message.
No, Your Majesty.
I cannot stand back.
My Lord, someone has to stay to
defend the fortress from within.
Arjun shall stay in the fortress
to defend women and children.
Because he cannot charge
into battle guised as a woman.
Won't I participate in the war?
What mockery is this,
elder brother?
Bheem is right, Arjun.
You must stay
within the fortress.
But...
Arjun. If Duryodhan sees
a woman in the battlefield
he shall surely doubt.
Let us go, My Lord.
My brothers and I
are ready for
the defence of Virat.
Please come.
Soldiers!
Defend your Kingdom.
Charge!
Please give our forces
the orders to charge
Commander in chief.
Virat has not yet shown any sign
of defence,
King of Gandhar.
If King Virat won't arm himself
how could we attack them?
But the preliminary attack
on the fortresses has begun
Grandsire.
How can there be an attack
without my orders
king of Gandhar?
Who ordered it?
Only the army of Hastinapur
takes orders from you
My Lord.
And I didn't order the attack.
The attack was made by King Susharman of Trigartha.*
*Modern Kangra district, the territory around the three rivers of Satluj, Beas, and Ravi.
Please give the orders
for the attack, My Lord.
Grandsire!
Greetings My Queen.
A vast army led by Hastinapur
has attacked the southern gate.
An attack from the other side?
But there is no one in
the fortress who can defend it.
Who shall go forth
for retaliation?
Forgive me, My Queen.
But Prince Uttar
is inside the fortress.
And it is the duty of the prince
to retaliate to this attack.
Yes!
I shall charge into the battle.
How is that possible?
Uttar is still very young.
He has no experience in battle.
No! No!
He cannot charge
into the battle.
Excuse me, My Queen.
But the son of a king cannot be
exempted from his duty.
I do not wish to be exempted,
either.
I am eager for battle, mother.
Be quiet!
Brihannala is neither a man,
nor a woman.
How would a eunuch know the
gravity of politics and battle?
My Queen.
There is no need
to insult Brihannala.
Brihannala handled the reins
of Prince Arjun's chariot.
And has faced many battles.
And even now, I am ready to be
the rider of Prince Uttar's
chariot.
Before any weapon
lays a scratch on Prince Uttar
It shall have to go through me.
This is my promise.
I shall instill the son of
the great warrior King Virat
with bravery
and not cowardice.
But will a woman
drive my chariot?
If that happens
all shall mock me.
But when your weapons
slay them
you shall be the one
laughing at them, Prince.
Come.
But, Brihannala.
Grandsire Bheeshma
is at the forefront.
What if he comes to know
of who the chariot rider is?
I do not fear
Grandsire Bheeshma.
And Prince Duryodhan
cannot recognise me before dusk.
Just a few hours remain
for my exile to come to an end.
Where are the Pandavas, uncle?
Why aren't they showing up?
It shall be dusk soon!
We do not have much time, uncle!
Did I not tell you, my lad?
The righteous ones
can witness treachery
but cannot commit it.
Look over there!
The Pandavas have arrived!
Uncle.
Look at this!
The prince of Virat is here
under a woman's protection.
He is a lad, Dushyasan.
Yet he has arrived for battle.
But those five Pandavas
have still not arrived
for battle.
They must be hiding
as a rat hides in a burrow.
Blow the conch, my lad.
They are hiding somewhere
inside Virat.
Arjun!
Come out!
Let go of your safety
and protect your honour.
Even Karna must be arriving
in order to slay you!
Come out!
With your bow, the 'Gandiva'!
Prince Uttar, pick up your bow!
Shoot arrows how I instruct you.
I shall not let anything
happen to you.
Pick up your bow!
Shoot, Prince!
Shoot the arrow!
Shoot, Prince Uttar!
Shoot the arrow, Prince Uttar!
Uncle, this lad must be slain!
If this prince dies
maybe those five Pandavas
shall show themselves.
Before the sun sets
we must drive them out.
Very well, my lad.
Grandsire Bheeshma!
Order our forces to attack!
I do not attack women,
king of Gandhar.
Only when a warrior arrives
shall my army charge forth
and my weapons will unsheathe.
Prepare for battle, prince!
Only a few moments remain.
I shall not let you be harmed.
- No, Brihannala!
I cannot fight
these warriors
and this vast army.
Protect me, Brihannala!
Steer the chariot
back to the fortress.
If you wish to be
a strong warrior
of the likes of prince Arjun
first learn to stand your ground
in the battlefield.
Raise your bow,
shoot an arrow!
You say Arjun is
a great warrior?
A warrior who is hiding
inside the fortress.
They claim that the Pandavas
are hiding in our fortress.
Then why won't they
come forth to protect us.
Protection is acquired by those
who dare to raise
their weapons first.
Prince Uttar,
raise your weapons!
Just a few moments more!
- No, Brihannala!
I cannot do it!
Protect me, Brihannala!
Steer the chariot away
from here, Brihannala!
Go' prince!
Go!
Your father has given
refuge to the Pandavas.
Before the sun sets
send the Pandavas
out of these gates.
Or else, every citizen
within this fortress shall die.
Go!
Warn Arjun!
Brihannala!
Why did you bring
the chariot here?
Steer it back into the fortress.
Brihannala!
Oh Fire God!
Today, it shall be a year
to my exile.
Today I am free to turn into
Arjun from Brihannala.
But today my mettle
shall be put to test as well.
And without your grace
this devotee of yours
is incomplete.
Please return my 'Gandiva' bow
and grace me, O' Lord!