'Guru Drona!'
Who are you?
- Eklavya.
Are you a tribal?
Do you come from the forest?
Have you come from
a different state?
And from whom did you learn
such extraordinary archery?
The one who has been
teaching you, prince.
Guru Drona!
That's a lie!
Child, I never accepted
you as my student.
Who are you?
Greetings, Sire.
I am the son of Nishaad, the
king of the forests of Magadha
Eklavya.
I secretly listen to your
teachings throughout the day
and practice the same
during the night
in front of your statue here.
How is that possible?
No one can call his ordinary
skills as a gift from me
and insult me.
Before calling me
your Guru
one has to prove his eligibility
to become my student.
Sire...
Whatever I have learnt till now
with your blessings
will prove my eligibility.
What have you learnt?
Ashwathama, my friend
two stones of the same
size and strength
what happens when they
collide with each other?
Both would break.
Have you understood anything?
He is the answer to Arjun.
Knowledge can be acquired
only by dedication.
All of us know that.
But what is the actual
importance of dedication?
Have we ever thought about it?
A human mind
always faces obstacles in the
process of acquiring knowledge.
Sometimes a student is jealous
of another student.
Sometimes one doubts
the teachings.
And sometimes the punishment
given by a teacher
fills the mind with fury.
No? Doesn't that happen?
Several thoughts
distract the mind.
And due to such an
unstable state of mind
we are unable to
acquire knowledge.
A mind become stable
only with dedication.
Dedication destroys the
arrogance of a human being.
It eliminates feelings like
jealousy, ambition
it calms the heart and helps
the mind concentrate.
In reality
there is no limit for knowledge
in the creation of God
nor that of knowledgeable
people.
Guru Dattatray*
*A Hindu deity encompassing the trinity of Brahma, Vishnu and Shiva, collectively known as Trimurti. Teacher of Parashurama.
derived knowledge
from a cow and a dog.
In other words
whether it's about
spiritual knowledge
or knowledge about life
or the knowledge derived
at a hermitage
to acquire it
more than the teacher
our dedication towards
the teacher is more important.
Isn't that true?
Think about it.
'I am the son of Nishaad, the
king of the forests of Magadha'
'Eklavya.'
'And from whom did you learn
such extraordinary archery?'
'The one who has been
teaching you, prince.'
Witnessing Eklavya's
archery skills
Arjun's self confidence
has shattered.
Look at his state.
If the boy has become
so magnificent
in spite of watching
from a distance
then think
if he stays at the hermitage
and learns
what a great archer
he would become.
My Lord.
I have been observing
that after meeting
the boy from the forest
you seem to be in a dilemma.
You stopped eating and
sleeping altogether.
What is bothering you?
Right now, for me, justice
is injustice.
I am unable to
understand my duties.
Arjun, for the past two days
and two nights
you have been practicing
without rest.
Now stop it.
- No, brother.
Eklavya, just by sitting near
Guru Drona's statue
could learn everything
and I couldn't learn
anything in spite of staying
with Guru Drona.
Brother, I am sure there is
something lacking in my efforts.
Unless I do not acquire
knowledge like Eklavya
until then I will not
stop practicing.
Come on.
Come.
If Eklavya becomes our friend
we wouldn't need to
be scared of Arjun.
Dushasan is right.
He can become the commander
of our army.
Ashwathama, even if
Arjun practices all his life
the sons of Pandu
won't be stronger than us.
I will personally
speak to Eklavya.
But how can I stay
at Hastinapur?
My knowledge is for Magadha.
Sure. But to help your
friend for some time
I am sure you can
stay at Hastinapur.
Once I get the kingdom
you can go back to Magadha.
Sire!
Where is Guru Drona?
And if you promise
I'll request my father to give
you a place at the hermitage
My father always listens to
me, Eklavya.
Of course.
I agree to everything
my son says.
You have established me
as your Guru
so now, I have to accept
you as my student.
But dear, I have a question.
Would you be able to give
an offering to your teacher?
Absolutely, Sire.
I will give you
whatever you desire.
Until I do not make
an offering to you
I will not use the skills
I learned from you.
Right now...
You will have to give it
immediately.
Command me, Sire.
As an offering you will give me
the thumb of your right hand.
Would you be able to do that?
Your dedication
pleases me, dear.
Hereafter, you are my student.
Now you should leave
the land of Hastinapur
and return to Magadha.
Right now.
Your teacher commands you.