What happened, mother Kunti?
What happened, Kunti?
I do not know, sister-in-law
but
it feels as though
something very bad has happened.
Mother.
Mother, did brother Bhim
come this way?
No
but weren't all of you together?
We were but now he's not to
be seen around, mother.
I seem to be having
a premonition, mother.
Mother Kunti,
I had seen brother Bhim
going with brother Duryodhan.
But that was
quite a long time ago.
If he is with Duryodhan
then you need not be afraid.
He will be back.
I hope, nothing bad happened
with the two of them.
Sahadev, ask Arjun to go look
for the two of them.
Go on.
- Alright, mother.
Uncle!
Beloved Duryodhan, in order
to secure your place as the king
you have taken
the first step today.
Now, dump his dead body
in the river Ganges.
The dead bodies of people that
are submerged in the Ganges
go straight to heaven.
This is a popular belief.
Then is he
d-dead, uncle?
Why are you getting
so scared, dear?
Death comes to all.
Do remember.
A kingdom always thrives
upon a heap of dead bodies.
The greed for polity
engulfs every man's heart.
Every person makes an effort
to create a state of his own.
That state might be
as big as that of Kuru
or only limited to one's family.
Man always makes an effort
to gain foothold of polity.
But what is
the real form of polity?
Have we ever thought about it?
A person who influences
the lives of many people
and is able to curtail
the freedom of many
experiences more polity.
The real form of polity is one's
influence over another's life.
But is real influence
not made up of love,
kindness, compassion
and righteousness?
When man uses cruelty and
unrighteousness to gain polity
he gives birth to protest and
revolt in the hearts of others.
And the result...
The result
is somewhat like this.
Yes.
He may find himself influential
and powerful for some time
but that is not true polity.
This is the reason
why sages like Bhrigu
and Vashishth are still revered
but not Ravan
and Hiranyakashipu.
Do certainly give it a thought.
Am I correct?
When gold is excavated from
the ground, King Dhritarashtra
it is mixed with
various forms of impurities.
Similarly, when a student
comes to a teacher
the love of his parents
and the security of a home
cause arrogance, fear
and stubbornness
as the impurities to be in him.
When gold is subjected to fire
it first starts to emit smoke.
This smoke
is due to the burning
of the impurities within it.
When all vile traits
are reduced to nothing
and when dedication
is born within a student
only then does he
become a disciple.
Only then does he accept
his teacher as his guru.
A teacher imparts
only knowledge to a student
but a guru
by realising the possibilities
that lie within his student
makes him successful.
I am here to become
the guru of the princes.
And by gaining knowledge
from you
the Princes of the Kuru dynasty
will become the best warriors
of this world.
This is what the royal court
of the Kuru kingdom believes
son of Sage Bharadwaj Drona.
His Highness has only
one expectation from you
that you must teach only
the Princes of the Kuru dynasty.
I too wish the same.
But
there is just one condition.
My son Ashwatthama will also
learn along with the princes.
Because
a son learns constantly
from his father.
We accept this condition,
Dronacharya.
Very soon, near the borders
of Hastinapur
a hermitage with various
conveniences will be built.
You may reside there
with your family
and impart knowledge
to the Princes of Kuru.
Pardon me, Chief Minister.
But the hermitage will be built
miles away from Hastinapur.
Because a honey bee that
does not leave its nest behind
and travel far away from it
it is unable to gather honey.
I do not accept this condition,
sire.
The Princes of Kuru
will live in Hastinapur
and get their education.
Then accepting them
as my disciples
isn't possible for me,
Your Highness.
Before making a decision,
think about it, Dronacharya.
That past incident of your life
is something the entire kingdom
of Arya is familiar with.
Apart from Hastinapur, is there
a kingdom powerful enough
that can give you shelter?
My Past, my weight
are my gems, Your Highness!
And I have not come here with
the wish of seeking shelter.
I am in search of worthy princes
to whom I can give charity.
The most noble charity
in the world.
That of knowledge.
But if the Princes of Kuru
value their comfort
more than my knowledge
then I must go someplace else
and look for my disciples.
Allow me to leave.
Your Highness,
with your permission
I would like to see off
my brother-in-law to his abode.
He is my guest.
- Permission granted.
And Chief Minister
start looking
for another teacher at once.
The Princes of Kuru dynasty
have always been pure gold.
They need not be purified.
They merely need to be moulded.
Stop, Dronacharya.
Do not be stubborn.
You will not get such
a golden opportunity again.
Tell this to your king.
The event of the past
has made you stubborn
but to earn money for my sister
and her son is your duty.
For how long can a mixture
of rice flour and water
be considered as milk and
consumed by my nephew?
I am well aware of my son
and wife's discomfort
Kripacharya.
You need not remind me of it.
I had knowingly
accepted this poverty.
And very soon, I shall acquire
immense wealth as well.
And the path to that
is through these steps.
In order to climb the steps
of the palace of Hastinapur
many Brahmins and Kshatriyas
are ever ready.
The one who can fearlessly
descend these steps
has the right
to ascend them as well.
You need not worry
because a guru
chooses his disciples.
A disciple is not wise enough
to choose his guru.
And I have chosen my disciples.
The Princes of Kuru
will become only my disciples.
Brother Bhim?
Search for son of Pandu, Bhim
till the boundaries
of the region of Arya!
Go to the farthest ends
of the earth if you have to!
Search for Prince Bhim
at the cost of your lives!
Go!
My son...
Where is he, Maha Kaal?*
*The destroyer of one who destroys i.e annihilator (Shiva).
Answer me!
How can you let a woman
suffer the fate
of losing her child?
My tears
will submerge
the entire universe.
My son...
Return him to me.
Return my Bhim to me.
Lord Vayu!* Where are you?
*The Lord of the winds, the father of Bhima.
You had promised me
that you shall
always protect my son.
He is a part of you.
Protect him, Lord!
Protect him.