I cannot wish
for your victory, brother.
I am
on your opponent's side now.
Pardon me.
By giving us your
unparalleled Narayani Army
you have shown us the path
to victory, Vasudev.
Now,
even if
you do not wish for our victory
we will
not blame you.
King of Gandhar
the way the strength of a bow
lies with the archer
similarly the strength of
an army lies with its General.
The Narayani Army is indeed
a superlative one in the world
but in the absence
of an exceptional General
even the Narayani Army can fail.
We would never worry
about that, Mighty Balaram.
We have
Maharathi Bhishma with us
as our General.
Until you have
His Excellency Bhishma with you
there is no need for the
Narayani Army, King of Gandhar.
But after His Excellency
gets slain
who will lead the Narayani Army
as its General?
Slaying grandsire Bhishma
is impossible,
Vasudev
because he has been
blessed with the boon
to die at will.
Brother
the result of a war
cannot be predetermined
like a game of dice.
Even His Excellency
can die.
That is not possible,
Vasudev.
Without using treachery
His Excellency Bhishma
cannot be killed.
Besides,
the side you have chosen
is a righteous one.
You cannot use treachery.
That depends upon the definition
of treachery, King of Gandhar.
Lord Ram was hiding
behind a tree
when he attacked Bali,
the King of the Monkeys.
You seemed to have
forgotten that, King of Gandhar.
And in order to slay
Dashanan Ravan
his brother Vibhishan
was approached for help.
If righteousness is
at the core of treachery
then even treachery
can be righteous
King of Gandhar.
In other words
you will engage in treachery
Vasudev?
Indeed.
In this war
the Pandavas
will emerge victorious
by any means possible.
Maharathi Bhishma
Guru Drona
and King Karna of Anga
will indeed be slain
and that too by using treachery.
If there is
a way to safeguard
all three of them
then go ahead and find it.
Panchali
the time to punish
your offenders has been set.
The date mentioned by you
in this letter
will be the day
the great war begins.
The great war had begun
the very day, My Lord
when the thought of
a game of dice had stemmed
in the mind of
the King of Gandhar.
On that day
the reign of unrighteousness
will come to an end.
The one 'akshauhini'
Narayani Army of Dwaraka
will battle for us,
father.
We now have
ten 'akshauhini' armies with us
while the Pandavas
have a maximum
of only
seven 'akshauhini' armies.
They have
the great Yadava Krishna
with them
son Duryodhan.
Even without the aid of an army
he had defeated Jarasandha
destroyed Kalyavan
and slayed
King Kansa of Mathura.
He...
And Shri Krishna is miraculous,
Your Highness.
The entire Aryan region
resonates of the tale
of how he had straightened
Trivakra's crooked back.
He had slayed
the female ogre Putana
when he was only six-months-old.
These are false tales,
Minister.
Merely false tales.
Who has seen
these so-called miracles?
Do not forget,
Duryodhan
that in this very court
Vasudev Krishna had defended
the honour of Drupad's daughter.
When Krishna
was not present here
how could he have
defended her, grandsire?
The daughter of Drupad
was born of fire, grandsire.
She is an illusory being.
How can someone be born of fire?
She must indeed be an ogre.
But we fear no one
and by spreading
such false tales
do not demonstrate
your fear,
grandsire.
Fear?
We fear for you,
Crown Prince.
You hope to win
with the aid of the army
but you seem to be forgetting
that if the entire army
of the crows
catches even a glimpse of Garuda
then the entire army
will flee from the battlefield.
The Garuda you are
talking about, Minister
has relinquished his beak
and claws voluntarily.
Vasudev will not
take to arms in this war
and everyone knows this.
Pardon me but now is
not the time to get scared
by thinking of the competence
of the enemy.
In fact, it is time for us
to examine our competence
and augment our self-confidence
because self-confidence
is the basis of competence.
Fear and apprehension are
vital for survival, dear Karna.
Be calm.
Before the war
it is necessary to examine
every viewpoint.
Every viewpoint...
But the Pandavas have
already challenged us to a war
Your Highness.
But the Pandavas have
already challenged us to a war
Your Highness.
They have even decided
the date of the war.
They...
They decided the date!
They decided the date...
The Pandavas seek an answer
from you, Your Highness.
Wage a war
or seek their refuge.
Seeking their refuge is out
of the question, friend Karna.
It is impossible.
We are prepared for the war!
Stop,
son Duryodhan.
Before we give them an answer,
it is vital to meditate over it.
Meditate?
Where is the time
to meditate over this, father?
Those Pandavas
have asked for an answer
from us today itself!
And what should we
meditate over?
Should we
meditate over
seeking their refuge, father?
No, son.
No.
I do not know if this date
will bring good fortune
f-for my sons or not.
Be calm.
We need to meditate over this.
Minister
the Great Sage Jaimini!
The Great Sage Jaimini
is the most renowned astrologer
in the entire Aryan region.
Send him an invite immediately.
As you say,
Your Highness.
I wish to know what
the result of this war will be.
I must find out whether this war
will benefit my sons
or...
Or will the presence of Krishna
become the good fortune
of the Pandavas.
Dear Abhimanyu
do you
see the gates to
the city of Virat over there?
Very soon
the formidable army of the
Pandavas will exit from there
and move northward
towards the kingdom of Kuru.
At that moment
the chariot behind the General
will be yours,
dear.
Will you be
the General, uncle?
No.
A person who will
not take to arms
cannot be the General.
Then who will be the General?
No matter who
the General is, dear
but the Commander
will be no one but you.
The task of taking this war
from the possibility of defeat
to the hope of victory
will be done by you,
dear.
I hope such a major
responsibility
does not scare you,
dear.
Why would I be scared,
uncle?
A sword is hungry
for blood after all.
A heart that has
the enthusiasm of victory
has no place
for the fear of death.
I am proud of you,
dear.
This war will usher a new era.
The old era will end
when His Excellency Bhishma
will be slain
and the new era will begin
because of you.
May the Empress have happiness!
Prince Arjun and Vasudev Krishna
will be here in the city
of Virat in a while.
Bring the items
for welcome, maid!
On my behalf
have gold coins and wheat
distributed in the kingdom.
Have a festival held!
Prince Abhimanyu should be
welcomed in a grand manner.
Make haste,
maid!
Are the five sons of yours not
arriving as well, Your Highness?
Father has sent a message
that he shall be here
with the army very soon
and the five sons of mine
will also arrive with him.
Ever since we moved away
from Indraprastha
I have not seen them.
I have never seen
Prince Abhimanyu
and the other Princes.
I am so eager to meet
all of them, Your Highness!
In times of struggles
when a child is born
with the hope of a new future
one's courage gets augmented,
Your Highness.
People are talking solely
about Prince Abhimanyu
in the entire palace,
Your Highness.
And very soon,
the entire Aryan region
will talk about him.
He is the son of Arjun,
the bearer of the Gandiva.
He is the child of Subhadra,
the sister of Govind.
He is the disciple
of Govind himself.
He is the brother
of the five sons of mine.
Yajnaseni Panchali
is his mother.
Pardon me,
Your Highness
but he is not your son.
He is the son
of Princess Subhadra.
No other child can be dearer
than one's own.
The affection of a child
who is born of another woman
can never be had by us.
Even if all the trees
grow in the same woods
not all the fruits
have the same taste.
I know quite well
that if you are
victorious in the war
then the Yadavas will make
Abhimanyu the next King.
However,
if you lose
then Abhimanyu
will apologize to Hastinapur
and settle in Dwaraka.
The only ones to make
a sacrifice for you
will be the five sons of yours
and not Abhimanyu.
You have not been able to
comprehend King Pandu's dynasty
Queen Sudeshna.
Sacrifice and righteousness
run through the veins
of this dynasty.