What happened, uncle?
Why did you stop that chariot?
Where are you going?
Gandhar awaits me, my darling.
Now, I have nothing
left to do in Hastinapur.
What are you saying, uncle?
You would leave for Gandhar
only after getting me anointed...
You had taken such an oath.
Anointed...
You cannot get anointed,
my darling.
All my life
I have tried to make you King
but now, I have
been defeated, my darling.
How did you get defeated, uncle?
Seeing that the Pandavas
are alive?
But I am still the Crown Prince.
I do not fear the sons of Pandu.
If they have
the strength of Panchal
then I have
the army of Hastinapur.
Do not make such a mistake,
my darling.
Deeming Bali, the King
of the 'Vanaras,' dead
Sugriv had become the King.
When Bali returned
safe and sound
not only did Sugriv
have to leave the city
but also the kingdom
of Kishkindha.
Upon learning that the previous
Crown Prince is alive
no one will deem you
the Crown Prince.
Our competence is not dead yet,
King of Gandhar.
I will use my competence
to make friend Duryodhan King.
My beloved Duryodhan
a river nourishes the fields
but when it floods them
it covers the entire land
with sand.
Then nothing grows on it.
The land becomes barren.
Similar is the case
with friendship.
But uncle, my friend Karna...
I do not doubt him, beloved!
He has great valour and
incomparable competence.
He is completely
dedicated to you but
when it comes to
righteousness and friendship
deciding between the two
is exceedingly difficult
for the King of Anga.
Today, had he
killed Bheem and Arjun
had righteousness and generosity
not stemmed within him
you could have had
the kingdom with great ease.
Had I killed Bheem and Arjun
today, King of Gandhar
the entire Aryan region
would have known
about the identity
of the deceased.
And it would have also known
about the people who are alive.
And then the great Bhishma
would certainly have brought
Yudhishthir to Hastinapur.
Such deep thinking!
After such deep thinking
did you decide upon not fighting
King Karna of Anga?!
No, King of Gandhar.
I had thought only of my duty.
It is the duty
of a competent warrior
to either strive for his victory
or
praise that of another.
And when a person takes a
decision based on righteousness
the decision is always correct.
And did you not think,
King of Anga
that when Yudhishthir
will return to Hastinapur
he will be protected
by great warriors
like Bheem and Arjun?
And behind them will be
the entire army of Drupad!
Do remember one thing,
my darling.
When Yudhishthir
will return to Hastinapur
that old man
will never let you become King.
Uncle
why do you not
suggest something?
There is a way out, my darling.
But this time,
you must listen to me.
And so must your friend.
Do I have your word?
You have my word, uncle.
Then listen...
The Pandavas are alive
but before this news spreads
to the people of Hastinapur
You must get yourself anointed
as the Crown Prince.
But
your father's heart
keeps turning towards
righteousness.
That is why
until you get anointed
you must keep it
a secret from him
that the five of them are alive.
Yudhishthir has
not yet been anointed.
If you get anointed
then
Yudhishthir's right
will get annihilated.
And the marriage to
the Princess of Panchal
will not benefit him
either, my darling!
Stop, priest.
Before the marriage
ceremony begins
I wish to have some answers,
Great Sage Vyas.
Right before my eyes,
my daughter
is about to enter a life
which will be more painful
than a funeral pyre.
You have deemed it righteous
but will the world?
Will she get happiness from
this terrible sacrifice of hers?
You are correct, King Drupad.
Princes
marriage is based upon
seven vows, which are taken
by the bride and the groom.
But this is
an atypical marriage.
In order to make it
fruitful and righteous
you must take
some additional vows.
The way a plant cannot be sown
in two different places at once
and a Minister cannot
serve two Kings
similarly, at a time, dedication
can only be towards one person,
sons of Pandu.
So, how can a woman
fulfill her duties
towards five husbands
at the same time?
A single person cannot dedicate
oneself to five people, My Lord.
But five people can certainly
be dedicated to a single person.
We five brothers dedicate
ourselves to Princess Draupadi
now and forever.
We shall accept
all her decisions.
Splendid, Yudhishthir.
For an entire year, Draupadi
will be wife to only one of you.
During that period
only that person can enter
Draupadi's chamber
to whom she gives
the right to do so.
For the sake
of Draupadi's happiness
I am asking
for this difficult vow.
But isn't the basis
of a relationship
not remembrance, My Lord?
Then after a year,
how will my sister
free herself from
the joys and sorrows?
She will get crushed
under those memories, My Lord.
Every year, I shall perform
an austere meditation
before the holy fire.
By forgetting the relationships
and memories of the past
I shall purify my soul.
My Lord
not only Princess Draupadi
but also we five brothers
shall perform such a meditation
every year.
We take such an oath.
I have another question,
My Lord.
For various reasons,
Princes have to
marry multiple times.
If the Pandavas
bring their other wives
then what will become
of my daughter?
People do not
fulfill their duties
towards somebody over which
everyone has the right.
This question relates
only to me, My Lord.
Only I have been married.
I give my word
that I shall never bring
my first wife
within the perimeters
of the city.
Irrespective of where we live,
there will be only one Queen
and that will be
Princess Draupadi.
We take an oath that
we shall fulfill our vows
for as long as we live.
May the Almighty fill our lives
with righteousness.
Priest
begin the marriage ceremony.
'This is such a vortex
of darkness.'
'This is an oath
for my honour.'
'It seems to be'
'on the verge of success.'
'The more difficult
the struggle'
'the stronger the basis.'
'This is my'
'duty as a woman.'
'My heart must remain steadfast'
'and this is a vow
I must fulfill.'
'My heart will remain steadfast'
'and this is why
I have been born.'
'The evening sky is
a shade of vermillion.'
'This is a grave moral dilemma'
'in the history'
'of genesis.'
'My heart must remain steadfast'
'and this is a vow
I must fulfill.'
'My heart will remain steadfast'
'and this is why
I have been born.'
'My heart must remain steadfast'
'and this is a vow
I must fulfill.'
'My heart will remain steadfast'
'and this is why
I have been born.'
'My heart must remain steadfast'
'and this is a vow
I must fulfill.'
'My heart will remain steadfast'
'and this is why
I have been born.'
'My heart'
'will remain'
'steadfast.'