'A person who is
blind since birth'
'is unworthy
of becoming the king.'
'When all the sons
are equally worthy'
'only then does the eldest son
have this right, Queen Mother.'
My lord..
Avoid!
I said, avoid!
Right now, I am not in a state
to converse with anyone.
Today my decision
to blindfold my eyes
seems worth it.
The world that does such
injustice to my husband
is unworthy to be looked at.
Pardon me, Prince.
The ministers of the court
have decided
that they will..
- Coronate Pandu as the king.
I knew it.
I am sure, he must have
been ecstatic. Am I right?
Who could be happy
at this decision, Queen Mother?
This will fill
my entire life with grief.
Grandsire
I am but a servant
to my elder brother
and for a servant,
his duties are his ornaments.
I have taken an oath to serve
my brother since birth.
I can take his side
not his place.
Something that inflicts a wound
and then applies an ointment
of words on it is politics.
I had no idea
when he learnt all this.
Pandu..
Then grandsire must have said
that keeping the pain
and dejection of oneself
locked up in one's heart
and carrying out one's duties
is the duty of every prince.
And you must bear this duty
on your shoulders.
A person can never be
greater than the throne
and love
can never be
greater than duties.
If through meditation,
rituals or medication
we could coronate
Dhritarashtra as the king
then we would have
gladly waited for it
but the situation is not so.
Dhritarashtra will
never be able to see.
That is why
in the best interest
of the entire Kingdom of Kuru
the responsibility
of this kingdom
falls to you.
Only after
everyone requested him
did Prince Pandu
say in the royal court
that during
the exile of Lord Ram
Bharat had carried out
the duties of the throne
similarly, he too would
carry out the royal duties.
So, have you come here
to take my slippers, soldier?
Will Pandu place them on
the throne and sit at its base?
What is the point of this act?
Even Lord Ram had been
exiled for 14 years
but in my case
everyone has sentenced me
to a lifelong exile.
A lifelong exile.
He is not Bharat.
He will not give up
the throne for anyone.
Neither will he
give it up for me
nor for my children.
Now, the Kuru dynasty
will be furthered by Pandu.
Now, the future
of blind Dhritarashtra
will be in darkness.
In darkness.
I have been tied
to this darkness forever
by that Pandu.
That Pandu has
tied me to it forever.
Son Shakuni.
Son, is time for us to leave.
I too was thinking
of this, mother.
Get up, Chandal!
Get up, dear Pishaach!
It is the order of my father.
We must leave.
Let's go.
Now, Gandhari's..
Now, Gandhari's
silent sacrifice..
Come on.
Pardon me, mother.
My dice refuse to budge.
Why are you joking, Shakuni?
- It's no joke, Your Highness.
Leave.
I am not joking, Your Highness.
I explained it
to the two of them
that we must return to Gandhar
but these two..
Shame is keeping them
from getting up, sire.
Isn't the name
of our ancestral kingdom
Purushpura, father?
But if you and l,
a king and a prince
return to Gandhar with
such an insult to our chivalry
then what will we
tell our subjects?
Shall we call
the 'land of men'
the 'land of eunuchs'?
This is what these impudent
fellows here say, father.
This is what they say.
Our insult?
Who insulted us, Shakuni?
This was Gandhari's fate.
- Fate!
Fate!
If fate cannot be trusted like
a gamble, father
then I will not side with fate
but with a gamble!
With a gamble!
At least before they
fall to the ground
these dice are in my hand.
I throw them in the air.
No one throws them
on my behalf, father.
But you have given
the dice of our lives
in the hands of that Bhishma,
father.
In the hands of that Bhishma.
That is why we have been
treated so poorly.
Gandhari has met with
great injustice, father.
She has met with injustice
and this truth is
piercing my heart
like a dagger, father.
Piercing my heart
like a dagger!
Shakuni!
Son..
Son, what have you done?
How can anyone stab oneself
with a dagger, son?
What have you done?
Father
this wound will remind me
of the great injustice
done to Gandhari.
You may proceed towards Gandhar.
I shall stay right here
in Hastinapur.
And until
I make dear Gandhari
the Queen of the Kuru dynasty
the Kuru dynasty will not
experience an iota of happiness
because
I won't allow it.
They won't experience
an iota of happiness
because I won't allow it!
When one deems
an incident to be unjust
then that incident
shakes up his psyche.
The entire world seems
like an enemy to him.
The greater the intensity of
the incident that seems unjust
the greater is the protest done
by the heart of man.
In reply to that incident,
he asks for justice.
And this is apt.
In reality, any form
of injustice in the society
destroys the belief and faith
of a person.
But
what is justice?
What does justice mean?
The one who was unjust
ought to repent
and the one
who experienced injustice
ought to renew faith
in his heart about society.
Does this not sum up
the meaning of justice?
But an unrighteous person
renounces justice and
embraces enmity and revenge.
He chooses to defeat violence
with violence.
The one who experienced agony
tries to inflict
greater agony to others.
And while walking down
this path, the oppressed
becomes the oppressor.
Very soon
he turns into a criminal.
In other words
there is very little difference
between justice and revenge
and this difference is called
righteousness.
Is it not true?
Think about it.
Your Highness!
Give me this sword.
That is
the difference
between you
and Prince Pandu.
You may raise your sword
but you never wound anyone.
But Prince Pandu's sword
wounds people
even without being raised.
Prince Shakuni
I could not recognise
your footfalls today.
That is because, Your Highness
henceforth I have
changed my way of walking.
Change your path along with your
way of walking too, Shakuni.
Gandhar awaits you.
I have left Gandhar behind me,
Your Highness.
Now my path will follow you.
I have changed my path.
That is why I have changed
my way of walking too.
My path does not
lead anywhere anymore.
My path has been obstructed
forever.
If one ties your feet
then one can dampen
only your speed
but cannot divert you from
your path, King Dhritarashtra.
Stop mocking me by referring
to me as the king, Shakuni.
The king of Hastinapur
is that Pandu now.
King..
The sun does not rise during
the night, Your Highness.
Then shall we stop
calling it the sun?
When it is day,
the sun rises for sure.
You are the sun of Hastinapur.
The throne of Hastinapur
had always been yours
is yours and will always be so.
When the time is ripe
you shall have your right.
And how is that?
I do not know right now
but I have faith in time.
Time always bestows us
with opportunities
and the one who makes
the most of an opportunity
is the victorious one.
Will you teach me deception now?
That too against my own family?
What family are you talking
about, King Dhritarashtra?
The family
that snatched your right
from you?
I have to agree,
Your Highness.
You are very generous
but in politics,
the other name of generosity
is foolishness.
- Shakuni!
I shall behead you
for this impudence of yours.
Then do so, Your Highness.
Then do so.
My beloved sister's heart
has already been
broken into bits by you.
Now you may chop my body
into many pieces as well.
Just for once think about it.
Just once.
When you had returned dejected
from Hastinapur's royal court
then to bear your
dejection and rage
my beloved Gandhari
was standing right before you
and not your family,
Your Highness.
We are folks of the mountain,
The way a mountain
gives away all its water
and keeps nothing for itself.
Similarly we too give away
all our love.
But my beloved sister's
love and dedication
could not be recognised
by you, Your Highness.
Only with her
will you find both happiness
and strength.
Strength?
How can a woman
bestow me with strength?
Woman?
Woman!
Ravan had only 20 arms
and with them he had
picked up Mount Kailash.
My beloved sister
can give you 200 arms.
200 arms.
With them you can lift
not only Hastinapur
but also
the entire region of Arya.
The entire region of Arya,
King Dhritarashtra.
Goodbye.