Who dare interrupts my speech!
M-My lord..
Son Dhritarashtra.
Mother?
Are you ready, son?
I have been ready for years,
mother.
Greetings.
May you live long.
Today, your wait will end, son.
Today, you will become
the Emperor of Hastinapur.
For the first time in my life
I too am experiencing
such great happiness.
Come, my son.
By the time Vidur and Pandu
are sworn into their ranks
we must reach the court.
Come, Gandhari.
Tell her, mother,
not to accompany me.
While moving towards the throne,
if someone hampers my speed
I will not
be able to bear it.
Let's go, sister.
Whether or not you can
match up to his speed
the Kuru Prince
cannot sit on the throne
without you.
Greetings, grandfather.
May you live long.
Greetings, Queen Mother.
May you prosper.
With this 'tilak,'
I inculcate
justice in my intellect.
With this 'tilak'
I inculcate dedication
in my intellect.
With this water,
I acquire the truth
and swear to abide by it.
With this water,
l acquire patience.
With this white apparel
I acquire righteousness
in my life.
l acquire valour.
By acquiring this golden scepter
I accept the throne of
Hastinapur as my lord and master
Henceforth, all my relationships
and affection
shall be secondary to me.
This Royal Scepter
shall inspire me to be fearless
and steadfast.
Like this armour
I shall protect the subjects
of our kingdom.
Like this sword
I shall always lead in war.
The flag of this dynasty
and kingdom
shall always be held high by me.
For the happiness and glory
of the subjects of Hastinapur
I swear to a life
of undying struggle.
For the reputation and
independence of the Kuru empire
I swear to a life
of undying struggle.
Long live Chief Minister Vidur!
Long live General Pandu!
Greetings, grandfather.
My teacher, greetings.
Greetings, Queen Mother.
May you prosper, my son.
After 25 years,
the throne of Hastinapur
shall get its lord today.
This is one amongst the happiest
moments of my life.
Today, you will take over the
duties of your father's kingdom.
For all these years,
Bheeshma and I
have safeguarded this throne.
Now, the time has come,
Dhritarashtra
to coronate you as the king
of the Hastinapur.
Stop, brother Dhritarashtra.
Chief Minister Vidur
what is the reason behind
stopping the ceremony?
The reason is, Queen Mother
that I have just taken an oath..
As the Chief Minister
of Hastinapur
I, Vidur, shall uphold
the truth, righteousness
the interest of
the throne of Hastinapur
and the happiness
of the subjects.
I will never forgo
any of these duties.
My relationships and affection
shall be secondary to me.
That is why, Queen Mother
it is my duty to stop this
unrighteousness.
What unrighteousness,
Chief Minister?
The coronation ceremony,
Queen Mother.
This coronation ceremony
is unrighteous.
A person who is
blind since birth
is unworthy
of becoming the king.
A person who is
blind since birth
is unworthy
of becoming the king.
What are you attempting to do,
Chief Minister Vidur?
Is this some sort of a facade?
Neither is this an attempt
nor a facade, Queen Mother.
This is written
in our scriptures.
A person who is
blind since birth
is unworthy
of becoming the king.
Sometimes, righteousness
can be cruel, Queen Mother.
In the best interest
of the subjects
righteousness demands
personal sacrifice.
How can you say so now,
Chief Minister Vidur?
You knew in advance about
the coronation ceremony.
Did righteousness
not strike you then?
Righteousness changes according
to situations, Queen Mother.
Righteousness changes?
I have heard such a thing
for the first time.
Although, I have heard
that motives change
but righteousness?
Hastinapur is a big kingdom.
It may have
different set of rules.
Prince Shakuni!
You do not have the right
to interfere
in our family matters!
Pardon me, great Bheeshma.
Pardon me.
A brother has the right to speak
in the favour of his sister.
This is an accepted norm
in the entire region of Arya.
Is it still the norm
in Hastinapur or not
can be answered only
by the righteous
and knowledgeable Vidur.
I can answer
your question as well.
To see absolutely no flaw
in one's elder brother
is the duty
of a younger brother.
But when the merits and demerits
of a king are being discussed
to look beyond the relationship
of an elder brother
is the duty of a Chief Minister.
But only the eldest son
of the family
has the right to become king,
Chief Minister Vidur.
When all the sons
are equally worthy
only then does the eldest son
have this right, Queen Mother.
The season of summer
precedes that of the monsoon
but the monsoon
are way more important
because it rains the most
during this season.
When deciding between
age and virtues
it is wise to choose virtues,
Queen Mother.
It is written in the scriptures
that the milk of a lioness
can be contained
only in a gold bowl
and not in one
made out of copper.
Similarly, the ability
to rule a kingdom
can be carried out
only be a complete person
and not an incomplete one.
- Incomplete!
You call me incomplete!
Pardon me,
brother Dhritarashtra.
Quiet!
Quiet.
I have been insulted enough,
Vidur.
When you're done preaching about
your so called righteousness
to this court
then have me informed.
Brother Dhritarashtra!
Stop.
Take me to my Lord, Sukta.
Alright, Princess.
Just because he has no vision
Dhritarashtra cannot
become an able king?
I do not agree to this,
Chief Minister Vidur.
Vision is the first weapon
of a king, Queen Mother.
If a king cannot
read his ministers
by their facial expressions
he will not be able to identify
the enemies of the kingdom.
When a king goes hunting
he sees the state
of his subjects.
He sees their joy and sorrow.
When one comes crying
to the king for justice
apart from hearing
the sounds of his cries
it is also essential to look
at his pain, Queen Mother.
How will a blind person
be able to do all this?
For these tasks
the Chief Minister, General
and the council of ministers
are present,
Chief Minister Vidur.
Pardon me, Queen Mother.
The Chief Minister,
council of ministers
and the General
are aides of the King.
It is their duty
to follow the king.
When the king
of a state is weak
the council of ministers
and the subjects
of the state become impudent.
Brother Dhritarashtra..
Brother, listen to me.
- Go away!
What is left to hear, Pandu?
I am incomplete?
Me?
The one who struggled with
his deficiency all his life
the one who gave it his best
to become normal
and now he's called abnormal.
He became the best.
I am incomplete?
I cannot become the king?
That is Vidur's opinion,
brother.
As the Chief Minister,
perhaps it's his duty.
But we can also put forth
our point. - Put forth my point!
Do I beg them?
Despite being the eldest child
in the dynasty
and the most capable one
should I plead for my rights?
Those courtiers, the council of
ministers and judiciary
who will be paid by me
and will be my servants..
Should I plead to them?
Please calm down, brother.
- I am calm, Pandu!
Had I not been calm
I would have killed you
for this betrayal!
Betrayal!
Brother, never have I..
I understand everything.
You and that
conniving son of a maid
have together conspired
against me!
Under the garb of love,
justice and righteousness
you want to snatch
my right from me, Pandu!
You want to become king!
This is accusations has
no merit, brother!
Never have l even dreamt
of such a thing.
Go away, Pandu
otherwise the fire
of my wrath will burn you.
Go away!
The Chief Minister,
the council of ministers
and the General
are aides of the King.
It is their duty
to follow the king.
When the king of a state is weak
the council of ministers
and the subjects
of the state become impudent.
That is why,
righteousness demands
that being complete and virtuous
is what is expected from a king.
And you are that person,
wise Vidur.
You must surely deem yourself
fit to become the king.
Prince of Gandhar!
Give Prince Shakuni a reply
Chief Minister Vidur.
The duty of a thorn is to
protect the tree, Queen Mother.
Neither does it have the desire
nor the strength
to take the place of a flower.
I am one such thorn
of the tree of this kingdom.
Whenever the question of the
kingdom's welfare will arise
I shall assume
the form of a thorn.
I know
that flowers are offered to God.
Thorns are the first ones
to be removed.
But that does not make me sad.
I shall always fulfill my
responsibility as a thorn.
Queen Mother
when it comes to the
royal throne of Hastinapur
I don't doubt Vidur's dedication
and devotion towards it.
You are correct, son of Ganga.
But even this throne
cannot remain vacant any longer.
That is why I suggest
brother Pandu should be
crowned as the king.