A fiery glowing visage
a torrid vigour
and a fervent soul define
your daughter, father.
This boon from the very gods
pays you her respects.
There's no need to
touch my feet.
The boon from the gods
can't be kept at my feet
and I, Drupad, doesn't let
anyone rule over him.
Then I have
just one apt place left.
That would be your heart.
Let's go, Dhrishtadyumna.
Panchal and I, your father,
have waited long for you.
You have to fulfil the oath
of your father soon.
Definitely, father.
Draupadi
I am your sister, Shikhandini.
Isn't father
happy about my birth?
When the sky is overcast
the sunlight doesn't lighten
up the earth.
His nous
is now clouded with rage.
But in due time
father will surely come to know
that you are the fortune
of Panchal.
Come on.
The customary bathing ritual
is at hand.
Follow me, Draupadi.
Draupadi!
This is your room.
All the females of
the royal palace stay here.
Attendants!
Draupadi's customary bath
needs the bath to be prepped.
'Panchkavya',* sandalwood paste,
*"Mixture of five products."
perfumed oil and others
must be arranged there.
Sushma go and get the
offerings made
to Goddess Parvati
from the temple.
Anuradha, arrange for clothes
and jewellery for the princess.
Princess, you collided with
the mirror knowingly, right?
Draupadi this is a mirror.
Who is this?
That's your reflection.
Panchal's most beautiful woman.
That's you, Draupadi.
Princess, don't you even know
what a mirror is?
Draupadi
all the gods have bestowed you
with every form of knowledge.
But not of those objects
that were made by man, not God.
Come on. Your customary bath's
time is at hand.
Draupadi
after the bath the attendants
will groom you.
Post that, we'd set out to
visit Goddess Parvati's temple.
I'll be back after arranging
the bodyguards and palanquin.
Malini how dare you
jest with the Princess!
Beg her pardon.
- Why so?
I wasn't miffed.
As you say, Princess.
But the progeny of attendants
should mind their limits.
Limits are defined by
one's disposition.
That's decided by one
[himself] herself.
One that ought to be minded
isn't a limit but a prohibition.
What are you holding?
It's a dolly.
What would you do with it?
I would get her married
with a nice and handsome doll.
All the girls have a dolly.
Have you never seen one?
Malini the Princess
was never a child.
She was born a youth.
She appeared out of the flames
of a 'yajna'.
She hasn't passed childhood.
What happens in childhood?
It's full of joy, Princess.
The entire world seems like
a curious puzzle to be solved.
There's no joy!
Mother keeps hitting me.
Always pointing out faults
and bossing me around.
I just wish to grow up soon.
Okay, then.
Fine.
You become my friend
and make me experience childhood
and when I come to know
how it feels to be a grownup
I will let you know.
So?
Would you be my friend?
But, Princess
she's an attendant's daughter.
An attendant's daughter can't
be friends with a Princess.
Really?
But we are friends!
Because we both can't understand
that difference.
She's so pretty!
- You are very pretty!
Even more
than this dolly of mine.
My dolly will marry
a handsome doll.
You too must get married
to a handsome prince, Princess.