Make an announcement
in the entire Kuru kingdom
that King Pandu has won
Kunti's hand in the 'swayamvar'.
All hail!
- King Pandu!
Prince, I have
brought you your meal.
Okay.
Set it down.
The taste...
It's a bit different today.
It has been prepared in the
Gandhar's culinary style, sire.
Gandhari wished
you to be introduced to
the taste of Gandhar's cuisine.
She herself...
- If you didn't like it
I will get another meal
ready in no time.
No!
The taste of
Gandhar's cuisine is good.
It's different but it's good.
Won't you take a seat?
So finally the dishes of
Gandhar did make
their way into Hastinapur's
royal kitchen.
It's my first try, Prince.
I must say,
it's quite a good one.
But it won't be famous
in Hastinapur.
Henceforth
the procedures of
Kunti province will be followed.
If the platter has a variety
of tastes
the joy of having food
increases, Prince.
If the tastes of here, Gandhar
and Kunti province join
what harm can it pose?
Don't try to preach to me!
You don't have the right
to offer me counsel.
I'm just trying to ease your
agitated heart, Prince.
I understand that you
are still disturbed.
But, Prince, the pillar
of a temple is as pious
as the stoup it holds.
As a matter of fact, the stoup
can't be without a pillar.
The one who was born
to be considered the'stoup'
could never be
the supporting 'pillar'.
And the 'pillar' meant
for support
wouldn't suit if it were
glorified to be the'stoup'.
Which stone has been
made for either of them
is something only the architect
knows best about.
We should accept the decision
of the Almighty, Prince.
This is the time to forego
of all bitterness
and welcome Pandu and Kunti.
- Don't touch me!
I haven't yet given you
the right to do so!
Every time...
Every time I try to
consider you as my wife
this very behaviour of yours
makes me feel
as to how much
my insult...
Gladdens you.
How very much are
you at peace by the same!
Remember, Gandhari
Pandu's welcome
will neither be done by me
nor by you.
I am your husband.
My orders define your
rules of conduct.
Now whether you abide by
the same or not
is a choice I leave to you.
Two persons
on coming closer
try to form boundaries and rules
for the other for sure.
If we ponder over every
relationship, we'd notice
that the source of all of them
are the very boundaries
that we draw for others.
And even if unknowingly,
a stranger oversteps the bounds
the very instant
our heart palpitates with anger.
What's the actual form of
these boundaries?
Have we ever given
it a thought?
By imposing boundaries
we don't allow the other
to decide for himself.
We impose our decision
on the other.
In other words, we reject
the independence of another.
And when independence
is rejected, his heart
is filled with sorrow.
And when he breaks
all the boundaries
our heart is filled with wrath.
Isn't that how it always
happens?
But if everyone respects
the independence of another
boundaries and rules
become extinct.
In other words
just like agreement is
the body of a relationship
isn't independence the soul
of a relationship?
Think over it.
No, dear.
Son-in-law
the first to be offered respect
is the King of the Yadavas
Shoorsen.
He is the one who
sired Kunti.
No!
Greater than the father
is the one who
brings up the child.
You are so right, sire.
The one who forsook one's
child after its birth
can never be the first
to be offered respect.
Your right will always
come second.
You may please proceed.
Please come.
Did you hear that, Priyamvada?
So generous and broad
is the outlook of my husband!
By selecting such a husband
I have made myself fortunate!
- Yes, Princess.
But now you must do
no such thing
that robs you of your fortune.
But I can't deceive my husband.
If in order to gain something
one has to lie
that's deception
but in order to shield oneself
from harm, if truth is concealed
it's not termed
a deception, Princess.
Don't try to weave
a web of words, Priyamvada.
The truths of the world
are but hazy at best
to palace dwellers
but do remember
that if the same truths
pass into the hands of a foe
they become but
trebuchets.
What...
What are you doing?
This is a shield, Princess.
To safeguard your
and King Pandu's happy life
from the attacks
of any vile person.
Till the time this thread
is tied around your wrist
you won't say a thing
about your past to your husband.
What are you doing?
- This is a shield, Princess.
To safeguard your
and King Pandu's happy life
from the attacks
of any vile person.
Till the time this thread
is tied around your wrist
you won't say a thing
about your past to your husband.
But... - There's no time
for options, Princess.
A king has many wives.
If King Pandu marries
a second time
this very secret of yours
will become a risk to your life.
And anyway
a secret portends
a danger to a woman.
Why...
Why do I get the feeling
that by tying this thread
you have but curtailed
my breaths.
If I keep this matter
a secret from my husband
then it would be
my second crime.
Moreover
after having forsaken my son
I have committed a crime.
God knows
who would have raised my son.
Whose family would have
served as his refuge.
Would he...
Would he have ever received
maternal love?
Or just as an orphan
is he destined to
suffer pangs of sorrow.
Where could my son be?
Where could be...
My Karna!
Help!
Someone, help me!
Hey! Look! Move away!
- Help!
What's going on?
Run for your lives!
- Someone save him!
Someone save him!
Save him!
Move back!
- Step back! - Save him!
What's going on!
Someone save him!
Move!
Son!
Karna!
Yes?
Radha, your son
is indeed divine.
Mother, I just...
Mother?
Mother!
- Shut up, idiot!
First you infuriate me
and then chant my name!
Come home and I'll
take you to task!
But why, mother?
What did I do?
I was just saving the kid.
And what about you?
Would the Lord save you?
Why don't you think before
doing anything?
But I don't require
any protection, mother.
You know that already.
- Shut up and come home!
Come on!
Come home and I'll
take you to task!
Come on home!
Mother!
Are you angry, mother?
Son, you first infuriate me
and then very coyly ask
if I am angry.
Why do you do any such deed
that makes me angry?
I'm Adhirath's son.
I will have to save
the child, right?
I know that.
But I have to save you from
your father's temper, right?
And after the deed you've
done today
deems your punishment necessary.
Father had gone to the Kunti
province with the King, right?
But now he's
on his way back.
Son, the King is coming
back with his Queen
and we have to pay them a visit.
Does that mean they will
actually see us?
But why would they see us, son?
Neither are we any criminal
nor any valorous warrior.
Mother, haven't you
always said that
being graced with the King's
attention is good fortune?
Or even great misfortune.
Son, attention from
great people
always has a profound effect.
Then we should be graced
with Their Highness' attention.
But how?
All hail!
- King Pandu!
'This is a shield, Princess.'
'To safeguard your
and King Pandu's happy life'
'from the attacks
of any vile person.'
'Till the time this thread
is tied around your wrist'
'you won't say a thing about
your past to your husband.'
All hail!
- King Pandu!
Why did you stop, Adhirath?
The Chief Minister is coming
to welcome you, Your Highness.
Greetings!
- Greetings, younger brother!
- Greetings!
His and Her Highness
are welcome.
Your Highness, Mother Queen
has ordered
that you should first pay
a visit to the district deity.
Won't you welcome your brother
and sister-in-law, Vidur?
I would welcome
sister-in-law
by being her charioteer.
Adhirath, if you may,
please proceed to your home.
Please take some rest.
My lord!
Radha, how are you?
Where is Karna?
He is busy preparing for
the King and Queen's welcome
so that Their Highness
be pleased.
What are you saying?
Why didn't you stop him?
My lord, how could I stop
him from welcoming the King?
God knows what kind
of welcome he would arrange!
He won't use a bow
and arrows, right?
You just don't understand
the gravity of any situation!
Now I have to stop him!
Where is he?
Lord Surya
I don't know of any mantra
but please bless my arrows
with the speed of light.
May no one be harmed by these.
'These are
the very same flowers'
'in whose golden colour reside
the light of Lord Surya and'
'countless memories of mine.'
Vidur, who showered
these flowers?
Such an amazing display
of archery!
Who did this?
This archer has
really pleased me!
Who is this archer?
Come forth!
You deserve the thanks
of mine and the Queen!
Come forth!