"The tenth day of war"
My child.
Till the end of this day.
We must repel grandsire
away from lady Shikhandini.
Once we find a chance.
We need to kill lady Shikhandini.
That's our goal today.
Lady Shikhandini!
The entire Kaurava army
will attempt to keep you
away from grandsire.
Their only intention
will be to kill you.
I and the whole Pandava army...
will shield you.
In order to get you.
They'll have to defeat all of us.
Warriors!
Today, we have one goal!
One objective and one plan.
We must aid Shikhandini
to get to grandsire by all means.
All these days anticipation which've been stymied.
Grandsire's annihilation.
Today, we must lift our effort manifold.
In order to protect her.
Today, before sunset.
We must make grandsire...
lay down his weapon by all means.
Hail Mahadev.
Your survival essential
for my victory, grandsire.
My dead is essential
for my liberation.
I will not let you die,
grandsire.
Though you are present
on the battlefield,
the Pandava army will never
be able to reach to you.
A walls made of bamboo,
can stop the wind
but not hurricane.
Look there.
Soldiers!
Attack!
Hail Mahadev!
This is mandatory to stop
Arjuna and Vasudev, friend.
If we don't stop them.
They will aid lady Shikhandini
reach grandsire.
The only person who can
confront Arjuna...
is the one who taught
him in warfare.
Arjuna, accept this gesture.
If you get defeated.
I will be proud of my capability.
If you win, I will be proud
of my teaching.
Give me a reason to be proud.
- Pick up your weapon.
- Master!
Not even Lord Indra can stop me.
For getting lady Shikhandini
to grandsire today.
Today, you'll have to satisfy yourself,
with the pride of your teaching.
And accept your death by my hands.
Death is decided only by God.
You ought to accept your defeat by my hands.
Nobody can stop me from getting to
Grandsire today.
Nakul.
Ashwathama is fighting a duel
with Lady Shikandini.
We must help him.
Soldiers.
Direct the launchers towards Bheem.
Crush Bheem's army.
Go to Grandsire,
I will keep Ashwathama busy.
Master's son, Ashwathama.
My sword is desperate to get
introduced to you.
What are you waiting for?
Before facing Grandsire you must
fight a duel with me.
My brother spared your life
in the Panchal war.
But I am not as kind as him.
Death's the only punishment
I can offer you.
Get to Grandsire.
Dusshasan should also get a chance.
To use his spear to fight.
Pick up the spear, Dusshasan.
Let your brother realize that
you are a warrior.
What is the situation, Sanjay?
When is the sunset?
Three more hours, Your majesty.
Lady Shikhandini is wounded.
And is trying to progress towards Grandsire,
your majesty.
In these hours.
Lady Shikhandini should be unsuccessful
in all attempts.
If Grandsire's death is avoided.
Our army's victory will be inevitable.
Yes.
Where is Lady Shikhandini?
You have the body of a man.
But you...
You still battle like a woman!
my lady.
Just look at you.
Your entire body is scarlet
with blood.
Your breath seeks permission
to leave your body.
However...
Your heart...
Your heart does not allow you to forget
taking your revenge.
Take the decision to live,
My Lady.
I shall allow you to leave
the battlefield.
Revenge is the sole aim
of this birth of mine.
Remembering it is the
basis of my life.
To my darling Duryodhan. His Excelency Bhisma's life is very important, My Lady!
However, to ensure His Excellency
Bhishma's life,
your death is not mandatory.
This is why, I only need to hold you
off till sundown.
After which, neither will you be
able to enter the battlefield.
Nor will dream of victory
of the Pandavas.
His Excellency is looking constantly
at the sun, Your Highness.
As though he wish to prevent the sun from setting in the sky just for a little while.
Where is Shikhandi, Sanjay?
King of Gandhar is holding
Shikhandi off, majesty.
Guru Drona is not allowing Prince Arjuna
to move forth, Your Highness.
Prince Nakula is battling
Ashwathama, Your Highness.
Crown Prince Duryodhan is hurling rocks at
Prince Bheem, Your Highness.
All the Pandavas are miles away from
Shikhandi, Your Highness.
Those Pandavas are the armour
of Shikhandi, Sanjay.
If Shikhandi is away from this armour.
Reaching uncle is impossible
for him, Sanjay.
It's impossible.
In other words...
In other words,
our army win.
You will see, Vidur. King of Gandhar
will not fail.
Never.
My victory is a boon granted
by Mahadev himself.
You cannot render it futile,
King Shakuni of Gandhar.
In order to realize Mahadev boon,
you will have to be born
again, My Lady.
The birth of yours
was futile!
Lady Shikhandini!
"An injured Shikhandi is being
taken by Prince Abhimanyu"
"to the camp of the Pandavas,
Your Highness."
He has lost a lot of blood.
His life is in danger,
Your Highness.
Splendid.
Splendid, Sanjay.
Splendid!
In other words
if Shikhandi is injured
then he will not be able to battle.
And if he is not present before uncle
then killing uncle will be
impossible.
Mother Draupadi!
Sister!
Mother Draupadi,
he has lost a lot of blood.
Take her over there.
Abhimanyu, go and call your uncles
Nakul and Sahadev
to camp at once.
Only their special
herbs can heal sister.
Leave at once!
Friend
the sun is about to set.
Did Shikhandi
reach grandsire or not?
Shikandi is merely the cause.
Your weapons shall be of use in this.
You need to focus
your attention on your duty.
At the moment,
it is your duty
to defeat Guru Drona.
Mother-in-law,
his breathing is irregular!
Why are my lords Nakul and Sahadev
not here yet?
Mother-in-law,
do something!
No!
Without fulfilling one's oath
no one has the right to die,
sister!
Get up!
Get up, sister!
Try to recall, sister...
Try to recall
your meditation.
Try to recall your oath,
sister.
Try to recall
Mahadev's blessing.
Sister!
Get up, sister!
Lord Parashuram
had taken to arms for you!
Today,
you must take to arms!
Get up, sister.
Sister!
When lightning strikes in the sky
it indeed wreaks
havoc on earth.
You are like a powerful weapon
borne by a God, sister.
You are Indra's "vajra"!
Get up, sister.
Get up and wreak havoc!
Get up,
sister!
Get up!
You are the basis of victory
in this war of righteousness.
Sister!
Sister,
you must get up!
Sister!
Get up,
sister.