Arjun will come
to the 'swayamvar'
and get married to you.
This is what King Drupad wants.
And what do you want, Govind?
When competence gets awarded
I derive great satisfaction
from it, beloved.
And in the world,
does competence
solely belong to Arjun?
Certainly not.
How is it possible
for Mother Earth
to give birth to only one gem?
King of Anga, Karna, is also
competent.
If he takes part
in the competition
then he shall certainly win it.
Charvak too is a great archer
and the King of Matsya
is no less either.
Then who am I
supposed to wait for?
Only competence?
Is competence
the sole virtue, Govind?
Is competence the sole joy?
Is wishing for joy in a marriage
not correct?
Wishing for joy in a marriage...
One who wishes for joy
does not get it, Draupadi.
One who knows joy, gets it.
If you figure out
what joy means to you
then you shall indeed have joy.
Why do you never give
a definite answer, Govind?
A definite answer...
Because the efforts made
to have the answers
is called life.
Answers are another form
of salvation.
Nevertheless
as you are going
to the Shiv temple now
you should ask
Lord Shiva himself.
He is the Lord of Death
and Salvation.
That is why, He always
gives a definite answer.
If you are to get your answer
then you shall get it
only from Him.
Greetings.
Is there an inn in this city?
We wish to stay here
for a few days.
All the inns are full.
You will not find
any place to stay here.
Are you travellers?
- Yes.
We have come from
the village of Ekachakra.
We wish to go to Naimisharanya.
Are you 'Brahmins?'
We have dressed up 'Brahmins.'
Was that half the truth?
Yes
because I never lie.
But there is half a lie
in half the truth.
You are correct.
If I utter half the truth
ever again
then the Almighty
will punish me.
But I cannot tell the truth.
That is why,
do not ask questions.
Did the lady have something?
Come inside.
I shall arrange
for you to rest and dine.
But you must
allow us to serve you.
It is mandatory
otherwise we shall
not accept the alms.
I am a potter.
I am old.
It is difficult
to dig up the soil.
You are young.
You may dig the soil up
and I shall offer you
a place to rest and dine.
Then we shall serve you first.
Tell us from where
we need to dig up the soil.
We need to dig up the soil
to make pots
and not a mountain.
We need to dig up
a small amount of soil.
Any amount of soil you dig up
will be insufficient.
Our King is organizing
a 'swayamvar' for our Princess.
We have guests over
from all over the world.
Pots, earthen lamps and vessels
are required in great numbers.
The 'swayamvar'
of Princess Shikhandini? - No.
The deities
of the fire sacrifice
have blessed our King
with a daughter.
Our Princess Draupadi is divine.
Her 'swayamvar' will begin
tomorrow at dawn.
The person who gets our Princess
will be most fortunate.
In order to make the pots
I require soil
from the river bank.
And in order to make the vessels
I require soil from behind
the Shiva temple.
I hope
I get a definite answer
from Mahadev.
Brother Bheem
since we are here, why do we not
pay homage to Mahadev?
You are correct.
'Brahmins,' do have
the sacrament before leaving.
A small banquet
has been held outside.
Why? - Princess Draupadi is
coming here for the veneration.
Brother Bheem, we should leave.
Let us have something first.
This is not alms but a banquet.
If Shikhandini is also here,
she will recognize us.
We should leave.
Brother Bheem, let's go!
Brother Bheem, go and dig...
Brother Bheem.
- W-What?
Go and dig up the soil.
I shall go get the cart.
Go on, brother Bheem.
The aroma of food
is tempting me.
Prince Arjun, please let me go.
King Vrikodar
pay attention to your work.
Brother Bheem, in order
to make the vessels
we were asked to bring
soil from behind the temple.
Let me go get it.
Stop...
Let me go and get the soil.
I can do it, brother.
- No... Let me do it.
Brother Bheem, I can go get it.
You need not worry.
I shall go get it.
I shall be back soon.
- But...
I-I will go get it.
It seems, King Vrikodar was
unable to suppress his appetite.
Govind says, you always
give a definite answer.
Will I get my answer, My Lord?
Stop, Princess.
Let's go, Princess.
Princess Shikhandini has
asked us to return soon.