Your Highness
you have lost the independence
of your younger brothers,
servants Nakul and Sahadev
in the game.
My darling,
who will you bet now?
When there is a reduction
in the opponent's property
playing the game
becomes truly enjoyable.
However, when there is
a reduction in his might
winning the game
becomes a joyful experience!
Uncle
Arjun will be my servant now.
A person who is
at par with Arjun...
Do you even have such a
person with you, Duryodhan?
My friend
King Karna of Anga!
The son of a charioteer!
How is the son of a charioteer
at par with a Prince?
Crown Prince Bheem!
Yes, I am the son
of a charioteer
but abducting a woman
who is to be married
to someone else
can be done only by ogres!
Friend Duryodhan,
have you decided to bet me
against such an amoral person?
No, friend.
I have decided
to make him your servant.
Friend Karna
will you give me the permission
to bet you in the game?
He shall indeed
give you the permission!
King Karna of Anga
has even sold his soul to you!
On behalf of Emperor Yudhishthir
I bet myself in the game!
Dear, Crown Prince Duryodhan
has bet
your husband in the
game of dice being played.
Until now, he was an accessory
to unrighteousness
but today
he is just a means.
Today, I am ashamed
to call Karna
as my son.
Human beings are
being treated like property
and being bet in the
game of dice, father-in-law!
Yes, dear.
I got to know from the
charioteer of the Crown Prince
that Duryodhan will enslave
the five sons of Pandu.
And in the end, by enslaving
the innocent daughter of Drupad
she will be subjected to insult.
Queen Mother.
Go on, Your Highness.
Just four more points
and you will reach
the castle square.
Uncle, my patience
is giving in now.
Make haste in making
Arjun my servant.
Your Highness,
I say this with great grief
that another piece of yours
has been captured.
You now have
only one piece with you.
You need to save it.
Only then will
Prince Arjun be safe.
Only twelve more points
to win this.
Go on, my dice.
Prince Arjun has been
lost by the Emperor.
May the Emperor have happiness!
Friend Karna
I give you a servant
as a present.
Arjun.
And Arjun,
where is your bow?
What is it called again?
The Gandiva,
brother Duryodhan.
I have heard that Agni Dev
had preyed upon the illusion
of the Khandavprastha forest
and had used that illusion
to make that bow, brother.
Give it to Karna.
Give your bow
to Karna, Arjun.
The blessing of Agni Dev
in the hands of a servant
does not befit him.
Give Karna your bow, Arjun!
Give it!
Do accept it,
King Karna of Anga.
If I have your permission
then I shall imprison each God
residing in the heavens
and have each one of them
make such a bow for you.
I have lost my independence
but not my competence.
Keep it with you, Arjun.
Keep your Gandiva with you.
I do not require
any celestial bow.
My skills as an archer
are celestial by definition.
Servant Arjun
go and kneel down over there.
We need to begin the game.
Your Highness
shall we begin the game?
You may certainly begin,
King of Gandhar!
The Emperor shall bet me
in this round of the game.
Get up, Duryodhan!
You need to bet yourself
against me.
No, brother Bheem.
I shall bet my beloved
younger brother
Dusshasan against you.
This is the only opportunity
to defeat me, Duryodhan.
You will never be able
to defeat me henceforth.
Your Highness
shall we begin the game?
I pardon you in advance for
losing my independence, brother.
I know that you shall lose me
but my mace shall never be
subservient to another!
Not even for a moment!
May the Emperor have happiness!
If we have your permission
then may we begin the game?
Before losing my independence,
will you answer a question?
After losing
your younger brothers
do you still take pride in your
character and righteousness?
I am ashamed of myself, Bheem.
I have no pride.
Then you cannot bet
yourself in this game.
If you remain independent
then you shall free us soon.
Go on and play,
King of Gandhar.
Go on, my dice.
King of Gandhar
only six more points
and your piece will
capture that of brother.
Go on and play.
Your piece has captured
that of brother.
I think, you will win
this round as well.
He shall indeed win,
brother Bheem
but has he ever wondered
what all he has lost
by winning this round?
No, he has not!
Keep quiet,
servant!
Servants do not have
the permission to interfere!
Then you may
punish us, brother.
Uh!
Master Duryodhan.
You should resume the game now.
Go on, my dice.
There you go,
King of Gandhar.
I have even lost
my younger brother Bheem.
Now, even Bheem is your servant.
Brother Duryodhan
you now have nothing
in your property
which you can bet in the game
and neither do I have
anything with me
in which I take pride.
I have lost all my pride.
So, I quit the game.