Sister-in-law!
Sister-in-law,
what...
What happened in Hastinapur?!
Sister-in-law...
Sister-in-law!
Do not embrace me,
Subhadra!
You will burn up.
I was housed within
a fire back then
but now, a fire
is burning within me!
I do not wish to see anyone!
No one!
Sister-in-law.
Sister-in-law!
Open the door, sister-in-law.
Open the door, sister-in-law!
Sister-in-law!
My Lord!
How could you let something
so dreadful happen, My Lord?
Sister-in-law has locked
herself up in her chamber.
Sister-in-law has said that
she wishes to see no one.
I made numerous attempts but
she refuses to open the door.
Panchali,
open the door!
Give me the opportunity
for reparation, Panchali.
Open the door!
Brother Yudhishthir
Panchali is
exceedingly agitated.
I hope she does not
set herself on fire.
Brother Yudhishthir,
let me break the door down.
Impossible...
Impossible!
I can even break stone castles
down with my might
but why am I unable to break
this wooden door, brother?
Panchali's resolution has
locked that door, brother
and breaking the resolution
of a heart in agony
is way more difficult
than breaking a castle.
This is Panchali's resolution,
brother.
Open the door,
Panchali!
Panchali,
open the door.
Brother Yudhishthir
we will not be able
to get her to open that door.
Only Madhav can
have it opened now.
Greetings, brother.
Greetings...
I cannot accept your greetings
at the moment, Prince Arjun.
Until Draupadi
pardons all of you
I cannot pardon you either.
Where is my friend?
She left the court
of Hastinapur immediately
and came to Indraprastha
all by herself
leaving all of us behind.
She has locked herself up
in her chamber, brother.
All of us made numerous attempts
but she refuses to open
the doors of her chamber.
She has closed the doors
of her heart, Subhadra.
How can she open the doors
of her chamber then?
Panchali
friends are those
who share the feelings
of their hearts.
I too have a share to the
agony of your heart, friend.
I am here to have
my share of the agony.
Go away,
Govind.
I have been tarnished.
The one who tries to clean this
will also become dirty.
Have faith
in my friendship,
friend.
A person bathing
in the river gets cleansed
but this does not
leave the river dirty.
Govind!
Why, Govind?
Why?
Why did this happen to me?
Such a grave insult!
What sins did I commit,
Govind?
I am reaping the fruits
for which actions of mine?
Whatever happened,
friend
was neither because
of your actions
nor did you reap the fruits
of any action of yours.
That was merely
an unexpected event.
The Kauravas reaped the fruits
of their past actions
by engaging in
such a grave misdeed.
Friend, this is the meaning
of the principle of actions.
A good deed
leads to a better one
while a bad deed
leads to worse deeds
one after the other.
The life of a person
who commits misdeeds
becomes hell,
friend.
But I am experiencing
the agony, Govind.
Then relinquish
that agony, friend.
But I am experiencing
the agony, Govind.
Then relinquish
that agony, friend.
What happened with you
back in Hastinapur
was not because of your actions.
However, the way you will
transform the forthcoming events
will certainly be
your own actions.
If you fill your heart
with sorrow and animosity
then you too
shall experience hell.
However, why should
their misdeeds
make you go through hell?
Relinquish this animosity,
friend.
Calm your heart down.
A river takes all the filth
tossed into it
and pours it into the ocean.
She cleanses herself this way.
You too
need to pour all your agonies
into the hands of the Almighty.
The Almighty is always prepared
to absorb the agonies
of the entire world.
In other words
I must pardon the Kurus
present in the court?
Yes, friend.
Pardon them
otherwise revenge
shall consume you.
You will not be able
to uphold justice.
Revenge,
misdeeds
justice
good deeds...
What is the difference,
Govind?
When they treated the supreme
Empress of the Aryan region
in such a horrendous manner
what will they do to the
ordinary women of the world?
Think about it,
friend.
Try to visualize the pain
of the world in yours.
Transform your sorrows
into a struggle.
Do understand this,
friend.
The one who lets one's
own sorrow consume oneself
becomes weak.
However,
the person
who deems the sorrows
of the society to be his own
becomes strong.
Thinking solely about
one's own sorrow
is a misdeed.
However, looking for a solution
to the problems of the world
is a good deed.
Yes, friend.
I am asking you
to begin first with Duryodhan
and pardon him.
That will be the first step
towards his destruction.
Look for ways to cleanse the
world of evil men like Duryodhan
and others like him.
Not just for yourself
but for the world.
You must fight for the welfare
of the weak men and women
of the society.
In this fight
for humanitarianism
there will be a lot of bloodshed
yet it shall be a righteous war.
So...
Will you be able to do this?
Yes, Govind.
My heart was
filled with darkness
but you have lit the lamp
of knowledge within it.
'The fishes shown in this scene'
'were generated
using computer graphics.'
Panchali
I threw those dice
with these hands of mine
which reduced my brothers
to the status of servants
and led to the
grave insult of my wife.
Bheem had taken an oath
to burn my hands.
Remember your oath,
Bheem.
Come here
and burn my hands.
No, My Lord.
You need not have
your hands burnt.
I pardon you.
I too must pardon myself,
Panchali
otherwise it will be
impossible for me to live.
Come here,
Vrikodar.
Burn my hands.