'Give this 'Brahmin'
ten cows in charity.'
'The son of Bharadwaj'
'does not accept charity,
Drupad.'
'If you seek alms
then go ahead.'
'I can write two villages
in your name'
'on a gold parchment.'
'But if you talk about rights'
'you will be
sentenced to death.'
I have spent my entire life
burning in the fire of revenge.
You had approached me as a
friend to ask for a few cows.
Had I deemed you my friend
this kingdom would
never have got divided.
I return you your kingdom
that had been conquered,
friend Drupad.
I have committed a crime
by refusing your friendship
and its punishment is
that I should have only
half the kingdom with me.
Pardon me, friend.
You are to die
at the hands of my son
and that is fate.
Everyone dies eventually,
friend.
But today, I am happy to know
that when Dhrishtadyumna
will behead me
it will not be out of anger.
It will certainly be to save me
from some grave crisis.
Then it will be best, guru Drona
if you deem the Prince
to be your son
and impart knowledge to him.
The knowledge imparted by you
will become the medium
of your salvation.
Then it must certainly
be a part of your plan.
That is why, you had
sent me a message to come here.
Vasudev
I had heard a lot
of your greatness
but today...
Today, I have seen it
for myself.
No, guru Drona.
Vasudev
pardon me.
I could not know you.
Your Highness
had you known your daughter's
love and dedication
knowing me would not have
been that difficult.
You have always deemed your
daughters to be your misfortune.
Just look at
Draupadi's greatness.
Look at her dedication.
Even the Kaumodaki mace
of Vasudev Krishna
was pacified by her.
Draupadi!
Stop, Draupadi!
Draupadi...
Draupadi.
Let's go inside, Draupadi.
I cannot go inside, sister.
I have been banished
from the city.
Draupadi, come inside
and apologize to father.
I am certain.
He shall certainly pardon you.
If a chariot loses its wheel
the wheel loses its definition.
But even after
a chariot loses its wheel
it is still called a chariot.
A child is identified
by its father's name.
Please do not bring arrogance
into the picture, Draupadi.
This is not arrogance, sister
but the ones who have
no self-respect
they cannot command
respect from others.
And in order
to have self-respect
it is important for me
to know first
what the purpose of my life is
and what my strengths are.
Goodbye, sister.
Attendant, to honour
Princess Draupadi
make the necessary arrangements
for a grand procession.
Prepare a gold palanquin!
She will enter the royal court
with great pomp and show!
Where is Draupadi?!
Where is she?
Father
Draupadi has decided
to leave Kampilya.
Impossible.
My...
My daughter cannot
renounce her kingdom.
She must certainly be unaware
that today, because
of Vasudev Krishna
I have had a change
of heart, Shikhandini!
S-She must not have gone far.
I shall go and bring her back!
Your Highness
let me
accomplish this task.
Princess Draupadi.
Princess
tell me what you did exactly.
W-Which mantra did you use?
Share that knowledge
with me, Princess.
Help me better myself.
I did not use any mantra.
No, you certainly did.
You pacified my magical
Kaumodaki mace!
How?
You must... You must
teach me that mantra
otherwise...
Otherwise I will jump off
the cliff and kill myself
and you will be
responsible for it.
Stop!
I did not use any mantra.
I had gone there
only to protect my father.
I do not believe you.
Without the knowledge of mantras
you could never
have protected him.
I am leaving.
- But I can
certainly brave the weapon
being charged at him.
In other words, you had
used the mantra of love.
Then I need not fear.
Everyone knows
the mantra of love
but no one is able to use it.
Now, if you wish
to jump off the cliff
you are free to do so.
Go right ahead.
I do not wish
to jump off the cliff.
I am merely looking for
the answers to some questions.
What is the importance
of my birth?
What is the purpose of my life?
To make my father accept
and respect me
what must I do?
So many questions!
And all of them
are worthless.
Your question should be
as to who you are.
If you know yourself
then you will get
all the answers.
Who am I?
Every person is an image
of the Almighty
but no one knows this.
In ash are hidden embers
and in ignorance...
In ignorance is hidden the soul.
And the one who is
unable to see himself
has the desire
of others to see him.
We wish other people to tell us
what we are
and who we are.
But others are surrounded
by their own ignorance.
And the one who
does not know himself
cannot tell us who we are.
In order to know who I am
what must I do?
You must bear righteousness
and in order to
re-establish righteousness
you must make
the necessary efforts.
But how will I
know righteousness?
Before knowing righteousness
you need to know its bases.
Righteousness has five bases
knowledge, love
justice, dedication
and patience.
Did you not ask me, Draupadi
why you were born?
You have been born to acquire
the five bases of righteousness.
The Gods have said
that you will build the
future of the Aryan region.
You will help
re-establish righteousness
in the entire world.
And this will only be possible
when these five bases
namely
knowledge, love
justice
dedication and
patience will be
acquired by you.
Shall we go now?
Life is waiting
for you, Draupadi.
Who are you truly?
Me?
I am the protector of cows.
My friends call me Govind.*
*Among his most common names are Mohan "enchanter", Govinda, "Finder of the cows", or Gopala, "Protector of the cows".
'Krishna, my Krishna.'
'The one who lifted the Govardhan* was Krishna.'
*He lifted the Govardhana hill and prevent the devastation of its pasture land by Indra.
'The one with
a peacock feather...'
Answer a question
of mine, Govind.
Did I truly
pacify that mace?
What do you think, Draupadi?
You had pacified it.
But it had been
pacified for you.
That is why,
the credit goes to you.
Shall we go now
friend?
Why is it taking
so long, Hidimba?
I am almost done
luring them, brother.
Bring them to the village
as soon as possible!
I have promised the ogres
that after years,
they shall have
tasty human meat.
Everyone is awaiting them
back in the village!
Bring them there
as soon as possible!
Come here...
Closer...