Prince Arjun.
Govind was correct.
Mahadev always gives
a definite answer.
In the 'swayamvar,'
that competition
shall await you.
This 'swayamvar' is only
for 'Kshatriya' Kings, Nakul.
We have disguised as 'Brahmins.'
No one will await us there.
We must follow mother's orders
and leave for Naimisharanya
tonight itself.
You shall indeed come
to the 'swayamvar,' Prince.
I have firm faith in it.
That is why, Govind had said
that fate does not
require an invitation.
Listen all!
The Crown Prince
of Vidarbha, Rukmi
is making his entrance!
Listen all!
The Crown Prince of Hastinapur
the son of King Dhritarashtra
Duryodhan, is making
his entrance!
Listen all!
King Karna of Anga
is making his entrance!
Listen all!
The King of Gandhar,
esteemed Brahmin
Pratipal Shakuni
is making his entrance!
Listen all!
The Prince of Hastinapur,
Dusshasan
is making his entrance!
The arrangements look splendid,
King of Gandhar.
And the place has also
been adorned beautifully.
What happens when spring
graces a desert, King of Anga?
One gets to see mirages then.
You still deem Panchal an enemy,
King of Gandhar.
But if an enemy is praiseworthy
brave men praise such an enemy.
You deem bravery to be victory.
I deem victory to be bravery,
King of Anga.
The benevolence
to praise the enemy
does not reside in me.
But guru Drona has befriended
the King of Panchal, uncle.
Now, the King of Panchal
is our friend.
Until proven one's enemy
one who deems
everyone his friends
is a fool.
And until proven one's friend
one who deems
everyone his enemies
is intelligent, my dear!
Drupad is still our enemy.
If he is intelligent
and wishes to
befriend Hastinapur
then he will have
his daughter married
only to my Duryodhan.
Draupadi
Guru Mother is here to have
your hair tied ritualistically.
Why is there a ritual
to tie the hair?
Princess
after marriage women do not
leave their hair open.
Only women who have
lost their husbands
leave their hair open.
I shall tie your hair after
applying this special oil.
Then your husband will
put a hair ornament on it.
Pray for me.
Pray for such a person
to win the 'swayamvar'
whose face would leave
the heart feeling ecstatic.
This place is empty, mother.
And it is also safe.
Son, are we far from Kampilya?
Yes, mother.
Very far.
Do go inside and rest.
We shall then proceed
towards Naimisharanya.
We shall not be able to rest
properly for days then.
And we may also not get
a proper meal for days.
Between this place
and Naimisharanya
is there not a big village
or city, brother Yudhishthir?
No, Bheem.
We must ask for alms
from a nearby village.
You and Nakul
must stay with mother.
The three of us
will get the alms.
No.
If the five of you go together
then you will be able
to get the alms sooner.
But mother
you will be alone here.
What should I fear, son?
I shall close the door.
I shall complete an undertaking
I had made a resolution for.
All of you should go now
but return soon.
Goodbye, mother.
In which direction should we
proceed, brother Yudhishthir?
Kampilya lies
towards North, Arjun.
We cannot proceed that way.
We should proceed
in this direction.
There must be a village
this way.
But will anyone be here?
What if everyone has gone
to see the 'swayamvar?'
Why would everyone go
I've heard, the King of Panchal
has organized a grand event.
And whoever goes there today
will be given
gold coins in charity.
Such an announcement
was also made by him.
And the subjects also wish
to see their Princess, brother.
I have heard that the
Princess is so beautiful
that upon seeing her,
one forgets one's woes.
Many Princes would
have gone there then
with the hope
to forget their woes.
All hail King Drupad!
Bless you all!
I welcome all the Kings
and Princes present here.
All of you must know
that the whole
of the Aryan region
was given a divine present
by the Gods.
From the sacrificial fire
a daughter as pure and radiant
as fire and bearing
divine beauty
was created.
She is like a flag at
the pinnacle of a temple
or at the zenith of a palace!
Similarly, to have my daughter
the Princess of Panchal,
Draupadi
as his wife would be the fortune
of only the most competent
person on the planet!
I ask the 'Kshatriya'
Kings and
Princes present
to have their competence tested
by coming forth!
Crown Prince Dhrishtadyumna
shall elaborate upon
the competition.
I welcome the guests
present here!
Such a device has
been set up here
which cannot be conquered
by an ordinary warrior.
This divine bow
can be lifted only by a person
who has nothing but confidence
in his competence.
If the shadow of doubt
creeps up on someone
then for him,
the weight of this bow
will be more than
that of a mountain.
This bow can be stringed
only by a person
who can free himself
of desire, anger and greed
and knows how to bear it.
To him, art should not be
a medium to obtain anything
but an opportunity to
further learn various arts.
Kings and Princes present here
do you see that fish
revolving in the sky?
Its eye is your goal.
'The fish shown here was made
using computer graphics.'
By looking at its reflection
in the water
the archer needs to
pierce its eye
with
only one arrow.
And the person
who wins this competition
will be married
to my beloved sister.
My dear, can you do it?
No, uncle.
I am not a proficient archer.
And uncle
no woman can be
important enough
for whom I shall
have to bear insult.
My dear
not Draupadi
but the relationship
with Panchal is important.
You know quite well
that Gandhar, Anga Pradesh,
Hastinapur
and even Ashwatthama's
half of Panchal
is on our side.
If Drupad's half of Panchal
also comes to our side
then very soon
you may become the master
of the entire Aryan region.
I cannot do it, uncle!
No one can win this competition.
This is not a 'swayamvar'
but a scheme to insult
all the Kings.
If they were truly looking
for a competent warrior
then they would also have
organized a fight with maces
and the ones involving
swords and spears too!
Who, in the whole
of the Aryan region
can win this competition?
I can win it, friend.
Had this competition not been
a part of a 'swayamvar'
I would have achieved this feat.
But you can still win
the competition, King of Anga.
No, King of Gandhar.
The rank of the son-in-law
of a big kingdom like Panchal
lies above that of
Crown Prince Duryodhan
and I cannot permit it.
But you can certainly transfer
the benefit of your victory
to your friend, King of Anga.
You must win the competition
on behalf of Duryodhan
and have him married
to the Princess.
But would it be correct?
Would winning a wife
for someone else
be appropriate?
Correct...
Why not?
The son of Ganga, Bhishma
has done this all his life.
If Duryodhan permits you
then you may take part
in the competition.
I give you the permission,
friend King of Anga.
You must indeed
win this maiden for me.
As you say, friend.
I shall take part
in this competition.