Allows us to start the battle
or order us to put down
our hands!
Brother, if grandsire do not give
his approval for battle,
will you put down your weapon?
Indeed!
Sire!
Issue an order to give up!
Sire! You know that
in this battlefield
the right to issue orders
on behalf of my father
has been given to me!
Heed my order
and get them to give up!
This is an order from the chief commander!
- Duryodhana!
My body is bound to serve
Hastinapur throne!
My heart is bound
and so too my mind...
But my mind is constrained by my duty.
Only my soul is free
like any other souls!
My soul can't issue
command or permission!
That very soul can
give rise to both curse
or gift.
Sons of Pandu!
I bestow my blessings to you!
In this war
punish all your enemies to death!
Uphold justice!
Go forward and kill me!
May you be victorious!
Please, your majesty!
Your majesty!
Her Majesty has organized 'Mrityunjay'* chant...
*Special mantra for Mahadev/Shiva.
Majesty, tread carefully!
Her Majesty has hosted
a 'Mrityunjay'
and offerings of milk!
Even in unknown surroundings,
I've never tripped.
But, these days...
My own royal chamber is like getting
in my way, Sanjay!
It is evident today
that in the truest sense
I have turned blind,
Sanjay!
Today, in the truest sense
I have turned blind.
Brother!
Great Sage Vyas has arrived!
Greetings, great sage!
- May you be prosperous!
Gandhari!
Great sage!
Today I long to hear
a few words from you!
Please help me reassure my heart.
I don't have any knowledge on how
to instill courage in yourself,
Majesty.
I'm just here to deliver
an unfortunate news.
Her majesty Satyavati
unfortunately has passed away!
Oh sage!
Her majesty's passed away!
- Yes, Vidur!
Animals and birds
afraid of the dark.
Therefore, they close their eyes
when the sun sets.
Now the whole Aryan clan
and Kuru dynasty
will sink into a terrible darkness!
I have a request, your majesty,
that it is time for you to move on
for the next world!
Her majesty was the ruler
of the Kuru dynasty.
Therefore I have brought
her urn.
Here,
please accept it, Dhritarashtra.
You will receive more of
such ash urn, majesty!
Her majesty Satyavati leads a good life, that's
why she has a long life.
Why is your hands are shaking while
receiving her urn?
Learning this news, how can you bear
the death of countless youth?
What will be my sons' fate,
sage?
Who will win
in this war?
What is the future
of the Kuru dynasty?
I want to know, great sage!
We sculpt our future
with our past, majesty!
If you want to know the future
then comprehend this moment.
Understand it,
then you will finally know the future.
If you desire to witness this battle
I will grant you a divine vision!
Come and sit right here,
you can watch what is happening at Kurukhsetra.
No, great sage!
No!
I do not have the courage like that anymore.
Gandhari
do you want to have this divine vision?
No, great sage!
With the oath that I had made,
I have not witnessed joy
throughout life.
So, now
why would I watch
the face of death?
I...
I've cloaked myself
with the veil of hope!
So I do not need to
face realities!
So...
So I do not need to know the truth!
Vidur
do you want to have this divine vision?
I'm sorry, great sage!
If I wanted to watch
destruction
I will surely now present
on the battlefield.
Great sage!
If you feel that it is fate,
then please grant me with
that divine vision,
through Sanjay.
I will hear the progress
of battle from him.
Sanjay!
- Yes, Your Majesty!
Always sow the seeds of enmity,
always satisfied with arrogance,
that is who you are, majesty.
Maybe it is time for you to
witness the results of it all.
This vision seems like enemy to the other eyes,
am I right, majesty?
Sanjay, I give you
this divine vision.
Vasudev!
Krishna...
Before the conch is blown
I want to check the army
from both sides.
Please drive the chariot slowly
in between of the two armies!
What do you want to see, Arjun?
To which direction will you see?
And what do you want to confirm?
Today, why do you want
to observe the whole army in the battlefield?
I want to observe the enemy's army, Krishna!
And my own troops as well.
I want to know
in this war, whose death
will establish justice,
and whose death will uphold injustice.
I just want to know
what would I accomplish in this terrible war
and what would I lose.
You have made sacrifice just coming
to this battlefield, Arjun.
So, why do you ponder over
gains and losses in vain?
A charity is one
where the donor loses
and seekers profit.
But the sacrifice is one
where donors give and all the world benefit!
However, Madhav!
I'm not here for charity.
Countless soldiers here are to lay down their lives.
I want to make sure
if in this great battle
whether I would
destroy injustice
or along I will jeopardize justice too.
You will do all of this now, Arjun?
Do you have the power of creation and destruction?
Supreme God himself effects creation
and destruction, Arjun!
You are a mere means!
Why do you intend to bear
responsibility to yourself
and let your vanity grows?
I have told you, Arjun!
People who learn the fact that he
does not own anything
is one to achieve something important!
Maybe you forgot.
Therefore see it, Arjun!
Go ahead and look
what you want to!
Because if the donor's hand tremble
before doing charity,
actions are not taken into account
in the truest sense!