Everyone in this world is
born with relevant powers.
But fear, endearment
and desire are reasons
that prevent the human
race from making an effort.
Those who don't try can
never succeed, my dear.
But your life could have
been put at risk.
My dear, life is always at risk.
Whenever an attempt is made
the chances of success
and failure
are divided in equal proportions
but if there is no attempt
the chances of failure
become a certainty.
Remember this my children
standing up against someone's
atrocities and injustice
can bring about
only one kind of harm...
At worst, you may die.
But to decide against
making an attempt
out of fear or endearment
can bring about two
certain kinds of harms.
Our soul succumbs
and the tyrants grow
fonder of injustice.
Am I right, my friend?
Please continue with
the tales, sire.
How did my uncle help the
Yadavs become prosperous again.
Prince Abhimanyu,
despite being his elder
I bow down in respect to the
greatest of the Yadavs, Krishna.
Because he has taught all
of us the music of life.
He has made
our lives prosperous.
Not only with money but
he has also left us richer
in the heart,
our thoughts and our souls.
Vrindavan witnesses music,
there is celebration all around.
Flowers add glitter to the trees
the animals seem
delighted in the forests.
The Yadavs have discovered
laughter, happiness
and great luck.
When everyone's feet
discovered dance
the flute came to prominence.
[FLUTE PLAYING]
Krishna, haven't you
begun with the act yet?
It can only begin
when Radha arrives.
[SONG]
Our entire village
can afford to donate 100 cows,
hermits.
That's not acceptable, Nand.
You'll have to donate 1000 cows.
Along with that, you will have
to donate wealth, grains, gold
et cetera in good quantity.
Nand, are you not aware
of Lord Indra's wrath?
The land on which you
reside is Lord Indra's region.
If you go against Lord Indra,
you are bound to suffer.
The entire society contributes
to Lord Indra's yajna.
You are not an exception.
When you went against
a less important king
you were exiled from Gokul
if the Lord of Lords
is upset with you
where on earth
will you find refuge?
But how can we donate
all that we have earned
after an entire
year's struggle, sire.
When Lord Indra killed Vritasur* and saved the human race
*A serpent or dragon, the personification of drought.
humans decided to show
support by worshipping him.
But Vritasur had attacked
the heavens.
Lord Indra had killed
Vritasur to protect himself
and not the humans.
You are an imbecile young man.
You are yet to witness
Lord Indra's wrath.
Hermit, are you saying that we
perform the yajna out of fear?
But fear takes away
from a human's soul.
Only when the devotion
is spurred by love
can the human soul
be prosperous.
What kind of devotion
deprives a man of his wealth?
Young man, your arguments
are pointless.
Lord Indra's yajna will
have to be performed
and it surely calls
for donation.
The yajna will begin
on the full moon night
of the month of asaadh.*
*June-July.
Make sure you are present
there with all the donations
along with the entire society.
Greetings.
Nand,
we'll have to abide by
the traditions.
The world is not run by
young and pointless thoughts.
But father, the only one
who forms the basis of life
should be worshipped.
Why should we worship
the one who threatens life?
What would you suggest, Krishna?
Father, we should
worship the Govardhan hill
which gives life to our cows.
We will surely hold Lord
Indra's yajna but only when
it is done with affection
and respect.
Father, fear cannot
be worshipped.
[MAN CHANTING]
Brother, have a look.
There are ample ghee pots.
Yes.
I can drink more ghee
than Lord Agni.
Okay, brother.
Prove it then.
Chitrar, have a look,
the place of yajna
has woods to be burnt.
Madhumangal, you know what
to do, right? - Yes, indeed!
Balram, shall we go?
- Let's go.
Ominous!
That's an ominous sign!
The holy place of
fire has been spoilt.
The yajna has been corrupted.
But, priest, I had brought
the ghee pot.
Go and bring
another pot of ghee.
Also, bring new offerings
as the yajna will have to be
started all over again.
Go.
- Okay, priest!
Have a look at that.
The children are
stealing the offertory.
Sire, this is an ominous sign.
This is the worst
that could happen.
The yajna has been corrupted.
Nand, you have gone
against our traditions
by paying heed to young men.
If Lord Indra is upset,
who will protect us?
My friend, when the Sun's
heat is at its warmest
and the water on land dries up
who gives us the water?
Govardhan hill.
Who provides us with
vegetables, flowers and wood?
We get all of this
from the Govardhan hill.
I find Krishna's argument
legitimate.
Govardhan hill protects
and nourishes us.
You are a fool!
That hill is just
a pile of rocks.
Lord Indra is a living power.
He is alive!
Look at this, Nand and tell me.
Who is more powerful than Indra?
Reverence is more powerful
than the Gods, sire.
We will not halt
the Govardhan yajna.
[LIGHTING SOUND]
Khirsna has put all our lives at stake.
There is still time.
Seek forgiveness from Lord Indra.
Lord Govardhan, help us.
[YELLING]
Khrisna!
The Govardhan hill will not able to
stand up to Lord Indra's wrath.
Khrisna, all of us will die.
Khrisna, you have humbled me today.
But that was not my intention.
I was only tyring to boost my own
and my Yadav clan's self confidence.
I am very pleased with you.
I wish to grant you blessing.
If you really wish to bless me.
Then suggest me a way of placing this hill down.
I will surely help you with that, Khrisna.
But the path of rightousness
that you have chosen,
will always be a tough one to tread.
If you part ways with it,
those who seek to follow you
will be left wandering, Khrisna.
I bow down to you.