In everyone's life,
there comes an event
when one determines
to disclose a truth
but the truth isn't able
to come out of the mouth.
Some fear embraces the heart.
Talking about an incident
or event
or else talking about
any mistake which one commits...
Is that a true feeling?
No.
This is just a fact.
That means, just disclosing
exactly what happened
is usual.
But sometimes, even while
disclosing that fact
one feels scared.
Perhaps, one thinks about
the emotions of someone else.
They even hesitate to speak
thinking it would hurt someone.
So...what's truth?
Have we ever thought about it?
When someone reveals a fact
even though the fear exists
that's called the truth.
In reality, truth is nothing
but another name of courage.
To be courageous one needn't
wait for the right time
because courageousness
is the nature of the soul.
In other words
isn't every moment right enough
to disclose the truth?
Think about it.
'After a few months.'
Earlier, messages were being
conveyed through the drum beats.
But now, we have
stopped receiving messages
from the battlefield.
We'll receive a message.
And the message
will surely have a good news.
There is a good news,
Queen Mother.
King Pandu has defeated
his enemies in the battle.
I had faith
that in the first battle itself
Pandu will achieve victory.
Without any controversy,
he has proved himself
as an emperor.
Organise a celebration
in the province.
Nothing should be lacking
in the welcome ceremony.
The period of your happiness
has started, Kunti.
On the very first day
of marriage
if a husband goes far away
I can understand how miserable
a wife feels.
I have no regrets,
sister-in-law.
The first and foremost right
of a king is on his throne.
To be at the second place
I don't have any objection.
- Never say so, Kunti.
When a husband doesn't
pay attention to his wife
her life becomes miserable.
I wish, you always be
your husband's priority.
Now it's time to decorate
your room again.
Maid, go with the other maids
and decorate the king's room
in the best manner.
After the news of victory,
what other news can there be?
Is there any...bad news?
No, grandsire. The news
is not bad but...
What's the news, Chief Minister?
The news is
we, I mean, King Pandu
helped the province Madra
and protected it
from a fierce war.
Subsequently, the king of Madra
requested King Pandu...
He must...
He must have requested.
To refrain His Majesty
from refusing
he must have requested
in a way that... - Vidur
be clear about what
you wish to say.
Queen Mother, the king of Madra
had made King Pandu
his son-in-law.
King Pandu is coming here
with his second wife.
Make arrangements to welcome
King Pandu
and his newlywed wife,
Chief Minister.
'A king has many queens.'
'If King Pandu
does another marriage'
'this truth will become
troublesome for your life.'
'As it is, a secret is always
troublesome for a woman.'
The arrival of the second wife
of King Pandu in Hastinapur
and into his private chambers
is gladly welcome.
I had a fear that the news
of second marriage of Pandu
will make Kunti sulk.
I felt she wouldn't
welcome Madri
but look, sister
Kunti accepted Madri as
if they were sisters by blood.
The way clothes conceal wounds
similarly, words cloak
feelings, Ambalika.
Anyway, whatever I can
behold exudes auspiciousness.
You trust your eyes
but I have learnt from my son
that eyes seldom
are trustworthy.
Greetings, brother.
Hastinapur and I are
proud of you, Pandu.
Even I am proud of my victory.
On this occasion of victory
I would like to make
an announcement.
Ever since my childhood
I have looked up to only
one warrior.
He never accepted defeat.
He has always celebrated
his struggle.
With his robust character
he has crossed all boundaries
and become the most supreme.
Every move I made in the war was
done following his footsteps.
I always tried to be
worthy of him.
And this is the reason
behind my victory.
And this warrior is the biggest
inspiration of my life
and he is my elder
brother Dhritarashtra.
Pandu...
- Yes, brother...
This victory is not mine
but yours.
Only yours...
See...
It's more like he got
what he wanted
without putting in any efforts.
Stay blessed.
Greetings, grandsire.
I wish you a long life.
Pandu, you have shown
immense valour.
We are proud of you, Pandu.
You must be tired.
Victory turns every
pain into pleasure.
No, Pandu...
Your body gets relief from pain
only after a proper rest.
You need to rest.
For a few months,
along with your wives
you shall go
on a forest excursion.
And that too immediately.
But, Queen Mother...
Pandu...
I don't want any
arguments.
It's a right of your wives
to spend some time with you.
This is an order.
Yes, Queen Mother.
Yours
and the king's room
is on the other side,
Madri.
Rambha!
Yes, Your Highness.
Show Madri
the way to her room.
What are you doing?
I am washing your feet
with my tears, sister.
I heard about
the king's valour in the battle.
And
I lost my heart to
him, sister.
But I didn't know
that His Highness
is already married.
I also didn't know that on
the very next day of marriage
he had to leave
for the battle.
Please forgive me, sister.
During our journey itself,
His Highness told me
that I have to apologise to you
the minute I get here.
I have wronged you.
But an unintentional
wrongful deed
is worthy of being excused,
right, sister?
Won't you accept your
younger sister's apology?
You are not at fault,
Madri.
Don't be sad.
In this palace you will
receive the love and respect
that I get.
After hearing your words
I feel at peace, sister.
I was thinking about you
throughout the journey.
Whether or not to be a subject
of His Highness' affection
I would have to
compete with you.
Or if I would lose to you
in this competition.
I had such doubts.
There is no competition
between us.
That I understood
on seeing you.
I am younger than you
and also much prettier.
If there would be
no competition between us
that would be best for you.
I will leave now.
His Highness must be
waiting for me.
The state of Queen Kunti
saddens me, my lady.
Even I feel sad, Sukhda.
But kings having more
than one wife
is a tradition.
In the presence of pain
and the absence of options
rather than accepting the same
it is referred to
as tradition.
But I completely
trust Pandu.
He will treat both his
wives equally.
Injustice isn't a part of
Pandu's nature.
And neither a part of
his ethics.
Haven't Kunti and Madri gone
with Pandu
on an excursion to the forest?
Just wait and watch
Kunti and Madri will
definitely get along.
Yes, my lady.
Queen Kunti's nature
itself is as such
that anyone would
get along.
And both the wives will receive
love from their husband.
Not being able to receive
a husband's love
is the greatest misfortune.
Greetings, Elder Queen.
Prince Dhritarashtra has sent
a message for you
to come to his chamber.
He has called me!
Yes, Your Highness.
He has called for you.