In this war whoever
is a hurdle to punishing
the sons of Dhritarashtra
must be slain!
Perhaps slaying Grandsire
isn't inevitable, Krishna.
Today he disarmed our eldest brother
but did not slay him.
Therefore, in this battle of justice
even Grandsire hopes for our victory.
And until he does not
interfere in our path to victory
slaying him isn't inevitable.
And just like today
even tomorrow
we shall reach Prince Duryodhan.
It's not just battles, Arjun
but every moment of life
gives us new experiences.
Those who plan based on past
experiences are disappointed.
If Grandsire's situations
and thoughts undergo a change
we should not face disappointment.
Greetings, Grandsire!
If you feel well, shall we
decide about strategies
for tomorrow.
With the help of a miracle
a person may
perhaps keep a lamp's flame lit
and stable amidst strong wind.
But if the wick of the lamp is dampened
its flame cannot be kept lit and stable.
Even the wick of my soul
is drenched with tears.
The very Yudhishtir, to see whom
upon the throne of Hastinapur
I enslaved myself to the
throne of Hastinapur forever
today...
Today I had to enslave
that Yudhishtir himself.
How can I feel well, Master Drona
in this battlefield?
But...
But battle plans and strategies
need to be discussed.
Have a seat.
What is your advice, Master Drona?
There exists a very
common battle formation.
Garland formation!
With this we can distribute
our army into smaller clusters
and make an attack.
No, Master Drona!
With this battle formation
we cannot supervise the activity
of the entire army.
Ought to this
either one of the sons
of Dhritarashtra may die
or one of the sons of Pandu could die.
Until my last breath I cannot bear
the burden of the death of
my children and grandchildren.
Therefore, today
on the battlefield
I captivated Yudhishtir.
I did not slay him.
I could not slay him,
Master Drona.
I could not.
In this battle
I have a single goal, Master Drona.
I cannot let anyone
among the Kuru clan die.
We must soon arrest Yudhishtir
and put an end to this war!
Prince!
What is the motive behind
summoning all these warriors?
Dear friend Karna, brace yourself.
Tomorrow at dawn you shall
be present at the battlefield
and exhibit your skill!
I believe you
won't break my trust.
My lad...
- Be quiet!
Be quiet, uncle!
Your advice has already
caused me enough damage!
It was your advice to yield to
Grandsire Bheeshma's insistence
and not to let my friend
Karna enter the battlefield.
What was the result of that?
Today you may have witnessed
that Grandsire Bheeshma stays
at the midst of our army
but fights on behalf of the enemy!
Prince, had you and your brothers
not been under my protection
all of you would perish
on the very first day of battle.
Honour is worthier than one's life.
And honour is measured
by trust, Grandsire.
You have broken my trust
and strangulated my honour!
You killed not just my honour
but the honour of all of Hastinapur.
You have brought shame upon
the name of King Shantanu!
Prince Duryodhan!
Had I not sworn to protect you
I would slay you right now!
Then raise your weapon!
Let's engage in a duel,
Grandsire Bheeshma!
The embracer of justice
and the son of Ganga!
Let us test today
as to how mighty
these treacherous arms are!
He had the chance
to slay Yudhishtir!
But he did not do that!
Had you slain Yudhishtir
the battle would end today,
Grandsire!
Shame on you!
Friend Karna!
I order you
as the King of Hastinapur.
Tomorrow you shall
enter the battlefield!
You are aware of my
decision as well, Duryodhan.
If your friend Karna even steps
onto the battlefield tomorrow
I shall not fight this battle!
In that case, do no fight the battle.
Your presence on the battlefield
makes no difference to me.
In fact, if you are not
present on the battlefield
I shall attain victory
even more easily.
Now I do not need you.
Duryodhan!
A necklace is held worthy
only when it has pearls in it
and is assumed respectable too!
If a pearl falls off a
necklace it becomes worthless!
Master Drona,
before storming at me
think of what is just yourself!
Grandsire Bheeshma!
Even you better ponder upon your duties!
You have embraced the pride
of being just all your life!
Now tell me, where is your justice?
You had sworn to guard
the throne of Hastinapur!
If today, you renounce the battlefield
what about that oath of
yours, Grandsire Bheeshma?
'I will spend my life
not as the King of Hastinapur'
'but as a servant to it!'
'Until you are seated upon the
throne of Hastinapur as King'
'until then I shall be a
servant to you and Hastinapur'
'and abide by your every order!'
Yes, Grandsire Bheeshma!
Under any circumstance
you have no rights at all
to renounce the battlefield!
Whether my friend Karna fights or not
you shall have to fight this battle!
Yes, Grandsire Bheeshma!
Think deeply!
You are in a huge moral dilemma!
You decide, Grandsire
as to which one out of your two pledges
would you like to fulfill!
Will you defend Hastinapur
or renounce the battlefield upon
seeing Karna enter the battle?
Ponder over it, Grandsire.
Do you wish to renounce your duty
and perish like a pest
in the dirt
or embrace your duty
and justify your death?
My decision is my friend Karna...
- Wait, friend!
Do not insult Grandsire
in this manner.
I have utmost faith
that Grandsire shall
not break your trust.
Let him fight the battle!
Moreover, I am always at your disposal
ready to lay down my life!
My lad!
The armoured one speaks wisely!
Duryodhan, my lad,
have mercy on Grandsire.
Any aged one's death should
not be meddled with, lad.
Very well, if you all insist
I can give him one chance.
But what shall I gain from it?
I solemnly swear
that until my death
I shall not renounce the battlefield.
Every moment, I shall stand
on the battlefield.
The way ought to Lord Shiva's fiery 'Rudra Tandav'*
*A divine dance of Shiva that depicts his violent nature.
the entire world was
plunged into darkness
similarly
I will erase all hope of victory
from the enemy's heart!
I shall obliterate
the entire army of the enemy!
Why do the winds
seem so strong, Krishna?
These are the winds of change, Draupadi!
Someone's circumstances
have undergone a change.
Mindsets have changed.
And now situations
shall change as well.
Would this change
become the reason of
our sorrow, O' Krishna?
Change does not bring
about sorrow, good lady
but it does bring about pain.
Therefore a human
always fears change.
He tries to oppose it.
But, good lady
change is the law of nature!
And joy...
Joy is a product of creation.
That implies, no matter
what pain change cause to one
in the end he does find joy.
Some feel the joy of success
while some feel
the joy of liberation.
Grandsire!
What formation do we assume
for tomorrow's battle?
What is the strategy?
Strategy?
There is just one strategy,
Master Drona?
The strategy to unleash rivers of blood!
Tomorrow I shall be at the
forefront of the army
and unleash chaos!
Witnessing the agony in your heart
I feel immensely sad.
But Grandsire,
you are abiding by duty.
But when it is time
to abide by one's duty
that time it is inappropriate
to express any grief
nor any affection.
I know, Master Drona!
Living up to the promise
made to my father is my duty.
Tomorrow, at dawn when I
shall enter the battlefield
love, affection, sacrifice,
hatred, pain, sorrow...
I shall renounce all of these!
My hands shall wield a bow
and the burden of duty
shall be over my head.
This battlefield
shall devour all possibilities
of a just kingdom.
All lights of Hastinapur
shall be extinguished by me.
But I...
I shall not mourn for it, Master Drona!
Just one night!
All the sorrows in my heart
shall crush all my feelings
by the end of this night
and tomorrow, at dawn
I shall step
onto the battlefield
like a heartless beast
driven solely by thirst for blood!