Greetings, Minister.
Listen carefully.
Henceforth, you shall have
only one task.
You must monitor all activities
of the King of Anga, Karna
and inform the same to me.
Do remember.
Each sentence spoken
by the King of Anga, Karna
and every word uttered by him
should register in your mind
and you must
remember everything.
As you say.
Mother Radha.
Son.
Karna!
Son!
I
shall stay here tonight,
mother Radha.
I have forgotten the taste
of the food made by you.
I hope, you will
feed me yourself.
Son, you...
Why do you seem so agitated?
What is it, son?
T-Tell me, son!
Do not ask him anything, Radha.
Let him catch his breath first.
The major flaw of the
environment of a palace
is that it is serene
on the surface
but very soon, it ignites
a fire within one's heart.
An unrighteous person's heart
burns with the fire of desire
but that of a righteous person
burns with the fire of remorse.
Son! That place
is not right, son.
Please give up the greed
of being a King.
Come back, son.
Stay in your home with us.
That is not possible, mother.
I...
I cannot forsake my friend.
That is why, I had told you
that we would nourish this house
with righteousness, Radhe
because I knew
that you would have to be a part
of unrighteousness there.
If you befriend a serpent
it is bound to bite you.
Prince Duryodhan is not
a serpent, father!
Even he has met with injustice!
And even this is true
that resorting to righteousness
will not aid him
in having his right.
If you are certain
that Duryodhan's approach
is the only possible solution
then why are you
so unhappy, son?
Do not ask me that, father.
I have given my word
to Prince Duryodhan.
When the pillars of a temple
collapse, it causes no grief.
But when
the idol in the temple's
sanctuary breaks
it gives birth to
unrighteousness, father.
This is the fire
that burns me up.
Tell me how to put out
this fire, father.
Please tell me how to
put out this fire.
Charity.
Engage in charity, son
because charity is the
only form of meditation
that washes away all sins.
And also pray that
may Duryodhan's plan
never succeed
may your friend be saved
from committing sins
and may you be saved too.
Greetings, Crown Prince!
- Greetings.
Greetings, Her Highness!
- Bless you.
Do come in.
This place is outside the city
of Varnavrat, Purochan.
Indeed, Crown Prince.
I had the ambition of making
a grand palace for all of you.
And I could never have got
so much space within the city.
That is why, I had the palace
constructed here, Crown Prince.
Where?
Beneath the earth?
Why are you jesting,
Prince Bheem?
It is right there.
Let me show you.
Do come in, Her Highness.
Please enter.
Purochan, before we enter
we must light a lamp
at the entrance.
I-Indeed.
Certainly, Her Highness.
Do come in.
Do come in, Her Highness.
This way.
Do come in, Crown Prince.
Why bother, Her Highness?
Let me hold it.
Please enter.
This palace is miraculous,
Crown Prince.
My sons and I have
put a lot of labour
into constructing it.
We have poured all our knowledge
into building this palace.
Wonderful, Purochan.
Never have I seen
such a beautiful palace.
Does the entire palace get
illuminated with only moonlight?
Indeed, Crown Prince.
We have placed mirrors
in such a way here
that moonlight is
sufficient for lighting.
There is no need to light
even a single lamp.
Now, a more beautiful
structure than this
can be made only by Lord Vishwakarma.*
*Ultimate reality (later developed as Brahman), the "Principal Architect of the Universe".
Splendid!
Marvellous, Purochan.
Brother Yudhishthir
you should reward Purochan
for this lovely creation of his.
To have all of you reside
in the palace made by me
is more than a reward
to me, Prince Bheem.
On a new moon night
how does the palace
get illuminated?
On a new moon night
how does the palace
get illuminated?
A-Actually...
Actually...
- Sahadev
who is going to stay here
until the new moon?
Why do you worry unnecessarily?
Just think of how many mirrors
are present in this palace.
Nakul is going to be
very pleased.
Incidentally, the question
is a valid one, Purochan.
How does the palace get
illuminated on a new moon night?
We will have to
light torches then.
No, Crown Prince!
I will certainly think of a way
before the new moon night.
Brother, your room must
also be quite marvellous.
Let's have a look.
I will be there.
Let's go, mother.
I forgot to tell Purochan as to
where to put that lamp.
What happened, Purochan?
Pardon me, Her Highness.
I dropped the lamp.
That is
an ill omen, Purochan.
The person who drops a lamp
meets with misfortune.
Now, light the lamp again
and place it near the entrance.
As you say, Her Highness.
He said that the cornerstone
of a temple is its pillars
and the sanctity of the temple
lies in the idol situated
in the temple's sanctuary.
When the pillars
of a temple collapse
it causes no grief.
But when the idol in the
temple's sanctuary breaks
it gives birth
to unrighteousness.
Pillars are the cornerstone
of a temple...
Which temple was the
King of Anga talking about?
I could not
understand that, Minister
but the King of Anga
seemed exceedingly unhappy.
As though he was
experiencing hell itself.
Duryodhan's enemies are
certainly the Pandavas
but why would the King of Anga
compare them to the
pillars of a temple?
When the idol in the
temple's sanctuary breaks...
He...
He was talking about
the Pandavas'
mother, Her Highness?
Duryodhan must certainly be
planning to kill sister-in-law
and her sons in Varnavrat.
I must talk to uncle at once.