I banish you and your family
from the kingdom this instant!
Leave Hastinapur
at the earliest!
You are banishing us...
Uncle
what crime are you
punishing us for?
Crime?!
You have come to this court
after committing a grave sin
Yudhishthir
and yet you ask me
what your crime is?!
The soul of my beloved
younger brother Pandu
must be crying bitterly
in the heavens today!
My ancestors must be hurt
and ashamed because of you!
Our deed is no sin, uncle.
The chaste daughter
of the Great Sage Kandu
Marisha, had married
ten Prachetas.
Marisha had given birth
to Prajapati Daksh, uncle.
And that is what led to
the genesis of the creation.
Had marrying more than
one man been a sin
the entire human race
would have been deemed
the fruit of that sin, uncle.
Sins and merits do not
depend upon a deed.
The intention behind the deed...
Was it righteous or devious...
Sins and merits depend upon
the intention behind the deed.
But the ones who see deviousness
as the source of merits...
How can such people have the
intelligence to understand sins?
Brother Duryodhan
an elephant
putting dirt on its head
should not be deemed
a devious behaviour.
In order to rid itself
of parasites
it engages in such
an unusual behaviour.
Man also comes across situations
where resorting
to atypical solutions
is the only way out.
Grandsire Bhishma
has also accepted
that our deed
is a righteous one.
Grandsire
I request you
to say something.
Your Highness
the situation that arose
in Kampilya...
I gathered information about it.
Then I discussed it with Vidur.
After scrutinizing it
from every possible angle
and in order to solve
this peculiar problem
by also looking into
other possible alternatives
they took this decision.
This decision of theirs
has the support of
the Great Sage Vyas.
This is an unrighteous deed
Yet
the sons of Pandu
and the Princess of Panchal
are guiltless.
We must accept their marriage.
Under no circumstance
will I accept it,
great Bhishma!
The words of a person
and the decision of a King
are two different things, uncle!
Irrespective of what an esteemed
person of a society says
rules are made by
the ruler of a kingdom
only after considering
all the strata of the society
including the most destitute,
ignorant and inferior, uncle!
And I am the King of Hastinapur.
I, Dhritarashtra, am the King
of the Kuru dynasty.
Any deed that encourages
wrong doers in the future
cannot be accepted by me, uncle.
I do not accept it
under any circumstance!
Your Highness
we five brothers and our wife
are ready to walk through a pyre
before the entire society
to prove our innocence!
Even the wrong doers
of the society will know
that after committing a deed
that seems unrighteous
they too will have to
walk through a pyre.
And Your Highness
poisoning a child and then
throwing him in the river
before letting a warrior
reach the arena
attempting to kill him
under a debris of rocks
and conspiring to kill family
by burning them in a palace
made of lac and clarified butter
are also deeds
which can encourage wrong doers.
If one continues committing
such deeds, Your Highness
then the throne of Hastinapur
will be left with no heir!
Your Highness!
Your Highness
I had pleaded to you
last night itself
to give my nephews,
my darlings
the permission to go to Gandhar
with me and settle there.
Your Highness,
your nephews and mine
cannot reside
in the same kingdom.
First, they commit such a
grave unrighteous deed
and to top it all,
they are accusing people!
Shame on them!
Uncle is correct, father.
What else can these people do?
A woman who has
relationships with five men
can neither know
what righteousness is
nor can she teach it
to her husbands.
Brother Duryodhan!
The one who insulted Panchali
shall be beheaded by me!
- Arjun!
Pardon me, Your Highness
but a person who does nothing
to defend his wife's honour
can only be a corpse!
He cannot be alive.
- Be quiet!
For taking to arms
in the royal court
I sentence you to death, Arjun!
You cannot sentence him
to death, Your Highness.
Your daughter-in-law
the future of this dynasty
the fortune of this lineage
was insulted by a person
but you did not sentence him
to death, Your Highness!
That is why, someone
who defends his wife's honour
cannot be sentenced to death
by you, Your Highness!
You can only
challenge him to a battle!
And I accept the challenge
to a battle!
To defend Draupadi's honour,
five formidable forces
the five Pandavas will rise
to the occasion, Duryodhan!
You will be annihilated!
Annihilated!
Stop!
Insulting the dynasty's
daughter-in-law
being unjust to the Crown Prince
creating an environment
of a battlefield in the court...
For how long will this
sacred court of Hastinapur
keep getting tainted
by your sons, Your Highness?!
My sons...
I cannot stay in this court
even a moment longer!
Your Highness
when a building
is feared to collapse
intelligent people
construct supportive structures
in it as a preventive measure.
I fear, Your Highness
that in order to protect
the Kuru dynasty
it is time now
to divide the kingdom.