Who is the real
King of Panchal, Drupad?
You have been defeated,
Kuru Prince!
The 104 brothers of yours
have also been captured!
Today, your grandfather
will be very proud
upon knowing of your capability!
Did your teacher
not teach you how to navigate
through this discus formation?
This is the discus formation
of King Drupad!
King Drupad's discus formation!
I will not kill you!
I will have your head shaved
and a donkey will be your ride
back to Hastinapur!
But before that
your grandfather
will have to come here!
Bhishma will have to come here!
Bhishma!
My daughter Shikhandini
will avenge my father's defeat.
On one hand, there are
the lives of the 105 Princes!
And on the other
the life of Bhishma!
Your Majesty,
they are just 100 Princes.
How is that possible?
The messenger had said that
105 Princes were coming
to fight in the battle!
Where are the other five?
Arjun, only you can navigate
through this discus formation.
You shall lead.
- As you say.
Not from there,
brother Yudhishthir.
From the West.
Brother Bheem, Nakul, Sahadev
do not enter from the gates.
The soldiers have
formed a fortress.
There is no
visible entrance, Arjun.
More soldiers?
Does no one know
anything about fighting?
Come here...
Come here.
Friend, those soldiers
are my enemies.
But their horses are my friends.
Tell them to let me through.
This is my discus formation!
Enter it, if you can!
Arjun, you need to
find a way out of this.
We must get back
to our brothers.
Do you remember
what mother said?
Together, we are indestructible.
If I knew, there would be
so many soldiers
I would have had a bigger meal.
Now, I need to have
a big meal after the battle.
Brother Bheem
did you defeat
just these many soldiers?
But I did not fall.
Then here you go.
Let's go, Nakul.
Drupad and the Kauravas
must be in there
surrounded by the soldiers.
We need to go there.
Sahadev, free all our brothers.
Must I do this?
Do not say that, Sahadev.
They are our brothers.
Them being captured
is our defeat.
Duryodhan, start freeing
the rest of our brothers.
We do not require your help.
Our father can free us.
Duryodhan, 105 of us
Kuru Princes have come here.
We need to be victorious
as a team.
We are the Kauravas
and you five are the Pandavas.
Never forget this.
Besides
if we could not
find a way out of this
then how will the five of you
figure it out?
Besides
if we could not
find a way out of this
then how will the five of you
figure it out?
Nakul!
Accept your defeat, King Drupad.
King Drupad who?
Are you certain Kuru Prince
that I am the King of Panchal
Drupad?
Or maybe I am
the King of Panchal, Drupad!
King Drupad who?
Are you certain Kuru Prince
that I am
the King of Panchal, Drupad?
Or maybe I am
the King of Panchal, Drupad!
Or maybe I am.
Even I can be him.
You have been defeated, Prince!
'What is this?'
'Brother Krishna said,
if you keep this with you'
'it will be of use to you
in the battle.'
'Did Krishna send these stones
to me for this very moment?'
'Do the five stones
symbolize the five Drupads?'
'Only one of the stones has
the eye right at the center'
'indicating that only one
of the Drupads is real.'
'In other words,
he is the real King Drupad.'
Not one but five Drupads.
Your illusion of the Five Gems
was fantastic, Your Majesty.
However, had you
advised your look-alikes
not to steal glances at you
for their next order
then maybe you would
have been successful.