The driver of man's life
is fear.
Man always succeeds in finding
a reason to be fearful.
The paths we choose in our lives
are also decided out of fear.
But are these fears for real?
Think about it.
Fear means,
in the coming times
an anticipation
of trouble.
But who is the lord of time?
The lords of time are neither us
nor our enemies and competitors.
Time is subservient to God.
So if someone
merely plans to harm you
can he harm you
in actuality?
No.
But a heart filled with fear
harms us a great deal more.
Is this not true?
In troubling times, a fearful
heart makes the wrong decisions
and makes the trouble
more agonising.
But a heart filled with faith
overcomes troubling times
likes a breeze.
In other words
the reason for which man
harbours fear in his heart
fear acts
in complete opposition to it.
Is this not true?
Give it a thought.
Aren't these mangoes
the sweetest, brother?
Anything achieved with strength
seems sweet.
Go ahead and eat.
As long as your elder brother
Bhim is alive
you shall continue eating
sweet fruits.
Go ahead and eat.
- And until Duryodhan is alive
he shall continue making
those sweet fruits taste bitter.
Why are you saying so,
Duryodhan?
Your brothers shoved mine
off the trees.
They stole their mangoes.
They insulted them.
He is my brother as well,
Duryodhan.
The way Bhim is my brother,
so are you.
And brothers need to be
taught a lesson...
Bhim, be quiet.
...when they become impudent.
Will you teach us a lesson?
You?
Who have come to our kingdom
as mere refugees?
Will you teach us a lesson?
Bhim, stop!
Bhim!
Duryodhan is your brother.
Bhim, Duryodhan, stop!
Stop, Prince! What kind
of a behaviour is this?
Release me...
I shall kill him today!
Release me.
- Stop, Prince Duryodhan!
Impudent Prince!
Like a fallen fruit
your wisdom is diminishing
with each passing moment.
How dare you behave so within
the premises of the palace?
You shall be punished for this.
Pardon us, grandsire!
Even Bhim
had instigated Duryodhan.
He is equally at fault
as Duryodhan.
Then both of you
shall be punished.
Standing in front of
the temple overnight
will be your act of repentance.
Now all of you need to
go back to your abodes.
Go!
Mother, we face a great peril.
No matter what you are
faced with
the five of you must share it.
Are they foolish, uncle?
How can someone be so happy
even after being punished?
They are not foolish.
They are devious.
Devious.
They have learnt the art
of fooling people.
When they had arrived
I thought you wouldn't be
too afraid of these people
but now...
But now, I am afraid of them,
beloved Duryodhan.
Then what must I do now, uncle?
Now you must
complete your act of repentance
along with them.
And think.
Before wearing a garland
of flowers
if there is even a single thorn
then it is wise to get rid
of it, beloved Duryodhan.
There are five thorns here.
Then these five thorns
need to be gotten rid of.
I will break them
and throw them away, uncle.
And first of all, I shall
deal with that Bhim.
I shall send him
to Death.
Bhim.
Bhim, what had
happened yesterday?
People were
discussing in the palace
that grandsire has
punished the five of you.
Not all of us, mother.
Grandsire had punished only me.
The rest of them
were punished by you.
Mother, we had come to tell you
when you were
worshiping the Lord.
You told us to share whatever
we had got.
That is why we meditated with
brother Bhim the whole night.
But what had happened?
Why was grandsire
compelled to punish you?
It was nothing, mother.
I just ate a few mangoes.
Yudhishthir, you tell me.
It was nothing important,
mother.
Yudhishthir, because I might get
angry or upset
these four here choose to lie.
But you never lie.
Tell me what had happened.
The truth is, mother,
that Duryodhan and the Kauravas
are unhappy with our arrival.
They intend to have us removed
at any cost.
Or...
- And?
What brother-in-law Vidur
had told me back then
is now making sense to me.
In a matter of 15 years
this place has
changed drastically, sons.
Sons, listen to me.
The five of you
must always stay together.
You must never forsake
any one of you.
Here, the five of you
are your only protectors.
I have a very bad feeling,
Yudhishthir.
A very bad feeling.
This is the poison of Gandhar,
beloved Duryodhan.
The forest folks of Gandhar
dip their arrows in this
in order to kill
even the biggest of animals
in just a moment.
Did you understand?
No?
You need not worry.
You will understand everything.
I have come up
with a plan, nephews.
A plan.
Brother Bhim,
catch that ball.
Brother Bhim, you can
eat 'laddoos' later.
First, you must pay attention
to the game.
What happened?
- You hurt my friend.
She has fainted because of you.
Where is she?
What is this?
In my hands.
That?
That is a doll.
No, she is my friend.
She is in great agony.
Because of you.
Stop crying, Dushala.
Now, brother Bhim will place
his hand on your friend's head
he will take her in his arms
and gently sway her.
Then she will be
rid of her pain.
Me?
Yes, brother. You must rid
our sister's friend of her pain.
Nakul!
Do you not treasure your life?
Please take her in your arms
and sway her.
Do it, Bhim.
If it makes her
namely Dushala, happy then
there should be no objection.
Brother, you as well?
Dushala, why don't you
have some 'laddoos?'
I don't want any.
Please give her some.
She has fainted.
Stop!
What happened? - My friend
fainted because of him.
And now, he won't even
give her some 'laddoos.'
Be quiet, Dushala!
Princes do not play
this silly game of yours.
Return brother Bhim his ball.
But, brother Duryodhan,
admonish him first.
Return the ball else I shall
take you to mother.
Brother Bhim, you need not
play her silly games.
Return the ball.
Return the ball!
Brother Bhim, pardon Dushala.
She is just a little girl.
But even Dushashan
and I wish to apologise to you.
No, no.
You need not apologise for it.
Alright. Let me get the ball
by descending into this well.
No.
Let me go.
No, brother Bhim.
Give me this opportunity.
Let me descend into the well,
brother Duryodhan.