Vishnu, who blesses
the whole universe
requests for your blessings.
Accept me as your son, mother.
I am taking my son to Gokul.
He will be safe
under the protection
of my friend Nand.
- But...
But how, Your Highness?
The prison gates are locked.
A battalion of soldiers
is standing outside.
It is raining so heavily.
The River Yamuna
must have flooded.
Under such circumstances,
how will we take
our new born son
to Gokul?
No, Your Highness. No!
Who can stop the Almighty,
Devaki?
Bless your son.
What a terrible night,
Vasudev!
Yes, my friend Nand.
It is the most terrible night
of my life
when I am asking my friend
for such a great sacrifice.
You are not asking me for it,
Vasudev.
It is time, which is asking
for the sacrifice.
Before the sun rises
every night seems
to be extremely dark.
But the sun definitely rises.
My wife Yashoda
has given birth
to our daughter tonight.
Take her with you
and hand your son over,
under my protection.
Please reconsider, Nand.
Possibly, Kans will kill
your daughter.
In that case,
the whole universe would be
beholden to my daughter.
Here, Vasudev.
Take her with you.
Vasudev.
Your Highness, a boy
has been born.
She is my friend Nand's
daughter.
Daughter, Your Highness?
In that case, brother will
not kill her, will he?
Devaki! Where is
your eight offspring?
Your son. My nemesis!
Where is he?
No, brother. It's not a son.
I have given birth
to a daughter.
No, brother. It's not a son.
I have given birth
to a daughter.
Daughter!
How is that possible?
Your eighth child
your son will be
the cause of my death.
That was the prophecy.
How did you give birth
to a daughter?
How is this possible?
I had told you
to ignore the prophecy
and refrain from committing
this sin.
You have committed the sin
of killing six infants,
Your Highness.
God wants to show you
the right path.
Hence, Devaki's seventh child
was not born
and the eighth child
is a daughter.
Give me your daughter,
Devaki.
No, brother!
Do not be so stone-hearted.
What could my daughter
possibly do to you?
Spare the life of at least
one of my children.
Have mercy!
Foolish Devaki
had I not promised Vasudev
I would have killed you too,
at this very moment.
I can't spare the life
of your eighth child.
No matter if it is
a boy or a girl
I have to kill it!
Give me the child!
- No, let her go.
Let her go.
- Let me go!
No... Brother, she is innocent.
Let her go.
- Devaki's eight child...
Brother, let her go.
- You are my nemesis.
No...
- Brother!
Let me go! No!
Now, the prophecy
will be proven wrong.
No! No...
Brother... Let my daughter go.
Let her go!
Brother! Brother!
Brother, no.
Let my daughter go.
Let her go! No!
No!
- Brother!
Enemy of the Yadav clan, Kans
your wickedness has crossed
all boundaries.
But don't forget.
The moon does get eclipsed.
But the eclipse doesn't last
for very long.
Even you will not live
for much longer.
The boy who will punish you
is safe.
And at the right time,
he will slay you.
The boy who will punish you
is safe.
And at the right time,
he will slay you.
Did Yogmaya* once again merge with Vishnu, uncle?
*Goddess Yogmaya, the sister of Krishna.
No, Abhimanyu.
To establish lawfulness,
Lord Vishnu's Yogmaya
keeps manifesting herself.
Sometimes in the form of power,
sometimes, devotion
and sometimes,
as a person.
How did you make
this miracle take place
as soon as you were born, uncle?
Sutsom, being
born as a mortal
cannot perform miracles.
One who is born
of a woman's womb
is bound by the rules
of a mortal body.
He cannot escape
birth, old age
disease and death.
But a miracle
did take place, uncle.
It definitely did, Satanik.
But that miracle
was performed by God.
When every person heartily feels
the need to put an end
to anarchy and establish
a lawful society...
When sin crosses
every boundary...
Then
God performs miracles
to protect morality.
To establish lawfulness,
when a person
gives up his selfishness
and attachment
and becomes ready to sacrifice
the whole creation gets filled
with miracles.
Because of the sacrifices
made by my mothers
Devaki and Yashoda
a miracle took place
in that prison, dear.
This is the balance of creation.
But God only performs miracles
when there is unlawfulness
all around
yet, lawfulness resides
in the people's hearts.
So that human beings
never fear struggle.
Whenever a person
battles sin even with
his last iota of power
God performs miracles
to protect him.
Even during the dice game
the Pandavas were subjected
to a lot of injustice.
But they never resorted
to unlawfulness.
Even after so much humiliation,
pain and oppression
your mother
did not accept defeat.
That's why, God performed
a miracle.
This means that if you wish
to seek help from the universe
this creation and God
then first of all
give up your selfishness
and attachment
and learn to fight
against the circumstances!
Am I not right, my friend?