'Duryodhan.'
The first one is
Prince Duryodhan!
All hail Prince Duryodhan!
Father, mother.
Greetings.
To fight me is difficult.
That is why
my name is Duryodhan.
I shall not allow my enemies
even the time to be fearful.
All hail Prince Duryodhan!
Greetings, uncle.
Greetings.
May you be victorious,
my dear.
May you be victorious.
I was certain, uncle
that you shall indeed be here
to fulfill your promise.
And until I fulfill my promise,
my dear
I shall stay right here
in Hastinapur.
So, uncle.
In this victory 'yagna' of mine
who is the first
to be sacrificed?
'Nakul.'
Go on, my dear.
Go on.
The first to compete
with Prince Duryodhan
is Prince Nakul of the Pandavas!
All hail Prince Nakul!
Mother, brother Nakul
is on his way.
Do you know that
when he was in Hastinapur
he used to make me laugh a lot?
Among all my brothers,
he is the handsomest.
All hail Prince Nakul!
Sanjay. - All hail Prince Nakul!
- What is happening?
Your Majesty, Prince Nakul
just made a wondrous entrance.
Sanjay, what is happening
at the moment?
Your Majesty
among Prince Duryodhan
and Prince Nakul
Prince Duryodhan is exhibiting
greater talent and skill.
Wonderful, son!
All hail Prince Duryodhan!
What was the outcome?
Nakul lost to Duryodhan,
sister-in-law.
Uncle.
That was not even a competition.
But it was certainly the first
step towards victory, dear.
Who is next?
'Sahadev.'
Next is Prince Sahadev
of the Pandavas!
All hail Prince Sahadev!
Sahadev?
Why not Bheem?
You must first get rid of
the smaller thorns, my darling.
All hail Prince Sahadev!
Sanjay.
What is happening at the moment?
- Your Majesty
among Prince Duryodhan
and Prince Sahadev
the former is exhibiting
wondrous valour.
All hail Prince Duryodhan!
Duryodhan defeated
my second son as well.
All hail Prince Duryodhan!
Ashwathama has given us
a new name, Nakul.
Now, we are not the Kauravas
but the Pandavas.
Nakul, I find this name
to be quite endearing.
It seems as though
father is with us.
Why? Did you not have
any premonition today?
I have the premonition
of victory.
A premonition of victory
after defeat?
Nakul, brother Bheem had told me
that if I take part in
the competition before him
I must not tire Duryodhan out.
He does not want
Duryodhan to say
that he lost to brother Bheem
because of fatigue.
Sire, if the third competitor
also turns out to be Pandu's son
then this competition
is certainly a deception.
This is deception.
Even if the names of the sons
of Dhritarashtra are announced
they will not fight Duryodhan.
All this facade
is only to facilitate Duryodhan
to be crowned as the prince.
I know this, Vidur.
But...
But the orders of the king
have left me
with no alternative.
Now, it is Yudhishthir's turn,
my darling.
I will oust him from
the competition in no time.
But if you are unable to do so
then do remember
that people who take pride
in their beauty
are afraid of their reflection
lest they see
their own ugliness.
If you try to corrupt
Yudhishthir's interior
then success will be
an easy one.
'Yudhishthir.'
Yudhishthir?
- Mother Kunti.
Why are brother Dusshasan
and the rest not here?
And between whom is this
competition taking place?
Maybe between your father
and uncle Pandu.
How can that be possible?
Father has not even gone
to take part in the competition.
And is uncle going
to descend from heaven?
Be quiet, Dushala.
Watch the competition.
I have given you my word
to stay quiet, son.
Let my name and my fame
not get tarnished.
Indeed, father.
Whether Duryodhan wins
or someone else does
your glory is bound to magnify.
Next is Prince Yudhishthir
of the Pandavas!
All hail Prince Yudhishthir!
Your Majesty, Prince Duryodhan
and Prince Yudhishthir
are exhibiting equal valour
in the competition.
Both of them are at par
in their skills, your Majesty.
All hail Prince Yudhishthir!
Try to recollect my words,
Duryodhan.
Recollect my words.
Yudhishthir, you truly
are very powerful.
The blood of which dynasty
runs through your veins?
From whom did your characterless
mother conceive you?
Pray tell me.