Who is that fool
who is blocking
the path this way?
Remove your cart!
What is the problem?!
Do you not have the strength
to remove the cart?
Eating a lot has given you
only a big exterior
but no intelligence.
'You 5 brothers will touch
the feet of us 100 brothers.'
'Right now!
And forever after.'
'You need not worry
one bit for Hastinapur.'
'Very soon, the reason
of your worry'
'will come to an end,
brother Bheem.'
'Poisoning all of us first'
'and then torching this place
were all part of a scheme!'
'This way, everyone will think
that we died in an accident.'
'Duryodhan has schemed
to burn you, our mother!'
Charioteer, remove that fool
and his cart from the path.
Crown Prince, the wheel
of the cart is probably stuck.
All of you are frail and infirm!
You cannot even remove a cart!
For such a base task
I will have to get down
from the chariot now!
Friend Duryodhan...
Stop, friend.
I shall go help him, friend.
The Crown Prince of Hastinapur
to push a cart in
the city of Kampilya
does not seem correct.
Stop, friend.
Revered 'Brahmin'
it is important for us
to reach the palace promptly.
Let me help you lift the cart.
Allow me, revered 'Brahmin.'
Stop!
You resemble...
You seem familiar.
Who are you?
What is your name?!
I...
- Brother Someshwar!*
*It means "Lord Krishna".
Brother Someshwar.
Friend, you should go back.
I shall remove this right away.
Allow me, revered 'Brahmins.'
Accept our heartfelt gratitude.
Be it a cart or life
when the wheel
gets stuck in the earth
it cannot be lifted
without the aid of someone.
Be it life or a cart
when the weight
exceeds the limits
only then does the wheel
get stuck in the earth.
'Brahmins'
here you go.
Here is some money as charity
from Hastinapur.
Pardon me, Prince.
We earn with labour
and renounce with love.
Neither do we accept charity
nor engage in it.
Charioteer, proceed!
Had you not come today
he would have certainly
died at my hands.
But brother Bheem
we have pardoned him.
- No!
I did not pardon him.
I have merely decided
not to punish him.
Then what is the point
in pardoning him, brother Bheem?
When the enemy
is right before you
forgetting the wounds
given by him
is not that easy.
Even when a mongoose
has been raised on milk
it will still attack a serpent
upon seeing it
because they are arch enemies.
You are correct, brother Bheem.
Let's go now.
But why has he come here?
To take part in the 'swayamvar'
of Princess Draupadi.
Will King Drupad have his
daughter married to him?
It is a 'swayamvar.'
A woman decides
her husband in this.
Who knows
who resides in her heart.
Handmaiden...
Handmaiden.
Where is that painting?
- What painting, Princess?
The one that Malini had brought.
The painting of Prince Arjun.
Go and bring it at once.
Draupadi
why do you require
that painting?
When Prince Arjun will arrive
at the 'swayamvar' tomorrow
you will certainly know.
I too wish to determine, sister
whether I will be able to
recognize Prince Arjun or not.
The truth is,
I wish to determine
whether the person I came across
was Prince Arjun
or not.
What do you mean?
Upon going to
the Shiva temple today
I had a strange encounter,
sister.
Upon seeing a 'Brahmin'
I felt as though
Lord Shiva was giving me
a sign.
The Almighty can never
give such a sign, Draupadi.
As to who you are to be married
will be decided at
the 'swayamvar' tomorrow.
And even if the Almighty
had given such a sign
He would have alluded
to some King or Prince
and not a 'Brahmin,' Draupadi.
Is the Almighty also bound
by the plans of man, sister?
No
but a Princess is bound
by her oath, Draupadi.
Whoever wins
the 'swayamvar' tomorrow
shall be married to you.
This is your oath.
What if
in the guise of a 'Brahmin'
it was Prince Arjun himself?
What if
upon seeing that painting,
I get the same sign
I had got in the Shiva temple?
Princess
where do we place this painting?
So, Draupadi...
Did you get any sign?
No.
I did not get any sign.
No one can recognize us
in this disguise, mother.
But had brother Bheem's
anger exceeded its limit today
the whole of Kampilya
would have found out.
This disguise can
camouflage our look
but not our temperament
and disposition.
If our cover is blown,
we will be in deep water, Bheem.
Grandsire will certainly
look for us
and take us back to Hastinapur.
The situation
we have been dreading
will come into being
right before our eyes.
We must leave Kampilya
soon, son.
Many Kings will be present
at the'swayamvar.'
Nakul and Sahadev's uncle
the King of Madra,
will recognize them.
And if Krishna and Balaram
are also present there
then they will certainly
recognize Arjun.
But mother
I have heard
people of the city say
that the King of Panchal is
hosting a difficult competition.
A competition that can be won
only by the best archer
of the world.
In other words
by brother Arjun.
The King of Panchal
must certainly
be awaiting brother Arjun,
mother.
The Arjun who had captured
the King of Panchal
was burnt to ashes
in Varnavrat, Nakul.
No one is awaiting this Arjun.
'As you are going
to the Shiva temple now'
'you should ask
Lord Shiva himself.'
'He is the Lord of Death
and Salvation.'
'That is why, He always
gives a definite answer.'
'If you are to get your answer'
'then you shall get it
only from Him.'
'And even if the Almighty
had given such a sign'
'He would have alluded'
'to some King or Prince'
'and not a 'Brahmin.'
Prince Arjun.