Uncle.
Greetings!
Bless you, Kunti!
You seem worried.
Come.
I come here
to put a burden on your
shoulder, uncle.
No one is more capable than you
whose shoulder can withstand
the weight of this world.
For a youth, the world's burden
brings honor.
And to have such burden
brings about joy.
After a while,
that burden becomes duty.
And assuming such duty
becomes one's pride.
After that the world's burden
becomes responsibility.
And assuming that responsibility
brings one's satisfaction.
However at my age now
the world's burden
is punishment.
My shoulder can lift
a mountain.
However my heart,
my heart has no strength to lift
the burden of responsibility anymore.
But this is my last request, uncle.
I...
I have Ganges water,
on the one hand,
and 'Panchamrit'* on the other...
*A mixture of five foods used in Hindu worship and puja, usually honey, sugar, milk, yogurt, and ghee.
Which one should I throw away
and which one should I keep, uncle?
You are greedy to hold both of them,
but how was it came to be, Kunti?
Both Arjun and Karna
bound by their oath.
I know about your secret, Kunti.
Please forgive me, uncle.
I made a mistake during my youth
and I repent for this.
Then why are you telling
me now, Kunti?
Because
Karna and Arjun had taken oath
to slay each other.
And just thinking about it,
is like pushing a stake
through my heart.
Karna fights for the unrighteous people,
but there is still truth in his heart, uncle.
Please protect them both, uncle.
Protecting Karna is not
my responsibility
and Arjun do not need protection.
But
Karna is also your grandchild, uncle.
Only children with the consent of
your husband
are my grandchildren.
But before you got married
any child you have
do not belong to Kuru dynasty.
I understand what's in your mind, Kunti.
Suffering is also part of my destiny
but
I'll try to sefeguard you from it.
Bless you, Kunti.
Dusshasan
regardless of gransire's battle formation
tomorrow on the battlefield
you have to stay in the middle
of the formation.
with the rest of our brothers.
Protection from grandsire
will provide security
for me.
No, friend.
Protecting you is my responsibility, friend.
All weapons directed at you
will have to go through me first.
Of course, King of Anga,
certainly.
Previously, weapons will only bouncing
off of your armour
but now they will go through you.
King of Gandhar!
Do you doubt my competence?
- No, King of Anga!
Now we only have faith on
your competence
because you gave away your
divinity as charity.
Is this what you call dedication?!
The truth is
if you really concern with the safety
of your friend
then you will not risk the life
just to uphold your righteousness
and end up at a loss like this.
My dear.
Karna, King of Anga
should be relieved from the task
of protecting you.
When one can not even protect one's
own life from enemy's arrows
how can he protect you?
I...
- Karna, King of Anga
if you like you may leave
this war.
And we hope
that the first arrow of Arjuna
will not end your life.
King of Gandhar!
Now Arjuna's arrows
will be able to hurt the King of Anga.
Because of that
he is prohibited to enter the battlefield.
What do you mean, grandsire?!
A warrior who has not
pledged his loyalty to his general
can not be
allowed to enter the battlefield.
All my life
I have dreamt to prove my competence
in the battlefield.
I have gone through difficult trials
to join this war.
I have taken an oath
to protect my friend.
And it is the purpose of my life.
You do not have the right
to smash my dream
cause this is the only way to prove it.
It's not my responsibilty to let you
proof yourself to the khsatriyas,
Karna, King of Anga.
Uncle!
No one can stop my friend
to enter the battlefield!
If that's the case
then give
the responsibility to protect you
and the other princes
to the King of Anga
because if he goes to war
then I'm not going to fight.
My dear
Karna, King of Anga
can not even protect himself
from enemy's arrows,
then how can he protect
your army?
Uncle!
Do not insult my friend.
Strength lies in attack and how
to counter it.
Sincerity and protection have no
strength at all.
My friend's competence
do not require a suit of armor, uncle.
When the time comes
sunlight can change all the water
on the earth to steam, uncle.
Just like my friend's bow
can wipe out the whole enemy, uncle.
Dear
I do not wish to doubt your faith
but if one's beaten on the battlefield
then one's loses one's life!
We can't gamble on the battlefield.
Uncle, I've made my decision!
My friend
will combat on the battlefield tomorrow.
Then listen carefully to my final decision,
Crown Prince Duryodhana,
Until I lead the army
your friend will not enter
the battlefield.
If that's your decision, uncle
then listen to mine as well.
You should resign your position.
My friend
will be made the next general.
Friend
to show me such respect
you have made me owe you.
However, in my opinion
you don't have to argue with
his excellency.
You need him, friend.
I need you more, Karna, my friend.
This is what grandsire wants
to protect the Pandavas.
The truth is
that grandsire and Guru Drona
never want to kill the Pandavas!
It is possible
the Pandavas will only be taken
captive by them!
And imprisoning those five
in this war
is not my intention,
friend Karna.
The very purpose of
this war is to
kill my enemies,
friend Karna!
And they will only be killed...
only be killed by you,
my friend.
The truth is the only one who will strive for
the sake of my success
is only you.
Let's go friend, before
making a decision
there's something important
for you to see.
Listen to them, friend.
There is only one name
in their hearts, friend.
Their dedication until death
and unwavering faith
stem neither because you nor I.
They have come here to
put their life at stake
simply because His Excellency
Bhisma is here.
The war will begin when the sun rise
tomorrow, friend.
And the power of an ordinary soldier
lies not only in his ability
or his courage.
His power rooted in his faith.
A soldier goes forward in the battlefield
with a faith
that his general would
protect his life.
And all their faith
rest in His Excellency Bhisma.
I'm afraid
that if His Excellency Bhishma resigns
then none of them will
take part in this war.
Not only that, friend.
After His Excellency Bhisma,
you must elect Guru Drona
as general.
Only after their death
will you to appoint me as general.
But Grandsire Bhisma has a boon
to die at his will, friend.
How can he be killed?
To protect Hastinapura
and its crown prince
is an oath he took.
Until he dies
the hundred Kauravas will not die.
And you will always be safe, friend.
Let this war proceeds
as His Excellency Bhisma
wants it to be.
The enemies are bound to
get hurt in the process.
If he imprisons Pandavas
then you can give them
a death sentence.
However if he dies
then I will be there
to help you and realize
your dreams.
But Karna my friend,
killing Arjuna is also your dream.
This has always happened
to me, friend.
Whenever I get a chance to prove
my competence,
fate snatches it away from me.
Sometimes, Surya Dev has set it up
in heaven.
In other times, fate just left me.
To fulfill your dream
I'm willing to sacrifice millions
of my dreams, friend.
I will stand outside the battlefield
and waiting for your order.
Obey His Excellency Bhisma's firm order.