'To emerge victorious in this war,
we must devise a stratagem to take down
His Majesty Bhisma.'
'On the day of the war.'
Madhav!
Your chariot's here, Parth.
Along with the charioteer.
No, Madhav.
You can't become my charioteer.
Do you not believe me, Parth?
I am very proficient with this.
No, Madhav.
You are a respected person.
I can't let you become a charioteer.
It doesn't matter, Parth.
If you feel like it
then consider me
just sitting in front of you.
As the horses are in my care
I'll never let your mind waver, Parth.
In honesty and deception...
Between truth and immorality...
Every time your mind
loses focus
it would be my duty
to bring you to the
right course again.
Both in custody of your chariot
or your life,
I am proficient in both, Parth.
All hail Mahadev!
Karna.
I will wait for you
on the battlefield.
Until you draw your bowstring
we will not achieve victory.
I also wait for that day,
friend.
I may be physically here
but my soul
will accompany you in the battlefield.
All hail Mahadev!
- All hail Mahadev!
May God bless you
with victory, sons.
May your war skills
will make you immortal.
I bless you all.
Do not worry about me, mother.
Sire!
I assure you that this day
I'll be back with victory
from the battlefield.
Dear...
I hope you win.
Your victory in this war is decided.
Accept my last greeting, mother.
No one realizes
that at the end of this war
who will greet the god of death,
and who will go through life
with memories of the war.
People of Kuru along with the Arya clan
including women, children,
pottery, blacksmith,
and farmers.
All will survive, my son.
to have pleasures in life.
Your enemy is also
enemy to society.
Have no mercy on them.
Fill the vessel of god Bhairav* with blood, my child.
*Bhairava or Kala Bhairava is the fierce manifestation of Shiva associated with annihilation.
Fill the vessel of god Bhairav
with blood, my child.
All hail Mahadev!
- All hail Mahadev!
Order the attack,
brother Yudhishtir.
Charioteer,
take the chariot to the front.
Yudhishtir.
Are you already scared?
Repent for your actions and
accept your punishment,
Dusshasan,
time to ask forgiveness
has long gone.
But if you want to save
your soldiers' life
then surrender yourself
and accept the death penalty,
brother Yudhishtir.
At least your righteousness will
live longer than you.
Grandsire Bhishma!
Do not forget
that you had taken oath
for the throne of Hastinapur.
Uncle speaks right, grandsire.
Do not bless me.
But before this war begins
I will not give up my ethic.
Therefore, by greeting you
and our teacher...
me and my brothers
here to ask for your permissions
for war,
Grandsire,
like birds build their nests
on branches in the shade of trees
and live happily
we've been living in a safe place
because of you.
Every part of us is indebted
to you.
Today...
we have been forced to take up
arms against you.
Like aquatic animals trying to
drink up dry the entire ocean.
Grandsire,
give us permission to war,
or order us to surrender
our weapons.