Madhav.
Indra Dev
do respect the
competence of Arjun
the son born
from your blessings.
His competence has
augmented your glory.
Vasudev!
I have promised
to protect Dakshak.
And a son
must honour the promise
made by his father.
Even Arjun has made
a similar promise
to his subjects.
Why is it,
Indra Dev
that everyone respects
the feelings and promises
they make themselves
but when it comes to the
feelings and promises of others
people fail to value them?
But Vasudev
what if the promises made by
father and son are in conflict?
Whose promise holds
a greater value then?
Both.
The success of a father
bestows knowledge to his son
and that of a son
brings glory to his father.
It would be correct,
Indra Dev
if you aid Arjun
in being successful.
Are you here
to ask for help, Arjun?
One cannot ask for help
by taking to arms.
Lord Indra
I was mere demonstrating
my art and competence
to please you.
But you had shot arrows at me.
You reside everywhere,
Lord Indra.
Is there any direction in which
I can shoot the arrows
in order to please you?
What help do you
seek from me, Arjun?
Before I tell you
about the help I need
I must tell you about
my oath, Lord Indra.
We shall always protect
the serpent community.
We shall even give them an equal
opportunity to prosper with us.
The city we shall build
shall gain fame by your name.
Our grand city
will be known as Indraprastha!
I am pleased,
Arjun.
How can I help you?
Do build the city for us
which we can name after you.
Your competence
and intelligence
have pleased me
immensely, son.
I will order Vishwakarma*
"All-accomplishing, maker of all," "all doer", he is the presiding deity of all craftsmen and architects.
to begin the construction
of your city.
Bless you!
Lord Indra!
Because you love your son
today
you have forsaken me.
I take the oath
that the last heir
of your son's dynasty
shall be
killed by me!
Pardon me,
Vasudev.
Please pardon me.
I had asked Dakshak
to seek your refuge.
Mayasur
had you not created an
illusory forest for Dakshak
humans and serpents would
never have had a struggle.
You have extraordinary
talents, Mayasur.
You are like the
Vishwakarma of the ogres
but you did not
employ your skills
for the betterment of the world.
You employed it
for your selfish gains.
You are correct,
Vasudev.
I made a mistake.
Pardon me,
My Lord.
Madhav
you allowed Dakshak to go free.
I request you
to pardon him.
I allowed Dakshak to go free
only because you had
promised Indra Dev, friend
that you would
protect the serpents.
Mayasur.
Since my friend
has requested me
I shall pardon you,
Mayasur.
But whenever you are
required in the future
you must employ your skills
to our advantage.
Certainly,
Vasudev.
I promise you that.
We are alive.
Friend
pray to Agni Dev now
and ask him
to put this fire out.
Agni Dev
with your blessings
Indraprastha has been
given a new life today.
I express my
heartfelt gratitude.
You have satiated my hunger
today, son of Pandu, Arjun.
I am very pleased with you.
It is in the nature of fire
that whichever object
is subjected to it
gets purified.
By devouring the illusion
of this forest
I have purified it.
And from that illusion is made
this illusory and powerful bow
which I present to you.
Like your disposition,
this bow
is also calm,
composed
and powerful.
That is why,
this bow
shall be known as
the Gandiva Bow.
You must worship it first
in your newly established city.
This bow shall multiply
your strength immensely.
Indra Dev has
fulfilled his promise.
Look over there.
The blessing of Vishwakarma.
Your city is being built.
Indraprastha.
All hail...
- King Yudhishthir!
Her Highness,
my daughter...
Where is my daughter Vrushali?
Look over there.
Who has been washed up
on the shore?
It is some woman.
Let's go.
Yes, let's go.
Oh! She is the daughter
of Vrishbhan.
It seems as though she is alive.
Let us take her to the Doctor.
Let's go.
Vrushali
are you alright?
Adhiratha?
Yes, dear.
You and Vrishbhan had
gone to Indraprastha.
Then how did you
fall into the river?
Serpents had attacked us
there, Adhiratha.
Even...
Even my father was killed!
I...
I fell into the river
while trying to save myself.
Here you go.
Drink this.
No one died,
child.
The Pandavas have
captured the serpents
and compelled them
to draw the venom out.
Your father must be alive.
Then...
Then I should return
to Indraprastha.
Adhiratha, I have to go
to Indraprastha
to my father.
I want to go there.
Certainly, dear.
Certainly.
Most of the subjects
of Hastinapur
are migrating to Indraprastha.
You may travel with any family
you are familiar with.
Yes.
- Let's go.
Let me help you with that.
- Do not forget that.
Make haste.
- Put this on the cart too.
Hey... - Be careful.
All of us will live
in the new kingdom.
All of us will live in the
kingdom of King Yudhishthir.
Yes, that's right.
Bring that along as well.
That would be useful.
Our King Yudhishthir never lies
and we wish to stand
by a truthful person.
So many people
are migrating to
Indraprastha, uncle?!
It is human nature,
my darling.
He hopes to find new joy
in the new objects he finds.
The water of the ocean
wishes to touch the sky
in the form of waves.
The water in the sky
desires to fall as rain
on the mountains.
And when rain falls
on the mountains
it rushes to meet the ocean.
When the Pandavas
were leaving with a few
of our subjects, uncle
you had said to let them go.
But now, Hastinapur
will become empty!
Is this
not an insult to father and me?!
It certainly is an insult,
my darling.
It certainly is an insult.
And it is also a major problem.
We must stop
these people from
leaving Hastinapur
my darling.
I need to meet His Highness.