Your Highness
why did you halt
the chariot here?
The first time
I had entered Hastinapur...
It was on a chariot.
But
this time
I am the culprit of Hastinapur.
I couldn't protect
its King.
I have no right to enter
riding on this chariot.
- Your Highness
even today, you are
the Queen of Hastinapur.
And the future Queen Mother.
Who has ever known
what the womb
of the future
gives birth to, Vidur?
Hence I request you,
Your Highness
enter the kingdom
as the Queen.
15 years earlier when
you had gone to the forest...
Those circumstances
don't exist anymore,
Your Highness.
Today, against
these five boys
a 100 boys are
standing there.
If you surrender your
rights, Your Highness
then the rights of your sons
too will be lost.
That which is lost
is ambition.
Not rights.
My husband has
taught my sons
the right values.
Sons
come here.
Yes, mother.
- Yes, mother.
This Hastinapur
is your house.
Henceforth
your father figure will be
your grandfather
Bhishma. Dhritarashtra
will be your uncle.
And Gandhari, your aunt.
Serving them will be
your duty.
Here, you have
a 100 brothers.
Be loving towards them.
Reciprocating their love
will be your duty.
Here, there will be no
differentiation between
Gandhari's 100 sons
and Kunti's five sons.
Here
there will be the 105 sons
of the Kuru clan.
These are the Pandavs.
The five Pandavs.
Because of them
you couldn't be coronated
as the Crown Prince.
But you yourself had
advised His Highness
that my coronation
cannot take place now.
My dear!
My dear
I had to say this
because of that old man.
He says
that he will not
be partial.
But he and Vidur,
the maid's offspring...
These two people
love these five Pandavs
a lot.
Always remember
that they are
not your brothers
but your enemies.
Enemies!
May God give you patience
and faith, child.
Grandsire
these are
my five sons.
I've brought them here
for your guardianship.
- No, Kunti
please don't say that.
They are not outsiders.
This is rightfully their home.
Come.
May you have a long life.
May God bless you, Kunti.
May God bless your children too.
May you have a long life.
Greetings.
Your Majesty
it's time for your sister-in-law
to enter the temple.
The priests are waiting
for her.
Let's go, Kunti.
The attendants will take
the children into the palace.
Before entering the palace,
even you have to
perform the purgation ceremony
and then, the ritual
of entering the temple.
Let's go, Kunti.
Bheem, stop making fun of him.
Get up, attendant. It's Bheem's
habit to make everyone laugh.
Call your companion wrestler.
- Come here.
It's the Prince's order.
Are you a wrestler, attendant?
- Yes, Prince.
I'm a wrestler from Magadh.
I live in the residence
for Magadhis.
If I come to your place
will you give me some lessons
in wrestling?
But, Prince, the princes
who belong to this place
don't follow
our style of wrestling.
We do it in a lively
and rural style.
We apply oil and soil
to our bodies.
Attaining that knowledge
is also important.
What if we ever
have to wrestle in Magadh?
Where will I get an expert
master like you?
Attendants,
you have finally come.
Hurry up.
Bring our footwear.
At the orders of His Excellency
we're now attending
to these princes, Prince.
I'm not talking to you!
I'm talking to these
five attendants.
The ones who are friends
with the servants
are servants themselves.
Come on...
Greet us!
Of course.
Nakul and Sahadev,
Dushashan is elder to you.
Greet him.
It's a must for the younger ones
to greet the elders.
It's not the matter
of being elder.
It's about superiority
and inferiority.
The sons of King Dhritarashtra
never greet anyone
rather, everyone else greets us.
All five of you will greet
the 100 of us right now
and forever after!
Pay your respect
to the sons of the King.
Even we are the sons
of the King.
Their father was the King
of the woods.
He used to rule over animals
and birds.
The coronation ceremony
in Hastinapur
was conducted for our father.
If you have a doubt
then enquire about it.
- Bheem, don't argue.
We will definitely greet you
but I hope you are aware
of the fact
that the one who doesn't
have the right to be greeted
becomes a sinner
if he is greeted.
Doesn't the Prince have
the right to be greeted?
There's only one prince
in the kingdom.
And there is only one prince
and that's me.
My younger brothers will greet
all of you
but before that
Yudhishthir should greet
me first.
Has the coronation ceremony
been conducted for you,
brother Duryodhan?
When?
Durbhiksh will tell us
when his coronation ceremony
as the Prince was conducted.
Attendants, you may go.
- At the order of His Excellency
we're attending to
these princes, Prince.
We can't leave them here
and we'll have to answer
to their questions.
The coronation ceremony has not
yet been conducted, Bheem.
I don't require a coronation.
It's only my right to be
enthroned as the Prince.
It is my birth right.
Duryodhan
only the presence of clouds
in the sky
doesn't make the earth wet.
The clouds
can be easily blown away
by strong winds
and the same is applicable
to one's rights.
So, intelligent people
do not display their rights
until the appropriate time.
Yudhishthir is the eldest
among you.
First of all,
all of you, greet Yudhishthir.
Pay your respects to him.
It's my order.
Duryodhan!