Now leave.
Early in the morning
get Rukmini to the temple
of Goddess Parvati.*
*The wife of Shiva and the gentle aspect of Maha Devi or Durga.
I will be waiting for you.
Hold on!
Who are you?
I'm a maid.
I haven't seen you here before.
This means
that you keep an eye
on all the maids here.
It is not respectable for
a soldier. - Don't argue.
Nobody is permitted
to meet the princess.
I have
brought Maharishi Durvasa's
sacrament with me.
If the princess does not
have this sacrament
she will never
get married.
No!
You cannot go.
Okay, soldier, tell me
is the prince of Chedi
handsome?
Maybe.
Why?
Okay, I'll have this...
I'll have this sacrament.
Then I'll get married to him.
This sacrament is very powerful.
The princess cannot get married
until she has this sacrament.
Stop!
This isn't a sacrament
but an opportunity.
If you want,
you can have some too.
Go give it to the princess.
Give it a thought, Rukmini.
Chedi's prince Sishupal is here.
Tomorrow morning the wedding
ceremony will be completed.
Do you know what will happen if
you decide against the marriage?
Prince Sishupal will get upset.
That is why I had told you...
Had requested you earnestly
not to invite him for
the wedding.
Don't act foolish, Rukmini.
Father will be humiliated.
Chedi and Vidharbha
will be at war.
A monarch like King Jarasandh
will be angry with us.
Don't worry about that, brother.
My Lord Krishna will protect you
from the monarch of Magadh.
Krishna! Krishna!
Krishna!
What are you saying!
There
you too have chanted his
name thrice just now.
This time, your death
will surely get averted.
Keep quiet!
You will get married
to the Prince of Chedi.
Now don't even let the
thought of that cowherd
come to your mind.
That shall be best for you.
You can build a dam on
a flowing river
but you cannot build
a dam on falling rains.
Chanting Krishna's name
is like shower of nectar
in my life.
How can I stop it?
I'm already married, brother.
My Lord will arrive
and take me with him
to his house.
This is impossible, Rukmini.
That cowherd can't even step
into my province.
Look in all four
directions, brother
there's only Krishna
everywhere.
Krishna everywhere.
Rukmini!
Wherever I go
I will get closer
to my Lord.
Stop rambling, Rukmini!
You will get married
to prince Sishupal.
You will now leave
this chamber
only to go to the
wedding booth.
Until it's the auspicious time
for the wedding
you shall not leave
this chamber.
Who are you?
This...
This is Maharishi Durvasa's
sacrament.
Fine! Go give it!
Maybe this sacrament can
reinstate some sanity to her.
You seem to be out of
your senses, prince.
Krishna has not only
entered your province
but your palace too.
I had completely forgotten
how beautiful peacock
feathers are.
I used to think
that they look beautiful because
they're on Krishna's crown.
Who are you?
And
how did you enter...
- I'm Arjun...
I'm cowherd, Branala...
You...
Who I am
is of no importance.
What's important is
that you had written a letter
to my brother Krishna.
And in that letter you
had written
that you will wait for him
at Goddess Parvati's temple.
It's time.
And you're still here!
This means
Krishna has arrived
on my invitation.
You will know that only
when you go there.
Please come.
Where are you both going?
Wait.
The princess is prohibited from
leaving the chamber.
Actually
Maharishi Durvasa's sacrament
has to be consumed
by the princess
in Goddess Parvati's temple.
That's not necessary.
The princess will not
leave the palace.
As you wish.
But
Maharishi Durvasa
already knew
that the princess would be
against this wedding.
Hence
he has
sent this special sacrament.
If the princess
goes to Goddess
Parvati's temple
and consumes this sacrament
while performing the veneration
then the sacrament will
show its miracle.
And she will get married
to the one
she is supposed to.
Believe me, princess.
Fine.
You can go, Rukmini.
Even I'll come along with you.
No...
I don't want to go anywhere.
I don't want any sacrament.
I will not go.
Only you can convince her now.
Once she consumes this
sacrament at the temple
she shall forget
to protest.
Come on, Rukmini.
I told you,
I don't want to go.
I don't...
- Come, Rukmini.
I don't want to go.
Detain him!
- What do we do now?
Lord Krishna says
that when there is an
opportunity to run
one should run.
Soldiers
that messenger shouldn't
be spared alive!
Catch him!
Princess Rukmini
you go to the temple,
I'll handle them.