Enter into a duel
or accept defeat!
- Duryodhan, defeat...
Calm down!
Lord!
All the princes would return
to Hastinapur tomorrow.
You have to arrange
for a celebration.
Celebrate about what?
Gandhari, only victory
can be celebrated.
Not failure.
And today, I have been defeated.
Defeated!
But lord, the princes of
Hastinapur have been victorious.
The subjects always
like celebrations.
But when my son returns
on hearing praises on the
paths of Hastinapur
what would be his plight,
Gandhari?
When the subjects sing praises
about Pandu's sons
how would my Duryodhan
tolerate it?
I...
I am blind.
But my son is not.
In the lamps lighted on the
doorsteps of the subjects
he would see all his desires
on fire, Gandhari.
All the desires.
If one dislikes the image
seen in the mirror
then the mirror isn't at fault.
Instead, the appearance
is at fault.
The subjects are like
the mirror.
Whatever the subjects
portray is the truth.
The truth about us and
Duryodhan is that
as the heir to the throne
only Yuddhistir has
the authority.
How would he agree to it?
How would he?
How would my Duryodhan sacrifice
his dream to become the king?
How would he bow his head
before Yuddhistir?
How would he?
Yuddhistir, let's
decide right now
between us.
Who is the strongest?
Who is destined to win?
I consider a duel with you
as a defeat, Duryodhan.
A fight between the princes
of the Kuru dynasty
isn't appropriate.
When two logs of
wood are rubbed
it results in fire.
And all the woods
burn down to ashes.
I don't need a preaching.
I need a result.
The throne of Hastinapur
belongs to me.
You must either take an oath
that you sacrifice the
throne of Hastinapur
or fight a duel.
I take an oath...
- Brother!
Do not take an oath which
would hurt our father's soul.
Duryodhan, I take an oath.
Whatever king Dhrithrashtra
decides
I will agree with it.
To make a promise
other than this
would be like deceiving the
subjects of the Kuru dynasty.
And the decision of
king Dhrithrashtra is
that his son
be coronated on the throne
of Hastinapur.
And that will surely happen.
'Hastinapur.'
'Panchaal.'
'Dhrupad will himself'
'perform the rituals
towards Ashwathama.'
'Dhrupad will himself'
'coronate Ashwathama
on the throne.'
'I return the half of the
divided kingdom to you.'
'You have no son
of your own, anyway.'
Father...
- Everything is ruined.
The way in which age old trees
get destroyed in a forest fire...
In the same way,
an ancient kingdom...
The popularity of which
could embarrass even the Gods.
The grand valour
of the ancestors...
Everything is ruined...
Everything is ruined!
If there is a forest fire
it only makes the land
more fertile, father.
More trees grow on
the same land.
I am sure there would
come a time again
when Panchaal's flag of victory
will be hoisted on the
palace of Hastinapur.
Who will bring such a time?
Who will bring such times?!
Would you?!
You are a helpless woman.
Would you be fighting a war
against those ace warriors?
You were defeated in
the very first attack!
You haven't witnessed the
potentials of Pandu's sons.
Haven't you heard the
sound of Arjun's bow string?
I felt like
it was Lord Indra's weapon.
They are undefeatable.
Would you raise your
weapons before them?
Would you point your
weapons at them?!
Yes, father.
Time defeats the greatest
of warriors.
But time cannot defeat me.
Father, I cannot die
until I kill Bhishma.
You know that very well.
These talks are futile,
Shikandini.
I do not agree that you have
been blessed by Lord Shiva!
I was a fool
to consider you as a
potential resource.
Shikandini, one cannot apply
turmeric on silver ornaments
and turn them into gold.
You are useless to me.
Go, Shikandini!
Only a perfect son
is greater than a mighty
and well-equipped army.
Until I do not attain a son
I will consider myself
childless!
I need a son
who can behead Drona.
Who can sit on the throne of
Hastinapur
and rule.
A competition?
What kind of competition,
father?
Sire Bhishma and
the chief minister termed
it as a competition.
We do not agree to it.
Dushasan is right, father.
Tomorrow, you have to
announce at the royal court
that your son will be your heir.
How would I, son?
Show me a way.
How would I?
You can give a mere reason.
Even if your prove that Dhrupad
or Drona cheated you
I will immediately declare
you as my heir, son.
What are you saying, father?
What is the need to
look for a solution?
You are the king!
When the sun rises, the moon
and the stars have to fade.
No one has the authority to
speak before the king.
Son, a king is independent.
He cannot be partial, though.
I cannot decide as I wish, son.
When you have no doubts over the
superiority of the Pandavas'
how can I make the
subjects doubt over it?
This means, you will announce
Yuddhistir as the King tomorrow.
Father, I believed you.
I wouldn't agree to it
at any cost.
At court, if you declare
Yuddhistir as the King
then I would revolt.
- No! Don't you do that, son.
Don't do that.
If you revolt, then...
- Then?
You would appoint an
army against me.
I know that.
The king who doesn't punish
the one who revolts
he has to renounce his kingdom.
Father.
Would you declare a war
against your sons?
Charcoal is born out of fire.
But even then, if charcoal
falls into fire
it's the duty of the fire
to burn it into ashes.
'Hail the sons of Pandu!
- Hail!'
Father, you can continue
with your rightful duties.
The chance is standing
right in your courtyard!
But you must mark my words.
At court, if you declare
Yuddhistir as the King
I will destroy the honour and
respect of Hastinapur. - No!
That's a promise.
- No...
Duryodhan!
Duryodhan...
Duryodhan.
Greetings, King.
We have been victorious,
thanks to your blessings.
We have fulfilled our duty
towards our teacher.
Bless you.
Your deed must have pleased
your teacher, Drona.
Am I right?
Greetings, your highness.
- Bless you.
Congratulations on winning
the competition.