Just give the Pandavas what
they ask for, Your Highness.
Heed my advice!
Give them what they want
even if it is in excess but
stop His Excellency Bhishma.
Make him the servant
of Hastinapur
so that in the future
going against
any of your decisions
would not be an option for him.
All hail His Highness!
His Excellency
wishes to come in.
Your Highness.
Your Highness!
Greetings,
His Excellency.
I apologize,
uncle.
You may punish me
as you like. I...
I shall accept it, uncle.
Why are you sitting
on the floor, dear?
Sit on the throne.
The King of Hastinapur
sits on the floor
only during a 'yajna.'
I am no longer the King
of Hastinapur, uncle.
The right to be seated
on the throne...
I had lost it long ago.
You are the King
and will stay so
for a long time.
Now
according to Vidur's suggestion
the kingdom
needs to be divided.
And you need to give
the Pandavas half the kingdom.
Which part of the kingdom
will we get, uncle?
Is there any other city
in the Kuru kingdom
which we can make our capital?
I know that,
dear.
Believe me.
I have no intention
of being unjust to you.
However
we are being lenient
to Duryodhan.
Of that I am sure.
But my hands are tied.
What do you mean by that?
When one upholds justice
with no love in his heart
no righteousness
or happiness
but has just a fatigue
and the sole desire
to end further labour
and in order to placate a person
when he is rewarded
or given a present
instead of being punished
it is called leniency.
The truth is,
such a situation
is the defeat of
the one upholding justice.
It is his failure.
I have laboured enough,
Dhritarashtra.
Dear
to make sure the Kuru kingdom
always houses righteousness
I have struggled endlessly
my entire life
and taken to arms when needed.
I require rest now.
I...
I shall go away
with Yudhishthir.
You may stay here with your son
and rule the kingdom by walking
on the path of righteousness.
What!
You will go away,
uncle?
If you go away
with that Yudhishthir
then who will
protect my kingdom?
I am...
I am blind.
I...
I have no eyesight,
uncle.
How will I be able
to protect my kingdom?
Who will respect me,
uncle?
If I give Yudhishthir
half the kingdom
then the prosperity
of Hastinapur
will get halved,
uncle.
No...
No.
If you go away
then Hastinapur will be
robbed of its strength, uncle.
It will be robbed
of its strength...
Then what will I do
with such a kingdom, uncle?
I...
Like the roar of an old lion
my voice too
will get drowned,
uncle.
I will have no competence.
No one will be
afraid of me, uncle.
No one will be afraid...
You will have to give Yudhishthir
half the kingdom, Dhritarashtra.
Why should I,
uncle?
Why should I give him
half the kingdom, uncle?
If you go away with him,
he will have the competence.
But what will I be left with?
Weakness?
His prosperity will magnify
with each passing day, uncle
but mine?
Mine will decrease
with each passing day.
Then how will dividing
the kingdom benefit me?
It would truly be just, uncle
when even if he takes
prosperity from me
the strength...
The strength would
remain with me.
Or maybe
he could have the strength and...
And prosperity
would remain with me.
If he gets both then it would be
unjust to me, uncle.
Possibly, you may get
the lesser share
but
if doing so can avert a war
within the Kuru kingdom
and establish peace in it, dear
then you should accept it
whole-heartedly.
This is an earnest request
to all of you from me.
But which region,
uncle?
Is there no region
in the Kuru kingdom
where there is no city?
An uninhabitable place...
A place
which is terrorized
by ogres and monsters.
There is,
Panchali.
The name of that city
is Khandavprastha.*
*It was a forest region (Khandava Vana) on the banks of Yamuna river, in modern day Delhi territory.
Then we shall ask
for that region.
This way, at the time
of the division
there will be no struggle
within the family.
Forget about finding
a city in that region.
There is not even
a hut there, Panchali.
How will you live there?
I am certain you know
how to make a hut, My Lord.
That would be more than
sufficient for me.
Panchali is correct,
Nakul.
Creating something from scratch
is always more gratifying.
And brother Dhritarashtra
will give
that region to you quite easily.
But living there
will be exceedingly
difficult, Draupadi.
But living there
will be exceedingly
troublesome, dear.
Troubles?
Difficulties give birth to glory
fame and prestige.
It is the mother to all three.
We shall ask for that region.
I have no region with me
which I can give to them
and yet preserve
the prosperity of Hastinapur.
If I have to protect my kingdom
then I shall require
prosperity, uncle.
And you have to admit it.
I assure you,
Dhritarashtra
that Hastinapur shall be
protected by Yudhishthir and me.
Whenever you need us
Yudhishthir and I
shall come to your aid.
And Yudhishthir
will never attack Hastinapur.
I believe that,
uncle.
But unfortunately, if such a
situation arises in the future
or my son does
something unrighteous
then you shall certainly
attack Hastinapur, uncle.
You know my son
quite well, uncle.
He knows what righteousness is
but can never act so.
Till date, you have stopped
his unrighteous acts.
In the future, you will
punish his misdeeds, uncle.
No, uncle.
I will never let that happen.
I will never let it happen...
That is why, I have
taken the decision, uncle
that I shall not declare
Yudhishthir King.
I shall not declare
Yudhishthir King...
I will challenge him
to a battle.
He will certainly slay me
in the battle, uncle.
He too is like my son.
I shall place my head on his lap
and bid adieu to this life.
Then I shall certainly
go to heaven, uncle.
I shall
certainly go to...
This decision of yours will
relieve uncle of a great burden.
Because of such benevolence
uncle has decided
to live with all of you.
That is our good fortune, uncle.
This is not only
your good fortune
but also that of uncle.
Do remember one thing.
Uncle has struggled
his entire life.
The number of sacrifices he has
made for the Kuru kingdom
cannot be achieved by a person
in a single lifetime.
Speak clearly,
Dhritarashtra.
What do you want?
All I want,
uncle
is for you to promise me
that under no circumstance
will you quit being on the side
of my sons and me.
Promise me this,
uncle.
Only then will I
divide the kingdom.
Promise me this,
uncle.
Grandsire has served the Kuru
kingdom his entire life, uncle.
Now, we five brothers
and our wife will be
at his service forever.
I have firm faith
that henceforth
grandsire will have to make
no more sacrifices, uncle.
Promise me, uncle.
Promise me.
You are asking me
for another sacrifice, dear.
So be it.
My father named me Bhishma.
In the name of righteousness
I can never tire out
in making sacrifices.
Today, I...
Today, I shall make
another sacrifice.
A container
can be emptied of its
contents only once.
But even after
one keeps drawing out
water from a well
it does not get emptied
because the water in the well
is obtained from
very deep within the earth.
Dhritarashtra
I have to demonstrate
the depth of my soul today.
I have to prove that I can
make numerous sacrifices.
Hence, I promise you
that until you are
the King of Hastinapur
I shall serve you and Hastinapur
as its servant
and deem every word
of yours an order.