There is just one punishment
for this mistake.
Banish him
from the Kuru kingdom!
But Arjun is my beloved
brother Pandu's son.
Hence, I won't be able
to punish him.
Minister!
- Yes, Your Majesty.
Now, you shall decide
on a punishment.
Why are you quiet, uncle?
It is the King's order.
Decide on a punishment.
Prince Arjun has made
a mistake, Duryodhan.
But I am certain that
his intentions were not wrong.
No one can predict
one's intentions, Minister.
But judgment should be based
on what is evidently seen.
I believe
that if His Highness Karna
forgives Prince Arjun
then he needn't be punished.
Friend Karna shall
definitely forgive him.
But Arjun must
first wash his feet
and ask for forgiveness.
Minister
order Arjun to do so.
Prince Arjun
you must wash the feet
of His Highness Karna
and ask him for forgiveness.
Only if King of Anga,
Karna, agrees to it.
I agree to it.
Pardon me, King of Anga.
Let's proceed, Sanjay!
The occasion of the banquet
has been destroyed.
But, Your Majesty...
I won't be a part
of this banquet, Minister!
But yes...
This banquet was organized
to announce something.
Let me make that announcement.
Tomorrow
in the morning
at the court,
the Prince of Hastinapur
will be crowned by me!
I am certain that
tomorrow, Duryodhan
will be crowned as the Prince.
Brother Arjun was insulted
for the same reason.
When he couldn't defeat him
with his intellect
he took to insult
so that we are unable to reason
at the court tomorrow.
What will we
reason about, Nakul?
That you are the right person
to be crowned the Prince.
No.
Only Lord Indra gets to decide
as to how much rainfall
a place deserves.
Every mortal has to
abide by that decision.
A King too possesses
a similar right.
But if one is declared a ruler
then it certainly does not mean
that he can own
that kingdom forever.
Lord Indra is immortal.
He is not a common man.
No one gets to rule
a kingdom forever.
That is why, it is tradition
that whoever is bestowed
with the throne
gets to be the rightful King.
What if one conquers that
very kingdom with his might?
Isn't he the rightful King then?
We will attain our rights
with our might, brother!
We shall battle it out,
if the need be!
Brother, we cannot forget
how Arjun was insulted.
With whom will you fight, Bheem?
With your own family?
With grandfather Bhishma?
With uncle Dhritarashtra?
With uncle Vidur
or with your cousins?
No, Bheem.
You must not
even think of a war.
We have to abide
by what the King says.
Enough, Princess.
Thinking of unhappy things
only magnifies sadness.
Do not cry anymore.
Today, one of my sons
was insulted
by another son of mine.
When a brother insults
another brother
the bitterness remains
for life, Priyamvada.
But they don't know how they
are related in the first place.
Princess, they consider
themselves as enemies.
And enemies insult each other.
When the time comes,
even Prince Arjun will have
his revenge for being insulted
and will be contented.
What kind of a consolation
is this, Priyamvada?
How can I...
How can I
see them as enemies?
Arjun's heart must be
writhing in agony.
He might find a way
to fight with Karna.
Before that, I must pacify him.
Mother.
Arjun.
What are you doing, son?
The fire bath, mother.
Your tears of sadness
make me do the fire bath.
By doing so, I am repenting.
Mother, you are crying
because of me.
No, son.
You are not at fault.
It is my fault, mother.
You have taught me
that the other name
for strength is patience.
A person who loses his patience
also loses his strength.
That is why...
That is why, I lost my patience.
And this is my mistake, mother.
This is my mistake.
And this is the reason...
This is the reason why
you have tears in your eyes.
When a mother cries
because of her son
a strange agony pervades
her emotions and even her laugh
gets tainted by it, mother.
Look.
I am smiling now.
Now, quit feeling sad.