Subhadra!
Brother, are you alright?
Why wouldn't I be, Subhadra?
It was you who was drowning.
You've forgotten your brothers
and stayed for so long
in Hastinapur.
I was afraid, Hastinapur had
become your in-laws' place.
Brother!
You are the apple
of my eyes, Subhadra.
Food tastes bland without you.
So, tell me.
Are you happy?
How can I be happy, brother?
I was terrorized
by that demon Kalyavan.
And brother,
I was so worried for you.
When you are worried,
you should meditate, Subhadra.
It helps immensely.
Besides, when one's
protector is Arjun
one need not worry at all.
Krishna!
No one can protect you from me!
Look, Kalyavan
is approaching us!
The other term for 'kaal'
is death, Arjun.
There is not a moment when
death doesn't approach a person.
Why worry about it, Arjun?
But
one must find time to
talk to one's loved ones.
So, tell me, Subhadra.
How is aunt?
I hope, she is well.
My heart yearns
to seek her blessings.
If you wish to stay alive
to seek her blessings
then draw your weapon, Vasudev!
Neither can my Sudarshan Chakra
nor your arrows kill him.
He can be slain only by
the fire of a sage's wrath.
So, what do we do now?
We shall run away.
Stop, Krishna! Why are you
fleeing like a coward?
Face your doom!
Stop, coward!
Shepherd, stop!
Stop and face your death!
How can you flee the battlefield
when death approaches you?
The future generations
will call you Ranchhod* and laugh at you!
*One who leaves the war area or battlefield, another name for Shri Krishna, when he left the battlefield in war with Jarasandh so that Mathura could be saved from destruction, he then went to Dwaraka.
I know.
The future generations
will refer to me by the name
of Ranchhod as well.
And for that,
I am grateful to you.
Now, quit talking and attack.
Krishna!
You said, your brother Krishna
is a courageous person.
Then why is he running away
in this manner?
You'll never understand my
brother Krishna, Prince Arjun.
He must certainly have
a plan in his mind.
Courageous men
have only one plan
to defeat the enemy.
And here, I don't see
Kalyavan getting defeated.
Kalyavan.
Hey!
Hey, shepherd!
Stop!
Where are you hiding?
Krishna!
Show yourself!
Where are you hiding?
Krishna!
Instead of fighting me
he is sleeping here.
Wake up, coward!
Wake up!
Do accept my greetings,
great sage Muchukund.
I have grown up hearing
the stories of your valour.
Who was that
who, without any reason
got burnt to ashes by me?
Nothing happens in this world
without a reason, great sage.
Perhaps
getting burnt by you
was his destiny.
And in order to
reduce him to ashes
maybe the Almighty
had motivated you
to leave your kingdom
and meditate here.
Who can ever know?
But do pardon me for interfering
with your meditation.
Now, you need not fret
and can resume your meditation.
Are you happy now, Arjun?
Greetings, Vasudev.
No.
You need not seek my blessings
because you have
a place in my heart.
Didn't I tell you, Prince Arjun?
My brother must have
indeed had a plan.
How did you achieve this,
Vasudev?
How I achieved it?
Arjun, do you know
about King Mandhata
and his son, King Muchukund?
Yes. He fought battles
all his life
and had conquered
the entire world.
And then he gave up his kingdom
in order to rest.
Yes, Arjun.
That person is indeed
praiseworthy who realizes that
worldliness is labour
and meditation
is the only form of rest.
Most people deem
worldliness to be happiness
and keep tiring themselves
but they do not even
think about resting.
For years
great sage Muchukund has been
meditating in that cave.
He had not opened his eyes
for 100 years.
All this meditation had
garnered him so much power
that when he would open
his eyes after all this while
the first person he would
lay his eyes upon would
be reduced to ashes.
Kalyavan was destined
to die this way.
I merely brought
the various forces together.
That's it.
Arjun
you should come to Dwaraka.
I have to talk to you
about so many things.
I have heard so much
about your might!
The migrants
from Hastinapur said
that you had constructed
a canopy of arrows
to protect yourself
from the roof collapsing on you.
And you even defeated
King Drupad.
I could do so only because
of your help, Vasudev.
The stones that you gifted me
had eyes on them and because
of them I could figure out
as to who the real Drupad was.
The one who didn't
have restless eyes.
Wonderful, Arjun!
You discovered such deep meaning
from those stones?
In other words,
that's not the reason
why you sent me those stones?
- Not at all.
Those five stones represented
you and your brothers.
I liked them and hence,
I sent them as a gift.
Prince Arjun,
don't believe my brother
because what he does and what
he says never mean the same.
Subhadra
the intelligence of a man
and the situation he is in
helps him understand things.
When it rains, a Peacock dances
but the Common Hawk-Cuckoo
cries.
The true meaning
of what a person says
can be understood
only by an intelligent person.
No wonder people
misunderstand each other.
But Subhadra
do you feel no shame
in talking of your brother so?
If people hear you,
they will say I lie.
'North-West, North,
North-East, East.'
'Dwaraka.'
Haven't you established
this kingdom, Vasudev?
It has prospered so much
in so little time.
No, Arjun.
I have not established
this kingdom.
The Yadavas have
worked hard to establish it.
I have merely used
my intelligence
to guide them.
The entire region of Arya knows
that you have
established Dwaraka.
And you say,
you have done nothing?
I am not lying, Arjun.
The truth is, I
do nothing.
And the one who realizes
that he does nothing himself
only he can achieve
an important feat.
Brother!
Won't you come
to the city with us?
Will you finish your entire
conversation right here?
Subhadra, I'll be there.
You should take Arjun
to the city.
I
need to leave to execute
an exceedingly important task.
But I shall return soon.
Vasudev
if you don't mind
then may I accompany you?
You wish to come along?
In fact, Arjun, you will help me
a great deal by accompanying me.
Just give me the order.
But do remember, Arjun.
This task will be exceedingly
difficult for you.
The truth is, this task will be
quite gruesome for you.