If we do not fail
their incognito exile
then there will
be a war.
Child, don't assume
that during that war
Arjun will fight Karna
and Bhima will fight
with you.
No, my child.
No.
Both the troops
will seek the help
of their other friends
who are kings.
The raging armies
will come together.
There will be horrifying
demolition.
And even if you do win
you will not be
greatly benefited.
A broken kingdom
a shattered empire
poverty
and struggle is all
that you will get.
My child, when there
is famine
not only does the water
on the land dry up
but also one's entire life
too gets dried up.
Hence
stop chanting about
waging a war.
My child
I am living with the aspiration
to make you the king
of a prosperous kingdom.
No war.
Just deceit. Deceit!
King of Sindhu, Jayadratha
Dushasana
send your envoys
to all the states
of the Arya empire.
Send your spies to every corner
of the Arya dynasty.
Find them!
Where have they gone?
Those five powerful men
and the most beautiful
woman in the world
cannot hide
this easily.
Find them!
Go look!
'Virat.'
Brother, there goes my mace
into its secret hiding.
Now it feels like the incognito
exile has begun.
It will be very difficult for us
to remain in hiding
if all of us are together.
The news of our incognito exile
must have definitely reached
every corner
of the Arya empire.
Everyone must be
looking for a family
with five men
and a woman.
Hence
we cannot stay
together.
We will have a new identity
for the next one year
and we will have to always
keep this new identity in mind.
But, brother, if someone
asks you who you are
then what will your
answer be?
I cannot lie, Bhima.
If someone asks me who I am
I will remain quiet.
Your remaining quit is not
sufficient, brother.
Your being quiet
can reveal our truth.
Can't you lie for just
a year, brother?
Not even for a moment,
Nakul.
Whether lightning strikes
a tree once or continuously
there's no difference.
The tree gets burnt
the first time.
Lie spoken once
harms the soul.
I cannot be defeated
by someone's conspiracy
and break my vow.
- But, brother
if we're caught again
then we'll be exiled again.
Another incognito exile.
This tradition will see no end.
- I know that.
That's the whole idea
behind incognito exile.
But, Sahadeva
if I had to use lies
to be victorious
then why would we
have to be exiled?
Brother Arjun, show us
the way.
Parth*
Arjun other name, Paartha "son of Pritha (Kunti)."
many couples have secretive
names for each other.
Even I give you
a name today.
Here after your name is Mantri Kank.*
*Sage Gold.
And until someone specifically
asks you
if you have another name
beyond Kank
you will introduce yourself
as Kank to everyone.
And when someone
does question you
you will remain quiet.
You can do this, right?
Yes.
If Draupadi has given a name
to her husband
then that will definitely
be my identity.
In the same manner, I will
give all of you a name
and for the coming year
that name will be your
only identity.
No, Draupadi, don't
give me a name.
Madhav has already
given me a name.
What name has he given you?
Brihn! It sounded something
like that, isn't it, Nakul?
I don't remember, brother.
But Vasudeva said
that brother Arjun looks
beautiful with that name.
Why?
What so special about that name?
There's a speciality,
Draupadi.
Now, you will have
to hide your clothes
or else he will
steal them.
Lord Agni, this bow was given
by you as a sacrament.
We're leaving our weapons
in your protection.
After one year
we will come back
to get our weapons
and we will attack
the Kauravas
to destroy them.
Bless us.
'Chaitra.'*
*The first month of the year in Hindu calendar.
Your Highness, Pandavas
are not there at Dwarka.
We went to Panchal.
But they weren't there, either.
Where are the Pandavas?
- Our messengers have sent
a message from Naaglok* and Kuntibhoj, brother.
*Naga Loka: Naga/serpent Kingdom (Bheem's drowning location).
Pandavas are not there either.
Pandavas!
Uncle
even the last spy
has returned.
The Pandavas are not there
in any of our
neighbouring kingdoms
that is for sure.
Dwarka
Panchal
Kashi
Naaglok
Madra, Kuntibhoj
every place where
the Pandavas have their family
they haven't gone
even there, uncle.
Where do we look for them?
In heaven!
My child, if they
were in Heaven
then why would we
look for them?
They are hiding
in one of these states
within the boundaries
Arya dynasty.
But where, uncle?
There's only one month left
for the completion
of the incognito exile.
Just 30 days!
I cannot find any other place
where we should look
for them uncle.
No place!
Think properly,
King of Gandhar.
Shakuni!
You are very proud
of your wisdom.
Vasudeva Krishna!
What could he have
thought of
that I have failed
to understand?
What are the things
that a human requires
so he can hide?
New attire
new name
new city
and a new occupation.
- Not occupation, my child.
Not occupation.
One cannot change
his occupation
very easily.
He can only indulge
in the occupation
that he has practise of.
But, uncle
warriors like
Arjun and Bhima...
If they were a part
of any army
then they wouldn't be
able to hide.
Not war!
What are their
other skills?
Nakul
he is the most knowledgeable
when it comes to horse riding.
Think, my child.
Think!
For the last one year
which kingdom's horses
have become the most famous?
Sahadeva.
A cow is the happiest
in Sahadeva's presence.
Think, my child.
Which kingdom's cows
have become famous
in the last one year?
And, Yudhisthira
is a scholar at monarchy.
Find out, my child
which king in the last
one year
has signed a treaty
with other kingdoms?
Think, my child.
Think!
I have heard
that the king of Virat
has signed a treaty
with many kingdoms
of the south.
His kingdom
has been prosperous.
The king has begun
work on making
100 new reservoirs.
Aroma,
odour
and human behaviour
cannot be hidden.
Our spies may have failed
to find them
but, my child
Pandavas
are definitely
in Virat.
In Virat!
Virat.
- Cook Vallabh. - Cook Vallabh.*
*"Beloved."
Please give us a 'ladoo'.
If you have so many 'ladoos'
then you'll become fat
like Bhima.
Am I fat?
- He isn't referring to you.
He's referring to Hastinapur's
Prince Bhima.
But he doesn't know
that Bhima
is the most powerful
in the world.
'Ladoos' give energy
to Bhima.
I want to become
the best archer in the world
just like Arjun.
- What's so great about archery?
Become strong.
Gain strength.
Here, child
have 'ladoos' prepared
by cook Vallabh.
You will gain strength
and become powerful.
Have one more.
Have them.
Cook, I want one too.
You!
Run away from here.
You want to be an archer!
Run!
Listen, child
take these two 'ladoos' for Tantripal.*
*"Guardian of the calves."
Who's Tantripal?
- There's a man
who is sitting
with the cows.
I'm scared that if he doesn't
get these 'ladoos'
he will start feeding on grass.
Here.
Go, child.
Go.
Tantripal...
Tantripal.
Cook 'ladoo' has sent
Vallabh for you.
I mean
cook Vallabh has sent
'ladoo' for you.
He himself loves 'ladoo'
since childhood.
What? You know him
since childhood?
Don't even ask, child.
Cook Vallabh once gave me a pat
on my back.
Look at what it has
become.
'Ladoo'!
These 'ladoos' are delicious.
Child, do one thing.
There's a person
at the stable.
His name is Granthika.*
*"Astrologer, narrator."
Go and give this 'ladoo'
to him.
Take it.
Hurry up.
Go.