My beloved nephew!
The first stage of our plan
was successful.
Now, the desire of
leaving Hastinapur
and going to Varnavrat
will stem in the heart of Kunti.
Uncle
how do you know that?
My dear!
My beloved nephew!
One who is familiar with
the nature of a female serpent
only he can play a been
and manipulate her.
Purochan has gone to meet Kunti
to sow the seed of desire
to go to Varnavrat in her.
Varnavrat is just wonderful,
Her Highness.
Just wonderful.
The elephants there
seem like moving hills.
This was when
you were not married.
Prince Pandu
used to visit Varnavrat
to examine the elephants.
And he was a beloved King
of us subjects.
He was very benevolent
and affectionate towards us.
Do you remember, Purandiri?
I indeed remember, My Lord.
After he passed away, God seems
to have become angry with us.
So, we wish to invite your sons
to the Varnavrat Shiv temple
to have them conduct
a veneration there.
We have taken this oath.
I have had
a beautiful palace constructed
for you and the Princes,
Her Highness.
And you will face
no inconvenience there.
I do not doubt your
architectural knowledge
but going to Varnavrat
and living there
is not possible, Purochan.
Yudhishthir has been crowned
the Prince just recently.
He has many responsibilities.
As ordered by His Highness,
Bheem, Nakul and Sahadev
have gone out of the kingdom
to manage the border issues.
And Arjun has gone to Dwaraka.
If my sons decide to go there
I will have you informed.
Your sons have made
the decision, mother.
We shall certainly move
to Varnavrat, Purochan.
Is that true, Crown Prince?
Indeed.
You are too kind, Crown Prince.
I am certain
that if you perform
a veneration in Varnavrat
the soul of the late King Pandu
will be contented.
We are also certain
of that, Purochan.
On behalf of the kingdom,
the subjects of Varnavrat
will be given money as charity
by mother.
Have this news
announced as well.
As you say, Crown Prince.
Now, allow us to leave.
Allow us to leave, Her Highness.
Why did you decide
to go to Varnavrat
all of a sudden, Yudhishthir?
Mother, be it a person
or situation
staying near them makes one
realize their demerits
while staying away,
makes one realize their merits.
I wish to test the merits
and demerits of Hastinapur.
I am close to it now
but I wish to go away
for a while.
That way I will be able
to compare the two.
Purochan.
Greetings, King of Gandhar.
What did that Kunti say?
Not Her Highness
but Crown Prince Yudhishthir
has given the answer,
King of Gandhar.
And very soon, they will
proceed to Varnavrat.
Splendid!
Absolutely marvellous!
Insects that fly often jump
into the fire themselves.
We merely have to start a fire.
This is called an ideal time.
This plan is based
entirely on you, Purochan.
If you succeed,
your future generations
will never have to
engage in labour
for I will make you
a filthy rich man.
However, if you fail
then your future generations
won't be able to engage in
labour for they won't be born.
You need not worry,
King of Gandhar.
Things will go
as you have planned.
I have brought this vessel
for Prince Duryodhan.
Place it there.
Now, you need to go to Varnavrat
to welcome the Pandavas.
When the time is right,
my messenger will come
to you bearing the order
from me.
As you say, King of Gandhar.
Goodbye.
Leave.
Beloved Yudhishthir
were you not going to reconsider
going to Varnavrat?
Greetings, uncle.
I have meditated over it.
A veneration is
being held in Varnavrat
in father's memory.
I think, it is not only
important for us to go there
but also appropriate.
- But why?
When it is time to curtail
Duryodhan's unpleasant deeds
will your going away from
Hastinapur be appropriate?
If I stay here, everyday
Duryodhan will hatch
a new scheme.
Then what's the point,
Yudhishthir?
When you shall return
he will begin scheming again.
No, uncle.
If water is
contaminated with soil
stirring the water
does not purify it.
If given some time, the soil
settles down on its own.
I am absolutely certain
that Duryodhan's
agitated mind will
settle down with time.
- Just think about it.
Suddenly, after such a long time
why did subjects of Varnavrat
think of brother Pandu?
Before this, no veneration
was ever held in his memory.
Brother Pandu going to Varnavrat
in his lifetime
is also not something
I can recollect.
Do you not find this odd?
I have meditated over it, uncle.
If we do face any trouble
in Varnavrat
my brothers and I will be
able to handle it.
But in Hastinapur, our hearts
are always troubled, uncle.
One needs valour to battle
external troubles, uncle.
But a troubled heart
can be pacified
only by hardening it.
But acting heartlessly
with my cousins
is not something
I will be able to do.
'North-West, North,
North-East, East.'
'Dwaraka.'
Be careful.
Do not step on that.
'Do not step on
those illusory circles'
'else you will land
in the Netherworld.'
'You dance quite well.'
Did I not tell you?
Wait, let me come to you.
Be careful.
I have dug holes in the ground
and covered them with a carpet.
This exercise is done
to strengthen one's memory.
But, apart from
your brother Krishna
you will not believe anyone.
Do you still doubt
brother Krishna?
No.
I doubted him before I met him
but
now, I doubt myself.
So, what brings you here?
There is a message for you
from Hastinapur.
Where is Madhav?
I need to seek
his permission to leave.
So, are you going back
to Hastinapur?
No, not to Hastinapur.
Brother Yudhishthir has asked me
to proceed to Varnavrat at once.
But you hardly stayed
in Dwaraka.
The wise men of Dwaraka say
where there is Krishna,
there is Dwaraka.
And a friend resides
in the heart.
If you see it from this angle,
Dwaraka is right here.
So, what's the point
of staying in this Dwaraka?
I must follow brother
Yudhishthir's order and leave.
Allow me to leave.
It is time now, dear.
I have heard the news
that very soon Arjun
will reach Varnavrat.
In the palace of Varnavrat
the five enemies of ours
will assemble.
In that very palace
will be held the 'Yuvrajasuya Yajna' for you.
*Young (yuv) king imperial burning sacrifice.
'Yuvrajasuya Yajna?'
When a King
proves his competence
he conducts a 'Rajasuya Yajna,'
King of Anga.
Beloved Duryodhan
is about to prove his competence
as the Crown Prince.
Hence, he will conduct
a 'Yuvrajasuya Yajna.'
What do you mean?
In Varnavrat, Purochan has
constructed a palace
not with bricks, stones
and binding agent
but lac
cotton
animal flesh
clarified butter
and dried grass.
He has constructed it with
various inflammable items.
This is 'Lakshagraha!' 'Lakshagraha!'*
*House of lac.
This is 'Lakshagraha.'
A 'yajna' will be
conducted there. A 'yajna!'
And in that 'yajna'
that palace will be used
as the sacrifice, friend.
And my enemies
will burn to ashes
in that 'yajna!'