'Duryodhan will indeed
be punished for his sins.'
'This is the curse
of Yajnaseni Draupadi!'
'If your sons have
renounced the Almighty'
'and embraced opulence'
'then they are bound
to be slain, Your Highness.'
'Emperor Dhritarashtra of Kuru,
all your sons will die'
'at my hands!'
'I will rip open Dusshasan's
chest and drink his blood!'
'The day my sons
gain independence'
'it will be the end
of all your happiness!'
'This is the beginning of a war,
King Dhritarashtra.'
'There will be a blood bath!'
'This is the beginning
of Mahabharat!'
'The day my sons
gain independence'
'it will be the end
of all your happiness!'
No...
- 'There will be a blood bath!'
'Father!
Father, save me!'
Duryodhan!
My Lord!
My Lord
are you alright?
My Lord...
'Bheem, please do not drink
the blood from my chest!'
'Duryodhan, I have killed
99 of your brothers!'
'Now, I will kill
you as well!'
'Brother Bheem,
please do not kill me.'
'Father,
please save me!'
'How will that blind man
save you, Vikarna?!'
'All your brothers
will die at my hands!'
'I will kill all you brothers!
- Bheem, do not kill me!'
'I have killed ninety nine...
- Father, save me!'
'I will kill you as well!
- Father!'
'Do not drink my blood...'
No!
'I will kill all you brothers!'
Brother.
Vidur! Vidur,
stop these cries!
Vidur, stop these cries!
- Brother Dhritarashtra.
Stop these cries, Vidur!
- Brother Dhritarashtra!
Calm down.
Those cries are merely
a figment of your imagination.
However, very soon
those screams
will be heard
from the battlefield.
Vidur...
Vidur,
save my sons!
Save my sons,
Vidur!
I can hear their screams
when I am asleep
and I am tormented
by the thought of their death
in my waking hours,
Vidur!
It seems as though...
It seems as though
someone is chopping off
the parts of my body
one by one, Vidur!
Someone is chopping off
the parts of my body!
I am in great agony,
Vidur!
I am in great agony!
You will indeed
be in agony, brother.
You had derived joy
from someone's agony, remember?
The possibility of their joy
will indeed be agonizing now.
Do remember.
The one to build an embankment
on a river does derive joy
but along with it,
one also gets surrounded by fear
because when
that embankment breaks
the river that gave life
to various cities
drowns them in its waters,
brother.
The embankment of treachery
made on the Pandavas' competence
has finally broken,
brother.
It will drown all your sons.
It will drown your sons.
Be quiet,
Vidur!
Be quiet!
Be quiet.
If you utter another word
about the death of my sons
then I will crush you
to death this instant, Vidur!
I will kill you!
I am bound to die,
brother.
Merely breathing the air
does not denote life.
When the heart is robbed of joy
and the soul is robbed of hope
it is called death,
brother.
With this war
the prosperity of the Kuru
kingdom will be destroyed.
Millions of young men will die.
I have dedicated my entire life
to this kingdom.
When it will be
left impoverished
I will be as good as dead,
brother.
You too shall experience
this terrible ordeal.
No, Vidur...
My younger brother.
My beloved brother.
Please show me a way
out of this dreadful situation,
Vidur.
Please show me a way!
Even if we seek the refuge
of the Pandavas
they will punish my sons
by sentencing
them to death,
Vidur!
The Pandavas will punish
my sons by sentencing
them to death.
No, they will not.
I have faith that they will not.
Return the Pandavas
their property
and apologize to them.
Even during the horrific
moments of the game of dice
when the Pandavas did not
forsake righteousness
they will not do so
now either, brother.
No matter in what form
the Holy Basil is consumed
it does not forsake
its medicinal properties.
The Pandavas will not forsake
righteousness now either.
Your sons must touch
Draupadi's feet
and apologize
brother.
They must atone for their sins
and accept
the punishment as well.
One thing is clear,
brother.
Your sons can be saved
only by Draupadi now.
Sister-in-law!
Come and sit,
Subhadra.
Do you know?
It is a tradition
of the Kuru Royal Family
where the mother
ties a protection amulet
on her son before marriage.
Look at this.
I have made this
protection amulet for Abhimanyu.
These five stones
were given to me by Govind.
These five stones represent
the five sons of Pandu.
I know,
sister-in-law.
Brother had asked me once
to take these to My Lord.
The protection of
all five of his fathers will be
with Abhimanyu with its help.
Where is Abhimanyu?
He is in his chamber
with My Lord.
He is getting dressed
for the marriage.
Sister-in-law
you should tie this
on Abhimanyu's arm.
Me?
But why me, Subhadra?
This is...
Because the mantra of his life
is to avenge your insult.
The right to offer him
protection is yours
and even the strength
to do so resides in you.
Instead of wearing an armour
why am I adorning
these ornaments, father?
Madhav was correct.
When a warrior goes to battle
with the hope of a better life
he meets with success.
King Virat has protected us.
By forging familial ties
with him
we are honouring him.
But if uncle
and Mother Draupadi say
that I cannot go to battle
right after the marriage
then I will have to
disobey them.
When all of you
will be going for the battle
and my brothers will be showing
valour in the battlefield
with weapons in their hands
I will not be able to stay
away from the battlefield.
I promise you
that I will not stop you
from going for the battle.
However,
if either
you or your brothers
are harmed in the battle
then even after the death
of the hundred Kauravas
we will be the ones
to be defeated.
That is why, in the battlefield
you will do no such thing
which is not required.
I will make
no such promise, mother.
I can make only one promise
that I will follow every order
of father Yudhishthir.
That would be adequate.
All five of your fathers
will protect you.
With this protection amulet
I shall bind all the sons
of Pandu to a cause.
The responsibility
of your safety
will now be theirs.
May you live long!
Do not place the weight
of my safety on the shoulders
of my fathers, Mother Draupadi.
Their shoulders have the weight
of protecting righteousness.
You need not worry,
mother.
I will string these stones
together and wear it on my arm.
As long as a son has
the protection of his mother
he cannot be defeated.
Besides,
I have...
I have two mothers.
Did you call for me,
mother?
Son Duryodhan
do you see these lamps?
These hundred lamps
represent the lives
of the hundred sons of mine.
Kunti has lit them
and
fate will extinguish them.
Mother
all our lives get extinguished
by nothing but fate.
No, son.
The lives of my sons
will be extinguished
in the battlefield.
This is the curse of Kunti
and the curse of a heart
tormented by injustice
can never be futile.
These things mean nothing,
mother.
In order to scare you
those Pandavas have come up
with this contraption.
If I extinguish
any one of the lamps
this instant
then, will
one of my brothers die?
Then here you go,
mother.
If the first lamp
represents my life
then I shall extinguish it
this instant.
It did not get extinguished,
did it?
These lamps will be extinguished
only in the battlefield, son.
Son, I called you here
only to let you know about it.
Quit the thought of a battle
and apologize to Draupadi.
Return them
their property, son.
Please save yourselves.
- Impossible, mother.
Impossible.
Man's life does not hold
more value than his pride.
The Pandavas had insulted me
in the court of Indraprastha.
My revenge
will be complete only with
the death of those Pandavas!
Son...
Son Duryodhan
just think once about
the situation your father is in.
His heart
is exceedingly agitated.
The uncertainties of the future
keep him awake all night.
Duryodhan
just look at the sadness
of your mother.
A mother who loses her sons
experiences the agony
of the bite
of a hundred serpents.
Her life becomes hell.
Even death does not embrace her.
Then tell Queen Mother Kunti
to be prepared
to experience such agony
because the ones to die
in the battlefield
will be the Pandavas!
They will die at my hands.
Mother
do not let such illusory lamps
scare you.
I do not believe
in these things.
If lighting and
extinguishing such lamps
could affect the life
and death of man
then all the people
who make lamps in this world
would be made to sit
in a temple.
In this war
I will emerge victorious.
I shall become the Emperor
of this land!