Is your
will power your own,
Radheya?
If you had that kind
of independence
then why would you have to
bear that crown again?
I am your wife.
I shall indeed stand by you.
Accepting every decision
of her husband
is the duty of a wife.
Stop, Vrushali.
Vrushali, I feel as though
you will never experience
any joy by living in the palace
and seeing you in pain
will make my heart
bleed as well.
I wish to be the reason
of your happiness, Vrushali.
I do not wish to be
the reason of your sadness.
If living in the palace
will make you unhappy
then you need not live there.
You have absolutely
no such obligation, Vrushali.
My child is growing
in your womb, Vrushali
and I am absolutely certain
that the values you will
impart to it in this hut
will be more than anything
it will ever get in a palace.
If you like
then you may live here
under the care and protection
of my parents.
A person sailing across the
ocean is guided by the Pole Star
even though it is
far away from him.
You too will have to
stay away from me
and guide me to happiness.
If it is written in my fate
then I shall indeed
reach that place someday.
'Every time I have left my home
wearing this crown'
I have lost something
very precious to me.
I must leave with
the Crown Prince soon
for Indraprastha,
Vrushali.
I cannot refuse him.
I am indebted to him
but one day, I shall pay off
all his debts and come to you
by freeing myself
of all my struggles
to rest.
Where have they built
the illusory court?
I can only see the woods
all around us.
Be careful,
Dusshasan.
I have heard that Mayasur
has built an even more fantastic
court than that of Lord Indra.
Is Lord Indra's court
this dark?
Lord Indra's court
is illuminated with the prayers
of us mortals, my darlings.
Such dedication to Yudhishthir!
Which being on earth
can illuminate this place?
A swarm of fireflies!
Let's proceed,
my darlings.
uncle.
Let's
Let's proceed,
my darlings.
Welcome, Crown Prince
Duryodhan of Hastinapur!
All of you are welcome to the
illusory court of Indraprastha!
W-What is this marvellous sight,
brother Duryodhan?!
Be quiet,
foolish Dusshasan!
Your words are like
salt being rubbed
into the raw wounds of my heart.
Be patient, my darling.
Be patient!
All this can be yours
and it shall indeed be so.
I have never accepted
defeat in my life.
Let it be,
uncle.
You made several plans
but none were successful!
I have no faith in you.
You have no faith in me!
What are you saying,
my darling?!
I am telling the truth, uncle.
I want success today...
Today!
Not in the future.
Henceforth,
I shall come up
with my own plans.
In order to be successful
one does not need a plan,
Crown Prince Duryodhan!
One needs to take a decision
and in order to take one,
one must rid oneself of fear.
Welcome, Crown Prince Shishupal!
You are welcome to the illusory
court of Indraprastha!
Crown Prince Shishupal
are you questioning
my competence?!
No
I am not
but your beloved
brother Yudhishthir is.
The sons of King Pandu
are questioning your competence.
Do you not know
how many Kings have come here
to Emperor Yudhishthir's...
Oh!
No...
They have come to the
undefeated Emperor Yudhishthir
to accept his dominance!
In the end
that deceitful
and treacherous cowherd
has made Yudhishthir
the undefeated Emperor
but the 500-year-old
throne of Hastinapur
has not yet been able
to achieve this feat.
Crown Prince Duryodhan
do you know why?
Because you
are impotent!
Shishupal!
Crown Prince Duryodhan
do you know why?
Because you are impotent!
Shishupal!
Do not resort to verbal abuses,
Crown Prince of Chedi.
The competition begun here
by the Pandavas today
shall indeed end
in the battlefield someday
and then
everyone will know
how competent each person is.
Are you not the King of Anga?
I had seen you at Panchali's
'swayamvar.'
Were you not called the
son of a charioteer
by Panchali?
And you had left the bow
right there at the arena.
Had I been in your place
I would have destroyed
that bow that instant!
But you are foolish!
Besides, nothing more
can be expected of you
King of Anga.
Crown Prince Shishupal
do you engage in verbal abuses
only to digest your food
or has this 'yajna'
left you unhappy as well?
Unhappy?
No.
I am exceedingly unhappy!
Whenever Krishna
succeeds in something
it leaves me deeply agonized!
Was Krishna not instrumental
in this 'yajna' as well?
I shall indeed
render it ineffective!
What kind of a
Rajsuya 'Yajna' is this
where none of the other
Kings are present?
But
we saw many Kings
and maids enter through
that door, brother Duryodhan.
Even Shishupal
went through it just now.
Where did everyone go?
Look, Prince Dusshasan.
Those maids
vanish the moment they reach a
certain length from the 'yajna.'
Many people must certainly
have gathered here
but because of the illusion
we are unable to see them.
Will you not seek my blessings
brother Shishupal?
In your entire life
I see nothing worth revering,
Krishna.
You are certainly older than me
but inferior in terms of action.
Even a 100-year-old
Indian Plum tree
is used only as firewood,
Krishna
and not to construct a house.
You sound like quite
the intellectual, Shishupal
but disrespecting people
elder to oneself
is a misdeed.
I do not fear anyone!
Besides, you had
promised my mother
that you would pardon a 100
misdeeds of mine, Krishna.
Besides, I am keeping a count
of my misdeeds,
Krishna.
Despite knowing
that it is a misdeed, why do
you get such joy from doing it?
What if, Shishupal
when the time is right
you forget the count
of your misdeeds?
Just because the limit is 100
pushing it to 99
is incorrect,
beloved brother.
So, Crown Prince Shishupal...
The way Vasudev's father
is an uncle to the Pandavas
similarly, is he
not your uncle as well?
Then why do you behave
in such a manner with him?
Oh yes!
I had forgotten
that at the time of your birth
Vasudev Krishna had stripped you
of all your powers.
I had heard of such a thing.
I had four arms
and a third eye when I was born.
I had the opulence of the Gods
but who knows what
that Krishna did
and stripped me
of all my powers.
Two of my arms and
the third eye.
The only enemy
I have in this world
is that wicked Krishna!
And just like me
you are utterly impotent here,
Crown Prince Shishupal.
The truth is, when it comes to
Vasudev Krishna's treachery
no one can
ever win against them.
I am not impotent like you,
Duryodhan.
Krishna was instrumental
in this 'yajna,' was he not?
I will tarnish the sanctity
of this 'yajna' at any cost.
I will let this 'yajna'
not get completed at any cost.
Krishna's plan will fail.