Brother-in-law
I accept your request.
I...
I will not leave Hastinapur
and go anywhere.
My darling
you now have
everlasting protection.
Now, you may do anything
but the sons of Pandu
will not be able to attack you.
Dear Draupadi
always...
Always be there for my sons.
Henceforth
it is your duty to dispense
advice to them.
How can I ever give them
any advice, mother-in-law?
Your sons need your affection
and experience,
mother-in-law.
No, dear.
A mother
thinks of the happiness
of her sons.
But a wife...
Along with the happiness
of her husband, a wife
also thinks of his honour.
Now...
Now that it is time
for my sons to have
their share of honour
and by conquering the world
they have the opportunity
to make their ancestors proud
maybe...
Maybe my motherly love...
My motherly love
may obstruct their path.
A decision taken by fate
is always correct,
dear
No, mother.
This decision of fate
is not correct.
Fate is hard-hearted.
Without your cheerful face
to guide us
how will we ever
find our way, mother?
How will we find our way...
What uncle did was unjust!
He has no right to drive
our mother away from us.
How can a mother
ever go away
from her children, Nakul?
I am...
I am always with you.
But
this is my home.
I had come here with my husband.
Brother-in-law is correct.
I can either live here
or in some hermitage
in the woods.
Until I am alive
there is no other place
I can call home, son.
But mother...
This is not the time
for such things, son.
Do remember.
No matter what situation
you face in your life
all of you must accept the
decisions made by Yudhishthir.
You will not argue with him.
You should go now, sons.
I will...
I will employ my tears
to wash away
all the hurdles
that come in your path.
Grandsire
let's proceed.
Under your guidance,
we five brothers
will try to establish
a righteous kingdom.
I have firm faith,
Yudhishthir
that the prestige of our
ancestors will indeed
be augmented by you.
That you will never go astray
from the path of righteousness.
Mark my words,
dear
that greed is the basis
of all that is unrighteous.
Rule your kingdom
but do not ever covet it.
You may indeed earn wealth
Do not ever get envious
of someone else's wealth.
And
do not ever flaunt your wealth.
Only contentment and restraint
can strengthen
your righteousness.
Grandsire
are you not coming with us?
Time is a prominent
form of a 'yajna.'
It is a 'yajna' that
goes on for eternity.
In that 'yajna'
all of us are required to offer
ourselves as the sacrifice.
And that sacrifice
helps in the establishment
of righteousness in this world.
I have taken the decision
that now...
Now, it is time for me
to be the sacrifice.
Why did you not tell us
before, grandsire
that you had promised to stay
here in Hastinapur?
Then we would never have
asked for dividing the kingdom.
For this very reason, dear.
For exactly this reason.
I knew that
if I tell you
then maybe you would not
accept the new kingdom.
And
for you to have your own kingdom
was far more important.
Grandsire
by giving a kingdom
uncle has snatched
a lot from us.
No, dear.
One's cornerstone
is honouring the limits
of one's competence.
So must I.
Think of it like this, dear
that by snatching everything
you had, Dhritarashtra
has challenged your competence.
I have firm faith
that the city you establish
in Khandavprastha
will forever act as
the center of the entire
Aryan region.
But who will live
with us, grandsire?
A King has his subjects.
And for the subjects
to stay with their King
denotes the King's success.
Look over there.
All of them are with you.
King Yudhishthir
all of us will come with you.
We will help you establish
the new kingdom.
By leaving Hastinapur empty
we cannot establish
our kingdom, Vrishbhan.
When you leave
Hastinapur will become empty
anyway, Your Highness.
Take us with you.
We will serve you.
We will do what you ask us to.
She...
She is my daughter,
Your Highness.
She will be a handmaiden
to Her Highness.
She will serve her.
What is your name?
Vrushali.