A person who was born blind
won't let be
Gandhari's husband, father!
Never!
Gandhari?
Gandhari, stop!
Gandhari!
It means...
It means, my dear sister
has been kept in the dark!
Firmness and callousness
have a very thin line
of difference, father.
But the difference itself,
runs quite deep.
A father is firm
and callous is but an enemy.
An enemy.
No, Gandhari.
No.
It's not the time to
shed tears, Gandhari.
It's not the time to cry.
I am still alive.
Your brother!
I will not let anything happen
that may cause grief to you.
It's my oath.
I am not scared
of Hastinapur.
They may have power.
They may have abundant wealth.
But you and your future
are not within their rights
to trample upon.
No rights at all!
Why did father do this?
Why didn't he inform that my
husband was born blind?
I wouldn't have at least
dreamt so big.
Gandhari, he isn't
your husband yet.
He isn't your husband.
The imbecile heart dreams
beyond limits, brother.
I had dreamt about my future.
The future shattered in no time.
Dreams are like
a bottle filled with fireflies.
Once it breaks,
all lustre is lost.
The shattered glass pierces
and bleeds the heart.
I am hurt
for father should have
at least told me.
Gandhari.
I will immediately send a
message to Hastinapur
that we do not accept
the wedding proposal.
They can attack if they wish to
but we do not accept
the wedding proposal.
We do not accept it.
Brother.
Didn't father have at least
that much faith in me?
Wasn't he confident of
the values he taught me?
Gandhari
what are you saying?
Brother, father has
pampered me very much.
Parents can never ask for
compensation of their love.
Cession in lieu of love can't be
forsaken by an offspring either.
When my parents are in a dilemma
I cannot refuse from
sacrificing, brother.
Father didn't have faith in me
and this bothers me.
But being a princess
I accept his decision.
But
with a man who
was born blind...
How would you be happy
with him, Gandhari?
How would you?
If I don't find happiness
then it's apt to consider
what's found to be bliss.
The happiness of the subjects
should be more important.
These are the values
taught by my parents.
As a son has rights
on his father's wealth
a daughter has rights on his
values, doesn't she?
This marriage
is acceptable to me.
But, Gandhari...
Brother, get ready
to proceed to Hastinapur.
Princess
why are you putting
out the lamps?
I am trying to get
used to darkness.
But, princess, aren't you
scared of darkness?
I am...
I am really scared of darkness.
But darkness is going to
be a part of my life.
I have to fight my fears.
Princess, you are
marrying a blind man
and not darkness.
To understand one
with dark cast over his eyes
one has to understand
the darkness, Sugadha.
How would have the prince
lived in darkness all his life?
When we stumble while walking
we are careful of
not stumbling again.
But
the prince may have
stumbled several times.
The fear of darkness must
have hounded him too.
Princess, I have no answers
to your questions.
But I have to find the
answers to all these questions.
Hereafter, I have to
stop depending on light.
I have to befriend darkness.
In this very darkness,
my married life
and steps to its success
will be visible to me.
Go, Sugadha.
Sugadha, leave!
'All hail!
- King Dhritarashtra!'
Dhritarashtra.
- Mother.
Greetings, mother.
- May you live long, son.
Mother, I... - I had seen
Gandhari yesterday.
The guest house used by
king of Gandhar and his family
she was seated there
at the porch.
She is really beautiful.
Here, wear this.
Mother, another piece
of ornament?
That isn't an ornament
it's a talisman.
Let's go.
The Queen Mother is eager to
take you to the wedding tent.
Let's proceed.
Where is Pandu?
I am here, mother.
Pandu, I can't see myself.
You should tell me,
how do I look?
Today is my first
meeting with Gandhari.
Your valour is known
all over Gandhar.
Your image in the eyes
of the princess
has already been discerned
before your meeting.
Let's go.
The auspicious time for
the wedding is nearing. - Sure.
Greetings, Queen Mother. - You
should go to the guest house
and give a message to
the king of Gandhar
to immediately come
along with Gandhari.
The auspicious time for
the wedding is here.
Queen Mother, their messenger
has brought a message
that princess Gandhari
is being adorned.
They will all start for here
in the next two half hours.
Sugadha, are you done
with the adornment?
Yes, princess.
All of you should now
wait outside my room.
Leave me alone for some time.
But, princess, it's time
for the wedding.
Let the future wait for me.
I want to be alone
for some time.
Leave, Sugadha.