Prince Uttar.
Would you like to be the chariot
rider for Pandu's son Arjun?
Pandu's son?
Are you Arjun himself?
Under this guise?
Capability is determined
neither by guise
nor by name.
Capability lies in the mind.
Steer the chariot, Prince Uttar.
Today, Arjun will fight,
not Brihannala!
Today, I must teach
prince Duryodhan
the laws of the battlefield.
This surely is
the reverberation of
Arjun's 'Gandiva' bow.
Yes, prince Duryodhan!
This indeed is Arjun.
Just by the reverberation
of his bow
seems to instill
terror in your heart.
How will you defend yourself
from the arrows fired
from this bow?
You were very eager
to face Arjun.
Arjun is here now.
Before commencing the battle
I convey my greetings
to Grandsire Bheeshma.
Live long and prosper!
I, Arjun, the son of Pandu
owing to the archery skills
taught by you
challenge you for battle!
Prince Duryodhan!
I have waited days and nights
to raise my bow against you!
Today, I shall teach you
the laws of the battlefield!
Arjun!
There is no need
for battle at all.
Because your exile
has rendered to be a failure.
It is your plan that has failed,
Prince Duryodhan!
Look towards the sun!
The duration of my exile
is complete!
Your exile has failed.
If you act immorally
I shall crush you!
Soldiers!
Attack!
Do you think flaunting your
archery before a mace fighter
makes you powerful, Arjun?
Just as a crow bothering
an elephant and flying away
you come across as
weak and evasive!
Fight with me.
Fight with me!
Prince Uttar, this is no more
your fight.
Now, Arjun's 'Gandiva'
shall dispense justice!
Friend Karna.
Fire the celestial weapon!
Why are you blocking
my arrows, Grandsire?
Grandsire Bheeshma, does Arjun
still need your protection?
I do not wish to shatter this
barrier you conjured, Grandsire!
Please clear the way yourself!
Today is the time to
avenge our humiliation!
Grandsire Bheeshma!
Such partiality!
Just to protect Arjun
you are ceasing
an ongoing battle?
Grandsire, this is
national treason!
Do not intervene in this battle!
Let this battle commence!
Duryodhan, you fool!
I am being partial
for your sake!
Or else
Arjun shall obliterate you all!
If you so confident
about Arjun's capability
then get out of the way!
I do not need
anyone's protection!
I do need protection,
O' armoured one!
My heart does need protection.
Arjun, my lad.
My arms are so powerful today.
But my heart...
My heart cannot bear
another trauma.
Arjun, my lad.
Cease this battle for today.
Do not sabotage your Grandsire's
love and trust.
When the blood of
my own kin is shed
won't the heart of your
Grandsire cringe in woe?
Please spare my aged eyes
of this terrible sight.
I have the boon
of death at will.
Do not give me a reason
to crave for death, O' lad.
Do not say that, Grandsire.
If I become
the cause of your death
I shall experience damnation
all though my life.
The one whom I always
respectfully bow down to
how can I raise my arm
against that person?
So cease this battle today,
my lad.
Please respect your
Grandsire's word.
Today I abide by your order,
Grandsire.
But you must give me your word.
If in future
a situation for war
presents itself
you shall not stop me!
Promise me, Grandsire!
Arjun!
Now the situation for battle
shall never arise.
Because you shall dwell
in the forests
and we shall live in the city!
The chance for battle
has arisen, Prince Duryodhan!
When ought to foolishness
a deer lurks into a lion's cave
it faces death that very moment!
All the deer is left with
are a few moments of struggle!
You may struggle too,
Prince Duryodhan!
Soon, the five Pandavas
shall arrive to punish you
for humiliating a woman
guised as your death!
'Come!
Slave Draupadi!
'Sit on my lap!
Come!'
'The way, in the courtroom
of Indraprastha'
'disarmed us in front of
the entire Arya clan'
'the same way,'
'disrobe her in this courtroom.'
'Just wearing nuptial jewellery
does not make a woman pristine.'
'How could such a woman
be worthy of our clan'
'who bears a relationship
with five men at once?'
'Such women are harlots!'
No, Panchali!
This isn't the time
to shed tears.
Only blood shall be shed now.
All those who humiliated you
shall bleed from their hearts.
Do you think I thirst for blood,
my love?
Why such a question, Panchali?
Time heals all wounds.
It is a common belief.
But even an exile of 13 years
could not heal the wounds
inflicted upon my honour.
That scene from
the filled courtroom
still makes my soul
writhe in agony.
Now I just yearn for war
day and night.
No, Panchali.
In all these 13 years
your heart doesn't crave
solely for vengeance.
It craves for dispensing
of justice.
The determination
to cleanse the society
grows firmer with time.
As honey ages
it develops medicinal qualities.
Therefore, Lord Krishna
has filled our hearts
not with vengeance
but a craving for justice.
Arjun is right, Panchali.
There is no need to brood.
Soon, the punishment for
the sons of Dhritarashtra
shall be announced.
And that punishment
shall be dictated by
the Arya clan's heiress.
The punishment of
the sons of Pandu
shall now be dictated by me!
The Pandavas
are still bound to dwell the
forests for 12 years, My Lord!
Because, before their exile
was complete
I had reckoned Arjun's truth.
When you saw Arjun
the sun had already set, Prince.
His exile has been a success.
You have to accept this fact,
Duryodhan, my boy.
That is justice.
When Arjun had entered
the battlefield with his bow
the night phase had
not yet begun, Grandsire.
It was indeed the last day
of their exile.
But the day had not passed then.
Therefore
the sons of Pandu
have to accept
dwelling the forests
for 12 years
and a year of exile.
This is law, Grandsire.
Duryodhan has violated
all codes of law, elder brother.
Even now he must be planning
something new for sure.
Brother Bheem is right.
Before brother Bheem
gets a chance to reign
we have to punish him.
If you have to catch a prey
quickness matters
more than strength.
But
is Grandsire's consent
not necessary
before launching the attack?
In order to retaliate
to our attack
what if Grandsire
enters the battlefield?
What do we do then?
Grandsire will not stand up
against us in the battlefield.
He knows who is just.
But Grandsire's duty
is to watch over
the throne of Hastinapur.