I will not marry the son
of a charioteer.
Son of a charioteer!
Is this 'swayamvar' a test of
competence or caste and class?
It is matter of great surprise,
King Drupad
that your daughter
was reminded of my caste
when I was about
to achieve the goal.
It is evident that your daughter
does not want to marry me
but had she not ridiculed
my birth like this
had she not insulted my caste
the entire world would have
been proud of the Princess!
You daughter does not know,
Your Highness
that in this gathering here
she has not only insulted me
but also those
millions of people
whose competence is not
determined by their lineage
but labour and strength!
Your daughter has
has committed a grave sin,
Your Highness.
Committed a grave sin.
Keep quiet and return
to your place, King of Anga!
The decision to whom
to get married
and in which lineage and dynasty
to get married into
is a right that lies
solely with the maiden.
This is not a right, King Drupad
but the arrogance
of your daughter!
You have turned this 'swayamvar'
into politics, King Drupad.
We had thought
that to end the enmity
between Kuru and Panchal
you had invited us
but
you solely wanted to insult us!
That is a lie!
I have no knowledge
of any enmity, Prince.
If my intentions were not pure
then this instant
may Lord Surya burn me to ashes!
The 'swayamvar' of a Princess
is never open to beings of all
types and sections of society
Prince.
Otherwise do beings like, 'yaksh,* gandharva,'* ogres
*Fairy, nature-spirits; **Male nature spirits, part animal.
spirits, ghouls and others
not have the competence?
But none of them can come forth
and approach a Princess
for marriage.
Honouring the rules
of a 'swayamvar'
is the duty of everyone.
The truth is, by deciding to
participate in the 'swayamvar
King Karna of Anga has broken
the rules of this undertaking.
If this is what you think,
Princess Draupadi
then listen well to this.
I am challenging you
that if you are to get married
you must do so
in this very 'swayamvar'
that too with such a person
who emerges victorious here.
Take a look around you,
Princess Draupadi.
Is there anyone who can
achieve this goal?!
I am here.
Did I not tell you
that a person who is
fated to receive alms
reaches the destination somehow?
King Drupad,
there is no one here
who can take part
in this competition.
Is there anyone?
A Prince or a King...
Does anyone want to participate
in this facade
of a 'swayamvar?!'
Break that bow!
Destroy that goal, King Drupad!
And take your arrogant daughter
and imprison her in
the corner of a palace forever.
- Kuru Prince!
Prince Duryodhan
King Drupad is grateful to you
for attempting
to break that bow.
You have proved
that it is not yet time for
the bow to be destroyed.
Brother Yudhishthir
he is Vasudev.
You must be aware,
Crown Prince Duryodhan
that the bow of Lord Shiva
was built for many purposes
out of which one was
the 'swayamvar' of Goddess Sita.
Only after the completion
of that task
did that bow break.
This miraculous bow did not
break at your mighty hands
and that can mean
only one thing
that a warrior who can
win this competition
is still present here.
A warrior who can
win this competition
is still present here.
That is why
I request you,
Crown Prince Duryodhan
to allow this 'swayamvar'
to be completed.
Your Highness, address
all the Kings present here
for one last time.
I address this gathering
for one last time!
If a King, Crown Prince
or 'Kshatriya' warrior
wishes to demonstrate his might
then he must come forth!
Govind
can a 'Kshatriya' maiden
not get married to 'Brahmins?'
She most certainly can.
But only if you want to.
Yes, Govind.
Address the 'Brahmins'
this time.
I have firm faith
that my hidden fate
will appear before
the entire world today.
Your Highness
it is said in the 'shastras'*
*Scholar/sacred texts.
that when the might
of 'Kshatriyas' falls short
and the knowledge of the
'shastras' is inadequate
then one should turn to
'Brahmins' for answers.
King Gadhi's daughter* was married
to Sage Richika* and all of us know about it.
*Parashurama's grandparents.
Your Highness
address all the 'Brahmins'
and ask them to take part
in this competition.
But Vasudev
my daughter was born
to become a Queen.
Marrying a 'Brahmin'
and asking for alms
does not suit a Princess.
When a fruit gets buried
in the earth
it cuts through it
after some time
and grows into a tree.
If your daughter was born
to become a queen
then she might just
turn a 'Brahmin'
into a King.