Don't waste your potential by
punishing yourself, Yudhisthira.
They, who are the cause
of this state of yours
need to be punished.
They, who tried to dishonour
my friend's dignity!
If the wife of five Pandavas
can be treated like this
then much worse can happen
to ordinary women
in Duryodhan's kingdom.
Give it a thought.
Justice and protection...
It's your righteous duty
to establish these two.
Not for revenge.
You will have to fight a battle
for the ultimate reality.
Here are the five gems
of the tiara
which Madhav had given you.
But don't adorn them
in the tiara.
Your vow was justified.
Until the battle is over
neither tie your hair
nor adorn the tiara.
Your open locks
will keep reminding us
of our life's goal!
If that's your promise
then listen to my
resolution...
Until I wash my hair
with the blood
from Dushasana's chest
I will not tie my hair!
That will definitely happen,
Draupadi.
I will wash your hair with the
blood from Dushasana's chest.
King Dhritarashtra
and Queen Gandhari's lives
will see no ray of light,
Draupadi.
Only darkness
will surround them!
Forgive me, Your Highness
but we have been ordered
to put off the lamps.
Orders to put off the lamps?
- Yes, Your Highness.
It's the Queen's orders
that there will be darkness
in the whole of Hastinapur,
today.
No lamps or flambeaux shall
be lit even in the royal palace.
Forgive me, but I will
have to carry out the orders.
Mother, what sort
of an order have you given?
Why are all the lamps
and flambeaux
of the palace
being put off?
Because the whole of Hastinapur
is in darkness today, Duryodhan.
No one is able to see
their future.
Everyone's stumbling
in darkness
but no one knows
it's darkness.
These lamps and flambeaux
give everyone
a false illusion of light.
- You can see darkness
because you're blindfolded,
dear sister.
In reality, today, Hastinapur
sees the light of fortune.
You should declare Diwali
in the whole kingdom.
- Brother!
You see fortune?
How?
Pandavas will definitely return
to take revenge.
They will kill
all my 100 sons.
But how will you understand
what I'm going through?
You have always given more
importance to ambitions.
Duryodhan...
You have taught Duryodhan
to love the throne
more than his mother.
I know that you have given
a lot of love to my sons.
But it's the result of your love
that Duryodhan
has continuously been committing
unrighteous deeds
in order to get the throne.
Brother
at least for once you
should have thought of me.
Other women bear their children
in their womb
for just nine months.
I
kept them in my womb
for two years.
How will I be able to bear
the news of their death?
Why will we die, mother?
You have no faith in my
strength, mother.
Keep quiet, Duryodhan.
I heard from the maids about
what happened at the court.
How all the apparels
covered Draupadi
in the court.
Even after seeing
that miracle
you're boasting
about your strength.
Draupadi's curse
is still echoing
in my ears.
'This is the curse
of Yajna's child, Draupadi.'
'Duryodhan will definitely
be punished for his deeds.'
Thirteen years later
when I'll return their
property to them
I'll definitely ask
Yudhisthira to promise
to not wage a war.
No such occasion shall arise,
Your Highness.
No property shall be returned.
In the incognito
year of exile
we will crush
the Pandavas
and send them
to exile
once again.
This is a false hope,
brother.
My heart
trembles every moment.
Brother...
Brother
till today I always stopped
you from doing unrighteous.
Today I request to you
do anything
unrighteous...
Yes, unrighteous deed!
Definitely.
I will take responsibility
for all the sins.
If Vasudeva Krishna
fights the battle
along with the Pandavas
then my family
will be ruined.
My family will be ruined,
brother.
It will be ruined!
Mother!
- Gandhari!
Vasudeva Krishna!
May you be glorious,
Pandavas.
For 12 years to come
prepare for war.
Arjun, like Goddess Durga's
trident...
Like Lord Brahma's
four faced weapon...
In the same manner
is Lord Mahadev's
weapon of destruction.
During the battle,
if you ever face a situation
where you have
to confront a power
which is beyond
your competency
then you will need
Lord Mahadev's weapon.
Hence, Arjun
go to Kailash.
Practice austerity
to please Mahadev
and acquire
the weapon from him.
Bhima
the science
of physical strength...
No one knows that better
than Hanuman.
Hence you will
go to mountain Gandhamadana
*Mt. Gandhamadana is the tallest peak on Pamban Island which lies in the Palk Strait between mainland India and Sri Lanka.
and near the Hanumanth cave
you will perform penance
for Lord Hanuman.
Acquire strength from him.
Nakula
Sahadeva
both of you will have to acquire
the benevolence of the Ashvins
so that when time comes
you're able to protect
your army.
Yudhisthira
you very well know
that righteousness
is the basis of victory
and the basis of righteousness
is serving the ascetics
as well as the company
of the highest truth.
Hence you and Draupadi
for the next 12 years
will serve the ascetics
and gather virtue.
Your wish is our command.
Subhadra will be safe with you
at Dwarka.
Definitely, Arjun.
Subhadra's son who
takes birth there...
I will train him
to be a warrior.
Your son Abhimanyu will
be immortal in history, Arjun.
All of you proceed
towards the forest.
May you be blessed
with a blissful life.
Why is righteousness
defeated, brother?
And why does unrighteousness
win?
Achieving something
is not victory
and losing something
is not defeat.
It's the impact of time,
Subhadra.
Change is the only thing
constant in life.