In order to
prove himself as the most
powerful man in Aryavart
this deceptive Krishna
has conspired.
Couldn't the greatest
of the great warriors
Bhishma be honoured?
Then why was Krishna
honoured?
Sishupal
I have no objections with
Vasudeva being felicitated.
Then why are you arguing
for no reason?
Why would you have
a problem, Bhishma?
After all, you are incompetent.
You have gone to
the extent of stealing girls
for your Princes.
Sishupala
are you keeping a count
of your sins?
Only 100!
I will forgive only
100 of your sins
as promised to your mother.
And before you came here
you have committed many sins.
Keep quiet, wicked man.
You're a lewd man
who marries
the wives of other men.
You married 16,000
of Narkasur's wives.
Everybody here knows
about your lewdness.
At Brindavan, you would
stand on one leg
and play the flute and perform
the dance of divine love.
We are all aware of that!
Radha was married
to Ayan Yadav.
Yet you trapped that
innocent girl
in your endearing
infatuation.
Has it slipped your mind?
Have you forgotten?
You are the world's most
immoral being, Krishna.
Quieten down, Sishupla.
Don't walk so blindly on
this sinful path
that you're unable to keep
count of those sins.
I am well aware of what
I'm doing, Krishna.
And I also know why
you're being honoured.
This is another evidence
of your lewdness.
Definitely, Draupadi
must have told her
incapable husbands
that you should be given
the greatest of honours.
You call her your friend,
don't you?
Friend!
How can a married woman
be friends with a man?
All of us know what relationship
you and...
It's time for you
to quieten down, Sishupal.
May your soul
rest in peace.
What sordid justice is
this, brother Yudhishthir?
How can killing a guest
like this
be considered appropriate?
After becoming
the mighty sovereign
is this how you're going
to establish righteousness
in the whole of Aryavart?
Calm down, Duryodhan.
Sishupal insulted grandsire
Vasudeva
and my father.
He disrespected my authority.
He also insulted daughter-in-law
of the Kuru dynasty, Rukmini
and also queen Draupadi.
He got the punishment
he deserved.
Yudhishthir
punishment can never
exceed the crime.
The punishment must always
be lesser than the crime.
You can humiliate someone
as a punishment for an insult.
How can you kill him?
Sin and crime are part of
a poisonous cycle, Prince.
If the criminal is not stopped
from committing a crime
he will go on to commit
many crimes.
He goes on to pollute his soul.
He loses control over himself.
He continues to
commit crimes
even without reason.
The way
an infant is forcefully stopped
from consuming sand
in the same manner
it is necessary
to stop a criminal
from committing crimes.
That's not a punishment, Prince.
It's sympathy!
Don't unnecessarily worry
about Sishupal.
He has been freed
from this poisonous cycle.
Don't try to fool me,
Vasudeva Krishna.
You have taken revenge in
the name of punishment.
You have violated
this yajna.
My dear
Vasudeva is right.
Be seated.
- Keep quiet, uncle.
Prince Sishupal was my friend.
We had sworn to
protect each other.
If I don't avenge
his death today
then my being
a warrior
will be questioned, uncle.
Vasudeva Krishna
I challenge you to a duel.
My dear, Vasudeva is right.
Be seated.
Please be seated...
Brother Duryodhan,
don't degrade the sanctity
of Indraprastha
by shedding your blood.
I don't forgive anyone
who dares to raise
a weapon against Madhav.
Brother Arjun...
If this is the beginning
of the battle
then I accept it.
Prince Duryodhan...
Before fighting the battle,
it is mandatory
to take the permission
of the King of Hastinapur,
Dhritarashtra.
But the king of Hastinapur
isn't present here, Minister.
The minister of Hastinapur
is present though!
You can indeed call for
a verbal duel with Vasudev.
But you can't use weapons
in somebody else's court.
I order you
to either put down
your weapon
or step down from
the post of Hastinapur's prince.
Else, I'll have to give orders
to Hastinapur's
Army General, Bhishm
to raise weapons
for protecting Indraprastha.
Brother Duryodhan
I request you
to put your weapons down.
My child...
Don't be foolish.
Destiny defeats the one
who has no control
over one's anger
even before anyone else
defeats them.
Drop your weapons.
This is not enough.
Your Highness
the one who has raised weapons
in your court
should certainly be punished.
To strengthen the confidence
of all the kings present here
on your just nature,
it's compulsory
that Prince Duryodhan
be punished.
I forgive brother Duryodhan.
Your Highness, punish him!
Yes, punish him!
Your Highness,
those who spit at the sky
make their own face dirty.
The sky doesn't forgive
but punishes them.
Similarly
you can't forgive
Prince Duryodhan
for his mistake.
Even Arjun
was punished, brother.
Whereas he had only tried
to protect the honour
of Panchali.
But how should I punish him?
Duryodhan is my brother.
By punishing him, I can't
hurt uncle.
Your Highness...
Destiny paves its own path.
Don't worry.
Just decide on the punishment.
Your Highness...
Shall I say something?
I don't see any reason
why we should hurt uncle
and her highness, by punishing
brother-in-law Duryodhan.
But Govind is insisting
on giving him punishment.
Then, Your Highness
it's considered
punishment enough
to sieze the weapons
of a warrior.
Order brother-in-law Duryodhan
to give up his weapon.
With due respect
we'll send his weapon
to Hastinapur.
How dare you decide
punishment for me
Draupadi!
Don't try to humiliate me!
Don't take it as humiliation,
brother-in-law.
This is a solution to the conflict
that has arisen in the family.
And it's an attempt to eliminate
the taint that was tossed
on your clothes
as well as your heart.
You possess a tainted character
yourself
and you worry about
my clothes?
Control your tongue, Duryodhan!
Brother Duryodhan,
it's my order
that within the boundaries
of Indraprastha
you're not allowed
to hold your weapon.
Bheem, Arjun, Sahdev
seize the weapons
from brother Duryodhan
brother Dushasan
and from the King of Anga.
Prince Duryodhan,
hand over your weapons.
This is my order.
Your Highness, the punishment
for raising weapons
in the court is death.
Grant me
the same punishment.
Whether or not
there's blood shed
how does it make a difference,
King of Anga?
Consider this to be equivalent
to death penalty.
Come on, hand over
your bow to me.