The architecture of the Gods,
Vishwakarma, himself
is helping the sons of Pandu
by building the city of
Indraprastha for them, brother.
In other words
to aid them in the
reverence of the city
it is time now to send them
one lakh cows.
Why do I hear a tone of doubt
in your voice, Minister?
Do you think I do not remember
my promises, Vidur?!
I do not doubt you,
brother Dhritarashtra.
It is easy to give charity
to the impoverished
but when being charitable
to the affluent
envy is born in the process.
I am alluding
to Prince Duryodhan,
Your Highness.
Minister!
The Crown Prince
is a gallant warrior
oh righteous one
Minister Vidur.
The Crown Prince will not break
his promise, Your Excellency.
But
why give away
one lakh cows, Minister?
Why do we not send
all the cows of Hastinapur
to Indraprastha?
Why do we not send them
all the gold coins
with your permission?
Why are you are being sarcastic,
King of Gandhar?
I am not being sarcastic,
oh intelligent one.
I am not being sarcastic.
The true property of a kingdom
is not represented by
either cows or gold coins.
The true property of a kingdom
is its subjects.
Beloved Duryodhan knows that.
But the thing is...
Out of his property,
my nephew
will give away
one lakh gold coins
and even one lakh cows.
If he exhausts his fortune
by helping the Pandavas
in becoming prosperous
then
how will he
gain all this wealth again?
Even today,
the subjects of Hastinapur
go to great pains
to make the kingdom prosperous,
King of Gandhar.
And they will continue to do so.
In other words
the subjects of Hastinapur
who wish to migrate
to the city of the Pandavas
should not be
permitted to do so?
This is
all I wanted to know, Vidur.
What do you mean?
Your Highness
a new city is being built there.
Many people
are leaving Hastinapur
and migrating to Indraprastha.
I fear, Your Highness
that if majority of the subjects
migrate to Indraprastha
then Hastinapur will never be
able to become prosperous again.
If that happens
then what will the Minister do?
A mahout* uses love to control an elephant, King of Gandhar.
*A mahout/mahamatra  is a person who rides an elephant.
And that is why
the elephant never
forsakes the mahout.
Duryodhan must also
employ love
to control the subjects.
Certainly,
Your Excellency.
Certainly.
But before one learns
to control it with love
the elephant
is captured quite cruelly.
You seem to be forgetting this,
Your Excellency.
The subjects of Hastinapur
cannot be allowed
to leave the city.
This is what I feel,
Your Highness.
You are correct,
Shakuni.
Minister!
- Your Highness.
You need to make
an announcement.
No subject of Hastinapur
can leave the city
and migrate to Indraprastha.
Any person who
disobeys this order
shall be imprisoned
and punished.
But dear...
Uncle
this order shall be executed
personally by you,
I hope you have
no problem, uncle.
It is my duty,
Your Highness.
Your Highness, why use
a sword to kill an ant?
His Excellency Bhishma
need not be bothered for this.
If you allow me
then in order to stop
the subjects from leaving
I can send King Karna of Anga.
Then ask the King of Anga
to close the gates
of the city of Hastinapur.
And to allow no subject
of Hastinapur
to leave the city.
As you say,
Your Highness.
Your Excellency.
Close the gates of the city!
The gates are closing!
- Make haste!
We must leave post-haste!
- Open the gates!
The gates are closing!
- Make haste. - Open the gates!
Make haste!
Let's go.
- They are closing the gates!
The gates are closing!
- Let's go! - Open the gates!
Open the gates! - Make haste!
- King of Anga
order the soldiers
to arrest all the subjects.
Open the gates!
- My entire family...
My Lord, where are you?
My Lord...
My Lord,
I am still on this side.
My Lord...
The subjects are leaving
the city, King of Anga.
Have the gates of the city
closed, King of Anga!
You need to be stern with them!
What are you thinking?!
Father...
Father!
My son is still inside!
King of Anga... - Be quiet,
Prince Dusshasan!
While closing the gates
of the city
one cannot close
the gates of one's heart.
I have accepted this duty
and I shall decide
how to carry it out.
Let's go.
Father...
Father!
Open the gates!
- Open them!
Calm down!
Please calm down!
- Let us go!
Please calm down.
- Please do not do this!
No one is allowed
to leave the city.
King Dhritarashtra
has given the order
that if anyone tries
to leave the city by force
then he shall be imprisoned!
Open the gates...
I request all of you.
Please...
Please return to your homes.
Return to your homes, please!
Our entire family
is outside the city!
Let us go!
- Open the gates!
That is impossible.
The gates of the city
cannot be opened.
The people who are outside
will be imprisoned and punished.
Open them...
- Open the gates!
All of you need to
return to your homes.
Let us go!
- Open the gates!
Open the gates!
- Radheya!
We have to go outside!
Vrushali!
Are you leaving
the city as well?
I had left with father
the first time
but fate brought me here again.
My father is outside the city
and he is alive.
Please let me go to him.
Just like me, the families
of these people
are also outside the city gates.
Why has His Highness given
an order to separate families?
No one can leave
one's kingdom, Vrushali.
But if we find happiness there
then why can we not?
Do not argue with me,
Vrushali.
Learn to accept
what you get here as joy.
There was a time
when, instead of accepting
the joy you had
searching for happiness
and seeking joy
was what you
believed in, Radheya.
Pardon me
King Karna.
But maybe
the head a crown adorns
seems to bring about a change
in its way of thinking.
My father was correct
that unrighteousness
resides not in a man
but in his crown.
Pardon me,
King of Anga
but I must open these gates
and go to the other side.
Vrushali, stop.
King of Anga
if you let this maiden go
then we will not be
able to stop anyone.
Vrushali, stop
otherwise you shall
be imprisoned.
Soldier!
Arrest this maiden!
King Karna of Anga!
King Karna of Anga
you had said that your mother
had renounced you
and that you did not
renounce her.
Then what happened today,
King Karna of Anga
that you had to renounce
the righteousness
and values taught
by your mother?
King Karna of Anga
this maiden said
that unrighteousness
resides not in a man
but in his crown.
My father,
my husband
and my son
have a crown on their heads.
That is why,
I request you
to not let the words
of this maiden come true.
Release this maiden.
Soldier.
King of Anga!
Do not argue with me,
Dusshasan.
It is the order of a mother.
Aunt Kunti
the order of His Highness
cannot be disobeyed.
I am still the Queen Mother,
dear Dusshasan.
And the order of His Highness
is meant for everyone.
I am
asking to make an exception
only for this maiden
who has a heart
that knows the truth
and also the dignity
to speak it out loud.
I have firm faith
in my brother-in-law.
He will not disregard
my request.
This maiden shall stay
in my protection.
When I leave for the
reverence of Indraprastha
I shall take her to her father.
King Karna of Anga
unrighteousness resides
not in the crown
but in the greed to have one.
Do you regard your greed
to be your duty?