You do not have the right
to the Empress just yet.
For that,
the Empress
must be won by you in the game.
I bet my wife
daughter of the King of Kashi
Bhanumati in this
round of the game!
Sit down,
servant Yudhishthir.
You are yet to play
another round
of the game.
Sit down.
Get up, Your Highness.
Get up.
Defend your honour
while there is still time.
No, Vrushali.
No one can snatch one's honour.
One can only give it up.
And I can give up my life
but never my honour.
You should go,
Vrushali
and pray for the protection
of your husband's honour.
How do I hold on to
the string of control, Govind?
Where are you?
Impossible!
Brother Yudhishthir, you cannot
bet Panchali in the game.
Brother Yudhishthir
do not let my
premonition come true.
Sit down to play the game,
servant Yudhishthir.
That is an order
of your master,
Emperor Duryodhan.
Sit down.
I cannot bet Panchali
in the game.
Do not tell me now
that a husband does not have
the right to his wife.
If the right to the independence
of your brothers
is something that you have
acknowledged
then you must also acknowledge
the right you have
to the independence
of your wife.
It is a tradition
of the Aryan region
that a husband
has the right to his wife.
Go on and play,
servant Yudhishthir.
Bet your wife
in this round of the game!
Do not play,
brother Yudhishthir.
This is not righteous.
Righteousness does reside
in traditions
but not all traditions
are righteous.
Do not play
otherwise the seed
of a great war will be sown
in the court
of Hastinapur today.
Brother, if you lose Draupadi
and her honour today
then the hands that roll the dice
in the game will have to burn!
I take the oath
that I shall burn
your hands myself!
I give you the order
to play
servant Yudhishthir!
Play!
He will not be able to play
because he may have
the right to his wife
but it is also essential
to take pride in her.
And how can someone
take pride in such a woman?
Duryodhan!
I curse you
that the day you die
you shall pray for death!
Neither will you be able to live
nor will Lord Yama
give you death!
This curse of yours
does not scare me,
His Excellency.
But this curse shall indeed
yield results, Duryodhan.
Only after pleading for death
seven times will you die!
All that unrighteousness
will assume the form
of pain and suffering
and surround your soul
in your end moments, Duryodhan!
And the Crown Prince is correct.
She is like my sister
because she is the daughter
of my father's friend.
A woman married to five men
and having relationships
with them
is someone I would be
ashamed to call my sister!
Ashwatthama
had you not been my son
I would have cursed you.
As a punishment
for uttering such words
I would have cursed you.
May your entire body
get infested with insects.
It shall indeed be so!
The filth of your soul will
appear on your entire body!
The society will abandon you
but Ashwatthama
you will not be able
to abandon your life!
Why would you
give him such a curse?
If you have such great faith
in righteousness
then go and slay your son.
Before an entire gathering,
when a woman
could insult a warrior
based solely on his caste
and completely negate
the respect and feelings of
others for her selfishness
how can she be a woman of
exceptional character?
King Karna of Anga
if you take such great pride
in your competence
then how can you utter abuses
like a weak beggar?!
Do remember
that you shall lose all your
competence and knowledge
at the time of your death!
Your soul will be depleted
when you die!
It will be depleted!
The desire to have
a moment of righteousness
will surround you in your
final moments, Maharathi Karna
but despair will
weigh your heart down.
Your entire life
will seem worthless
in your final moments.
Splendid.
Marvellous.
So, it has been proved
that servant Yudhishthir
does have
the right to his wife
but pride
lacks in this case.
I indeed take pride
in Panchali's devotion
in Panchali's sacrifice
in Panchali's purity!
Apart from Panchali
there is no other devoted wife
who walks this earth
at the moment
King of Gandhar!
It is said that
at the time of death
every unit of the body
and every particle
fights to live.
Every unit of my body
will fight to win.
I cannot lose Panchali.
Bring new dice
and new pieces.
Only then will I play
the game, Your Highness!
You are a servant now!
An order
cannot be given by you.
Either obey my order,
brother Duryodhan
or sentence me to death
this instant!
'These dice'
'are made from the bones
of my late father.'
'They obey every word of mine.'
Dusshasan
bring new pieces.
Uncle, your magical dice
have been broken!
Take these pieces away
and bring new dice.
The generosity to accept
the request of a servant
does reside in me.
Go on.
There you go,
servant Yudhishthir.
The new pieces
and new dice are here.
Play...
Against the wife
of Emperor Duryodhan
Lady Bhanumati
you need to bet your wife
Draupadi in the game.
Sit down and play,
servant!
Go on and play,
Go on,
dice.
Twelve.
May servant Yudhishthir
have happiness!
Your wife Draupadi has been
lost by you!
The Princess of Panchal
the Empress of Indraprastha
the great pride of the Pandavas
will enter this court as a maid!
Do maids
not have the permission
to enter
the court,
grandsire?
Attendant
bring that maid Draupadi
to this court!