'A while later.'
Uncle
what are you rejoicing over?
The Serpent King Takshak
got defeated
the cows reached Indraprastha
and even the reverence
of the city took place!
Very soon, they shall perform
the Rajsuya 'Yajna,' uncle.
Are you rejoicing
over this, uncle?
Uncle
this time,
your political games...
Were a success,
my darlings!
They were a success!
The Serpent King Takshak
may have been defeated
but the victory is ours.
Until Arjun completes
his penance and returns
the Pandavas
will not be able to conduct
the Rajsuya 'Yajna.'
The opportunity to stop
the Rajsuya 'Yajna'
is finally in our hands,
my darlings.
It is finally in our hands!
But uncle
how will we stop them?
Listen.
There are two great forces
in the Aryan region.
The Yadavas of Dwaraka
and Jarasandha of Magadha.
Both of them are enemies.
The strength of the Pandavas
are the Yadavas
because Krishna
is on their side.
If
the Yadavas
decide to help us
then the Pandavas
will never be able to conduct
the Rajsuya 'Yajna.'
And Jarasandha
is an unrighteous man!
The Pandavas
will never be an ally
to Jarasandha!
But uncle
we have got the news
that Arjun and
the Princess of Manipur
Chitrangada have got married.
Uh!
And the Serpent King
Kauravya's daughter
Ulupi has also been
married to him.
In other words,
even Arjun
is getting married to magnify
his strength, uncle.
My darling,
do not worry about that.
Even with the aid of
the King of Manipur
and the Serpent King Kauravya
Indraprastha cannot become
a powerful kingdom.
The key element here
are the Yadavas.
But the Yadavas will
never side with us, uncle.
They will.
The leader of the Yadavas
is Krishna
and Krishna
never disobeys
his elder brother Balaram.
It is time now
to approach Balaram
and form an ally with him.
Very soon
we shall leave for Dwaraka
for this purpose.
You must become
Balaram's disciple.
You must learn the art of
fighting with a mace from him
and become a darling of his.
You will be married
to Balaram's beloved sister
Subhadra, my darling.
In the meantime
Arjun will be engrossed
in his penance
in the jungles
of the Aryan region
and wandering about aimlessly!
An arrow is formed
not with the aid of mantras
but with that
of one's heart, friend.
You must calm your heart down.
How do I calm
my heart down, Govind?
My Lord is travelling
by himself.
Neither does he have
domestic help nor security.
He is not wearing anything
on his feet either.
In this austere penance of his
who will take care of his needs?
And I cannot stop thinking
about this, Govind.
Worry is the most definitive
form of love, friend.
You are worried for Arjun
and that is no surprise.
But when I think about Arjun
I feel as though I am...
I am being unjust
to the rest of my husbands.
I am failing to adhere
to my oath, Govind.
This is a dreadful situation.
Perhaps, Sahadev should have
entered your chamber
to get the Gandiva Bow.
Then Arjun would not have to...
What are you saying, Govind?
Then Sahadev would have
had to leave the city.
How would I have been
able to bear that?
Then Bheem and Nakul...
- No!
Staying away from any of my
beloved family members
is unbearable for me, Govind.
Staying away from
your loved ones.
That sentence can be divided
into two parts, friend.
The first deals with distance
and the other with...
Love?
Yes!
Love .
In other words
the distance between two people
is not measured
by physical proximity
but by the depth of one's love.
You must calm
your heart down, friend.
You are not being
unjust to anyone.
Each of the Pandavas
is equally dear to you.
The benefits of Arjun's penance
will be reaped not only by him
but also by the entire
Kuru dynasty, friend.
You must be patient.
When you receive news
that may question your faith
you must remember
that time does not take
the path made by man.
Man must walk on the path
illuminated by time.
This is called fate.
So, will My Lord meet
with some danger, Govind?
How would I know that, friend?
You are able to see
the future, Govind.
I do not see the future, friend.
I only see man
and understand his nature.
The nature of a man
builds his future.
That is why, I am able to see
his future to an extent.
I do not know if danger
will befall Arjun or not
but I certainly know
that even in danger
he will see an opportunity.
That is why, there is no reason
to worry for Arjun, friend.
You must learn
to be patient, friend.
How can I be patient, Govind?
By making yourself believe
that no matter where any of your
family members is travelling
he is always near you
and in your loving heart.
Only still waters can
reflect an image, friend.
If you calm your heart down
then you will be able
to see Arjun in it.
Madhav
you had asked me to come
to the Somnath temple
to complete my penance.
So, here I am.
Prince Duryodhan,
this is the place
where Lord Shiva had freed
Chandra Dev from his curse.
Ever since, we have been deemed
the descendants of Chandra Dev
while we deem
Lord Somnath our Deity.
Here in Dwaraka,
all tasks
take place methodically
and ritualistically.
This way,
King of Gandhar!
The veneration of Lord Shiva
will be conducted first by you.
Why are you
embarrassing me, Vasudev?
High up in the sky
in the region of Garuda*
*A large mythical bird, or humanoid bird. Garuda is the mount (vahana) of Vishnu (Krishna).
no vulture can ever fly.
And I had been named
by my revered father
King Subala.
Shakuni
in other words
a vulture.
So, how can I perform
the veneration before you?
Why can you not,
King of Gandhar?
By having Duryodhan
and Subhadra married
the idea of forming an alliance
between the Kurus and Yadavas
was yours, was it not?
In other words
a vulture can now venture
in the region of Garuda
quite freely.
King of Gandhar
will you not pay your respects
to the sages present here?
I have heard
that paying one's respects
to Lord Shiva's devotees
makes Lord Shiva happier.
Certainly.
Vasudev Krishna!
This is the only man
who spoils all our plans.
When Balram proposed your name
to marry Subhadra
though he expressed
his happiness
yet I doubt him.
He is definitely brewing up
some plan
otherwise at such critical time
Arjun would never
have been at Somnath.
What game this man is playing
is completely beyond me.
I think it's called 'Lagori'.*
*Seven stones.
If you have put your mind
on hold, my dear
give some rest
to your tongue as well.
Why are you so worried
for Arjun's presence over here,
uncle?
Now he can't interrupt
my wedding.
If he abducts Subhadra
he would have to fight
Vasudev and Balram.
And Arjun
will never raise arms
against Vasudev and Balram,
uncle.
You are really not aware
of the true colours
of Vasudev Krishna.
The spider never eats
without knitting the cobweb.
Krishna's act without planning...
That's not possible.
He has got
a very dangerous mind.