Human!
There's human
in my land.
But I am not scared.
I have Lord Indra's blessings
with me.
On this land of mine
no human
can establish
his kingdom.
It's time to destroy them all.
Hail Nageshwar!*
*Shiva's first jyotirlinga/temple (the radiant sign of the almighty).
Is this the reward for
being kind?
If we had opposed
the partition
then they would be compelled
to coronate brother Yudhisthira
as the king of Hastinapur.
After a war, Nakul.
War is not a better choice
than partition.
Are you scared of battles,
brother Arjun?
A distinguished warrior is
always scared of war.
He doesn't fear
his death
but the loss
of other's lives.
If you're so concerned
for the lives of others
then make arrangements
for my meals.
I'm dying out of hunger.
Let me first pay my obeisance
to Mother Earth
then I'll arrange for
the meals.
Mother Earth
accept the prayer of the ones
who wish to dwell in your
propinquity.
Bless us so that we perform
the veneration
with all our heart
and our hard work.
And we don't want
anything beyond our necessities.
We will always respect
the other living beings
who dwell in your shelter.
Bless our subjects with
peace and prosperity.
Run! Run! Run!
It's Takshak and his army.
Run! Run!
Oh God!
Brother we'll have to make use
of our weapons.
We'll have to protect
everyone.
Draupadi, you be
with the subjects.
Bhima, you and I will
protect the subjects.
Nakul, Sahdev, stay with Arjun.
Come on!
Vrushali!
V-Vrushali.
Vrushali.
Come on, run!
Wait, Takshaka!
There's no need for
you to attack.
We're not here to fight
a battle with you.
We all are the children
of Mother Earth.
All of us can live
here peacefully.
Father...
Father!
Why?
Why did all this happen,
Your Highness?
So many innocent people died.
They have been punished
for having chosen
the path of religion.
Why have they been punished
for having faith
in your potential,
Your Highness?
What enmity does
Takshaka have with us?
Calm down, Draupadi.
How can I calm down,
Your Highness?
Vrushali had said
that it's always the subjects
who have to sacrifice
for the welfare
of their king.
But, I had told her, then
that no
that will not happen
here on.
But, look
she's been proven right.
How can a kingdom nurtured
by so many deceased bodies
bring us welfare?
Have patience, Draupadi.
They aren't dead yet.
If the poison of the snakes is
removed at the earliest
then they all can be saved.
So...
So then get rid of
the poison, Prince.
What are we waiting for?
They are miraculous snakes,
Draupadi.
Only those snakes
who have bitten them
can remove this poison.
We will have to find
those snakes
before they succumb to it.
Where will we
find those snakes?
That evil Takshaka and his army
disappeared long ago.
To go and find each one...
We don't have
that much time.
Don't call them evil, Bhima.
This land was theirs.
Those snakes tried
to survive with the humans.
But they were not
benefitted at all.
They had to lose their land
and move to the forests.
That is the reason behind
Takshaka's enmity with humans.
When the rights of
the children of Mother Earth
are snatched from them
that's when rebellions like
Takshaka take birth.
You mean, Takshaka who
murdered so many humans
is not a sinner?
No.
Takshaka is not a sinner.
He has just lost
his path.
He is increasing the discord
between humans and snakes
which is benefitting no one.
And the entire snake clan
that is following him
are victims
and not criminals.
If we have decided
to establish a kingdom here
then along with
the humans
welfare of the snakes
too is our responsibility.
And if we do that
then the entire
clan of snakes
will love
and respect us.
All the snakes are hiding
in that forest, brother.
But the forest too
is filled with illusions.
You're right, Sahdeva.
A demon by the name
of Maya lives there
who is friends
with Takshaka.
He has created that illusion.
In front of brother
Arjun's weapons
all illusions fail, brother.
For that, we have to
fight a battle, Nakul.
With Lord Indra Himself.
Lord Indra!
Lord Indra
come and fulfill
your promise.
You had promised
that on this land
other than snakes
no one else shall dwell.
Today...
Today
on this land of snakes
the humans have come
to claim their rights.
Lord Indra!
Please, appear.
Please, appear before me.
You forgot
your promise
Lord Indra.
I haven't forgotten,
Takshaka.
I have kept this land void
of water for such a long period
so that no one
other than you
can reside here.
But the humans who have
come here now
are divine.
The person who attacked
you with arrows
has taken birth because
of my blessings.
I consider him my son, Takshaka.
The essence of
five Gods
have given birth
to these five Pandavas.
Remember
no matter what
the circumstances be
you cannot defeat them.
But you can, Lord Indra.
Or is it
that after
seeing your son
you have become
blind in love.
Don't be foolish, Takshaka.
Realise the truth.
When water falls
at a certain place
it makes the place wet.
In the same manner
when there's competence
it finds a place
of its own.
I bind you
with your promise,
Lord.
Even if you have to
kill your own son
you can't break this promise.
You will have to
stop them.
Okay, Takshaka.
I cannot break my promise.
But remember
there are powers
in this world
that can defeat me.
I have been defeated
many a times.
King Nahusha
was a human.
He had defeated me.
If I am defeated
by the Pandavas
then you can be in
a much worse state.
You cannot be defeated, Lord.
I am
an illusive snake
and Mayasur has
made this forest
illusive too.
You just support us
by being the secret force.
We will shatter
all their dreams.
Yes
the snakes are blessed
with Lord Indra's protection.
And you're Lord Indra's Godson
an incarnation
and were born out of his traces.
You are his Godson.
Lord Indra is like
your father.
Will you be able to
fight a battle against him?