When a mother cries
because of her son
a strange agony pervades
her emotions and even her laugh
gets tainted by it, mother.
Look.
I am smiling now.
Now, quit feeling sad.
Today, you have made me
very happy, son.
Sit down here with me.
I will feed you myself.
Today, even grandfather Bhishma
was deeply hurt because of me.
Shall I go and apologize to him?
Then I shall return for my meal.
'You decided to forge an enmity
with Anga Pradesh?'
'You have given Hastinapur
an invitation to a war!'
'Prince Arjun'
'you must wash the feet
of His Highness Karna'
'and ask him for forgiveness.'
'Pardon me, King of Anga.'
Greetings, grandfather.
What happened at the banquet
today was inappropriate, Arjun.
I am here to apologize
to you, grandfather.
Why should you apologize?
What I did was inappropriate.
What Dhritarashtra did
was inappropriate.
To take your and Karna's
personal differences
and to colour it with politics
was utterly inappropriate.
But Vidur and I
kept quiet.
I am not angry with either
you or uncle, grandfather.
I understand your dilemma.
No, Arjun.
You do not understand.
You do not understand...
When offering greetings to a Shiv Lingam*
*Linga/rock symbol of Shiva.
the ants crawling over it
also receive the greetings.
Similar is the state of people
who serve the throne.
If an undeserving person
is the king of a place
then anything done by the people
who serve the throne
can never be appropriate
in totality.
That is why, it is important
to coronate a deserving person
the King of Hastinapur.
But if
tomorrow at the court,
Dhritarashtra
takes an inappropriate decision
then the Kuru kingdom
will see all its hopes crumble.
Grandfather
if you allow us
then at any given point
of time, us brothers
can have our eldest brother
coronated as the King.
All of you are indeed
great warriors
but if you draw a weapon
against Hastinapur
then I shall stop you
from doing so.
And until the Almighty
himself aids you
you cannot defeat me.
Right now, I
see only one way out.
Pray to the Almighty, Arjun.
Pray to Him.
Whenever man is faced
with a dreadful situation
he prays to the Almighty.
He pleads to the Lord to aid him
overcome the situation.
But
what does this prayer
truly mean?
Have we ever thought about it?
The meaning of a prayer
is to take one's apprehensions,
one's worries
one's resolutions, one's options
and one's plans
and place them at
the feet of the Almighty.
In other words
instead of worrying about
what one's actions will yield
acting righteously
and deeming the Almighty's plan
as one's fate...
Is this not praying?
But is understanding
the Almighty's plan
ever possible?
Those plans always culminate
into the results of our actions.
But if someone
stops acting altogether
can it be termed as praying?
The truth is,
actions equate to life.
And keeping oneself
from coveting results
is praying truly.
If a prayer
impedes one's actions
and prevents man from acting
then is it a prayer or defeat?
Think about it.
Greetings, father.
You seem very happy, son.
Yes, father.
I am very happy!
You had taken an oath
that you will make me King.
But father
to aid me and the generations
that come after me
have a prosperous future
was not something
you had ever planned.
I have made such a plan.
And how is that, son?
Father, when my friend
Duryodhan becomes King
he will aid me
in protecting my kingdom.
I made him promise me today.
An incapable person
is always the first
to make promises.
What do you think, father?
Will my friend not become King?
No, he will not.
He will not.
The Prince will be crowned
based on his competence.
And he not becoming King
is in the best interest of
the Kuru kingdom and Hastinapur.
But father
tomorrow, King Dhritarashtra
will declare his son
as the crowned Prince.
Are you telling the truth?
Who gave him the right to do so?
Father
how can you question
the rights of a King?
No.
I am questioning my own rights.
You will not understand.
Go to bed.
Today, Hastinapur is celebrating
the coronation ceremony
of its Prince!
Sculptor
let my idol be so high
that the other idols
look smaller in comparison
because I am to become
the most able
and most powerful King of India.
But Prince, to make
the idols of the same height
is tradition.
The idol of a new King
cannot be taller than
that of his ancestors.
A King's order is more important
than tradition, sculptor!
I shall go right away and get
the permission of His Highness.
Stop, Dusshasan!
Why should we break
tradition unnecessarily?
The idol cannot be too high
but
it can be at an elevated place.
That was a splendid suggestion,
friend Ashwatthama.
Now, the question is, what should
be kept beneath this idol?
Have my idol placed
below yours, friend.
And have your idol
mounted on my shoulders.
That cannot be.
I stand by my friends,
King of Anga.
And I stand on the shoulders
of my enemies.
Brother, then there should be
five idols beneath yours.
Why base them on five humans?
Those idols can also be
of five animals.
And one of them
will be a donkey, friend.
With a bow and arrows
in his hands.
Bheem!
Gandhari.
What is this, brother?
Offering to the dead.
Do you not know what it is?
And which ungratified spirit
is offered iron, brother?
An ungratified spirit
is offered wheat flour.
But an ungratified desire
is offered iron.
Today, my ungratified desire
shall finally be fulfilled.
Today, my nephew
will become the crowned
Prince of Hastinapur.
And very soon
Hastinapur
will transform into Gandhar!
In other words
by making Duryodhan
the crowned Prince
you wish to destroy
the kingdom of Hastinapur?
You are foolish,
beloved Gandhari.
I will not destroy
the kingdom of Hastinapur.
I will destroy
only the arrogance
and the unjust values
of this dynasty.
This empire may be called
the kingdom of Kuru
but it will become
Gandhar!
Because its governance
will be based upon Gandhar's
rules and principles.
Brother...
- Sister
you cannot protest to this
because I am not doing anything
that will harm either
your 100 sons or your husband.
My fight had always
been with the
son of Ganga, Bhishma.
The arrogance with which
he had arrived in Gandhar
will be blown into pieces today.
Today, the son of Ganga, Bhishma
will be defeated!
Forever!
Today, in Hastinapur
the Prince of the Kuru Kingdom
will be announced!
King Dhritarashtra
is making his entrance!
All hail King Dhritarashtra!
Ministers and people
in the court
all of you must be eager
to know the King's decision
but, Your Majesty
before you announce
the crowned Prince
if the great Bhishma
blesses the Princes
then the education of
the Princes will be complete.
But only if you allow it.
Certainly.
Uncle shall address the court.
What is he about to say?
Apart from blessing us
what else can he say, uncle?
Listening to one's enemy
makes not only the people
who hear it repent
but also the ones who don't,
repent as well.