I can accept your proposal,
King Shakuni.
But there's only
one problem.
The great warrior
Karna.
Such a great warrior
cannot be left independent.
Me?
- Yes.
I don't belong to
the warrior class, Emperor.
I'm a charioteer.
I am no king.
Charioteer or warrior...
It makes no difference to me.
You are devoted to your friend
and not towards me.
The mightiest emperor
is the one
to whom even skilled warriors
surrender their arms.
I hand over a kingdom Malini* to you.
*Malinipuri.
You will be its king.
And will swear allegiance
to me.
Any plant that is going to
yield sweet fruits in future
is to be planted
in my orchard.
And not in
anyone else's orchard.
I apologise, Emperor.
I do not wish
to take up
the responsibility
of a kingdom.
I have returned
an acquired kingdom.
Maybe King Shakuni
compelled you to
renounce the kingdom.
So that a skilled warrior
remains independent
and carry out his orders
and not mine.
Great warrior Karna
I am a wrestler.
A wrestler!
Not a moron.
You will surrender
as a king
and only then can this plan
be successful.
Friend
there is a very complex
situation in front of us.
What do we do now?
I request to you,
friend.
Don't ask me
for anything
that becomes a burden
for me.
My child
It's important
to stop Karna.
I am afraid
Vasudev Krishna
is on his way
to Magadh
with the intention
to attack.
At that time
Karna protecting you,
will not be enough.
He has to be there to protect
Emperor Jarasandh.
Or else
the entire plan
will be down the drain.
But, uncle
how do I persuade him?
Go tell him
that the ones who go
to the ocean
in search of a pearl
keep themselves
tied to the boat.
Now that you are in a pact with
an unrighteous emperor
like Jarasandh
then it is necessary
that he keeps you
tied to righteousness.
Or else
you will drown
in the ocean of unrighteousness.
You have done me many a favour,
friend.
If I'm able to repay
them in this life
I will be satiated.
I will not be able to take
any more of this burden.
Don't say that, Karna.
I have not done you
any favour.
Whatever you got was
the result of
your capability
and knowledge.
You considering me
your friend
makes me feel honoured.
Friend...
- Let me complete, friend.
The other day,
out of anger
I had called you
a charioteer.
I am a charioteer, friend.
I'm the son
of a charioteer.
And Vrushali explained
to me
that if I continue to see my
birth as an embarrassment
then I will never be
happy in life.
You addressed me
as a charioteer's son.
I hold no anger for that.
- You may not.
But I'm angry
with myself.
Do you know why, Karna?
Do you know why
I am angry with myself?
Because I know what
righteousness is.
But I'm unable to walk the
path of righteousness, friend.
I end up insulting
my friend.
I end up committing
a lot of unrighteous deeds.
You stop me,
yet I commit.
The sins I commit
are like a crack
in the wall
that keeps deepening
by the day.
Your path maybe
impure, friend
but your intentions
are not.
You are fighting
against injustice.
Do you know, friend?
You know, the day
I'm able to resolve injustice
I'll be able to walk the path
of righteousness.
Do you have faith,
my friend?
I have complete faith.
But if uncle's plan
fails to succeed today
then it will never succeed.
This crack of
unrighteousness
will tear my life apart,
friend.
I require your support,
Yes.
Yes, I'm being selfish.
But won't you stand
by me today?
Unrighteousness can
be eradicated, friend
but only with the help
of your faith.
Will you support me?
'Regardless of if a horse
is pulling a chariot or not'
'but till he dons a bridle'
'he cannot be considered free.'
'Get lost, charioteer!
Listen to your father'
'for he is aware that
a charioteer is incompetent.'
'Go away, charioteer!
Go away.'
'Go away, charioteer!'
'If this young archer
is a king'
'the he can challenge Arjun.'
'I'
'Emperor of the Kuru lineage,
Dhritarashtra'
'right away, declare
this young boy'
'the king of Anga.'
'The entire Hastinapur's army is
there to protect your friend.'
'But only you can protect
me and my harmony, lord.'
'Prince, I accept to
bear the king's orders'
'and at the king's feet
I vow'
'that hereafter'
'my property'
'and even my life'
'will forever be at your
feet, Prince.'
'If needed'
'you can wear the crown
once again.'
I accept
your orders, Prince.
What happened, Madhav?
Why did you stop?
King Shakuni.
There isn't another man as
intelligent as King Shakuni
in the entire Arya dynasty,
Parth.
But unfortunately, he uses
his intelligence
for his selfish purpose
and not for benevolence.
What do you mean?
I didn't get you.
Circumstances have
changed, Parth.
Now, we will not be able to
gain victory over Magadh.
What do you mean?
Won't we kill Jarasandh,
Vasudev?
Now that depends on you,
Bheem.
I have heard that
as a child
that you had learnt to wrestle
from Magadh's wrestlers.
Do you remember
any techniques?
Definitely.
A lot of them.
Then the death of Jarasandh
is definite, Bheem.
But now
the princes of Indraprastha
cannot enter Magadh.
A Brahmin wrestler
will now have to
enter Magadh.
Oh, Lord Bhairav!*
*"Terrible" or "Frightful", sometimes known as Kala Bhairava, is the fierce manifestation of Shiva associated with annihilation.
Oh, Lord Mahakaal!*
*The Destroyer of one who destroys.
Please accept the sacrifice
of 100 rulers.
May I be blessed with
the life and the power
of these kings.
Get those
disciples of Krishna!
In the place meant
for the Rajsuya Yajna
why is he planning to carry
out a sacrifice?
If he wants to
kill those kings
then why doesn't he
kill all of them at once?
My child
sacrificing men is considered
very pious at Magadh.
And that is why Jarasandh
is considered a sinner
by the entire Arya dynasty.
Uncle!
I have an extraordinary news.
The Pandavas were approaching
Magadh with their army.
Suddenly they changed
their path.
The army changed
its path!
Surprising!
They must have
gotten scared.
My child, if a leaf flying with
the winds changes its path
it can be considered abrupt.
But
if a bird
changes its path
it is considered
a strategy.
I'm unable
to understand
what Vasudev Krishna
has as a strategy.
Hail King Jarasandh!
Madhav
we've to stop the kings
from being sacrificed.
That's very simple, Parth.
Jarasandh
cannot ignore a challenge
to wrestle.
That forms the core
of his maxims.
Emperor Jarasandh
an animal sacrificed
during a yajna
is first fed well.
Only the sacrifice which
is completely satiated
adds to one's merit.
Won't you give
your sacrifices
an opportunity to
feel contentment
before their death?
Nothing can give contentment
to a person
who is about to die.
- That's untrue, Emperor.
For the worshippers
of bravery
to witness your art
of wrestling
is the biggest reason
of contentment
and that's what I have heard.
This friend of mine
Vrikodar
challenges you for
a wrestling match.
I don't have the time now.
The auspicious moment for the
sacrifice is at hand, Brahmins!
You denied the challenge
of wrestling?
Friend, it's a very happy
moment for us.
We won!
Now you can tell all the
wrestlers of the Arya dynasty
that Emperor Jarasandh
did not accept
your challenge.
This is a very happy moment.
Let's go.
Stop!
First try to displace my leg.
Then you can dare
to challenge me.
Which leg, Emperor?
Don't be too proud.
Any of them.
I have come to Magadha
to displace both your legs.
Who are you?
After having consumed
the food
you don't question about
the cook's caste
Emperor Jarasandh.
You have accepted
the challenge.
Now you'll have
to wrestle.
Vasudev Krishna!
Greetings.
Pandu's son Bheem
is very excited
to have a wrestling
match with you.