King Karna of Anga!
Greetings.
Have you come here
to look at our city?
Bless you, Arjun!
I have no interest in your city.
This maiden here is Vrushali.
By the time the subjects of
Hastinapur
were allowed to migrate
to Indraprastha
she had already left Hastinapur.
That is why,
she is your subject.
I am here
to drop her off safely.
And what arrangements have you
made for your safety King?
Did you forget
that our mother
has been imprisoned?
Not only mother
but also the subjects have been
imprisoned by Hastinapur.
The subjects have not been
imprisoned, Prince Sahadev.
Just to maintain order
in the kingdom
such a restriction has been
imposed on them for a while.
Crown Prince Duryodhan
will certainly
work towards the interest
of all his subjects.
And Prince Nakul
Queen Mother Kunti is not
a prisoner in Hastinapur
but a member
of the royal family.
It is her decision
not to come here.
That is a lie!
Why would our mother not come
to the reverence of our city?
Do not argue, Nakul.
The shadow of a container
does not have the right
to decide in which direction
its shadow should be cast.
All its life
the container
and the light decide its fate.
How would the King of Anga know
what the truth is
and what isn't?
He merely rotes what
brother Duryodhan says.
I have renounced the kingdom
of Anga, Arjun!
I am an ordinary subject now.
I have no obligation
to decline a duel with you
and neither do you!
Pick up your bow, Arjun!
Let us decide right away
who is superior amongst us!
Calm down, Maharathi Karna.
When there is a reason to fight
we will certainly
engage in a battle.
But at the moment
you are a guest of Indraprastha.
And the Pandavas will not
draw their weapons on a guest.
I do not require
your protection, Vasudev.
I am protected
by Lord Surya himself.
I am not here to serve
as a guest to the Pandavas
but to deliver their
mother's message to them.
She has sent the message
to become an independent state
right after the reverence
of the city.
Until Indraprastha
has a flag of its own
she will not enter this city.
Are you the only one who knows
this message, Maharathi Karna?
Did you not tell
your beloved friend?
I am a friend of the
Crown Prince Duryodhan
and not his spy.
Until all of you had
not heard this message
your being independent
was merely a suspicion.
And reporting suspicions
is the task of a spy.
But now
this is an information
and I will certainly
inform my friend about it.
And if there is a battle
then in order
to protect my friend
the first one
to take to arms will be me.
This is my duty.
Wonderful, Maharathi Karna.
This is what
we expected from you.
Do take this maiden
to her father.
Listen, maiden.
Is your name not Vrushali?
Another heroic man like him
does not exist in this world.
Before the distance between
you and him increases
if you like
you may go after him.
Maharathi Karna!
You never let a person go
empty-handed, Maharathi Karna.
Can I get something
in charity as well?
But I have nothing that I can
give you as charity, Vrushali.
Both the kingdom
and the royal treasury
have been renounced by me.
The last few coins left
had been strewn by me
on the river bank.
After renouncing
the royal treasury
what remains with you
is what I wish to have.
May I have
your companionship
as charity, Radheya?
Life with me will be
difficult, Vrushali.
With you
even a difficult life
will become easy, Radheya.
Will you let me walk with you?
Only if you guide me
will I let you.
Only a true warrior
can say that he is a friend
and not a spy.
King Karna of Anga
is an excellent warrior.
Till the two of them
are together
the maiden will be safe.
Till the two of them
are together
Maharathi Karna
will be safe, friend.
Uncle!
Karna has sent a message.
The Pandavas have decided
to perform the Rajsuya 'Yajna'
to become independent, uncle!
We cannot stop them
but we can fight them.
Then we shall fight!
We will not fight.
If we fight them
then that sin
will be our cross to bear.
At the time of the division
both the parties had
promised each other
that they will
not attack the other.
Then what is the solution
to this, uncle?
When a river floods
it cannot be stopped.
But before the river floods
a dam can certainly
be built, my darling.
After the reverence
of their city
the Pandavas
can perform the Rajsuya 'Yajna'
and we cannot stop them.
But
we can certainly stop
the reverence of the city.
One lakh cows
are going
to Indraprastha
for the reverence.
Before those cows
reach Indraprastha,
we must
stop them,
my darling.
But how, uncle?
The Serpent King Takshak.
Serpent King
one lakh cows
are going to Indraprastha
for the reverence of the city.
If you wish to have your revenge
then before those cows
reach Indraprastha
you should steal them
Serpent King Takshak.
My Lord
Takshak stole our cows and fled.
He fled northward with our
one lakh cows, My Lord!
He fled!
What about the security?
What about the soldiers?
- He bit all of them!
The reverence of the city is to
take place tomorrow, brother.
But without the cows
how can the reverence
be completed?
Uncle Shakuni
has come up
with a splendid plan.
Call Nakul.
Get all the soldiers treated.
Employ the serpents of the city
to draw the venom
out of the soldiers.
Ask brother Bheem to make
arrangements to guard the city.
With us busy
looking for the cows
they might intend
to attack the city!
Let me go get my bow.
Brother Arjun
your Gandiva Bow
is in Panchali's chamber!
Apart from brother Yudhishthir,
Panchali's chamber
is off-limits
for the rest of us.
'For an entire year,
Draupadi'
'will be wife
to only one of you.'
'During that period'
'only that person can enter
Draupadi's chamber'
'to whom she gives
the right to do so.'
Brother, if you enter
Panchali's chamber then...
Then...
Then I must
renounce Indraprastha
and go into an exile for years.
I know, Sahadev.
In order to protect the cows
if I leave the city tonight
I will be able to enter it only
after completing my penance.
But at the moment
this is my duty.