Uttar!
'Except your five husbands, the whole dynasty
will be wiped out in this war.'
'Master, today in the battlefield, I will raise
the flag of victory.'
Uttar!
Uttara
your brother is the first martyr.
A new foundation of the nation
is being build,
and the first flag raised on it,
will be Uttar's, son of
King of Virat.
Until the end of time,
Pandu's dynasty will be indebted
to Uttar, Uttara.
Prince Uttar's sacrifice
will not go in vain,
King of Virat.
Our enemies will definitely have
our vengeance for this.
Water...
Yudhistira should've been
died today, Grandsire.
If only King of Virat's son didn't
display courage!
- Don't worry, my dear.
Tomorrow, his excellency Bhisma would certainly
captured Yudhistira with his own hands.
Today we've shown destruction to
our enemies' soldiers.
Tomorrow in the battlefield, no soldiers
will protect him.
They all will be in fear,
after seeing our might!
Fear?
Foolish Duryodhana!
A widow's wailing will not make even
her youngest child frightful.
So why do they have to fear?
Moreover what courage had you displayed, except for
killing a 15 years old youth?
Even it was not with your own hands,
but by forcing me to do it!
King of Madra,
from common soldier to the general,
the value of one's courage is
devoted to the king.
Both victory or defeat, the value is still
When the opening dish is served, there's no difference between 'laddoo' and 'kheer' because both of them are sweet, King of Madra.
We have victory today,
and in this battle, the other name of
winning is courage.
Uncle's right.
Today's victory
will add strength to face
tomorrow's battle.
I want to know,
winning can lift spirit in war.
Until you experience defeat,
how can be any lift in potency?
Prince Uttar not just saved
Brother Yudhistira's life.
But saved us from defeat as well.
He has become a guardian.
From now on, he won't let defeat
to fall on us.
Righteousness is destined to achieve victory!
Crown Prince Duryodhana,
don't forget,
that in a war without the King's presence,
all responsibilites are imposed
on the crown prince.
And in this war,
the king's not present, but you are.
That's why, think like a king.
And,
other than thinking about victory,
think about your ability.
What if
today's win
becomes loss tomorrow?
Sons of Pandu will certainly
make a plan
which effect's will demolish
everyone's morals here.
Today, grandsire had broken
our battle formation.
But tomorrow, it won't happen again.
Tomorrow, before the sun sets,
we will capture Duryodhana.
The first day of war,
from 7 'akshauhini' army,
one had been destroyed
by King Yudhistira.
And Vasudev
there's one question in our soldiers' mind.
If this is a righteous war, then why did we
experience defeat today?
A righteous was is also a war,
General Dhristadyumna.
In war, one can't escape neither
from winning nor losing.
General Dhristadyumna,
a soldier's duty is to strife
with his weapon.
Winning or losing is in the Almighty's hand.
But Prince Arjuna after Prince Uttar's death,
fear has gripped each soldier's heart.
How can our soldiers retaliate Grandsire Bhisma
and Master Drona attacks?
It is right.
As long as his excellency Bhisma
has a role in this war,
victory is impossible for us.
Defeating Master Drona becomes
impossible as well.
If grandsire still takes part in this war,
he will destroy all our armies.
Tomorrow, I will challenge grandsire,
one on one.