[CRYING]
Radha.
Brij Bihari.*
*One who travels.
Were you telling the truth
to Lady Yashoda?
Will you never return
to Vrindavan?
Radha.
I am taking all the
memories of Vrindavan
along with me.
But Banwari
how will you engage in
playful interactions over there?
Without you, your Gopis*
*Milkmaids.
will lose their minds.
I am leaving another part
of my life here, Radha.
I shall not engage in any more
playful interactions henceforth.
But playful interactions
will never cease in Vrindavan.
Where there is Radha
there are playful interactions.
[MUSIC]
Krishna!
Krishna, Balaram
this is the city of Mathura.
The agony of your lineage
the prison cell of your parents
and the land
of your fated actions.
Let's proceed.
This is a garland
for your victory.
We have woven
our tears into this.
Do accept this on our behalf.
His Highness has
ordered us to kill you.
In other words,
are you the one
for whom I shall require
no order before killing?
You talk just a
tad bit too much, boy!
Yes.
I do love talking.
This is my brother
Balaram.
He solely loves to fight.
You may die at his hands.
Before engaging
in a duel with us
you must lift that bow
if you have the strength.
Even numerous strongmen find it
difficult to lift it together.
That toy?
If we break that
will the owner of the toy
ask for money from us?
[THUNDER ROARING]
Who are you, Lady?
Why have you fallen at my feet?
My body is crooked
from three places, My Lord.
That is why,
everyone calls me Trivakra.
Are you truly the one
who has come here to slay Kansa?
No.
I have not come here
to slay anyone.
I merely straighten
crooked things out
be it the crookedness
of parts of the body
or that of the soul.
I merely heal things.
Guard!
Go to the prison
and bring Vasudev and Devaki
to the grappling combat arena.
If you see any danger
looming over me
then that very instant
you need to behead them!
Go!
- All hail Shri Krishna!
- Stop!
Greetings, uncle!
Will you not give me
your blessings?
To wish for your glory
is something I would
never desire.
To wish for your long life
is also something
I would never desire.
What blessing should I give you?
Give me the blessing
that people will be
left bewildered
at the kind of death
I will meet with.
Yes, everyone
will say that
and this is my blessing to you!
I am contented
with that, uncle.
No one can call dying
in a grappling combat
a bewildering death after all.
So,
it is certain
that I cannot die at your hands.
Now, listen.
I am asking you
to release our parents.
Return the kingdom
to your father, King Ugrasen
and also his crown and throne
with due respect.
I shall pardon you,
uncle.
[LAUGHING]
Do you want me to beg before you
and plead for mercy?!
Foolish boy!
You need to prove
your competence first.
Go to the grappling combat arena
and fight Chanur and Mushtik!
If you stay alive
then you can think about
pardoning me.
I have a request,
uncle.
My brother Balaram
will engage in a
grappling combat with Mushtik
if you have no objection to it.
Shall we proceed to the
grappling combat arena?
I want those two boys
dead in the arena.
Chanur, Mushtik!
Do what you have to,
engage in any tactic you like
but they should not stay alive.
Mushtik!
Chanur!
Get up!
Uncle,
what have you thought
about asking for forgiveness?
Engage in a grappling combat
with me, Krishna!
If I die in this combat
my guard will slay your parents.