Let me go, father!
- I said, stop.
Father, I have to go
welcome them! - You are a fool.
Who asked you to welcome them
in this manner?
Why? Did you not enjoy
the spectacle?
I only wished
to please the king.
You wished to please him?
Do you think competing against
the king will please him?
You are better at archery
than any 'Kshatriya'.
Upon knowing this, will it
please the king or anger him?
I have explained it to you
so many times.
The son of a charioteer
should behave like one.
Son, your skills won't
please the king
but your dedication towards
him will.
No, father.
Our king is not like that.
And look at the face
of the Queen.
She has such an
affectionate look.
Just like mother Radha.
Let me go, father!
No, Karna.
Karna, no.
Look at that, your Highness.
A group of people from
the forest are here.
They must have welcomed you so.
Long live King Pandu!
Four.
One, two, three, four.
One is bound to come across
obstacles, Sanjay
but the one who knows
how to overcome them
is the one who never loses.
But some obstacles
cannot be overcome, Shakuni.
Those are like shackles of fate.
True, your Highness.
You are absolutely correct.
Some obstacles are like
shackles of fate.
Sanjay, tell me.
How will you overcome
the obstacle you face?
If the dice roll...
Yes. If I score six points,
I can overcome this obstacle.
In other words, the dice can
liberate you from the shackles.
You need to befriend
your dice, Sanjay.
Befriend them!
I am not talking about
a game of dice
but about life.
- Life!
Life!
I too am talking about life,
your Highness.
It is all in our heads.
We have memories.
Walks on two legs.
We see him around us
but we
mistake him a for a human being,
your Highness.
Who are you talking about,
Shakuni?
Prince Pandu
who has recently returned
after getting married.
To me, welcoming him is like
rolling the dice right.
Sister, why is
Gandhari not here?
Sukta said that
Dhritarashtra does not
want Gandhari
to welcome the new couple.
But the new bride must be
welcomed by Gandhari, sister.
Ambalika
even Gandhari was welcomed
by Kripacharya's wife.
It was so for there was
no married woman
in our family back then.
But if there is a married woman
in the family
and yet we make someone else
give the traditional welcome
wouldn't that be an ill omen,
Queen Mother?
I shall let no ill omen befall
my family, mother Ambalika.
Greetings, sister-in-law.
- Greetings.
Greetings.
I welcome
the Queen of Hastinapur.
Sister-in-law
My wife wishes to seek
your blessings.
Do bless her.
What do I bless you with, Kunti?
A happy married life,
children
a long live and welfare...
You have already been
blessed with all this.
Bless her by saying that
her wishes will come true
and that she will
face no obstacles.
Recognize the pawns,
your Highness
and keep rolling the dice.
All the obstacles
will be eliminated.
You are correct,
mother Ambalika.
And blessings
get rid of obstacles.
Where is brother Dhritarashtra?
Is he still angry?
Kunti, all the daughters-in-law
of the family
install their family
deities in this temple.
Give the priest the idol
of your family deity
for the consecration
ritual of the idol.
Sister-in-law
I have been blessed by everyone
but
neither did I get the
blessings of brother-in-law
nor did I get to meet him.
In the journey from the kingdom
of Kunti to Hastinapur
my Lord was talking
only about his elder brother.
His valour, his generosity
his fondness towards my Lord...
He said
that if his elder brother
blesses me
I would not require blessings
even from the Almighty.
I do not know, sister-in-law
whether or not I have the right
to say this.
Please pardon me.
But, sister-in-law
what I heard in Kuntinagar
is making me a little restless.
Absence of a festoon
at the entrance of a house
is not a matter of concern,
sister-in-law.
But the presence of a single
thorn in the orchard of a house
is not good.
There is no thorn
in this orchard, Kunti.
Your brother-in-law
has a very big heart.
To say it cannot house
his brother and his wife in it
is out of the question.
If you have heard that there's
a conflict between them
then it is untrue.
Some conniver must have
started this rumour.
Your brother-in-law has
boundless love for Pandu.
If love and deceit
compete against each other
love always triumphs.
Deceit always triumphs,
your Highness. - Deceit!
A warrior engages in a battle,
Shakuni
and not in deceit.
Battle!
Battle.
Deceit is like a battle,
your Highness.
A battle of the mind.
Do not consider deceit
to be bad, your Highness.
The people who get hurt
because of our actions
call it deceit
and the ones who benefit from it
call it strategy, your Highness.
In this game of life
Prince Pandu rolled the
dice perfectly
and defeated us.
Even I harbour
nothing but hatred
towards King Pandu.
Hate.
But now, we must
keep our minds calm
control our anger
come up with a new game
and defeat Prince Pandu.
Attention!
King Pandu is
making his entrance!
Welcome, King Pandu.
Welcome.
Greetings.
- Greetings, Prince.
Savant, greetings.
Congratulations, your Highness.
Upon hearing that you
won the 'swayamvar'
my brother-in-law told me
that his younger brother
can never lose.
Greetings, brother.
May you live long.
Kunti and I were waiting for you
to bless us, brother.
Brother-in-law could not make it
only because of me.
He kept saying that
you would have reached
but I insisted
on playing one final
round of the game.
Then he was free to go.
Even I have heard that you
love these dice dearly, Prince.
Love!
You may assume they are two
wives of mine, your Highness.
Two dutiful wives.
Brother...
Kunti wishes to come
here to seek your blessings.
If you allow me then
may I go and get her?
I-Indeed...
- No!
No, we should go and greet her.
It is the right of a new bride
that everyone goes to
her to welcome her.
Your Highness...
I request you
to allow brother-in-law
to bless her Highness
tomorrow morning.
Besides, he does not have
anything to gift her at present.
He must also
present her something.
Because the one to be blessed
is not only his daughter-in-law
but also
the Queen of Hastinapur.
Alright.
Tomorrow morning, we will
come here to seek
your blessings, brother.
Certainly.
Greetings, brother.
Saying that you will
certainly bless them
was good thinking
on your part, your Highness.
I think, my game of dice
is finally making
some sense to you.
While making a decision,
we always
deem the suggestion, advice,
aid and consultation of others
as our foundation.
And the foundation
of our future
depends upon our decisions
made in the present.
So, is our future the result
of someone else's advice
and someone else's suggestion?
Is our entire life the result
of someone else's intellect?
Have we ever thought about it?
Our experience tell us
that different people
give different advice
in the same situation.
A devotee in a temple
believes in charity
but a thief says
that given an opportunity
he would steal
the idol's ornaments.
A pious heart
dispenses righteous advice
and a depraved heart
dispenses unrighteous advice.
Accepting righteous advice
propels man towards happiness.
But accepting such advice
is possible only when one
is pious.
In other words, before accepting
someone's suggestion or advice
is fostering righteousness
within one's heart
not important?
Think about it.
'If one lies to gain something'
'then it is deception.'
'But if one hides the truth
to escape from harm'
'then it is not deception,
Princess.'
'And till the time you have
this thread on your wrist'
'you will not say anything to
your husband about your past.'
I will not base my life
on deception.
My Lord
should know the truth
about my past.
In the journey
from Kuntibhoj to Hastinapur
I could not muster the courage
to tell him about it.
We hardly had any privacy.
But today
the moment my Lord arrives
the first thing I will do
is tell him about my past.
My Lord, upon seeing
Karna's archery skills
were the King and Queen
not impressed?
Yes, they were impressed.
But when they
would have learned
that he is the
son of a charioteer
their amazement would have
turned to anger, Radha.
You are well aware, Radha
that people of our caste
can become only charioteers
and not become warriors.
But why, father?
You always tell me that
the best work
is always commended.
Do not argue with me, Karna.
When a person achieves
highest quality in his work
only then does he
garner respect.
But when a person
does someone else's work
he does not garner respect
but competition.
My Lord, the King will
see him as his competitor...
Is this what you are
trying to say?
And the King...
- Not the King.
The warriors of the kingdom
will see him as a rival.
Not only us, our entire
community will face their wrath.
I feel, the King will be pleased
and will give me a reward.
And father, you always say
that the person who protects
the best in a society
is a true king.
You are still
arguing with me, Karna!
I already said that this
concerns our family's safety!
It is the question of safety
of not only our family
but also of the entire society!
Yet you insist
on displaying your skills.
Alright.
You may do so.
Here is an arrow.
Let the entire world know
that a charioteer who
can defeat warriors
has been born in
in Hastinapur.
I am not concerned about
your mother and I.
We will brave it.
Pick up your bow and arrows.
Pick them up!
Karna...