The boundaries of the
province aren't its limits
but its identity.
Respecting
and understanding it
is the duty of every prince.
In face of an enemy's attack
what should be
a king's first reaction?
Ashwatthama?
If the enemy is weak
battling against and defeating
him is the best option.
If strong, a diplomacy
is the best course.
The enemy can never be strong.
Strength isn't just measured
on physical terms, prince.
A wealthier one
is also stronger.
Master, there's no gain in being
diplomatic with a stronger foe.
Because a stronger person
considers it a weakness
and doesn't respect
a diplomacy.
That will weaken us in strength
and self-confidence.
By being diplomatic with
a weaker person
the subjects of both kingdoms
are benefitted by trade
and others.
The weaker person never
violates the diplomacy.
Thus, a diplomacy with
a weaker person is justified
and battling a stronger foe
justifies bravery.
But only a single behaviour
is just for any foe, master.
Be it strong or weak.
Whoever falls in here
can't get out.
Bhim will also have
a similar death bed.
Why did you stop?
It's dusk, master.
I can't see the target now.
That means your eyes limit you.
A warrior must know his limits.
Not my eyes, master
the darkness is my limit.
If one is unable to break
a stone by his hands
is the limiting factor
the hands or the stone?
Who's sharpening
his weapons now?
It must be Arjun.
He has been freed of the task
of herding cattle, after all.
That's so unfair, brother.
We'd herd cattle
and he'd gain knowledge?
Fool!
The master's orders
shouldn't be called unfair!
The sad thing is, we are,
after all, students
but you... Ashwatthama, why
is Arjun being your obstacle?
The amount of time Arjun gets
to practice, must be yours.
My very words.
Arjun is anyway our enemy
and he's an enemy of
friend Ashwatthama too.
Arjun is an enemy of us all.
What if I kill him with
my arrow right now?
I can fire arrows
guided by sound.
Guided by sound?
What do you mean?
I mean, the source
of sound in utter darkness
becomes the target for my arrow.
Just like King Dashrath's arrow
had hit Shravan.*
Name of the boy mistakenly killed by Rama's father, King Dashrath (in epic Ramayana).
But without challenging,
it's improper to attack.
That's what master had said.
But that rule is for warriors.
Ashwatthama is
after all a Brahmin.
That's right, friend.
Here you go.
I'll remove a thorn in
your side right away.
How did he do that?
Through the sound of
my bowstring he came to know
that an arrow was being shot.
When did he gain this knowledge?
We should leave
before he comes here.
Something needs to
be done about him.
Arjun!
He is here. Then who was
the archer in the forest?
My cow is tied here!
How dare you tie
your cows here?
Brother Dushashan, this cow
is neither mine nor yours.
It is the master's.
The cow that the master charged
me with will be tied here!
Move!
Guru Drona!
Brother!
- Brother!
- Brother Bhim! - Brother Bhim!
Brother Bhim!
Brother Bhim, give me
your hand.
Brother, hold my hand!
- Help me, Nakul!
Brother, grab my hand!
Brother, brother Bhim
has fallen into the quagmire!
Brother, grab my hand!
Give me your hand!
Brother! - Brother Bhim!
- Brother!
Brother Bhim!
- Brother Bhim! - Bhim!
Bhim, don't try to get out.
You will sink further.
We'll try to find a way out.
Brother Bhim!
Master!
- Master!
Brother Bhim!
Brother!
Bhim, wait!
- Brother!
Master!
Master...
Brother Bhim and brother
Duryodhan had a duel.
Brother Duryodhan made brother
Bhim fall into this mire.
Help me!
- Stay calm.
In face of a trouble,
find a way to get out of it.
Facing off against
an unprecedented trouble
is a part of education.
Brother!
Brother, help me!
'It's dusk, master.'
'I can't see the target now.'
'That means your eyes
limit you.'
'A warrior must know
his limits.'
'If one is unable to break
a stone by his hands'
'is the limiting factor
the hands or the stone?'
'That means your eyes
limit you.'
'A warrior must know
his limits... If one is...'
'...the hands or the stone?'
'That means your
eyes limit you.'
Brother!
Brother, grab this branch!
We'll pull you out.
Pull!
Arjun.
Wonderful, dear!
No one's that quick
to grasp archery.
You're one in a million.
You'll become the best
archer of the world.
I'll make you the best
That's my oath, dear.
You'll practice with divine
weapons from tomorrow.
Tell Bhim and Duryodhan
to have a restraint on
their anger while they are here.
Else they would be
expelled from the seminary.
'Whose arrow is this?'
'It's not mine.'