The lives of my sons
is now my life,
uncle.
For a smile from their child,
a mother and father
can even sacrifice
their own lives.
No, uncle.
If this war
jeopardizes the lives
of my sons
then I do not want
this war to take place.
But Duryodhan...
My son wants this war
but I don't.
What decision should I
take now, uncle?
How should I come to a decision?
You have never taken a decision
in your life, Your Highness.
The way a cloth
flying in the wind
changes its direction
according to the wind's decision
you too have spent
your entire life in this manner.
And in the end
such a cloth gets stuck
on a thorny bush
and gets shredded to pieces.
Everyone knows this,
Your Highness.
Do not use such
harsh words, uncle.
I have not come to you
as a king.
I have come here as your nephew
to seek advice from you.
The time to dispense advice
has already passed.
What advice should I
give you now?
Make Yudhishthir
the King of Hastinapur...
'If you willingly'
'give up your position as
the crown prince to Duryodhan...'
'Then I will not only
discharge my duties'
'but also regain my happiness.'
Do not attempt to burn
the sons of Pandu in Varnavart...
'In Varnavart'
'uncle Pandu's family
will burn to ashes'
'along with their memories.'
Allow them to live in peace
in Indraprastha...
'Go ahead
and attack Indraprastha'
'but please give up the thought
of setting yourself on fire.'
'I do not wish
to merely defeat them, father.'
'I wish to insult them.'
Do not organise
a game of dice...
'Along with the knowledge
of the scriptures and weapons'
'a game of dice is also
a part of us Kshatriyas.'
'That is why,
my son Duryodhan'
'has organised a game of dice.'
Do not let
the daughter of Drupad
be disrobed in the court,
Your Highness...
'Maid Draupadi must obey
her master Duryodhan's'
'every command.'
Do not send the Pandavas
on an exile
and force them into a life
of anonymity, Your Highness...
'All five of the brothers
along with their wife Draupadi'
'will have to go
on an exile for twelve years'
'and live an additional year'
'in anonymity.'
What advice should I
give you, Your Highness?
I know that I have committed
numerous mistakes, uncle.
I have been visionless
ever since I was born,
uncle.
An...
An
unknown fear always
surrounds my heart.
Now
if I have made a mistake
in this state of mind
then how am I at fault?
Being visionless is not
your limitation, Dhritarashtra.
Being visionless from your mind
is, however, your limitation.
You never let the absence
of vision pull you down.
Then why did you...
Why did you think that
you are less than anyone else?
And when an outsider
pointed out your shortcoming
why did you believe that person?
No outsider said anything.
You had said it.
Only then did I believe it.
When did I say
that you lag behind
others in power?
Try to recall,
uncle.
Try to recall the day I was
about to be crowned the king.
'A person who is
blind since birth'
'is not worthy
of becoming the king.'
You believed
what Vidur said that day.
You believed that a person
who is blind since birth
cannot become the king.
That is the tradition
of the entire Aryan region.
Neither Vidur nor I
are at fault here.
The greed you had
within you, to rule
the kingdom
and gain power
has reduced you
to your present state.
You have never
honoured traditions.
That is why,
the entire Aryan region
is on the verge of a war today.
If this war takes place
then my sons will die.
And if it does not take place
then the Pandavas
will punish my sons.
My sons will die even then.
Will the advice
to avert this war
be acceptable to your sons,
Dhritarashtra?
Will King Shakuni of Gandhar
allow them to accept it?
If you truly
wish to seek peace
then order
King Shakuni of Gandhar
to leave Hastinapur immediately.
A Garuda formation
can be built only
on an even ground, friend.
If the army of the enemy
bombards stones from a hill
then the soldiers might just
get crushed under their shields.
These battle formations of yours
are various ways to have
your army killed.
By talking of defeat
before the war
you are displaying your
weakness, King of Gandhar.
In the past ten years
I have conquered different
kingdoms in all four directions.
I have emerged victorious
in over 300 battles.
The uses of battle formations
and their importance
are not unknown to me.
And out of those battles,
how many were
against Vasudev Krishna
King of Anga?
A desert
may expand as much as it wants
a forest may give birth to
as much vegetation as it wants
and a river may flow
as fast as it can
but at the sea-shore
all of them
must come to an end.
Vasudev Krishna
is a formidable foe
and you may not know it,
King of Anga.
Uncle
why does Vasudev Krishna
leave you so fearful?
Fear?
One is fearful
of unknown objects, my child.
However, I know the powers
of Vasudev Krishna!
He is
so intelligent
and treacherous
that your entire...
That your entire army
can be destroyed
solely by him
in the battlefield
without any help.
A true battle formation
would be one
which would lead Vasudev Krishna
to be captured by you.
My child
as long as I am with you
you need not worry
even a bit.
A way to tackle Vasudev Krishna
is something I will
certainly find out.
Minister!
You are...
King of Gandhar,
His Highness has requested you
to leave the Kuru kingdom
at once
and proceed to Gandhar.
Your Highness!
Your Highness
what kind of an order
have you given?
What does banishing uncle
in this manner mean?
The Minister must have
been the one
to put forth this advice.
I had given
this advice, dear.
The King of Gandhar has damaged
Hastinapur's future enough.
It is time now
for Hastinapur
to think about its benefit.
Does the benefit
of the Kuru kingdom
not imply that
of the Pandavas, grandsire?
Your benefit, son.
You
and your brothers are
being blessed with life.
What the King of Gandhar
and the King of Anga
are advising you about the war
and on what basis
are not known to me.
However, rain water
cannot be held
in the palms
of one's hands for long.
The day the sons of Pandu
come to the battlefield, in the
ensuing battle of righteousness
my competence too
will fall short.
You will understand this truth
when the King of Gandhar
will stop dispensing
his harmful advice to you.
The truth is
quite the opposite to this
Your Excellency.
The truth is
that the anger
of my dear Duryodhan
can be controlled
only by my advice.
Otherwise
during the Rajsuya 'Yajna'
when these warriors had been
stripped of their weapons
there would have been a war.
When dear Dushala's husband
was insulted
there would have been a war.
When Hastinapur
was about to be attacked
by the Pandavas
there would have been a war.
If you have
decided to banish me
in this manner
then this is your burden
and no one else's,
Your Excellency.
Allow me to leave,
Your Highness.
You have permission on behalf
of His Highness, uncle.
You are welcome here.
And on behalf of His Highness,
it is an order, General
to prepare the army
for a battle.
Tomorrow at dawn
the army of Hastinapur will
attack the kingdom of Virat.
Tomorrow at dawn
the army of Hastinapur will
attack the kingdom of Virat.
Duryodhan!
No, Duryodhan.
This war will not
take place, son.
You may stop the army
of Hastinapur, father
but me
and my brothers
cannot be stopped by you.
You cannot stop my friend Karna!
We 101 warriors
will attack the kingdom
of Virat tomorrow!
Instead of living
this life of humiliation
it would be better if we die.
I will not change
my decision, father.
I will not change it!
Son Duryodhan...
- My child...
No...
Shedding one's blood
does not wash away one's insult.
However, if one sheds
the blood of the enemy
then the taint of the insult
gets washed away.
That is why
if victory in the war
is not certain
then shedding one's blood
is foolishness.
My darling
do not be intransigent
about a war.
At this moment
you must forget about the enmity
and all your struggles
and stay peaceful and calm,
because in doing so
lies your benefit.
King of Gandhar
hearing you talk
about establishing peace
in Hastinapur
is both astonishing
and delightful.
Then you may keep the delight
with yourself, Minister Vidur
and send
the astonishment
to the Pandavas.
And if I have made any mistake
then please pardon me.
Your Highness
I promise you
that my dear Duryodhan
will not refute my advice.
He will certainly
meditate over
the proposal of peace.
Will you honour this request
of your uncle,
my dear?
Alright.
If you insist
then I will not
attack this early.
However... - That is enough,
my dear.
That is enough.
As I leave the kingdom, I have
honoured His Excellency's wish.
I shall always be
proud of this
Your Excellency.
Allow me to leave,
Your Highness.