Will we
be successful here,
uncle?
Certainly,
my darling.
When compared
to the ties of blood
the ties of tears
are more tenacious.
Use your tears
to tie
him.
Uncle
the last time we came here
we were gravely insulted!
How will coming here again
benefit us?
If the circumstances
you face
cannot be made
favourable for you
then you must
make them unfavourable
for the enemy.
When the situation
of the enemy worsens
the resulting benefit
will come to us.
But uncle,
how is that possible?
Look
over there.
All the strength
of the Aryan region
is on one side
and the might of those two men
is on the other.
The side these Yadavas
take in the battle
will be stronger
than the other.
Vasudev Krishna's affection
lies with the Pandavas and I
know that
but the mighty Balaram
deems you
his most favourite disciple.
Getting Subhadra
married to you
was a dear wish of his.
Think of how we were
insulted back then
my darling
and shed tears for it
today.
The mighty Balaram
will certainly agree
to take our side.
My darling
we must persuade Vasudev Krishna
to take our side as well.
Vasudev will never go against
his elder brother
and if Balaram
is on our side
then
even if the Pandavas
strive for their entire lives
they will not be able
to have their revenge.
And that will
lead them to their death
and we
will not even
have to do anything.
Greetings, guru.
Bless you.
Beloved Duryodhan
the entire Aryan region
is talking about you.
However, it would have
pleased me more
had this talk
been about your prowess
in mace fighting.
Greetings,
King of Gandhar.
Greetings, Balaram.
Welcome.
Vasudev.
Let's go.
You have given
my darling Duryodhan
a lot of things
mighty Balaram.
You gave him
the knowledge of warfare
gave him respect
gave him love
but
did not show him the path
to joy and contentment.
That is
precisely why we came
to Dwaraka.
Joy and contentment
are not places,
King of Gandhar
where one must go.
Both of them are paths.
The path of joy
leads to struggle
and that of contentment
to peace.
Where does the Crown Prince
wish to go?
What
is happening here,
Vasudev?
This is the Narayani* Army of Dwaraka, King of Gandhar.
*Narayani Sena was the Army of Krishna.
It is creating
a labyrinth on the sea-shore
and at the moment
you are right in its center
as a captive.
But why,
Vasudev?
We came here
with the hope
to forge a friendship.
We are not here to fight.
Is the friendship forged
during times of trouble
not stronger,
King of Gandhar?
But do not worry.
You do not need true friendship
because at the moment
there is no reason
for you to worry.
A boy of royal blood
is playing a game
to navigate
through this labyrinth.
A boy
is playing a game to navigate
through this labyrinth!
He is Arjun and Subhadra's
son,
King of Gandhar.
He was born with
the competence of Arjun.
Even at this age he can
navigate through the labyrinth
made by the Narayani Army
and reach the center.
His name
is Abhimanyu.
Bless you!
Wonderful, dear.
Wonderful!
What?
Have you become
an accomplished warrior?
We have guests over.
Could you not restrain yourself
from displaying your skills
before them?
Our guests
were scared,
dear.
Uncle, I was not
demonstrating my skills.
I just could not restrain myself
from displaying my competence.
And a display of competence
does not scare guests
but enemies.
Brother Duryodhan had navigated
into King Drupad's labyrinth.
If you can navigate
out from this one
then we will be scared.
My father is bound
to teach me that
but who will teach uncle?
Dear Abhimanyu
does your father have
no support of competent warriors
that a boy of your age
is being made to navigate
into a labyrinth?
I had imbibed this knowledge
when I was in the womb.
And coming to navigating
out of a labyrinth...
Before a battle,
all the weapons are sharpened
and I too am my father's weapon
uncle Duryodhan.
Beloved Duryodhan
it has been days
since I have had the opportunity
to have a mace fight
with an able warrior.
How about
we have a little
mace fight of our own?
Only then will we talk.
As you say,
guru.
Pick up your mace,
beloved disciple.
Vasudev
it seems as though
the mighty Balaram
does not deem this
a friendly duel.
The truth is,
my darling
is being beaten up by him.
Does one
not beat up and hurt another
in a friendly duel,
King of Gandhar?
The guru is punishing
his disciple.
The guru had taught his disciple
the art of mace fighting
but the disciple
deemed playing a game of dice
more appropriate.
The game of dice
has ended
thirteen years ago
Vasudev.
It had begun then.
Thirteen years ago
you had begun this game,
King of Gandhar.
And when a game is begun,
it is also vital to end it.
When one team employs
a strategy in a game
the other team also has
the right to employ
its own strategy.
It is time now for the Pandavas
to employ their strategy
King of Gandhar.
Abhimanyu!