If grandsire continues
battling in this manner
then he will annihilate
our entire army.
Tomorrow, I shall challenge
grandsire to a duel.
And Guru Dronacharya
is fated to die
at the hands of
General Dhrishtadyumna.
Tomorrow,
at any cost
you must retaliate
against Guru Dronacharya.
Retaliating against Guru Drona
by himself is impossible
for General Dhrishtadyumna.
Arjun should help him.
Stopping Guru Drona by oneself
will not be easy for anyone.
If brother Arjun
will battle Guru Drona
then who will retaliate
against grandsire?
Just like a 'vajra'
he will annihilate
our entire army.
There is only one way out.
It is mandatory
to keep His Excellency
away from the battlefield.
And if
His Excellency will be
away from the battlefield
and at that very moment
Guru Drona
will be battling Arjun
then Duryodhan
will have no one to protect him.
But Madhav
is it even possible
to keep grandsire
away from the battlefield?
Using treachery.
Yes, friend.
I had said
that treachery will indeed
be employed in this war
and it is time now to employ it.
Treachery?
But resorting to treachery in
a war is unrighteous, Vasudev.
Even this war is a result of
treachery, brother Yudhishthir.
And if the basis of treachery
is righteousness
then employing treachery
is righteous as well.
And in order to boost
the morale of our army
it is mandatory for us
to gain victory tomorrow.
And in order to gain victory
we shall be required to take
only five steps.
Only five steps.
'Second Day of the War.'
After yesterday's defeat
what strategy have
the sons of Pandu
come up with today,
Sanjay?
Are they trembling with fear
at the very thought of defeat?
Today, the sons of Pandu
have kept Prince Yudhishthir
at the end of their
battle formation, Your Highness.
'In order to protect him,
General Dhrishtadyumna'
'King Virat and the Upapandavas
are present, Your Highness.'
'The ones leading
the battle formation'
'are Prince Nakul,
Prince Sahadev'
'and Prince Abhimanyu,
Your Highness.'
'On one side of the formation,
there is Prince Arjun'
'while on the other, there is
Prince Bheem, Your Highness.'
But what kind
of a battle formation
have the sons of Pandu
come up with, Sanjay
where Yudhishthir
is right at the end?
Such kind of a formation
is aggressive in nature,
Your Highness.
It can cut right through
the enemy army, Your Highness.
And its sides
can leave the enemy army in
total disarray, Your Highness.
The 'Krouncha Vyooh.'*
*Crane-shaped formation.
This battle formation
of the Pandavas
is advancing towards
the army of the Kauravas
Your Highness.
But what formation has
grandsire come up with
in retaliation to this one,
Sanjay?!
Assume the form of a 'Maha Vyooh!'*
*To block the outflanking move of the enemy.
Crown Prince Duryodhan
shall stay under my protection
in the middle of the formation!
Guru Drona
shall lead us
and protect us from any attack
launched against us!
Dusshasan
Ashwatthama,
King of Gandhar
King Shalya
and King Susharma, attack the
sides of the enemy formation!
The 'Krouncha Vyooh'
can be broken
by stifling the neck of this
bird-shaped formation.
Attack!
- Attack!
Attack! - All hail Mahadev!
- All hail Mahadev!
All hail Mahadev!
King of Madra!
Do not mourn the death
of Crown Prince Uttar
because he shall
always live in my weapons!
Prince Arjun!
The army of Trigartha
has been assembled
only to battle you!
These soldiers have
only one goal in their lives
and that is to slay you!
Neither does another warrior
have the competence to kill them
nor do they have the intention
of striking at another warrior!
Do not employ words
to attack me, King Susharma!
Resort to weapons instead!
Friend
it is time to take
the first step to our victory.
That is the sign from Arjun.
The garland of victory
shall await you, dear!
Leave at once!
Charioteer.
Today, you shall get the answer
to yesterday's treachery
King of Madra!
Do you hear that?!
The entire battlefield
is resonating with that answer!
Steer the chariot to the middle
of our formation, charioteer.
One must not battle where
there is mist.
Steer the chariot at once!
What else is happening
in the battlefield, Sanjay?!
Why are you not telling
me anything?!
Nothing is visible in the
battlefield, Your Highness.
The battle formation
of the Pandavas
has been completely
hidden by clouds.
The miraculous weapon
of Prince Arjun
has left the entire battlefield
confounded, Your Highness.
Where is Arjun, Sanjay?
Where is Arjun?!
It is time to take
the second step to our victory.
His Excellency and Guru Drona
need to be separated from
Crown Prince Duryodhan.
Brother Yudhishthir,
are you prepared?
No, Vasudev.
I cannot bring myself
to do this.
I had told you,
brother Yudhishthir
that His Excellency's
ties and his weakness
lie in the fort of Hastinapur.
If you attack Hastinapur
then His Excellency
will leave the battlefield
trailing you.
But we had decided
that the war will be fought
only on this battlefield.
This region of Samanta Panchaka
lies amidst five lakes.
Those five lakes are
the boundaries of this region.
We cannot battle beyond
these confines.
No, Vasudev.
Leaving the battlefield
is not appropriate.
Leaving the battlefield is also
a kind of battle formation
brother Yudhishthir.
Think of it as
a kind of battle formation.
Charioteer
take the chariot forth.
'Along with one 'akshauhini'
army, Prince Yudhishthir'
'is exiting
their battle formation'
'and advancing towards
Hastinapur, Your Highness.'
Yudhishthir is advancing
towards Hastinapur!
It is time to take
the third step to our victory.
Brother Bheem
brother Yudhishthir
is going to attack Hastinapur.
Would you not like to deliver
this news to Dusshasan?
Certainly, Vasudev.
My mace shall deliver
the message to that fool!
Sanjay...
Sanjay, what else is happening
in the battlefield?
How...
How can Yudhishthir
leave the battlefield and
attack Hastinapur?
Out of the greed for victory
righteousness keeps getting
sacrificed, Your Highness.
Possibly, the defeat
of the first day
has replaced righteousness
with victory within them
Your Highness.
Sanjay, where is Bheem?
Pick up the mace,
Dusshasan
and remind me once again
about the strength of your arms.
What if I forget about
their strength
while ripping your arms out.
Get up!
King Virat, go and help
brother Yudhishthir out
by proceeding
towards Hastinapur!
In order to help Dusshasan out
I shall stay right here.
Brother Duryodhan!
A very large section
of the enemy army
is headed towards Hastinapur,
brother Duryodhan!
Brother Yudhishthir is leading
that army, brother Duryodhan!
He is headed towards Hastinapur
to indeed attack it, my darling.
Then grandsire will
have to trail
Yudhishthir at the earliest.
In order to protect Hastinapur...
But battling outside the borders
of Samanta Panchaka
is unrighteous!
And brother Yudhishthir
can never act unrighteously.
If you keep pulling the tail
of a cow, my darling
then it too can charge at you.
If he gets
the slightest hint of defeat
then even Yudhishthir
can resort to unrighteousness.
Impossible!
I have firm belief
in Yudhishthir!
He can never act unrighteously!
Your Excellency
belief gives one great comfort
but in the battlefield
disbelief provides one
with great benefits
while belief results
only in losses.
Uncle is correct, grandsire.
Can we gamble in such
a situation?
If your belief
turns out to be false
and Yudhishthir goes
to Hastinapur and slays the King
then what will you do?
I order you, grandsire
to trail Yudhishthir.
Then who will protect you here?
In order to protect
my darling Duryodhan
numerous Maharathis
are present here
Your Excellency Bhishma.
However
over there
Yudhishthir is by himself
and you can slay him
in such a situation.
I order you, grandsire
to trail Yudhishthir
and protect Hastinapur
and the moment
you get the opportunity
you need to slay him.