Brother had said
where the Sudarshana Chakra
fails to work
is where the melody of flute does.
He had also told me
that only if I bear
humility in my heart
will I be able to win
over the High Queen.
Sister-in-law.
No!
You cannot address me
by that term.
I'm not addressing you
as 'sister-in-law'
but you will address me as one.
Sister-in-law!
Please pardon my husband.
I have given you
all that I had with me.
Now, please allow us
to enter the city.
Unfortunate is he
who cannot revere
Madhav's flute.
Do proceed to the gates
of the city.
Let me make preparations
to welcome both of you.
"This is such a complex
matter of rights."
"This is a matter of honour."
"It seems to be"
"on the verge of success."
"My heart must remain steadfast"
"and this is a vow
I must fulfil."
"My heart will remain steadfast"
"and this is the purpose
of my life."
May you be blessed
with a son, Subhadra.
May the Almighty make your son
inherit the glory and valour
his father possesses.
Panchali...
I have wronged you.
I hope you will pardon me.
I've accepted the peculiarities
of my fate, My Lord
but my heartache will fade away
the day I comprehend
the meaning of such fate.
Madhav had ordered me
to get married, Panchali.
The future of the entire
Aryan region
rested on this marriage.
Madhav had told me so.
And brother Balaram had said...
I am not asking you
the reason, My Lord.
I wish to know what it means.
Man decides why
he does certain things
but its meaning...
Its meaning is decided
by the Almighty.
It meant only one thing...
The subjects of the entire
Aryan region
deserve to be happy
and contented
and free from exploitation.
And unrighteousness needs
to be eradicated from the world.
All this is possible
only when brother Yudhishthira
becomes the emperor
of the Aryan region
and you
become the Empress
of the Aryan region.
Mother's orders
Madhav's wish
and our efforts
are propelling us
towards this goal.
If that is the case, My Lord
then my heartache will fade away
the day when, in order
to realise this meaning
you will take the first step.
The road to the 'Rajsuya Yajna'
of Indraprastha
has many obstacles in it.
Please begin to get
rid of them, My Lord.
Uncle...
We must approach
Shishupal of Chedi for aid.
He is an enemy
of Vasudeva Krishna.
No, my child.
No.
Even if you assemble
an army of monkeys
you will not be
able to fight a lion.
Shishupal is foolish.
He deems verbal abuses
to be weapons.
Krishna can crush him
in a single moment.
The Yadavas are afraid
only of King Jarasandha.
Krishna had killed
his own uncle Kansa.
Kansa was the son-in-law
of Jarasandha.
In order to exact his revenge
King Jarasandha had attacked
the Yadavas several times
and left them terrorised.
In the end, the Yadavas
had to leave Mathura
and flee to Dwaraka.
My child, you are not acquainted
with King Jarasandha's might.
But, uncle...
Why would Jarasandha help us?
We are not going
to approach him for help.
We are going to seek his refuge.
I, the Crown Prince
of Hastinapur
am to seek his refuge?
Indeed, my child!
Indeed.
The climbers of a forest
seek the refuge of a tree
and then, drain the nutrients
of that very tree.
This is politics.
If you wish to conquer
the entire Aryan region someday
and become its emperor
then you must
seek the refuge
of King Jarasandha today.
If you wish to defeat Krishna
and stop the 'Rajsuya Yajna'
of Indraprastha
then only King Jarasandha
will make that possible.
If Jarasandha kills the Yadavas
then how would it
benefit us, uncle?
If you cannot break a stick
then you must
cleave it
right through the middle.
If the Pandavas
and the Yadavas
are separated
then breaking them
will be easier.
He is the only person
who can make
the entire Aryan region
shudder at his very mention
because Jarasandha
cannot be killed.
Because Jarasandha
Cannot be killed?
How can that be possible, uncle?
Jarasandha's father,
King Brihadratha
had two wives
but no children.
The Great Sage Chandakaushika
gave King Brihadratha a fruit
in order to bear children.
The King divided
that fruit into two
and gave one half
to each of his wives.
Both his wives gave birth
to two halves of a child.
It was then that the King
prayed to the female ogre Jara.
The ogre Jara used her powers
to join the two halves
which brought the child to life.
Since Jara had amalgamated
the two halves
the child
came to be known
as Jarasandha.
All hail Emperor Jarasandha...
- Hail!
Come forward and demonstrate
your might!
Come forth!
All hail Emperor Jarasandha...
- Hail!
He cannot be killed
with any weapon.
The secret to killing
King Jarasandha
is known only by the ogre Jara
and the Almighty.
No one else knows about it.
All hail Emperor Jarasandha...
- Hail!
Let's go, my child.
Let's go, my child!
Only after consuming poison
did Lord Shiva
earn the right of bearing
the crescent moon on his head.
Gulp down this poison of insult.
Hail the Emperor!
Greetings, King Jarasandha!
Emperor Jarasandha!
So, you are the one
who had approached
Vasudeva Krishna
to marry his sister.
Pardon the heart of the Prince,
Your Highness.
He fell in love.
That is a lie,
King of Gandhar!
I have heard a lot
about your feats.
All your actions
reek of politics
and not love.
Because your political ploys
were unsuccessful there
you have come to Magadha
to achieve success.
To me, Emperor Jarasandha.
Your Highness,
when one door closes
one must open another.
That is how rodents behave,
King of Gandhar.
When the entrance
to their shelter gets closed
they scurry in another direction
to dig a new passage.
However, the den of a lion
has only one entrance
and the courage
to block that passage
is possessed by no one!
No one!
Your Highness,
do not let your might
become your terminal point.
We have come to you
with a proposal.
You ought to perform
a 'Rajsuya Yajna.'
The entire army of Hastinapur
and the enemies of the Yadavas
will stand by you.
You ought to declare yourself
the Emperor
of the entire Aryan region.
When one does not have the
strength to fight one's battles
engaging in one is foolishness,
King of Gandhar.
Foolishness!
For all these years
you have fought your own battles
Emperor Jarasandha.
Yet, Vasudeva Krishna is alive
and the Yadavas are prosperous.
Your Highness...
If even one of the flames
goes unextinguished
the wind is deemed weak.
And now, Vasudeva Krishna
has become the sun
from being a flame!
Even taking that cowherd's name
in Magadha is a crime!
So, how dare you praise him!
The three of you shall be
sentenced to death!
Soldiers, arrest them!
Have them beheaded and send
their heads to Krishna!
My darlings...
Surrender yourselves.
Have faith in the gambit
of Shakuni.
Very soon,
the Pandavas
will be unable
to understand the difference
between a door and a wall.
Very soon,
the Pandavas
will be caught
in our web.