Just like how the dark clouds
pour forth the rains
and cleanse themselves.
Just like how the water in the
rivers cleanses itself
by leaving the dirt aside
as it flows.
In the same manner,
it is the duty of the king
to punish himself in order to
purify himself.
How can I get rid of
my responsibilities?
Atonement
is greater than justice
and punishment, Pandu.
True atonement is one
in which
anything else in life
seems trivial in front of it.
I understand
but I become frail thinking
of Hastinapur's future.
Will this throne be
vacant again?
Even while shouldering the
responsibilities of the kingdom
you can live the life
of an ascetic.
No, grandsire.
If one builds his house
on a slope
he is bound to fall
into the ditch.
If I live amidst this leisure
sooner or later I will forget
about my atonement
and get caught in the
worldly pleasures.
How would you feel then,
grandsire?
When after 25 years
of struggle
you gave Hastinapur
a king
who is invariably
incapable?
I am the testimony to
your capability.
I know there isn't anyone
more capable than you.
While in his last moments,
sage Kindam asked me a question
as to what kind
of a king was I.
I couldn't distinguish between
a mystical deer and a human!
This question of his is
haunting me, grandsire.
We kept brother away
from the throne
stating that he's
incomplete.
But as a king
what sort of completeness
have I established?
I supplicate before you
let me go live in
the forest.
Let me fulfil my punishment
and improve my karma.
May God bless you.
To improve karma
is important for a human being,
Your Highness.
When one's soul
burns in hell
the pain is just unbearable.
Hence
to atone for one's sins,
during one's lifetime
is a good deed.
- Stop rambling, Shakuni.
I am not rambling,
Your Highness.
I am not rambling.
If I was in the place of
King Pandu
then I too would have
done the same.
I would have taken
the Lord's name
and spent the rest of my
life doing penance.
And I would have
permitted you too.
But I cannot permit Pandu to
go live in the forest.
He is my brother.
The very thought of him
living a difficult life
makes me shiver.
Difficult!
You, in true sense, are
generous, Your Highness.
You're generous.
For real, my sister
is blessed to have you.
She is very lucky.
Just like how
on a lotus leaf
a drop of water
cannot hold on.
In the same manner
sin
crime
temptation
greed
cannot hold on to
your pure heart.
Why are you changing
the topic, Shakuni?
What does my heart
have to do with this?
For me this is what is
important, Your Highness.
The brother
who deceitfully
dethroned you...
The one who
amidst the entire
royal assembly
had you humiliated...
But yet towards
the very same person
you have so much affection
within you.
You instead of
being worried of the future
of your unborn son
are worried about the
pain of your
deceitful brother.
You are great, Your Highness.
You are great.
Brother Shakuni!
Sister Gandhari!
The use of words
should be used as
a medication
so it can heal the pain
of one's heart.
But to use those words
to trigger the pain
is not right.
Wonderful, Gandhari.
Wonderful!
After marriage,
a girl turns into a woman
and becomes capable of giving
advice to her brother
is what I had always heard.
But I'm seeing it for the
first time today.
I'm not giving you
any advice.
I'm requesting, brother Shakuni.
Don't do anything to
divide my family.
I'm not trying to divide,
sister Gandhari.
I'm not trying to divide.
May Lord Yama claim
my life, if I'm doing so.
I'm showing His Highness
the right path.
You have blindfolded yourself.
Your marital commitment
is unbelievable.
But
to inform His Highness about
the ditches in the path
has to be done by
someone after all.
Brother Shakuni...
- Hear me out!
His Highness
will be the one to decide
as to what's right
and what's wrong.
After King Pandu
Hastinapur's throne
shall see your son
as the king.
This is the least hope
His Highness
might be having.
So when the time comes
will King Pandu,
for the sake of your son
abdicate his authority?
Will he do a deed
as great?
Greatness! No!
No.
Had he such greatness
in his heart
would he have
been deceitful towards
his elder brother?
When destiny has played its game
and King Pandu,
of his own will
is abdicating
the throne of Hastinapur
then who are we,
mere humans
to disrupt the plot of destiny?
I just had to say this.
The rest has to be thought over
by His Highness.
Good bye, Your Highness.
Lord
please tell Pandu to give up his
decision of going to exile.
Remain silent
and let me gauge the situation,
Gandhari.
What's the situation indeed for
us to accept a life in exile?
The sin of killing the sage
was unintentional, wasn't it?
This is not the punishment of
the sin, Madri
but of being unaware.
If a king starts committing
crimes unintentionally
justice and peace can
never prevail in the kingdom.
When you had asked me
to get the deer skin
I should have given that
a thought then.
That means the fault is mine
and I accept that.
Punish me for that
but how is it necessary for you
to bear the harshness of exile?
No, Madri. It's not your fault.
Asking something to a husband
can't be a fault. - Then who's
the one to be blamed for?
His Highness'?
The attempt of trying to fulfil
my wish
is a mistake, isn't it, sister?
I understand.
All too well.
Henceforth, His Highness will
always listen to you
and not me.
I promise you.
I didn't mean that, Madri.
- Don't find faults, Madri.
Try to accept that the mistake
has been made. - I do accept.
I have made a mistake
but the consequences will have
to be borne by our sons
who have not yet come
into this world.
If they take birth in the forest
they will be left wanting of
their right over the throne.
Madri, the ones who haven't
been born as of yet
why to plan for their future?
Whatever they will be
destined to
will be their fate.
I am a princess.
That my progeny would
be enthroned as ruler
is what I have been
taught since I was a mere child.
So I have the right to ponder
about their future.
In the Kuru lineage,
it's not right
but competence that has
the upper hand, Madri.
Will only your sons have that
competency
and not mine, sister? - You both
can never bear sons.
What do you mean by that, Lord?
'I curse you'
'if you ever try to establish
marital relations with a woman'
'or try any conjugal acts
with her then you shall die.'
This is the reason
why I have decided
to go into exile.
I'll also come along with you,
Lord.
No, Kunti. The harshness
of exile are not meant for you.
You both will stay here
in the palace.
- Without a husband
the palace seems
to be like a forest
but if the husband is beside one
then even the hut in a forest
equates a palace.
I still can't understand
the meaning of your decision
but if you've already taken
a decision
and sister is going with you
then I too shall come with you.
If sister's place
is by your side
then I share the same fate too.
I have come to Hastinapur
along with you
and I shall go along
wherever you take me.
It will be a place
devoid of amenities.
Only hard work would be
in your destiny.
The crime was done by
the three of us
so is the predicament
we are in
and thus will be the atonement
done by us.
Lord, please go ahead with the
arrangements for the journey.
Madri
you must get ready
for the journey.
Sorrow, anguish, planning
and projection...
My consciousness is far away
from every such thing.
Everything seems
befuddled to me.
Bhishma, I'm unable
to find a way out.
You are being hopeless
but in vain.
There's a reason behind
being dejected, Bhishma.
Do you see that boat?
Even the intense flow
of this river
can't drown this boat.
But even if a small hole
appears in this very boat
then the same boat will drown.
A similar hole
now gapes at us
whilst being in
the empire of Hastinapur.
If Pandu abdicates
then Hastinapur
will again become weak.
Weaker than before
because now
subjects will talk about it.
The rumours will be spread.
The subjects will be upset
see the king leaving.
And the kingdom where the
subjects are upset and disturbed
becomes very weak.
You are aware of it, Bhishma.
I will
not let the throne
of Hastinapur stay vacant.
We shall declare Dhritarashtra
as the king.
But it's against
righteousness and tradition.
Dhritarashtra shall
not be coronated.
He will be a de facto king.
He won't be able to carry out the Rajsuya 'yajna'.*
*The king's inauguration sacrifice performed by the ancient kings who considered themselves powerful enough to be an emperor.
But he'll be able to mete out
justice and righteousness.
You are quite apt,
Bhishma.
In the future, any child
being born in the Kuru lineage
shall be coronated.
But, Bhishma, will
Dhritarashtra accede to this?
Your Highness!
Your Highness, forgive me.
I have made a big mistake,
Your Highness.
What happened, Shakuni?
Your Highness!
Your Highness
I told Bhishma
that the throne
offered up just as alms
won't be acceptable
to you.
I have made a big mistake,
Your Highness.
You are quite apt, Shakuni.
I don't consume
food partaken by others.
I don't accept
anything in charity.
Charity!
In know it, Your Highness.
Now I have started
to understand you
that's why, before anyone
could even think about
enthroning you
I diverted the topic.
But I thought about it,
Your Highness.
The king of Panchal may not
belong to the Bharat lineage
he at least hails from
the Chandra lineage.
Then why don't we invite him
to manage our
kingdom of Hastinapur?
What are you
rambling about, Shakuni?
I can get you beheaded
for this thought.
But, Your Highness, someone has
to be the ruler, after all.
And your son is
still being nurtured
in my dearest
sister's womb.
He can't be coronated
until you become a king.
But you consider
your own kingdom
as a charity.
Pandu will have a son.
He will become the king.
Until then, the responsibilities
of the kingdom
shall be handled by Queen Mother
and grandsire, okay?
King Pandu can't have children,
Your Highness.
What?
- I have learnt
that sage Kindam has
cursed your brother.
If taken in this manner
this is not charity,
Your Highness.
If you are considering
it to be charity
then there's no other way out.
Attention!
His Excellency Bhishma
is arriving.
Greetings, grandsire.
May you have a long life.
Greetings.
Dhritarashtra,
after Pandu's exile
the throne of Hastinapur
has become vacant.
It needs a king.
Dear, the council of ministers
has decided
that in Pandu's stead
you should be announced
the de facto king.
For the sake of
Hastinapur's welfare
you will have to shoulder
this responsibility
Dhritarashtra.