'Aiming at a higher goal'
'when you wish
the death of Bhishma'
'you will certainly become
the reason of his demise.'
'Then I do not wish to live but
I shall return in my next life.'
'And when even your soul
is fatigued and aged'
'I shall come to you
as your doom.'
'I shall hear the footsteps
of death approaching you'
'Bhishma!'
'Even when a woman takes
to arms in the battlefield'
'can any man
ever strike at her?'
'Women will not be able
to participate in this war.'
None of these pyres
belong to you.
Numerous young soldiers
will die on these in exchange
for a handful of coins.
Widowed women
will try to gather what is left
of their husbands from these.
Countless mothers will be seen
trying to safeguard
the severed heads of their sons
from hungry swine and foxes
while crying bitterly.
When a crow or vulture
will pluck out the eyes
of a nearly dead soldier
the screams of wounded soldiers
will drive a stake
through everyone's heart.
This land will consume the
future of countless children.
Robbed of their fathers
children will cry silently
for the rest of their lives.
However,
one aged man
will mock their misery
and stand right here
bearing the sins of his life.
In this very Kurukshetra!
Because he deems
his life quite lovely.
In order to stay alive
at this age
is this the web of treachery
you are weaving Bhishma?
The Almighty is my witness,
Lady Amba.
I have never engaged
in any treachery in my life.
Neither for power nor property.
Neither for affection nor life.
It was not my proposal
to bar women
from taking part in the war.
And this was not
my decision either.
That is a lie!
You are deceitful.
You are wily and treacherous!
Did you forget the promise
you made to Lord Shiva, Bhishma?
I burnt myself in a pyre as Amba
and that fire is still burning
within Shikhandini
because of you, Devavrat.
Because of you!
My life
my wishes
my happiness and my dreams
were destroyed by you, Bhishma!
Just take a look around you.
Look, Bhishma!
Take a look around you!
This war was born
from the dejection of the woman
who has spent her entire life by
covering her eyes with a cloth
whether she says so
explicitly or not.
This war was born from
the anger of her brother
whether you believe it or not!
And you are responsible
for all this, Bhishma.
Yet you have such greed to live!
How do you gather the courage
to even look at your reflection
in the mirror,
Bhishma?!
Does it not kill you with shame?
That too is your misfortune,
Bhishma.
Until I confront you
you cannot die.
Lady Amba
you had said
that when fatigue will
weigh down even my soul
you will come to me.
I am experiencing
that fatigue today.
These crutches
these herbs
these pyres...
All this is a celebration
of death amidst life.
My soul is dying
to have liberation
but I am helpless,
Lady Amba.
Until you return as a man
you will not be able
to enter this battlefield.
I will indeed enter
this battlefield.
I will indeed have
my revenge, Bhishma!
In this very life!
In this very battlefield.
But before that, you must
experience your misfortune.
You will have to annihilate your
dynasty with your own hands.
Upon seeing the Kurus bleed
you will cry tears of blood.
Your misery is not yet over,
Bhishma.
Your heart will plead
to the Almighty for liberation.
Your weak soul will not be able
to bear the weight of your body.
Neither will your arms move
to greet someone
nor will your feet
allow you to march.
You will be rooted to the ground
and will be anxious to hear
the footsteps of death!
Await your liberation!
Await your death!
Await me!
'Two Days Before the War.'
Greetings, father.
Bless you.
In the darkness of life
thinking of you has always
illuminated the path to me.
But today...
Today, in order to dispel
the darkness within me
I require your light, father.
Only your duties can dispel
the darkness within you, dear.
While discharging your duties
if someone tries
to obstruct your path
then be cautious.
Do not fall for his deception.
With this hope, I have come
to seek charity from you, son.
That is not called charity,
My Lord.
That is the right
of every parent.
When someone has
the right to bless others
how can he ask
for something from me?
I ask for just one thing
as charity.
Henceforth, do not engage
in any more charity, son.
I have taken an oath,
father
that after offering you water
early in the morning
if one asks me for something
over which I have a right
then I indeed give it away.
A river that descends a mountain
never ascends it.
I too cannot break my oath,
father.
Besides, when you yourself
are protecting someone
how can anyone
ever deceive that person?
Do not forget that your enemies
are the blessings of other Gods.
And these Gods are hoping
for the victory
and success of their sons.
Very soon, for the benefit
of his son, Lord Indra
will come to you to ask
for your ear-rings and armour.
Very soon, for the benefit
of his son, Lord Indra
will come to you to ask
for your ear-rings and armour.
My armour and ear-rings!
- Yes, son.
These make you immortal
and denote
your divinity as well.
Without them,
the weapons of Arjun
will be able
to pierce your body.
But will the weapons of Arjun
be able to reach my body,
father?
If the statue of God
is sculpted from a rock
then it denotes
the divinity of the rock
and not its toughness.
My competence lies in my arms!
It lies in my archery, father!
For being concerned for my life
I shall always
be indebted to you.
However, to me
my oath is more important
than my life.
By slaying Arjun,
I will show the entire world
that competence is not born in a
specific dynasty, clan or sect.
Competence is born
in the soul of a human being.
If Lord Indra does not know this
and even his son
is more scared of my armour
than my archery
then I shall take my armour
and give it away willingly,
father.
I, Susharma,
King of Trigartha
pledge my weapons to you,
General Bhishma.
In this war,
my army and I
shall deem every order
of yours our duty.
If any of us
disobeys your orders
then may we meet with our doom.
Duryodhan
King Karna of Anga has not yet
pledged his loyalty to me.
Grandsire
all these warriors
are independent.
That is why,
they can
pledge their loyalty
to anyone they like.
Friend Karna says
that his loyalty lies with me.
That is why,
his loyalty
cannot lie with anyone else.
In the battlefield
the orders of a General
are paramount.
And every soldier
will have to pledge his loyalty
to the General.
Do not forget
that along with you
the responsibility of security
of all the Kings present here
is on me.
Tell your friend Karna
that before the war begins
he must pledge
his loyalty to me.
King Karna of Anga.
Greetings,
King of Gandhar.
Greetings.
You have to pledge your loyalty
to His Excellency Bhishma
tomorrow at dawn.
Is that
an order of the Crown Prince?
No.
It is the intransigence
of His Excellency Bhishma.
But for this war
the contentment of
His Excellency Bhishma
is quite important.
The freedom of my friend
and him fighting according
to my wishes
is more important to me,
uncle.
My darling
even an ordinary soldier knows
that a mightier warrior
than His Excellency Bhishma
does not exist
in the entire world.
Only because he is on our side
is our victory certain.
I have conquered numerous
regions, King of Gandhar.
When the time comes,
I will prove
that my competence
is not less than that of
His Excellency Bhishma.
In his conquests
friend Karna has defeated
numerous Kings, uncle.
Their soldiers have seen
how the armour of my friend
renders their weapons powerless.
More than the competence
of His Excellency Bhishma
I have
faith in the armour
of my friend, uncle.
Friend
the Pandavas and their army
can be defeated by me
even without my armour.
I know,
friend Karna
that your competence
does not lie in your armour
but in your armour
lies my protection.
Your armour has the power
to withstand even a Brahmastra.
If the Pandavas
attack me with a weapon
then this holy armour of yours
will protect me like a fort,
friend Karna.
Friend Karna
As long as you bear your armour
and stand before me
it is impossible to kill me.
This armour of yours makes
you invincible, friend.
However,
it makes me immortal.
Your holy armour is
undoubtedly important to you.
However,
it is
more important to me,
friend.
'Very soon, for the benefit
of his son, Lord Indra'
'will come to you to ask for
your ear-rings and armour.'