I must discharge my duties.
Then grandsire,
what is the solution?
May you live long.
There is only one solution,
dear.
Whoever takes sides
with the unrighteous
needs to be slain by you.
You need not ponder
why one is protecting
the unrighteous.
Just engage in the battle.
There is no other way now
to keep Hastinapur
safe from a battle.
If we do engage
in a battle, grandsire
then Panchali's father
will charge with his army too.
King Virat will also
take part in it.
Even the King of Gandhar
will charge with his army then.
The army of Anga
will also take part in it.
Eventually all the Kings
will take part in this battle.
In other words
it will become a war for the
entire Aryan region soon.
Millions of soldiers
will be killed
numerous women
will be left widowed
and the battlefield will
engulf the future of numerous
children in darkness grandsire.
There will be destruction
on a massive scale.
How can punishing the entire
Aryan region for our
personal insult be correct?
Had I deemed this
your personal insult
I would never have advised you
to engage in a battle.
Before sowing wheat
in the fields
the remainder of the old crops
need to be pulled out.
To establish righteousness
in the Aryan region once again
the old unrighteous ways
need to be annihilated.
Vasudev Krishna was correct.
A war is mandatory.
Vasudev had asked me
on which side I will be.
My weapons shall be
subservient to Hastinapur
but my blessings
will be for the five of you.
Go on.
Gather all the Kings
of the Aryan region
who are on your side.
Be prepared for the war.
Make your grandsire proud by
displaying unparalleled valour.
May you live long!
May you be victorious!
You let the Pandavas go,
grandsire.
Why were people
who attacked Hastinapur
not slain by you?
I had set about to protect
Hastinapur, dear
and that is precisely
what I did.
I do not attack the ones
who do not
take to arms before me.
The Pandavas have challenged
the Crown Prince of Hastinapur
to a battle.
Protecting me
is your duty,
grandsire.
And until I am alive
I shall keep discharging
that duty, Crown Prince.
However,
when I die
in the battlefield
you will have to face
your punishment.
How can you die,
grandsire?
You have been blessed
with the boon to die at will.
Do not forget
that they know
how to kill me, dear.
The day the daughter of Drupad
Shikhandini will stand before me
I will have to lay
my weapons down.
That day
all of you will have to
protect yourselves
and that day will arrive soon.
Very soon, the Pandavas
will attack with their army
and the...
And the competence
all of you take such pride in
will be put to the test as well
and that too very soon.
Indeed...
The advice to attack Hastinapur
must indeed
have been given by you,
Your Excellency Bhishma.
It is their right.
I have merely
given them my support.
In other words
you
decided on your own
to take the greatness
of Hastinapur
and destroy it,
Your Excellency Bhishma?!
If the Pandavas lose
then the prosperity
of the Kuru kingdom
will be destroyed
but even if they win
the Kuru kingdom
will be left impoverished.
Who will benefit
from this battle
Your Excellency Bhishma?
We are the unrighteous
but what about
your righteous ways?
You
broke a vow
renounced love
and betrayed the trust.
You have become the cause
of death of millions of people.
You have
tarnished life
and transformed death
into agony.
Your Excellency...
Your Excellency!
Let's go
my...
My
darlings.
For numerous years
I have hidden myself
from you, mother.
How could I face you
after being a part
of the shameful game of dice?
By standing in your waters
I have offered holy water
to Surya Dev in a manner
similar to a person
bearing a white cloth
and trying to clean
a piece of coal.
The cloth becomes dirty
but the coal
does not become clean.
I too have tarnished your name
in the game of dice, mother.
How can...
How can I attain
salvation from this dilemma?
On one hand, there were
the duties stemming from my oath
and on the other, my vow to walk
on the path of righteousness.
I have attempted to end
this dilemma today, mother.
But how could I have sown
the seed of a great war?
I have become the cause
of death of millions of people.
How can I
attain liberation
from this sin, mother?
How can I?
Son
you have attained liberation
from all your sins today.
Liberation?
How is that,
mother?
I could have averted this war
but in the greed to help
the Pandavas get justice
I have subjected
the entire Aryan region
to an exceedingly grave crisis.
How could you
have averted this war,
son Devavrat?
I could have
defeated the Pandavas.
I could have slain all of them,
mother
though that would indeed
have been a grave sin.
For all these years
my efforts to keep Duryodhan
away from the throne
would have gone in vain
but at least this war
would not have arisen, mother.
But why do you wish
to keep Duryodhan
away from
the throne, son?
Duryodhan deems the throne
a piece of property
and not a duty.
When he ascends the throne
he will unleash such a reign
of unrighteousness
that in the future
the subjects will experience
nothing but misery.
In other words, the future of
the subjects of the Aryan region
has been safeguarded
by you, son.
But what about the present?
I have filled the present
of the subjects with agony.
I can see
millions of dead people
floating on your waters.
Millions of people are scattered
in my waters in the form
of ashes every day
and it will continue to be so.
By averting a war
no one can become
immortal, son.
However,
in the future
establishing righteousness again
will become highly difficult.
In the life of man
he does not have a choice
between struggle and peace, son.
He has a choice
between less and more struggle.
This is the truth of life.
You may have
burdened the subjects with
the struggle of a great war, son
but you have curtailed
the struggles
of the forthcoming generations
today itself.
That is why, do not doubt
your decision, dear.
You have been liberated
from all your sins today.
Go on
and discharge
your duties in this war
and await
your salvation with joy.
Now, this battle has become
our duty, brother Yudhishthir.
The way a crazed horse
jumps off a cliff
along with the chariot
similarly even Duryodhan
is propelling the entire society
towards a war.
How can we stop him?
If we give up our greed
to have the empire
and decide to spend
our remaining lives in a forest
then the war can be averted.
Should we not punish them
for insulting Panchali then?
Should we allow Duryodhan to
commit more misdeeds, brother?
We are the sons of a King.
Despite living in a forest,
father had imparted to you
all the qualities
of being a good King.
How can we forsake
the society so?
But how can we
battle grandsire and Guru Drona
in the battlefield?
In both the armies
we have people who are related
to us in some way or the other.
How can we watch them die?
When grandsire had
asked us to take to arms
Arjun, you were
the first to say
that your arrows
can never be aimed at him!
Then how will you
pick up your bow?
But you never disobey
grandsire, My Lord
and even the order
to engage in this war
was his.
He cannot be dissuaded.
Just think of grandsire's
mental state, My Lord.
He must have turned his heart
to stone before asking you
to attack him.
What could have been
the reason, My Lord?
He saw his daughter-in-law
being disrobed in the court
and yet he said nothing.
The tie that had
rendered him speechless
must indeed have
given him great pain.
If he could, he would have burnt
all sinners with his mere eyes.
Can you imagine the dejection
he must have felt when his eyes
were flooded with tears?
He is not asking
for a war, My Lord.
He is asking for liberation.
Nevertheless
if all of you doubt
the decision of a war
then go to Dwaraka
and question Govind.
I have firm faith
that Govind will indeed be
on our side in the war.
Panchali is correct.
If Vasudev is willing
to take our side in this war
then we can indeed believe
that this war
is a righteous one.