The head that bows before others
has no right to bear a crown.
I cannot stand this
unrighteousness any longer!
King Dhritarashtra,
before an earthquake
the mere sound of its arrival
makes even the smallest
of birds shudder.
But even after hearing
of such unrighteousness
did your heart
not quiver even once?
The Almighty may not have
given you vision
but He certainly has
given you ears.
Unrighteousness!
What unrighteousness,
Great Guru Drona?
The rules of this game
were made in your presence.
Has anyone broken those rules?
King Dhritarashtra
you are indeed unable to see
the impending calamity.
Very soon, you will be
so grieved to be blind
which you would
have never felt before.
Leave this court at once,
Great Guru Drona
otherwise I shall take revenge
for this insult this instant!
Friend Duryodhan
now
you may bet me in the game.
I accept the right
you have on me
but I
have a request.
If you lose
then sentence me to death.
I cannot live the life
of a servant!
What are you saying,
son?
Father
I am standing by my friend.
Duryodhan my friend,
you may bet me in the game!
I bet my friend Ashwatthama
in the game.
He is like
a brother to me.
Great Guru Drona
you have been ordered
to leave this court
by His Highness.
As my son has been
bet in this game
I cannot leave this place.
Then you may certainly grace
this court, Great Guru Drona.
I too shall forget
how I was insulted
but you must promise me
that henceforth
you will never leave
the court of Hastinapur.
Promise me!
I promise you.
Then do be seated, Guru Drona.
Be seated.
Now, if the Emperor wishes
then he may bet
another brother of his.
Brother...
The opportunity
to get sacrificed first
was snatched by Nakul from me.
This time,
I shall bet myself.
No, brother Arjun.
It is crucial for brother Bheem
and you to stay independent.
Please try to understand
this foreboding feeling
that I have.
I fear that
something gravely unrighteous
will happen in this court today.
Please stop that.
May the Emperor have happiness!
Do play, Your Highness.
Do play.
King Ashwatthama of Kampilya
has been bet this time
and your younger brother,
the son of Lady Madri, Sahadev
needs to be bet by you.
This is not a game
but a revenge for something.
Sister-in-law
if you have an iota of shame
a sense of pride in your dynasty
or even an iota of righteousness
within yourself
then stop this game
this instant!
I...
I am merely an embankment
made of sand, Kunti.
Today, the unrighteousness
of Duryodhan
has assumed the form of a flood.
I will crumble
but will not be able
to stop this flood.
You are bound to crumble,
Your Highness.
The day your sons will be
punished for this treachery
you will indeed crumble.
I am the Empress
of the entire Aryan region.
The order to stop this game
shall be given by me.
Gatekeeper
the rules of the game
are very clear.
Women of royalty
are not allowed in this court!
Crown Prince Duryodhan
no order is a constraint
for an Empress.
Stop this game,
Your Highness.
This gathering is unrighteous!
This game is unrighteous!
Do not play this game.
Get up, Your Highness.
That is not possible,
Your Highness.
You have agreed
to play this game.
You are bound by your word.
Break that promise!
When an ironsmith gets entangled
in the chains while making them
he ends up breaking them,
Your Highness.
An iron chain is not
considered an ornament.
When the Gandiva Bow
of Prince Arjun is on your side
and even the mace
of Vrikodar Bheem
who are you afraid of then?
Dear Yudhishthir
lest you lose your throne
I had
come up with these rules
but now,
these very rules
have resulted in these
repercussions.
Get up, dear.
Get up, dear Yudhishthir.
Get up.
Panchali is correct,
brother Yudhishthir.
Do get up.
Just give me the order!
I shall free Nakul this instant!
May the Emperor have happiness!
Your Highness, despite being
a guest in my court
you will attack me?
Are you willing to challenge
my competence?
Bheem
it is my duty
to honour my promises.
I cannot order you
to resort to arms here.
That is your duty as a person,
brother Yudhishthir
and we respect it
but as the Emperor,
you have another duty
towards the Aryan region
and all the Kings who
have accepted your reign.
How will you
carry out that duty?
Arjun
it is your duty to obey the
orders of your elder brother.
You might as well
disregard that duty.
Just say that you disobey the
orders of your elder brother.
Nakul
why are you kneeling down there?
Your elder brother
is playing this game.
Why should you
accept its result?
Just say no.
None of you can give up
your righteous ways.
Do play,
Your Highness.
Do play.
I have bet Ashwatthama
and you need to bet Sahadev.
Your Highness
you had said that you
would lose your property
your empire
and even your throne
but you have lost
my husband instead.
Is this what you call
righteousness?
Do play, Your Highness.
Do play.
Stop!
It is a rule
that in the presence
of women of royalty
this game shall not be played.
I shall stay right here.
May the Empress have happiness!
Your Highness,
I request you
to leave this court.
Apart from my husbands
I am not bound to take orders
from anyone else
King Dhritarashtra.
Splendid.
Splendid,
Your Highness.
Splendid.
Your Highness, do you wish to
seek the refuge of the Empress
to break your promise?
Splendid!
If the foot of a person
climbing up a mountain slips
he ends up straight
in the trench.
To a righteous person
even the smallest
of an unrighteous deed
can make him fall
in the trench of sins.
Now, you should
order the Empress
to leave this court
otherwise
we shall leave.
My darling
let's go.
We must end this game.
My darling
let's go!
Stop,
brother Duryodhan.
Panchali
leave this court.
Dear Draupadi...
Dear Draupadi,
what happened?
What happened in the court?
Leave!
It is my order
for the both of you to leave.
I require some solitude.
And no one will go to the court!
My husband is engaged in
honouring righteousness there.