They...
They were talking about
the Pandava's mother?
Duryodhan must surely
be conspiring to have
the Pandav brothers and their
mother killed at Varnavat.
I must speak to
Grandsire Bheeshma about this.
Why did you have to
wake me up, brother?
You will be eating alone.
Nakul, I'll share
the food with you.
But first, help me
locate the kitchen!
Years ago, an attendant
had told us the way.
Use your sense of smell.
My senses had failed me and
that's why I woke you up.
There's no aroma of food
emanating from anywhere
in the entire palace.
Come.
Let's find the kitchen.
Guard!
Nakul, don't raise your voice!
Everybody will wake up!
The guard is supposed
to stay awake.
Greetings, Prince!
Guard, show my brother
the way to the kitchen.
Prince, the kitchen is
located outside the palace.
You mean, this huge palace
doesn't have a kitchen?
Forgive me, Prince Bheem!
I wasn't aware that you have
your dinner, late in the night.
From tomorrow,
this maid will stand outside
your chamber, holding a
plate full of delicacies.
Please step forward!
But why did you not construct a
kitchen in such a huge palace?
The maids preparing the food
should remain outside the palace
so that you and the queen
are not inconvenienced
that's why, Prince.
But it's very inconvenient
for me.
Get a kitchen made in
the palace.
But, Prince Bheem...
- Why do you stutter?
Will the palace go up in
flames if food is prepared here?
What are you afraid of?
No, Prince Bheem.
Why would I be afraid?
And why would the
palace go up in flames?
Follow my dictum!
As you wish, Prince!
'This is rather astonishing!'
'Such a huge palace
has no dining room!'
'If you pronounce Yudhistir as
the crown prince in court
'tomorrow, I will not care
about the reputation'
'and dignity of Hastinapur.'
'Very soon'
'you will be rid of
your worries, Bheem!'
Leave us alone!
You called for me, father?
Why is Purochan at Varnavat?
Have you made Purochan
construct a new palace?
Indeed!
My dear brothers will
be staying at Varnavat.
Therefore, I had to get a
palace constructed.
This means you are responsible
for their journey to Varnavat.
Tell me the truth!
Why do you seem
so stressed, father?
Why am I stressed?
I am worried because I am afraid
that you must have planned
something at Varnavat which
would be totally unscrupulous!
Unscrupulous!
Father, there's no morality
in anything immoral.
If a drop of poison is
put in milk
the milk becomes
contaminated, father.
When I had poisoned Bheem
you knew then that it's immoral.
But it didn't trouble you
all that much, father.
Yes, I wasn't troubled
back then.
A powerful man wishes
for more power!
Someone with moderate
income wishes for wealth.
But in old age.
In his old age when he knows
that he will die soon
then a desire for fame,
glory and honour
are what he yearns for.
The body doesn't last
but one can at least
hope that their name lasts
until the end of time.
My son.
Please don't engage in
activities which might malign
My image posthumously!
I know that you are the
epitome of righteousness.
Whenever a choice has to
be made between my happiness
and your righteousness
I am the one
who suffers injustice!
That's the reason
behind me not disclosing
My Plan to you!
Son!
Please listen to me.
During acquisition of kingdoms
warriors do die but...
Murdering a woman
is disgraceful, son.
If anything happens to Kunti,
what do I answer Pandu
in the netherworld
past my death, son?
What do I answer him?
Father.
When a flame burns, it's
not just the fuel that burns
but the wick too.
One who bothers about the wick,
cannot obtain light.
But you have never lit a lamp
in your entire life.
Perhaps that is why
you are unaware of this fact.
In Varnavrat, even the memories
of uncle's family shall burn.
This is my decision.
Go inform His Highness
that the prime minister needs to
discuss an important matter.
Pardon me, Sire.
His Highness Bheeshma
is in the playground.
He is examining the new
recruits in the army.
Soldiers, if the enemy surrounds
you from three directions
and leaves you
no way to escape
then retreat backwards,
feigning defeat.
This makes the enemy carefree
and he lets his guard down.
Then, seize your
opportunity and...
Attack!
In battle, it isn't strength
that is important
it's the timing.
What is the reason
for your smile, Vidur?
It's surprise, Grandsire!
Greetings!
- Bless you!
They say that a 'Gandharv'* may sing all his life
*A community associated with singing and dancing to entertain the gods.
yet he never sings
the same tune twice.
He brings forth something new
every moment.
Even you teach me something new
every day, Grandsire.
I had taught you this strategy
in your childhood, Vidur.
Yes you had, Grandsire.
But then, I hadn't been able
to understand the fact
that in battle, timing is more
important than strength.
Waiting for the right moment
isn't defeat
but it's strategic instead.
I shall take leave,
Grandsire.
Bless you!
Vidur!
Were you here for a purpose?
- Yes.
And that purpose
has been served, Grandsire.
When one learns what he
wants to, he is happy.
And when one learns what is
worth learning
then he attains bliss,
Grandsire.
Greetings, Grandsire!
Greetings, Sire.
Have this sack of grains sent
to Varnavrat immediately.
Any message along with that,
minister?
Yes.
Just tell them
that when a single grain
is sowed into the soil
it yields many more.
Nakul.
Which damsel awaits you
at Varnavrat
that you are grooming
yourself so much?
I have heard that just the royal
maids are present in forests.
Not the princesses.
In fact, I suggest that you look
into the mirror too, brother.
Have you ever thought
what would happen
if an ogress falls in love
with you?
Nakul.
- Bheem!
Mother is waiting.
We should get going.
Mother!
It's time for the veneration!
But Arjun isn't here yet.
Let us wait a while for him.
Arjun will be here soon, mother.
Let us begin the veneration.
Long live the sons of Pandu!
- Long live the sons of Pandu!
Glory to King Pandu!
- Glory to King Pandu!
Glory to King pandu!
- Glory to King pandu!
Long live the sons of Pandu!
Greetings, princes!
Greetings, queen!
Princes, the minister has
sent you all a present.
'Why has uncle
sent a gift here?'