'I'll give you whatever
you desire.'
'Till I don't give
you the guru-donation'
'I will not use the skills
I derived from you.'
'As a guru-donation'
'you will give me
the thumb of your right hand.'
Here, I have brought
a gift for you.
Just check.
You will be very pleased.
Are you happy?
Is your soul at peace
having an innocent's
thumb chopped off?
What do you mean?
- What do I mean?
Go and ask the master
who to make you an expert archer
asked Ekalavya for his
thumb as an offering.
So that better archers than you
can't even fire arrows now.
What are you saying,
brother Duryodhan?
You should be ashamed of making
allegations at the master.
You should be the one
to be ashamed.
To prove your superiority
you make one suffer thus?
Has your recluse of a father
taught you such strategies?
Take a look at
the chopped thumb.
Someone's dreams
lie destroyed.
His future has been chopped off
just because of you!
Along with that your
righteousness
and your respect has been
laid to waste too.
Arjun, dew drops can't
fill up a reservoir.
Superiority attained in
charity has no value.
Had I been in your stead
I would have taken an oath
to never touch the bow.
Right now!
You can ask me anything.
Aren't you confident
about me, master?
Can't I become the best
archer through practice?
What concerns me is how much
you believe in your master.
Have you assumed that
to make you superior
I am being impartial to my
other students?
The clouds shower more
rains on the forests
and less on the deserts.
But a master's knowledge
is never biased.
So the master is termed
superior to the clouds.
Then why such an offering
from Ekalavya?
What offering should a master
ask from his students
can be rightfully decided
only by a master.
But, master, why ask for an
offering which is a disgrace?
I know
that the sons of Dhritarashtra
would accuse me of being biased.
Not only them
the future generations would
also accuse me of being biased.
Arjun, I was helpless
before my duty.
Ekalavya would have used my
knowledge for Magadha
which is an enemy of
the Kuru dynasty.
Can the boundaries of a kingdom
control knowledge, master?
No.
But the master delivering
the knowledge
is bounded by his oath
and his promises.
My mouth eats the grains
given by the Kuru kingdom.
So my loyalty is only towards
the throne of Hastinapur.
Had Ekalavya attained knowledge
from another master
and become a better
archer than you
I would have been pleased.
But...
But the allegations
made on you...
How would they
be cleared, master?
There is one solution, dear.
You should prove undisputedly
that you are the best.
Why just Ekalavya?
Even Bhishma can't be
a better archer than you.
Prove it, dear.
Prove it.
If you do that
I will get rid of
the allegations.
Ashwatthama, my friend.
We are here to seek
your permission.
Permission?
We, the sons of Dhritarashtra,
are leaving the seminary.
We were fortunate to find a
friend like you at the seminary.
But we are sure
we will not attain anything
more than this here.
Moreover
can you attain anything
when Arjun is here?
I have my doubts on that.
What is the matter son?
You look a bit ill.
Father, I want the weapon
created by Brahma.
Today.
Lord Brahma's weapon?
Son, to attain the weapon, you
have to prove your credentials.
Isn't being your son
enough?
Before you give Brahma's
weapon to Arjun
I want it, father.
Son, I haven't taught Arjun
about Brahma's weapon yet.
You are already teaching
him the mantras.
Why are you so partial to Arjun?
Thanks to the partiality
the sons of Dhritarashtra are
quitting the seminary today.
Due to the partiality,
the seminary will be shut soon.
Your son is displeased
with the partiality.
If water stored
in a pot smells foul
then surely someone has
dirtied it.
If you are displeased,
I am sure
you are being supported
by ineligible people.
But still
I have to clear the doubts in
the minds of your friends.
Because I can never see you
hurt and displeased ever.
Never.
Go tell the sons of
Dhritarashtra
Dronacharya will
take a bath in the river
and take an oath to
be unbiased.
Everyone should assemble
at the river bank.
Father! - Master!
- Master!
Master!
- Dushashan!
Go bring my weapon Dushashan!
So?
Do all of you wish to
quit the seminary?
You can surely go.
You have my permissions.
But remember
to collect more water
from a stream
one needs a bigger vessel.
And to attain more knowledge
from a master
one needs to have
a broader mind.
A fertile mind is attained
only with dedication.
If you leave from here today
you will surely be very
less eligible.
And if you stay back
it is possible
that you may develop a
better mind to learn more.
The decision is up to you.
Arjun is the best student
of the seminary.
So he will become
the best archer of the world.
All the students attaining
knowledge from a master
do not attain the same
kind of knowledge.
All students are seen
listening to the master
they are seen worshipping him
but can't attain the same
kind of knowledge.
Have you ever thought as to why
does that happen?
The truth is
that the students who do
not attain knowledge
try to exhibit dedication
but they do not understand
the real meaning of dedication.
By offering flowers on
a master's feet
or by following the
master's orders
is dedication
actually proven?
No.
Dedication
is achieved indeed when
one has no doubts about
the master.
A student should finish the task
even before a master instructs.
A student and a
master should think alike.
Until a student doesn't
see the forms of Lord Brahma, Vishnu and Mahesh*
*One of the many names of Shiva.
within their master
until then his dedication
isn't true.
In reality, dedication
isn't a task.
Dedication is the feeling
of our heart
and a state of mind.
In other words...
Isn't our ignorance
only because our mind
is at fault?
Think about it.