The son you are about to beget
would inherently possess
my energy and resplendence.
Son?
'I, Sage Durvasa, grant
you a mantra'
'by which you can invoke
any demigod'
'and summon him to you.'
'You would be able to beget
a son as glorious as him.'
But, Lord... I...
I haven't been married yet.
How can I beget a son?
Then why did you
invoke me, Kunti?
I committed a folly, Lord.
The consequences of the folly
will be borne by you, Kunti.
You will surely beget a son.
Sage Durvasa's curse
has no remedy
and neither can his boon
be any less bountiful.
As soon as I disappear,
a portion of my energy
will stay back with you
in the form of a baby.
I can't stop it from
happening, Kunti.
But what is my father's fault
in this, Lord?
He would be equally defamed.
It would be widely known
that King Kuntibhoj's
daughter's character
is unchaste.
On top of that,
it would also be said
that if a Princess
could beget a son
before being married
then everyone else could.
No one would believe
that it was all due to a boon.
I understand
your quandary, Kunti.
This son of yours
is a result of a boon.
I also give you another boon
that even after giving birth
to a son
you will stay a maiden.
Your character will
remain pure and pious.
Accept this boon earnestly.
Surya dev so gaye chhaya andhera
(Lord of the sun has slept, and shades are darkened)
Chup chaap ye gagan so gayi hain dhara
(Slowly the heaven sleeps, and earth as well)
Tu bhi so jaa laal mere
(You are asleep as well, my child)
Kehana na maa ka tu taal re
(Don't let your mother words' go by)
So jaa mere laal re
(Sleep, my light)
(Sleep, my child)
Hmm…hmm...laa...laa...
Tu hriday ka mere, tukraa hai
(You are part of my heart)
Mere naina ka hai tu taara...
(and star in my eyes)
Meri bhul kshama kr laal mere
(Forgive my fault)
Mera pyaar, tu mera dulaara..
(My dear, you are my child)
Godi meri, mamtaa tarpe
(in my lap, my love has died)
Maa bhi baas hai laachaari ha
(nothing left but helplessness)
So jaa mere laal re
(Sleep, my light)
(Sleep, my child)
Surya dev so gaye chhaya andhera
(Lord of the sun has slept, and shades are darkened)
Chup chaap ye gagan so gayi hain dhara
(Slowly the heaven sleeps, and earth as well)
So jaa mere laal re
(Sleep, my light)
(Sleep, my child)
Please forgive me, son.
I'm helpless.
Due to my selfish reasons
I can't let my father
be ridiculed by all.
Please forgive me!
Lord Surya
please protect your son.
Don't worry about my son, Kunti.
He is in my sanctuary now.
I have provided him with
a divine armour and earrings.
No power in the universe
can pierce this armour of his.
The gilded sheen of his earrings
will shatter the darkness of his
life and be a guiding beacon.
My son will be
indomitable, Kunti.
He will be known all over
the world as Karna!
Karna!
My son!
My son...
No!
It's best to forget
the past, Princess.
Reminiscing the past
will cause dark clouds akin to
these to loom over your life.
Shall I forget?
How do I just forget,
Priyamvada?
Forsaking one's progeny
doesn't make him the past.
My son...
My son still lives
somewhere.
And till the time he draws
breath
he is my present.
But keeping this matter
a secret is best, Princess.
But from whom?
From the one who
would be my husband?
No, Priyamvada.
Just like flowing water
can't serve as a founding stone
in the very same way
life can't subsist on lies.
But, Princess
after knowing of this truth,
who will agree to marry you?
There must be someone...
There must be someone
for whom
my identity
isn't defined by my folly.
There must be someone
who will
accept me
along with my past.
There must be someone.
Greetings, sister-in-law.
You are welcome,
Your Highness!
You weren't disturbed, were you?
Before setting out for
the task at Kuntibhoj
I have come to
seek your blessings.
May you always be victorious,
Your Highness.
May your fame and glory
have no limits.
May you be successful
in every endeavour.
Can't you address me
just as Pandu, sister-in-law?
Addressing a king by his name
is a crime, Your Highness.
But the term 'Your Highness'
coming from you
pierces me like
a thousand thorns!
My heart brims over
with a feeling of guilt!
This throne belonged
to elder brother
and it is...
- No!
Had the throne been
your brother's
it'd have been his.
Since it wasn't so, it clearly
means, the throne is yours.
That was destiny.
Now, you have to become
worthy of the throne.
You had come here to become
the Empress and... - No!
I had come here to become
the wife of your elder brother
and that I am.
Had I come to become
the Empress
I would have married
the throne itself.
How can you be so benevolent?
Because a sister-in-law is
tantamount to a mother
Your Highness.
A mother has just one desire.
That her son
should get everything.
That he should achieve
all the pleasures of the world.
I feel, as if not just a 100
but I have the boon
to have 102 sons.
Promise me, sister-in-law
that when I am seated
on the throne
then and only at that time
would you address me
as 'Your Highness'.
Else, you'd consider me a son
and call me by my name.
Then not just you
but I would call your wife
by her name too.
Now, make haste to
reach Kuntibhoj
and get me my sister-in-law.
I have not laid eyes on you
but I can affirm that no
beautiful damsel of the world
would ever refuse
to be your wife.
Your blessings adorn my luck
which is why I feel confident
but without seeking
brother's blessings
I never start on any task.
This blessing is also on
his behalf, Pandu.
His heart is still
in a state of turmoil.
But he still loves you
as much as he used to.
I believe that, sister-in-law.
My adoration for him
is still the same.
I promise you
my wife and I
would always serve
you and elder brother
till the very end of our lives.
May you be victorious!
My respects to you,
sister-in-law.
My respects too.
The kings and princes
of the Arya region
by gracing the 'swayamvar' of
my daughter Kunti
you have indeed added
to my honour.
It has been the grand
tradition of the Arya region
that a maiden
is given the paramount right
to select her husband.
I request
that the decision
of my daughter Kunti
be heartily accepted by you
regardless of your being
enemies or allies.
You would offer the newlyweds
your blessings
and best wishes.
Come, daughter.
Today, I would
introduce you not to kings
as today, you would
be choosing your fate.
Father, before taking a decision
I would like to ask a question
to all the young men here.
My decision
will be based on the answer
to the same.
Only if you permit me.
- Sure.
In a 'swayamvar',
every maiden
has the right to ask questions
to the kings.
Attending kings and princes
my daughter wishes to clarify
a doubt she has.
The one whose answer
will be deemed most fit by her
will become
my daughter's husband.
I hope no one has any objection.
Prince Ashwakumar may have one,
Your Highness!
Whenever a question about
intelligence crops up
the princes of the Ashwa clan
aren't in the same league as us.
Please don't overstep the maxims
laid out for a 'swayamvar'.
A test of strength isn't
displayed at a court
but in battle.
Who are you?
- I am Hastinapur's Emperor
a son of the Kuru clan...
Pandu.
I beseech you both
to please return to your seats.
I request you to ask
your question.
My question goes thus...
Sage Gautam's wife Ahilya
had had a conjugal relationship
with Lord Indra.
Sage Gautam had punished
his wife.
Then why did Lord Ram
free Ahilya from the same?
By forgiving her mistake,
didn't Lord Ram
set the wrong example
for generations to follow?
The answer to this
is very simple.
The Lord is known
as The Benevolent One.
He can forgive
any sinner.
Then why weren't Bali
and Ravan forgiven?
That's discrimination.
Then why don't you answer
the same?
The answer is...
Every punishment has
its extremes.
Perhaps the Lord
would have felt
that it was time
Ahilya was freed.
But as per me,
the petrified Ahilya
would have repented
for her sins.
No!
The truth is that Lord Indra
had appeared before Ahilya
in the guise
of Sage Gautam.
The conjugal relationship
Ahilya established
was only due to the knowledge
that she was with her husband.
Sage Gautam had cursed
her in a fit of rage
but Lord Ram
was a king.
And a king, before
announcing a sentence
has to mandatorily know
if the punishable deed
is a crime or a folly.
If the intentions aren't wrong
or the nous is pure
repentance and atonement
alone suffice.
There's no need for punishment.
Thinking the same
Lord Ram must have
forgiven Ahilya.