Are you a Knight or
a coward?
Bheem, be prepared to die.
Those who do not fear death is
true knight, you're stupid.
Think of your sins and ask
forgiveness to God.
You never do good in this life.
Perhaps you will be reborn...
May you...be better
in the next life.
Bheem!
Dusshasan, in a duel between
mature Knights...
Immatured knight should
not interfere.
Keep stalling any longer, friend.
Brother Bheem is not yet winning.
Get up, Duryodhan!
Come on, get up!
Quickly, Duryodhan!
Give up Yudhishthir.
I can not give myself
to you, Grandsire.
But in this duel I will try
to beat you.
Yudhishthir I do not want
to kill you.
Give up,
and I will take you to Duryodhan.
It will end this war,
my son.
Is Duryodhan to stay alive
to see it, Grandsire?
This is why I hate this war,
brother Bheem.
To crush you under my feet.
Come on, get up!
Why are you lying on the ground like
a tail insect, brother Bheem.
Get up, if you have the courage.
Come on, get up!
Hit me.
Get up.
Your enemy's right in front of you.
Get up!
Get up, brother Bheem.
Get up.
Come on, brother Bheem.
Brother Bheem!
Get up!
You are our pride.
Get up, brother Bheem.
Heeyah!
Mark and remember my vow,
Duryodhan!
You ordered to undress Draupadi.
First I will pull your tongue and then
crush your head.
It's impossible.
It's not possible, brother Bheem.
I am the Crown Prince.
King of Hastinapur, Dhristarasta's
not here.
So I'm in power here.
The right to imprison and kill me is only in the hands of your brother Yudhishthir.
You're stupid, Duryodhan.
Didn't you get authority over the kingdom in uncle's absence.
Then I had authority over the kingdom in my brother's absence as well.
And as the Crown Prince I have
the right to punish you.
This is why Vasudev told brother
to head to Hastinapur.
So you will not get
Grandfather's protection.
Yeah!
'Come on, let's get intimate.'
'Come here, servant Draupadi.'
'Sit on my lap.'
'Dusshasan, remove the clothes.'
Prince Bheem!
Your king is in my hands.
And without his permission you can't
attack Prince Duryodhan.
Ha...ha...ha...
And if he ordered you to
kill Prince Duryodhan,
I'm going to kill him.
Bheem!
If I die, the war will end today.
Kill Duryodhan,
and let Grandsire kills me.
To restore peace in Aryavrat, I'm ready to sacrifice my life.
Strike, Bheem!
The sun will set soon!
My dear!
Sanjay...
Sanjay, why are you silent?
What happened to my son?
What is going on with Duryodhan?
Quick, tell me!
Majesty,
Bheem has assaulted Prince Duryodhan
with his mace.
He attacked Duryodhan!
King Yudhishthir is under threat of
his excellency Bhishma's spear.
Brother Bheem, to win you must
have more eagerness.
Unless you can let go of your attachment.
Your duty, your brothers and
also your family,
You will remain bound to them, and victory will always be away from you.
And attachment will only bring
defeat, brother Bheem.
Just defeat.
My duty, my brothers,
and my family is my courage,
Duryodhan.
And the day when you have to
face my courage again...
It will be your last day,
Duryodhan!
Your last day!
It will soon arrive!
The war is over for today,
Majesty.
Pandavas had won the war today, Majesty.
But...
uncle did not let their
victory complete.
He saved my son Duryodhan from Bheem.
Wait and see, Sanjay!
Until uncle in charge in the battleground,
sons of Pandu will not win.
Sons of Pandu's victory is very unlikely.
Our victory today is priceless,
Emperor Yudhishthir.
Our army courage and spirit
have increased manifold.
Now they believe that under
your leadership,
and Vasudev Krishna
we are surely will win.
We achieve victory today.
But Grandsire experience
have beaten us.
No.
Brother Yudhishthir did not fight
with all his might.
However, Madhav.
Grandsire has a boon to die
as he wishes.
It is impossible to kill him.
He probably got the boon but it doesn't
have to be at his will.
It is possible to severely hurt him.
That will cause him can't
continue this war, friend.
It is also not possible, Vasudev.
Grandsire is the epitome of chastity.
We will not be able
to attack him.
Nobody's that holy, brother Bheem.
Neither the acacia tree nor
the sandalwood.
When dried, they are ready to burn.
It is a law of nature.
Anyone who tread the road of
Kaurava's punishment,
must still be destroyed.