This is
a different circumstances.
How does the current situation
any different, mother?
Sons,
King of Anga...
Karna, King of Anga...
Karna, King of Anga has
showed the largest examples
involved in charity.
He gave away
part of his own body as a charity.
He gave away his shield as a charity.
As a warrior he is worthy to die on
the battlefield
and not in the camp of treatment.
Moreover, a better chance to slay him
now rest with Arjun.
If King of Anga die for what
he thinks is right
then he will not be punished for
his improper conduct,
Nakula.
Mother's right.
Nakul, Sahadev
you two have to go to the rescue
King of Anga life's.
But brother Yudhishthir
we also need to go to welcome
uncle Shalya.
This is more important,
Sahadev.
King of Madra
will be welcomed in Kurukshetra by me.
Greetings, King Shalya.
Who had set up camp in the middle
of the road?
Who holds such important
that the road to the main camp has
been hampered?!
In order to welcome you, we do not
just block the road
but also holds our breath, Your Majesty.
And in this war
if you help us by agreeing to fight
for our side
it will be like the help of Lord
Shiva himself
Majesty.
This way, Majesty.
Where are my nephews,
Nakul and Sahadev?
All hail King Shalya!
Majesty, all the princes are busy
preparing for war.
They are here at Kurukshetra.
They may not have time.
Your Majesty, we are here
to welcome you.
The king is here?
Where is he?
- He's in the camp.
He has been waiting for you,
Majesty.
This way, Majesty.
All hail King Shalya!
Son!
Prince Nakula,
Prince Sahadev,
I bow before your knowledge.
Our holy herbs can not cure our
enemies more than this.
We will soon be venerating your corpse
Karna, King of Anga.
Mother,
let's go.
We must proceed towards our camp.
No, sons.
Until I live
I stayed in the camp of
Hastinapur, sons.
Mother,
if you stay with the enemy
you may then live in danger during
the war.
It is not right to trust the enemy
under any circumstances.
Do not worry, Prince Sahadev.
Just like a son
I will protect your mother.
Mother,
before the war's started, we will come
to seek your blessings.
Let us go, Nakula.
Uncle Shalya must have arrived.
Uncle!
Uncle,
this is not our camp.
This camp belongs to our enemy.
I'm sorry, my dear nephews
but now, even I is an enemy to you.
This evil man
son of Dhritarashtra is just a wily fox who
have deceived me!
He made me to promise to help them,
dear nephews.
Making you promise!
But why did you make a promise
like that, uncle?!
What situation could it be
that you make a promise like that?!
I thought King Yudhishthira was welcoming me
and their praises left me blind.
Unknowingly
I promise to give them my help.
I was bound by my promise,
dear nephews.
And now, I have to fight along with
these evil people!
All around the world a brother
assume their sibling's children
equivalent to hundreds of 'Brahmin!'
Then how can you leave
your sister's children, uncle?
For me, the two of you more than
my own children.
Sahadev,
Nakula,
my prayers will always be with
the Pandavas.
But I am helpless in this case.
That wicked Duryodhana
has shown that low values
are part of himself!
His blind father
only worthy for
begging outside the temple!
And these are the values given
by their mother
to these devils!
His blind father
only worthy for
begging outside the temple!
And these are the values given
by their mother
to these devils!
King Shalya!
- My dear!
Stay within your limits!
Calm, my dear.
Relax.
King Shalya
using derogatory words like that
for my brother-in-law and sister
is unlike people like you.
Are you angry, Shakuni?!
You deceitful man!
Come forward
and let us have a duel here!
No, King of Madra.
I'm not your lover
that your sour words
would hurt my heart.
There will be a duel...
You will be involved in a duel
with your two nephews
on the battlefield.
I am going to have a duel with you!
And I will slay you, uncle Shalya.
I will kill you for this betrayal.
And uncle Shakuni
this scam must be yours.
So remember this oath,
you will be killed in this war!
And it will be in my hand!
Let's go, Nakul!
Whether King of Madra will be
punished or not
is not an important thing, Nakula.
At this time
we can not get angry or
think about revenge.
We only have seven 'akshauhini' army
while they have eleven
great 'akshauhini' army!
This problem is more important.
We must have someone who can help
in the beginning.
Grandsire Bhisma
Guru Drona
King of Anga
Crown Prince Duryodhana
Susharma
and now
even the King of Madra.
When all of these soldiers
wreak havoc on our troops
that our soldiers' Maharathis
will be completely absorbed in
protecting our troops.
We will not even get a chance to
attack.
If you all
remove yourself from the attachment
anger and fear
and fight with all your heart
for the establishment of truth
then, have faith that
our army will stand without
we even notice it.
The strength of a maharathi
rest in his heart
and not in the strength of his army.
In order to win in this war
praying for the death of
his excellency Bhisma
is your duty.
In order to win in this war
praying for the death of
his excellency Bhisma
is your duty.
His excellency's death?
But...
- But what, friend?
His excellency is Kaurava
army general.
Protecting the Crown Prince
Duryodhana of Hastinapura
is an oath he had taken.
Until he continues to fight
in this war
our victory is impossible.
You have taken an oath to
establish truth,
and sacrifice
is the primary basis of truth.
And more important than life
is sacrificing it.
And sacrifice of love and
affection
which seems to be more important
than life itself
is very important.