Tonight,
the Pandavas
will slay Kichak.
I am awaiting
the sound of the duel
between Bheem and Kichak
to reach my ears.
Then we shall leave immediately
and render the life of anonymity
of the Pandavas
futile.
Let's go,
Princess.
I shall give you a lesson in the Rudra Tandava* tonight.
*Divine Shiva dance which depicts his violent nature, first as the creator and later as the destroyer of the universe, even of death itself.
At this hour?
Yes, Princess.
The appropriate time
to assume the Rudra form
is tonight and at this hour.
Soldiers,
stay right here
and do remember
that no one is allowed
inside this chamber.
Why is the chamber
so dark, Sairandhri?
What are you up to?
If you think your husbands
will kill me
right here in this chamber
then you are making
a very big mistake.
Let me
illuminate the chamber.
In order to have light
one must endure
the heat of fire, Kichak.
In order to get rid of
the darkness in your mind
you too must burn.
You are foolish.
This is neither Panchal
nor Hastinapur
but the kingdom of Matsya
and the courage to kill me
resides within no one here.
Bheem?
You could recognize Panchali
but not me?!
Do you wish to engage in a duel?
Do not be foolish,
Bheem.
If you are defeated
then you will be killed.
However,
if I get defeated
then all of you will have to
go on an exile for twelve years
Yet again.
It would be better
if you seek my refuge
and leave Draupadi
here with me.
Even if it is stuck in the mud
an elephant is still
a majestic being, Kichak!
Neither can hundred dogs
provide it with protection
nor can they harm it.
And I am not stuck
anywhere either.
I am utterly free
to punish you!
I will have to call out
to Duryodhan just once
and he shall
be here immediately.
Only when your voice
leaves this chamber
will Duryodhan be able
to hear you, fool!
That is the sound
of Brihannala's feet.
The rhythm of Tandava
will spell out your doom.
Those are the horses
of Damgranthi.
Listen carefully!
Their neigh is ushering
your death at lightning speed.
Those are the cows of Tantripal.
They are announcing
your punishment!
Listen!
You cannot leave
this place, Kichak.
Then how will you send
a message to Duryodhan?
Do you hear that,
my darling?!
Who could be making
such sounds at this hour?
They are indeed the Pandavas!
The Pandavas?
Why would the Pandavas produce
such sounds at this hour, uncle?
So that we fail to hear
Kichak's screams
while they kill him.
Let's go,
my darling.
We must save Kichak.
After killing Kichak
if the Pandavas hide themselves
then we will never
be able to find them.
If we apprehend the Pandavas now
then we will succeed
in our cause.
Let's go,
uncle.
Let's go.
General Kichak got slain...
Whoever committed this heinous
act will certainly be punished.
King Virat
go and apprehend
the Pandavas then.
General Kichak was slain
by the Pandavas.
The Pandavas are not present
in the city of Virat.
They are not present
in the kingdom of Matsya either.
By uttering such rubbish
do not attempt to spread
fear in the city, Crown Prince.
King Virat
General Kichak
was on to the Pandavas.
The coming morning at dawn
all the immigrants and guests
were to produce themselves
in the court on Kichak's orders!
His murder proves
that the offenders of Hastinapur
are present in your kingdom.
King Virat
we merely wish to look
for our offenders
in your kingdom
and we seek
your permission for it.
Impossible!
I have made
no such promise to you.
The one who made it
has been killed.
His promise has died
along with him.
In other words,
you are
taking the side of the Pandavas
Your Highness.
However, you seem
to be forgetting
that a man who builds an abode
next to the cremation grounds
has his food
tainted with the ash
of the deceased.
Since you have taken
the side of the Pandavas
you must also face
the consequences.
What you are implying,
King of Gandhar
is beyond my comprehension.
However, before I
lose my composure
all of you must
leave this place.
Soldiers
escort these three
to the borders of the city!
King Virat
each brick of your castle
will crumble.
Each subject of your kingdom
will die a gruesome death.
I shall slay
all your children
right before your eyes!
Tell the Pandavas
that if they have the competence
then they ought to be
prepared to protect you.
Very soon,
the army of Hastinapur
will attack the city of Virat.
It will attack
the city of Virat!
Hear all!
King Virat is on his way!
Your Highness
the inner part of the shell
that encloses a pearl safely
is way more brilliant
than the pearl itself.
Similarly,
your psyche
is illuminated with
the light of righteousness.
I have been humbled today
to have met a more
righteous man than me.
Emperor Yudhishthir
the moment you had come
to the city of Virat
I had decided to keep you hidden
and offer you protection.
However,
I am of the opinion
that it would be better if you
leave the city of Virat now.
Duryodhan must be awaiting you
with his army outside the city
and Hastsinapur is going to
attack us very soon.
This battle is being
orchestrated
to render our life of anonymity
futile, Your Highness.
If we produce ourselves to them
then there will be no battle.
Impossible!
If I cannot keep my promise then
it would also imply my defeat.
Emperor Yudhishthir,
all of you
must head West
using the secret passages.
I shall hold them off until you
complete your life of anonymity.
No,
King Virat.
We cannot forsake
our duties either.
Now, this battle
is not just yours
but ours as well.
We shall stay right here
and engage in this battle.
If we must produce
ourselves to them
then we shall accept it
as our fate.
If we must produce
ourselves to them
then we shall accept it
as our fate.
Brother Yudhishthir,
I am of the opinion
that when the Kuru army
stands outside the city of Virat
it will be the last day
of our life of anonymity.
We shall fight them
in our disguise.
If Duryodhan cannot
recognize us in twelve hours
then victory shall be ours!
Impossible!
This battle cannot take place.
In the Matsya kingdom,
the Crown Prince of Hastinapur
was gravely insulted,
grandsire!
So,
how can you say
that a battle cannot take place?
Without being invoked first
no God ever takes part
in a 'yajna,' dear.
Without informing first
no King or Crown Prince
can ever enter another kingdom.
Why did you travel to the
kingdom of Matsya, Crown Prince?
The General of the city of Virat
Kichak had invited us,
Minister.
The King of Virat had no right
to insult us so!
If that is the case
then King Virat must come
to Hastinapur and apologize.
If he does not do so
then we shall
fight him in a battle.
This is tradition.
You wish to while away time
in some way or the other,
Your Excellency Bhishma.
What about you,
Crown Prince?
You are trying to launch
an attack at the earliest.
Your Highness
there can be dire consequences
to this battle.
Forming an alliance
with the Pandavas
will be next to
impossible for us
if we do so.
Do the Pandavas
scare you,
Minister?
Or do you have
a soft corner for them
in your heart?
What kind of a Minister
advices one to forget how
one's kingdom was insulted?!
This is not only my insult
but also that of all of you!
This society
gives respect
only to those people
who can safeguard
their respect, father!
People in the future will say
that Hastinapur had been
rendered powerless
when Emperor Pandu
had stepped down as the King
and had made his blind brother
the new King.
Be quiet,
Duryodhan!
You have said enough.
People of the court
Duryodhan is correct.
A battle will indeed take place
Your Excellency.