Despite being the Empress
of the vast Aryan region
Panchali is working as a maid.
This breaks my heart,
brother Yudhishthir.
Nakul, working as a maid
would have left one sorrowful
had one deemed oneself a slave
and Panchali can
never deem herself one.
Our life of anonymity
is almost over.
Just fifteen more days
and all of us will be free.
I can almost feel our freedom.
A person facing East
can see the sunlight
even before sunrise.
Panchali
why are your apparels torn?
I have left a piece
of my apparel
with another wicked man
so that I do not forget him
when it is time to punish him.
Kichak!
Did he misbehave
with you again today?!
I shall crush
his head this instant!
Not now,
My Lord.
Just like Jarasandha
very few people can slay Kichak.
Everyone knows about this.
If the news
of Kichak's death spreads
then Duryodhan will know that
we are in the city of Virat.
Panchali is correct.
We need to stay anonymous
only for fifteen more days.
Hear all!
The Prince of Kuru
the son of Emperor Dhritarashtra
Crown Prince Duryodhan
is making his entrance!
Welcome,
King of Gandhar.
Crown Prince.
I welcome all of you
to the city of Virat.
King Virat, may there be
appreciation in your prosperity
and might.
Do accept my
sincerest greetings.
Do be seated.
What brings you here,
King of Gandhar?
In the last 500 years,
the royalty of Gandhar
and Hastinapur visiting
the kingdom of Matsya
is something
I have not heard of.
That is completely untrue,
King Virat.
That is a false accusation.
The royalty of Hastinapur
has certainly been
to the Matsya kingdom
and the city of Virat
has also been
a home to it.
When?
A year ago.
For the past one year
the five sons of King Pandu
and their wife
have been in your refuge.
I have given refuge to no one,
King of Gandhar.
King Virat
the sons of Pandu are
offenders of Hastinapur.
If you try to keep them hidden
then you must face
the army of Hastinapur
in a battle.
I fear no one,
Crown Prince.
You are welcome to command
your army to my kingdom.
Your Highness
there is no need for a battle.
Crown Prince
had we known
where the Pandavas are
we would have
brought them to you.
The wife of the Pandavas
has beauty that can
be surpassed by no other.
If an exceedingly
beautiful woman
has been living in your city
for the past one year
then bring her to the court
General Kichak!
'My husband has taken
the vow to put an end'
'to all the evil-doers
of this world.'
'I am protected by
five mighty Gandharvas.'
This is not the court
of Hastinapur, Prince Dusshasan
where women are dragged into!
This is the court of King Virat
where such lowly behaviour
is not permitted.
King Virat!
Stay within your limits!
Do not cross them!
Your Highness
I think
we have no reason to be an enemy
to the kingdom of Kuru.
Crown Prince
in the past one year, whoever
migrated to the city of Virat
shall have to walk in this
very court and show himself.
Until then,
do accept
our hospitality tonight.
But King Virat seems to have
a different opinion
General.
In the kingdom of Matsya
the General and the King do not
have different opinions, Prince.
My decision
is that of His Highness.
Do not worry,
Prince.
Tomorrow at dawn
all the guests and immigrants
shall be present in this court.
Soldiers
order all the immigrants to be
here in the court tomorrow.
What kind of an order is this,
brother Yudhishthir?
We need to be present in the
court at dawn to show ourselves.
King Shakuni
was given a promise
by General Kichak
that he would help him
look for us.
Can Duryodhan
and the King of Gandhar
recognize us
despite our disguise?
An onlooker merely sees
an unfamiliar shape, Nakul.
However, a keen eye always finds
what it is looking for.
Had they casually met us
they would never
have recognized us
but they will indeed recognize
us in this display of people.
If Kichak has made a promise
with such great faith
then he must have discovered
Panchali's true identity.
If that is the case
then why did he not disclose
her identity in the court?
I know of his
nefarious intentions.
If he has discovered
Panchali's true identity
then that wicked man will
try to take advantage of it!
Empress Draupadi,
do accept
my greetings.
I know
who you truly are, Sairandhri.*
*"Female attendant employed in royal female apartments."
You are leading
a life of anonymity
and the five Gandharvas
who protect you
are truly the five Pandavas.
I also know about this.
However,
you do not know
that the Crown Prince
of Hastinapur
has reached this kingdom
in search of all of you.
If he discovers
your true identity
then you will have to go
on an exile for twelve years
Yet again.
Now, only I
can protect you
Draupadi.
Come to my chamber tonight.
I shall think of the ways
to protect you.
Do you understand,
Draupadi?
You are married to five men.
Another husband
should not bother you.
Tomorrow at dawn
if you
and your five husbands
are not compelled
to be at the court by me
then Duryodhan will indeed not
discover your true identities.
I hope you understand
Draupadi.
One more thing.
Do bring some wine with you when
you come to my chamber tonight
Draupadi.
This is an impossible
situation, My Lords.
If I accept
Kichak's indecent proposal
then I shall have to
embrace death.
If I do not accept it
then all of us will have to
go on an exile
for another twelve years
and an additional year
leading a life of anonymity.
Then we shall kill Kichak
and flee from the city.
Yes!
It is merely a matter
of fifteen days.
Our life of anonymity
is almost over.
Can we not hide in the woods
for the remaining days, brother?
We cannot run,
Sahadev.
If we are not present
in the court tomorrow
then everyone will indeed
discover our identities.
Duryodhan will attack King Virat
and King Virat has
given us refuge, Sahadev.
This city has been our home
for the past one year.
Protecting it
is our responsibility.
We cannot let our life of
anonymity go in vain, brother.
It is almost time for the war.
I am eager to crush the heads
of Duryodhan and his brothers!
A delay of another
thirteen years
is intolerable to me.
We must look for another way.
We can find a way out,
brother Bheem
if we ask ourselves
the correct questions.
Does Kichak wish
to have only Panchali
or by helping Duryodhan
is there an additional
motive in his mind?
So,
do you
wish to acquire the throne
of the Matsya kingdom
Kichak?
Indeed.
Virat is weak.
I am the true King.
However, I can
ascend the throne
only when King Virat
and his son Uttar
get killed in a battle.
If I kill him myself
then the subjects
of the Matsya kingdom
will never accept me.
In other words
you must attack
the Matsya kingdom
slay Virat and his son
in the battle
and make me the new King.
If you promise me this
then I shall bring
your offenders to you.
We accept it,
Kichak.
We give our word to make you
the new King.
You can now have a peaceful rest
and await dawn.
There is another ambition
I must fulfill
before dawn.
Kichak must certainly
be plotting
to dethrone King Virat
and I am certain
that his nefarious schemes
are not hidden from the King.
Even if that is true
it still does not help
our case, brother Arjun.
Our life of anonymity
will certainly go in vain.
You are correct,
Sahadev.
However, for eyeing
Panchali lewdly
Kichak needs to be punished.
I have a plan with me.
Uncle
are we truly going to
attack the city of Virat?
No, my darling.
That old geyser
will never attack.
Then why was Kichak
promised so by you,
uncle?
In the path to one's ambitions
do you know
what the biggest obstacle is?
What?
One's greed.
Greed for women and wine.
Kichak has
greed for Draupadi
otherwise he would never have
asked for time till dawn.
He is foolish.
He does not know
that righteousness dwells
within the Pandavas.
Out of the fear of going on
an exile again, the Pandavas
will not forsake their duties
towards Draupadi
and neither will they
ever do so.
In other words
tonight,
the Pandavas
will slay Kichak.
I am awaiting
the sound
of the duel
between Bheem and Kichak
to reach my ears.
Then we shall leave immediately
and make the life of anonymity
of the Pandavas
go in vain.