Have all five of you brothers
got married?
Uncle
we five brothers
have got married to Draupadi.
One...
One woman
and five husbands!
Hastinapur
and its doctrine!
Unrighteousness!
I was awaiting the advent
of righteousness
and you five brothers
have committed this blasphemy,
Yudhisthir.
The throne
that is stained even
by withered flowers...
On that pious place
you wish this sin
and this overt muck
to be glorified on it?
Grandsire...
- Arjun!
Uncle...
Come, nephews, follow me.
Yudhisthir's right
has been stifled.
Look at this balance.
A side of it has
the Pandavas' righteousness
all their good deeds.
We tried poisoning Bheem
and they forgave us.
You asked for the first chance
in the war with Panchal
and they gave you that.
We tried burning
them down in Varnavat
and they forgave us yet again.
At every step,
they upheld righteousness
displayed exemplary character
but...
- But
today just one misdeed
of theirs
has ruined
all their good deeds, uncle.
Just like this.
It seems now as if
God is with us.
You are right, friend.
In this unrighteous world,
maybe God and human
have to choose between
the severity of unrighteousness.
Now you have understood.
You thought of my deeds
as being unrighteous
but now
just have a gander at who
weighs the more in immorality.
I distrusted them right from
the start.
If they pretend to be so good
then surely
their hearts...
Must be maligned with
some heinous sin.
Uncle
what do we have to do now?
What do we...
What do we have to
do indeed, dear?
We just have to relax.
All that has to be done
will be done by that old man.
My dears
every tide that swells up
the ocean
when is dirtied by the sand
is consumed by the ocean itself.
Now Bhishma will announce your
kingship in Yudhisthir's stead.
King Duryodhan!
- Hail him!
Grandsire...
Grandsire.
The Pandavas' decision
has many reasons behind it.
Sister-in-law, unknowingly
assigned Draupadi to
all the brothers.
Had Draupadi married
a single Pandava
the other four had to
become recluses.
In Kampilya
such situations arose
that... - That they had to
bow to unrighteousness!
They had to resort
to such blasphemy!
What such could be
a situation, Vidur
that makes unrighteousness
and blasphemy acceptable?
How?
How on earth?
Till a human being has
a way of adopting solitude
why would he resort to
unrighteousness or blasphemy?
Had Yudhisthir become a recluse
we'd have had to make
Duryodhan the king.
What difference
does it now make?
If anyone among
them becomes the king?
My Hastinapur will surely
face a downfall.
Righteousness will surely
be ruined.
Vidur
for years, I have safeguarded
this throne.
I have struggled incessantly
to ensure righteousness prevails
in Hastinapur.
Despite many challenges,
I was patient
because a hope lingered
in my heart
that a day...
A day would come when
God shall lend me a hand.
The demise of Vichitravirya
the battle with Lord Parashuram
the forest exile of Pandu
and then...
Pandu's demise.
Duryodhan's birth
the solitude
of Queen Mother Satyavati.
I...
Even after all this,
didn't give up being patient.
But now my patience
has given way, Vidur.
I...
I didn't expect this
from Yudhisthir!
Grandsire
you still can't lose
your patience.
You are the foundation
of Hastinapur's potential.
The loosening of a single brick
can never bring down a palace.
Even if this deed of Yudhisthir
is considered unrighteous
and a blasphemy...
Still, grandsire
give a thought to Yudhisthir's
other virtues.
Silence, Vidur!
Quell your words!
The loosening of a single brick
begins the downfall of a palace.
This blasphemy of Yudhisthir
can never become acceptable
to me.
Never.
Cast your eyes there.
Do you know
that the throne of the empire
and the flag
differ in what ways?
The throne stands for potential
and the flag stands for hope.
True words, Vidur.
This flag is the hope
of the empire.
It doesn't bow
to the wind.
A king should be as such, Vidur
who, upon sighting a challenge,
livens up with energy.
Faces that challenge
rather than cowering
in its fear
and accepting unrighteousness
and blasphemy.
When this flag
stops fluttering in the wind,
it means
that the flag is torn.
When a king...
Accepts unrighteousness
and blasphemy
it should be considered
that his potential
has been ruined.
Today
Yudhisthir's potential
as a king has been ruined.
Now this throne
is out of bounds
of Yudhisthir's rights.
If grandsire addresses
our deed as blasphemy
and ousts us
and enthrones Duryodhan
as the king
we have to follow
his order.
In the court, grandsire
stole his eyes away from us.
We hadn't forsaken
Hastinapur then, brother.
Right after we left the court
we should've
forsaken Hastinapur.
Why did we even return
to our palace?
This is our home, Bheem.
Home is defined by the
existence of rights, brother.
Brother Bheem is saying
just the same.
The very way in which this is
our home and we have come here
likewise, you alone have the
right to the throne, brother.
You'd have to acquire the same
only by seeking.
Our hearts aren't
malicious either, brother.
The deed which appeared
a blasphemy to grandsire
was perfectly normal
as per Sage Vyas.
In so being, another question
of import is raised, brother.
If we follow any such order
of grandsire
then it would be proved
before the world
that we have sinned
and so has Draupadi.
If we follow any such order
of grandsire
then it would be proved
before the world
that we have sinned
and so has Draupadi.
We can't allow Draupadi's
character to be slurred thus.
Thus, we have to be firm
in our defence.
But disobeying grandsire's order
is also a sin.
That's the quandary I am in.
Draupadi
what do you opine?
The quandary that you state
has still got me perplexed,
lord.
Is it a danger arising
out of righteousness
or a danger to righteousness?
It would be both now.
Rights are righteous.
It's causing the danger.
Orders are also righteous.
They are in danger.
If you permit
I would like to speak
with grandsire.
Why?
Rights are decreed by
your sense of righteousness.
The danger arising out of that
will have to be averted by you.
In the court tomorrow.
But the danger looming
on our righteousness
is due to me.
I will find a solution to that.