O storyteller
tell us something more about
Dwarka's regent, Krishna.
So be it, Prince Uttar.
Along with brother Balram
the frolics of Lord Krishna, in Vrindavan.*
*A town 10 km from Mathura, an ancient forest, where Krishna spent his childhood days.
The son of Yashoda,
had mesmerised the world.
Capers of the naughty
and cute Lord Krishna.
He stole butter, played pranks
and annoyed men and women alike.
Make haste! Why are you looking
back, Koumudi?
I am afraid, the boys of Nand
might be hidden here.
That day, when I went to deliver
butter to the palace of Pathua
those wicked boys
broke my pitcher.
Yashoda's son loves butter,
Shubhangi.
But little do those boys know
that if this butter doesn't
reach King Kans' palace
his soldiers would punish us.
They are unaware of
King Kans' fury.
Don't worry. Yashoda kept
Krishna hungry, all day.
Moreover, she punished him
by tying him to a tree.
He will not dare to break
your pitcher, now.
She doesn't know what
all can Krishna do.
Balram, had Krishna been here
he would've given them
a befitting reply.
But where is he?
Let's search for him.
- Where?
Come on, let's search for him.
Krishna!
- Krishna... - Krishna!
Krishna...
- Krishna! - Krishna...
There you go, again he is
playing the flute!
Why does he play a flute while
herding cows?
Aren't we here to listen
to this music?
Oh, yes... Krishna!
Krishna, those maidens are
taking butter to Mathura.
Butter!
Krishna, we'll be punished
severely, if we get caught.
Two days back, my father
spanked me so badly
that even now, I can't sit.
Eat some butter and apply
some on your wounds.
Everything will be fine.
Do mix turmeric* in it.
*A perennial plant of the ginger family.
Come on, Krishna.
Take out your catapult.
Look at that!
One by one, Krishna broke
all their pitchers
and is stealing butter and milk,
as always.
He'll be punished.
Last time, he stole clothes.
- Come on.
Wicked! Wait...
Run!
Yashoda!
Yashoda, look what your
Krishna has done.
He ate away three day's butter!
If you can't control that monkey
of yours
you should tie him up, at home.
- Your kids may be monkeys!
My Krishna's beauty
is captivating.
Then keep admiring him, all day.
Why is he making our lives
miserable?
Better if you punish him,
else we'll have to do something.
Let me see.
But if he hasn't eaten
the butter, remember
I'll give you a punishment that
you'll remember all your life.
Come on.
- Yes, surely.
Smacking the butter on his lips,
Krishna was relishing it!
People of Mathura were satiated
when he burped!
Krishna, you are again
being mischievous!
Because of you, these women
reprimand me.
Don't you care for your mother?
Tell me, you wicked.
Mother, it hurts.
It hurts me too.
When they complain to me.
Did you steal butter again?
- No, mother. I didn't steal it.
Liar! Look at the traces
of butter on his lips.
This butter?
Actually, when I got the butter
after breaking your pitcher
he told me to eat some!
I said, 'I don't eat
stolen butter'.
'All of you can have it'.
Then Madhumangal, forcibly,
fed me this butter.
Saw that? My son disregards
stolen items.
Now, go away!
Hey, but he broke the pitcher!
- But I didn't eat the butter!
But your mother had
to face all this.
Come on, time for some
punishment from your father.
Come on. come on...
Mother! I didn't eat the butter!
- I know, come on.
Come on!
Come...
Come.
We have to give half
of the harvest to Kans.
In the entire empire
farmers give one-fourth of the
harvest, as tax.
But, Kans...
Kans demands half the share!
He keeps half of it and gives
the other half to Magadha.
In turn, Magadha offers him
protection.
Magadha's greed and
Kans' hunger for power
will annihilate all the Yadavs,
Respected Nand.
We'll not bear this injustice
for long.
Kans will be killed, soon.
- Who will kill him?
Somebody will surely come.
Surely...
Have faith.
Dear!
Kans will be killed.
But before that he will
kill all of us.
What makes you say that,
Yashoda?
Why will he kill us?
When all these maidens
go to give milk, butter and ghee,* as tax
*A class of clarified butter.
Krishna and his friends
break their pitchers.
They also sneak into their
houses and eat all the butter.
Krishna! Come here.
There you go, ask your son.
Now, what will they do?
Where will they get
so much butter from?
How will they pay
their tax to Kans?
Don't you know
what Kansa can do?
But you do know
what us children can do, mother.
You can do anything.
The cereals meant for the
people of the kingdom
is fed to the cows by you.
And you feed the fruits
to the monkeys.
Why do you want
to make Kansa our foe?
Father
it's our land, our effort,
our cattle
and products obtained
from their milk.
They are the cereals, fruits
and flower that we grow.
Why should Kansa relish them?
That's not ethical.
You are right, my son.
But we are helpless.
Kansa possesses the strength
of Jarasandh from Magadh.
A cattle gives up on food
when unwell
which makes
its condition worse.
So, rather than
being helpless here
it would be better
if we relocate
to a different place
for some time.
We can move to Vrindavan.
My friend Vrishbhan
can shelter us there.
But to move to Vrindavan,
we'll have to cross river Yamuna.
How are we going to do that?
The river is
the abode of serpent Kaliya
and he has established
its right over the Yamuna river.
He doesn't allow anyone
to cross the river.
He is the son of Kali.
How are we going to defeat
this seven headed serpent?
On one hand there's Kansa,
and on the other, serpent Kaliya.
How are we going
to get any relief?
Krishna!
- Krishna!
Krishna, don't be audacious.
Serpent Kaliya has spared
no one alive.
But we can't be as evil
as the serpent Kaliya.
I will surely spare him alive.
Don't you worry, Madhumangal.
Krishna!
Krishna...
- Krishna!
Krishna!
Krishna...
- Krishna!
Krishna!
Foolish boy...
Who are you?
How dare you come
to this river
which is the abode
of serpent Kaliya!
Everyone has a right on
the water of this river, Kaliya.
You have turned
this water body poisonous.
Leave this river
as soon as possible
else, you will be punished.
Foolish boy!
Look at my size
and that of yours.
How are you going to
punish me?
Leave this place.
I warn you for the last time.
Krishna...
- Krishna!
Krishna!
My King, please do something.
Forgive me, Krishna.
Don't kill me.
I will follow your order
but I am safe in the waters
of Yamuna.
Your forehead
now bears my footmarks.
That will keep you safe,
wherever you are
as long as you don't
harm a living being.
My King, please do something.
Save my son.
Krishna!
Krishna...
- Krishna! - Krishna!
Krishna!
You displayed such courage,
Vasudev!
Were you aware that you
are going to defeat Kaliya?
Of course I was aware of it.
God has blessed me
with special powers.
Hence, he was meant
to be defeated by me.
What kind of special powers?
God has blessed me
with a great power.
Do you what to know,
what it is?
The power to put my effort.
I am definite
that if with my effort,
courage and devotion
nothing is impossible.
But, uncle, all of us
make an effort.
You are right, Satsom.
Everyone puts an effort
and that's
the only thing necessary
to emerge victorious.
The fact is,
there's no special power
that God has only
blessed me with.
God never differentiates
between his children.
Everyone is born with
powers that are necessary.
But reasons such as
fear, attachment and greed
stop a person from trying.
And one who doesn't try
can never be successful,
my dear.