Vidur
I will not be returning to
Hastinapur with you.
No, Queen Mother
you cannot take such
a big decision.
Hastinapur needs you.
No, Vidur.
My endeavours have
been completed.
Just like when a finger
is removed from the water
the void space is filled
my existence too
has been reduced
to the same.
Now because of me
there will be no void
place in Hastinapur.
Please leave, Vidur.
In Ved Vyas' seminary
I shall spend the rest
of my life.
Please take Pandu's sons
and return to
Hastinapur.
Mother...
- Vidur...
This...is the order
of the Queen Mother.
Vidur
the Queen Mother has
one last order.
I had come here
to take the Kuru empire's
emperor along with me.
And you...
You are taking Kuru empire's
emperor along with you.
After today, it's
your responsibility
that Hastinapur's throne
sees Yudhishtir
as its king.
Go, Vidur.
Citizens!
The bereavement of Kuru empire's
former emperor, Pandu's death
can never be
forgotten.
But now
it's Emperor Dhritarashtra's
orders
that the one month long
bereavement period
has ended today.
Hence, in the entire
Kuru empire
business and trade
rituals
and blissful occasions
can begin all
over again.
And in this regard
His Highness has announced
the first celebration.
Two days from now
Prince Duryodhan's
enthronement as
the Crown Prince
will take place
in the assembly.
The public has
been ordered
that on this blissful
occasion
the entire Kuru empire
may have festivities.
King Dhritarashtra!
Hail King Pandu!
Child, it's not,
'Hail King Pandu'.
It's 'Long live King Pandu'.
Long live King Pandu.
It's twelve again...
- Kind attention!
His Excellency Bhishma
is arriving!
Disperse!
Greetings, grandsire.
Greetings.
You should have
called for me.
I have come here
to play the game of dice,
Gandhar Prince.
I have heard
that a game of dice
offers peace to the mind.
Peace...
Peace!
Definitely, Your Excellency.
But still
you could have
called for me.
Why did you take
the trouble of coming here?
I haven't taken
any trouble.
My shoulders have been
burdened with troubles.
Whose was so impudent,
Your Excellency?
By the orders
of His Highness
I will have him prisoned.
I can do this myself,
Prince Shakuni.
A deceiver of
the Kuru lineage and empire
can be reduced to cinders by me
just by my gaze.
And to do this task
you don't even require
the permission
of His Highness!
Be seated,
Your Excellency.
Please...
Please have a seat.
Who will throw the dice first,
Your Excellency? - Me!
Because
Prince
you have begun
many a game already.
Your scores aren't sufficient,
Your Excellency.
How many points are
sufficient, Prince Shakuni?
A minimum of
six points,
Your Excellency.
Do you have the requisite score?
Indeed, I do,
Your Excellency.
One.
King Pandu has passed
away, Your Excellency
hence King Dhritarashtra is
no more the de facto king.
He is now
the Emperor.
Two.
King Dhritarashtra
loves his son a lot.
Three.
His Highness has complete
faith in my devotion.
Four.
His Highness' orders
for you, are tantamount
to God's testament
Your Excellency.
Five.
People's associations
are misguided now
due to the absence
of the Chief Minister.
Six.
The Emperor's satisfaction
lies in
Duryodhan's enthronement
as the Crown Prince.
Now let me disclose my
six points to you
Prince Shakuni.
One.
As per Kuru empire's traditions
before a prince
completes his education
a coronation ceremony
is unviable.
Two.
Without
the people's associations
ministry
and the justice council
being consulted
even the king can't
take a decision on his own.
Three.
Pandu has passed away.
But Queen Mother is still alive.
Four.
Your father, King Subal,
seems to be unhealthy.
Returning to Gandhar
and managing the kingdom
are your foremost duties now.
Five.
I have vowed to protect
the Kuru throne.
And, six.
Orders not to kill you
haven't yet been given to me
by His Highness.
One more thing.
Whether it's Dhritarashtra's
son becoming the king
or Pandu's, I shall not
be partial to either of them.
But Kuru empire's tradition
shan't be broken either.
Prince Shakuni
I am aware
that Dhritarashtra is
heavily influenced by you.
Until Pandu's sons
don't return
the coronation of
the Crown Prince shan't happen.
Please convey the same
to him, yourself.
Or else, do remember,
Prince Shakuni.
An elephant stops in its tracks
on spotting a mouse.
That accounts for compassion,
not weakness.
Disperse.
My Lord,
I have a request.
If it's regarding Duryodhan's
coronation, let it be.
I have already decided.
How could you decide without
consulting the Chief Minister?
Chief Minister?
The one who had objected to
my coronation
will never let my son
be coronated!
I trust Vidur.
He is never unjust...
You could trust him,
Gandhari
because you weren't
born sightless
rather you've just
blindfolded yourself!
But I was born blind.
My distrust is my wealth
and my power!
Thus, instead of trusting
and regretting later
I prefer distrusting and getting
my wishes fulfilled!
Right, Shakuni?
Didn't I speak the truth?
- Indeed, Your Highness.
But does His Highness distrust
his son too? - Shakuni!
The subjects say so,
Your Highness.
It's the hearsay of the subjects
as to what such was an urgency
to coronate the prince
as the Crown Prince.
Or if His Highness was so weak
to have his desire fulfilled
through the Chief Minister.
Is Vidur the de jure king?
Your Highness, my heart
was shattered on hearing this.
But mere subjects
have less wit
and more power. What can
be done? - What do you mean?
Your Highness, I mean, only
after the Chief Minister returns
do we announce the Crown Prince.
- But, Shakuni, you had said...
I was an imbecile,
Your Highness. A mere fool.
Whilst worrying about
your well-being
I guided you over to
a path leading to sorrows.
Forgive me, Your Highness.
Forgive me.
But the rumours within a city
are like the stench of garbage.
They ride the winds
and go about.
Now your prestige deems it,
Your Highness
that in a packed assembly
you get the Chief Minister
to announce the Crown Prince.
So that it's made apparent to
the subjects of the province
that you are their king
in actuality.
But, Your Highness,
the question still stays
that if the Chief Minister
could be enforced to
make this announcement.
If Vidur refuses
to announce
I shall have him decapitated!
I am a king
not a puppet to be
pulled around by strings.
Your Highness.
I'm not able to understand
why you changed your colours.
But the impeding of coronation
benefitted the Kuru lineage.
My intentions aren't
any such, dear Gandhari.
I have changed just my colours
not my oath.
The king to the throne
of Hastinapur
will be Duryodhan only.
At any cost.
Any at all.
Don't go, Karna.
Son, even if you
do learn archery
what could you
possibly achieve by that?
Think about your mother
for a moment. Don't go, son.
I have promised you, mother.
I will return soon
after I have mastered
all skills.
No, son.
Now you will never return,
Karna.
Kuru province doesn't harbour
any Suta warrior.
But, my lord...
Why are you asking my son
to give up his homeland?
This is the desire
of His Excellency.
That Karna fulfils
the probability he was born for.
He wishes to master archery.
So he must give it a try.
I do not just wish
to achieve mastery!
In this very land,
within these very people
I wish to be hailed
as a maestro!
What use is success,
unless people accept it?
I am going to attain knowledge,
father.
Tradition being the pretense to
destroy my skill, isn't a right
of the Kuru empire subjects.
I am leaving Hastinapur
only for a short while.
I am not giving up
the Kuru land.
I shall live in this very
Kuru province.
One among the skill centres
of Kuru province
will be my alma mater.
This is my solemn oath.
That means, you will clash
with the subjects?
A toad doesn't grow big enough
by puffing out its cheeks
that it may clash with a bull.
That is what I wish to discover,
father.
Am I a toad or a Taurus?
Even if I waste a lifetime in
a quest to discover my calibre
I shall gladly accept it.
Bless me, mother.
Father
I shall prove Your Excellency
Bhishma's advice wrong
and return soon.
And I will live right here,
in Hastinapur
lifelong.
Son...