Arjun, my son.
This is a request from your grandfather.
Go and invite my liberation.
Bring Shikhandini
to the battlefield
at the earliest.
King of Yakshas.
[WIND BLOWING]
Why do you keep rendering
my meditation futile?!
You had promised me
that when the time is right
you would help me
complete my meditation.
Each time you tried
to render my meditation futile
I resorted to even more
austere meditation.
You will have to help me.
Answer me King of Yakshas!
Answer me!
I was born again only to slay
His Excellency Bhishma.
And if I am unable to have
my revenge even in this life
then this life is worthless to me!
I shall destroy this body
and be born again!
Either help me make
this life of mine worthwhile
or commit sin of being
responsible for my death!
Mahadev
even this life that you gave me
was futile.
Allow me to die.
Grandsire will die
only when he gives up
his weapons, uncle
and he will do so
only before Shikhandini.
And because she is a woman
uncle had lady Shikhandini
barred from entering the battlefield.
But she has received a boon
from mahadev, Prince Dusshasan
and a boon granted by a God
can never be fruitless.
All of you need to stay cautious.
Friend Karna
as long as Lady Amba's soul
resides in the body of a woman
she will not become
the reason of grandsire's death
in this war.
Grandsire is invincible.
Defeating Grandsire is impossible.
Do you not say,
Govind
that fate does not require
an invitation?
Sister too will have to complete
her meditation
and enter the battlefield.
But we cannot create our next
strategy based on this belief Draupadi.
His excellency took a decision
today
that he will not slay anyone.
However, the army of the Kauravas
will indeed have his protection.
This war will continue
for eternity.
Even then neither will we attain success
nor the sons of Dhritarashtra.
And our army is getting depleted.
Now we have only two...
only two akshauhini army.
Very soon our army will be annihilated
and it is a rule of a war
that if an army gets destroyed
or when all the soldiers flee
the king of that army
must accept defeat.
In other words
as long as Grandsire alive
our victory is impossible.
If Grandsire remains alive for too long
then our defeat is inevitable.
If lady Shikhandini is unsuccessful
in her meditation
then this war of ours
will also be unsuccessful.
[HORSE NEIGHING]
You seem to be forgetting brother Sahadev
the Mahadev Himself
had promised Lady Amba
that when she
aims at a noble deed
she will indeed become the cause
of His excellency's defeat.
Moreover, Mahadev's promise
can never be false.
That is why,
I had advised Shikhandini
to go to the King of Yakshas.
What do you mean Vasudev?
It means, Your Highness,
that I am here.
Lady Shikhandini
I am here because the promise I made you
Till yesterday, the society
knew you as a woman
but now, no one will
accept you as a man either
Like a swan and a peacock
are equally beautiful
but neither does one of them
a swan a peacock.
Nor a peacock a swan.
You will have to bear numerous
blemishes and appellations.
I am prepared
King of the Yakshas.
Years ago when you
stopped me from killing myself
you had made me a promise
that you would make me
a man for a day.
Today you must fulfill your promise
King of the Yakshas.
That is why, I performed
such an austere meditation.
Now, you must fulfill your promise.
I respect your oath.
For a day
I shall assume your womanhood
and give you my manhood.
The moment you leave this pyre
you shall be a man.
Your name shall be Shikhandi
and with my blessings
no one will suspect you.
But do remember
you will transform into a man
this evening
but you shall stay a man only
till sundown tomorrow.
You have only one day
with you to discharge your duty.
Only one day.
Before sundown tomorrow,
Bhishma will die at my hands Draupadi
and after that, I must renounce
this society forever.
However you must not
mourn my absence.
Vasudev has said
that numerous sacrifice will be made
in this war of righteousness.
Do not fret about my sacrifice.
After this war. I shall finally have my revenge
and the entire world will have justice
and righteousness!
My darling!
My darling that wicked Yadava
Vasudev Krishna
has deceived us.
He has weaved such web
of treachery
that we have been defeated with just one blow.
What happened uncle?
My darling
our spies have brought the news
that Shikhandini,
the daughter of Drupad
has exchanged her gender
with the King of the Yakshas
for a day and has come here
as a man.
In other words
tomorrow in the war
the son of Drupad
Shikhandi will be present
and when confronted against him
His excellency Bhishma
will give up his weapons.
However
it is quite fortunate
that this transformation lasts only for a day.
If his excellency Bhishma is not present
in the battlefield tomorrow
then he cannot be slain.
My darling go at once and command
his excellency Bhishma
and persuade him to leave
the battlefield tomorrow.
[HORSE NEIGHING]
Grandsire
Shikhandini,
the daughter of King Drupad
has returned as a man to slay you.
So Lady Amba is here.
Lord Shiva himself has
illuminated the path to realize
the promise He made.
This time. Lady Amba must indeed
have aimed at a higher goal
or an even nobler deed.
That is impossible Grandsire.
Then you need to leave this battlefield.
You cannot battle until sundown tomorrow.
Crown prince Duryodhan
you have reminded me of my duties
and now, you are advising me
to resort to unrighteousness!
I cannot leave the battlefield.
Obeying my orders is your duty
Grandsire.
Hence, I command you
to leave this battlefield.
Bless you dear but I cannot obey your order.
Vasudev Krishna enlightened me
that a man who is tied to his duties
cannot be bound by
the orders of someone else.
I have been awaiting Lady Amba
for years.
Tomorrow...
Tomorrow, before the sundown,
I shall give up my weapons
forever.
Food in the hands of some people
seems like a curse
while even a weapon
in the hands of others
seems like a boon.
The right hand of the Almighty
always raised to grant one a boon
similarly grandsire's entire life
is filled with boons.
While attacking him.
It will feel as though
we are desecrating an idol
of the Almighty.
Merely imagining grandsire's death
is driving a stake though our hearts.
Grandsire's presence would always give us
a feeling of great trust
and deep peace, Panchali.
From tomorrow,
the peace in our lives
will be lost forever.
But we have deemed this bloodshed
our duty, sons of Pandu.
The day this war had begun
It was decided then
that we must also slay
His excellency Bhishma.
For nine days straight
we have been trying to defeat
his excellency
and now when it is time to achieve
our objective
and my sister Shikhandini
made such grave sacrifice
for your victory
what is the meaning
of being so emotional?
Brother,
my lords are not at fault here.
The decision to wage a war
and to take an oath are of the mind
but the heart...
The heart knows neither
an argument nor any duty.
It shudders at the very thought
of death of a beloved person.
Govind
you need to show us
a way out now.
This is the peculiarity
of human nature, friend.
The way the moment a swing
reaches one end
it gets pulled toward
the opposite direction
and begins to move towards it similarly
an intelligent human being
begins to have contrary thoughts
the moment a task gets completed.
This very quality
is both his weakness
and his strength.
This is the very quality
that keeps a man away
from sins and atrocities.
However this very quality
also keeps him
from achieving success.
But what is the solution
to this dilemma, Vasudev?
The solution to this
can be offered only by
his excellency.