Treating women in this manner
is not correct.
Their powers ought to be
duly honoured.
Why do you not apologize
to His Highness, Princess?
At times like this, I always
apologize to my father.
I will apologize to him.
I have insulted
father unknowingly.
I shall indeed apologize to him.
But before that I will prove
that women do not belong
on the bottom rung.
But you are all alone, Princess.
How will you achieve this?
Who will aid you?
Do you intend to jump
into the water
or are you waiting for it
to jump on you?
Pardon me.
I could not contain
my curiosity.
You seem like a Princess
from your apparels.
Did you steal those apparels
and jewellery from Kampilya?
I merely wish to know
because the city of Kampilya
and all its wealth
belong to me for I am
its ruler now.
If you have stolen the apparels
and jewellery from Kampilya
then do return them
otherwise
you shall be punished.
Who are you?
And since when does
Kampilya belong to you?
Me?
I am Krishna Vasudev.
I am about to win
the city of Kampilya
and make all its wealth mine.
Will
you fight by yourself?
How can anyone
possibly fight by oneself?
There must be an opponent
to fight with.
I am about to fight
the King of Kampilya
Drupad
and his entire army.
Let's see who braves my Kaumodaki mace*
*Vishnu's power to destroy materialistic or demonic tendencies (Anarthas) that prevent people from reaching god.
in the battle.
All hail King Drupad!
All hail Mahadev!
- March forth!
Drupad
where is your son?
When I heard that you performed
a 'yajna' to have a son
I decided to come here
to bless him.
My son has not been born
to seek your blessings, Drona!
He has been born to slay you!
I know.
In order to slay me
you have asked for a son
from the Gods.
But for how long will this
reciprocal tradition of insult
and revenge be continued by us?
Extinguish the fire burning
within your heart now, Drupad.
Did you get scared,
great warrior Drona?
I have not come here
bearing fear in my heart.
I have nothing but true love
in my heart
and I wish to bless your son.
After insulting a person,
showering love is easy, Drona.
Had you forgotten
how you were insulted
I would have had faith
in your love.
But you defeated me.
You defeated me!
You took half
the kingdom from me!
If you like, I can return you
your kingdom this instant
because even today,
I want your friendship
and not your kingdom.
It is too late, Drona!
You are a 'Brahmin!'
You can receive charity!
But I am a 'Kshatriya!'
I will never accept charity!
I must now be victorious, Drona!
I must now be victorious!
If I draw my weapon, your
entire army will be destroyed.
But I shall not draw
a weapon on your son.
You did not deem me your friend.
But I still deem you my friend
and your son like mine.
I bless him that may
all his wishes come true.
Dhrishtadyumna
your enemy is
right in front of you!
What are you waiting for?!
Draw your weapon!
I will not draw
my weapon, Drupad.
Your son has been
born to slay me.
So, allow him
to fulfill the purpose
of his life this instant.
Draw your weapon,
Dhrishtadyumna.
Who are you?!
Who am I?
A fish living in the ocean
cannot possibly know it,
King Drupad.
That is why, do not ask
unnecessary questions.
All you need to know is that I
shall not let you commit
an unrighteous deed.
Unrighteous? Who gave you
the right to decide upon
what is righteous
and what is unrighteous?!
One needs guidance of the soul
to decide upon righteousness.
There is no requirement
of any right, King Drupad.
Had you looked within yourself
you too would have known
what righteousness is.
Greetings, guru Drona.
Greetings, Krishna Vasudev.
Guru Drona has
approached you with amity.
He has even refused
to draw his weapons.
You cannot slay him now,
King Drupad.
Will you protect Drona?
I shall also protect you,
King Drupad
but only if you give up
your unrighteous ways.
Soldiers!
Annihilate that arrogant man!
Do not be foolish, Drupad.
Listen to Krishna Vasudev
and accept my friendship.
- Be quiet, Drona!
Dhrishtadyumna, attack!
If this is what you want,
King Drupad
then do attack.
Attack!
I had told you to give up
your unrighteous ways
and that I would
protect you then.
But you are oblivious
to righteousness, King Drupad.
Now, I must slay you.
Father..