King Drupad
the deities of this 'yajna'
will fulfill your wishes.
Your fate and the betterment
of the Aryan region's future
lies with the children
born from this 'yajna.'
What happened, Arjun?
There is someone in the bushes,
brother Yudhishthir.
I think, an animal
is proceeding towards us.
Greetings.
Who are you and what has
reduced you to this condition?
We hail from Panchal.
The King of Panchal, Drupad,
had imprisoned us.
We have fled from his captivity.
Do begin.
Sages, do accept
my heartfelt apologies.
No
you need not apologize.
We were terrified.
Hence, we were in hiding.
Though sages should not
get frightened
but when a mighty person
tortures people, fear becomes
a part of
a weak person's nature.
Who torture sages
in this region?
This is a grave sin.
The King of Panchal, Drupad.
But he is not at fault.
When anger and greed
take over a person's heart
righteousness
is the first virtue
to be expunged.
The fire of his insult
is burning him.
A son who can behead Drona
is what he is asking for.
And His Highness also wishes
to defeat the sons of Pandu.
In order to defeat
the five Pandavas
he is asking for just one son?
Did he get such a son?
We were unable to perform
such a 'yajna'
but the great sages Yaja
and Upayaja saved us.
By sacrificing all the merits
they had earned
they have asked for a son
from the Almighty for Drupad.
At the moment, such a 'yajna'
is being performed in Kampilya.
The Gods are pleased with
your sacrifices, King Drupad.
It is now time for
the fulfillment of your wishes.
Ask for the kind of son
your heart has been
dying to have, King Drupad.
A son is one
who deems the ambitions
of his father as his fate.
By sacrificing my sword,
I ask for a son
whose anger is
as sharp as a sword!
By sacrificing my armour,
I ask for a son
whose pride
is indestructible
like an armour!
By sacrificing my blood, I ask
for a son
whose entire being
is laced with vengeance!
I wish for a son
who will behead Drona
and place his head at my feet!
King Drupad
'dhrishta' means steady
and 'dyumna' means light.
His glory will be everlasting
and you have been blessed
with such a son
by the Gods!
His name will be Dhrishtadyumna!
My son Dhrishtadyumna!
Give me your blessings, father
so that I follow your orders
and be prepared to even
sacrifice my life.
May you live long.
May you be invincible!
Come and embrace your father.
My son Dhrishtadyumna.
But why did all of you
not perform such a 'yajna?'
We do not have as much merits
as great sages Yaja and Upayaja.
We would not have been
able to give a son to Drupad
who is not destined to be his.
He is destined to have
only a daughter.
What do you mean?
- Great sage Upayaja had said
she will change
not only the fate of Panchal
but also that of
the entire Aryan region.