The way
this court has been
drowned in darkness
similarly,
King Dhritarashtra
we will fill
your life with darkness!
We will fill it with darkness!
What kind of nefariousness
is this, Duryodhan?!
Brother Yudhishthir,
just give us the order.
Let us resort to arms,
brother Yudhishthir!
Duryodhan!
I will annihilate
every bit of this palace!
Brother Yudhishthir,
either kill all of us
or give us the order
to kill this Duryodhan!
Duryodhan!
The court of Hastinapur
has never witnessed
such misbehaviour!
Think of the propriety
of the Kuru dynasty
just this once.
Just this once...
King Dhritarashtra!
Open the eyes of your heart!
Do not allow unrighteousness
of this gravity in your court.
Crown Prince Duryodhan!
No such thing can happen
in the court of the Kurus!
This cannot happen!
- Your Highness, this cannot be!
Be quiet!
Quiet!
Ask Yudhishthir!
Can a master not punish
his servants and maids?!
Are you, your brothers
and Draupadi
not my servants and maid?!
Answer me,
Yudhishthir!
We are.
We are your servants and maid
but what kind
of a punishment is this?
I am not a maid!
A kingdom is conquered
with might, Duryodhan!
Not with treachery!
Look at that,
grandsire!
Just look at the behaviour
of that maid!
Is punishing her
not the correct thing to do?!
It is incorrect!
Enough of this,
Duryodhan!
Enough of this!
This is reprehensible!
And upon seeing such
reprehensible behaviour
I cannot stay in this court
even a moment longer!
Stop, Your Excellency Bhishma!
Uncle, you had promised me
that my sons and I
will never be abandoned by you.
'I, the son of Ganga'
'swear on the purity
of my mother'
'that I will not be
the King of Hastinapur'
'but spend my entire life
as its servant!'
'Until you are
the King of Hastinapur'
'I shall serve you and
Hastinapur as its servant'
'and deem every word
of yours an order.'
Be seated now
Your Excellency.
Say it,
grandsire.
Dear Draupadi
it has been proved
that you...
You are
a maid.
Crown Prince Duryodhan
the correct mode of punishing
servants and maids
has been specified
in our judicial system.
But a maid
being stripped of her clothes
is not something that is
present in any judicial system.
What's the punishment for taking
to arms in the court, Minister?
In the court of Indraprastha
were we punished according
to the judicial system?
No, Minister.
Only to insult us warriors
our weapons
were snatched from us.
Even you were present there.
Why were you quiet then?!
Warrior?
Had you been a warrior
you would have been
in a battlefield.
You would not have been
a part of this treachery.
There are many monkeys who have
long hair on their heads
but no one calls them
a lion because of it!
Draupadi!
Do not argue,
King of Anga.
Do not argue.
Duryodhan
this court cannot allow a woman
to get insulted in this manner.
My darling
give up the idea
of disrobing Draupadi.
Uncle!
I am correct,
my darling.
The environment of the court
is not favourable.
The correct thing to do would be
to utilize this time
effectively.
The great guru Drona
and His Excellency Bhishma
are 'Maharathis'
and you must
bring them to your side
so that in the future
they draw their weapons
only at your command.
Alright.
If everyone present in the court
gives up their weapons to me
and pleads with me
only then will I think
of letting maid Draupadi
go off the hook.
Plead with me,
guru Drona!
Your Excellency Bhishma
Minister
plead with me!
And you...
You five servants
must also plead with me!
All of you must plead with me!
Duryodhan
all of us will give up
our weapons
but all of us
plead with you
to pardon
Draupadi now.
Grandsire
I had promised to think about it
and I have made up my mind.
Maid Draupadi
cannot be pardoned by me.
I cannot!
Dusshasan!
Dusshasan,
go on
and strip maid Draupadi
of her clothes!
Stop, brother Dusshasan.
Brother Duryodhan,
listen to me.
Without the knowledge
of right and wrong
no person can ever become King
but you are the Emperor now!
If you let
such injustice prevail
the subjects of the Aryan region
will revolt against you.
Vikarna, whose side are you on?
Have you forgotten your father
and deemed Pandu
to be your father now?!
Brother Dusshasan, giving sound
advice to one's elder brother
does not imply
revolting against him.
Brother Duryodhan,
when a King loses in a battle
he is bound to give up
his weapons
but no woman should be
disrobed in this manner!
A warrior being
robbed of his weapons
and a woman being disrobed
are two different things.
The daughter of Drupad
is the honour
of the Kuru dynasty
and that is the truth.
Honour of the dynasty!
What are you saying,
Vikarna?
If having long hair on his head
does not make a monkey a lion
then wearing a married
woman's head ornament
does not make a woman pure.
The fruits of the Cannabis plant
are fruits as well, Vikarna
but they are not
at par with mangoes.
How can you call such a woman
to be honourable?
A woman
who has relationships
with five men!
Such women are harlots!
Whether such women
are clothed are not
makes absolutely no difference!
Dusshasan
strip that maid of her clothes!
Duryodhan
please do not commit
such a misdeed!
Stop, Dusshasan!
Be quiet!
Be quiet,
guru Drona.
Please be quiet,
His Excellency.
And you as well
sons of Pandu.
You should also be quiet now.
Protecting me
is out of your league now.
The courage to stop
this unrighteousness
in the name of righteousness
resides with none of you!
What good is righteousness
if it turns one's strength
into one's weakness?
What good is the truth
if it does not incinerate
the deeds of wicked people
but the courage
of the person speaking it?
What good is the truth
if it does not incinerate
the deeds of wicked people
but the courage
of the person speaking it?
None of you have understood
the true form of righteousness.
An earthen lamp
does provide luminance
but when the flame gets
extinguished, the same lamp
blackens the hands as well!
And the righteousness
residing within all of you
has lost its luminance now.
That is why,
protecting me
is out of your league now.
If I am
to be protected now
then the Almighty himself
will do so.
Come, Dusshasan.
Come and test your might.
Govind.