Kripi
now, our son Ashwatthama
will never have to drink rice
flour mixture instead of milk.
My friend Drupad will rid us
of our poverty forever.
Let's go, son.
Let's go.
Drupad
do you remember something?
This is the same palace
and I was standing right here
in this spot.
And you
were sitting there
on your throne.
Long live, Your Majesty!
A Brahmin has come to meet you.
He says, he is your friend.
- My friend?
It is me, friend.
It is me, friend Drupad.
Your companion during your stay at the 'gurukul.'*
'Seminary', -kula refers to the teacher's domain, comprised of the teacher's home and school, where students are embraced as part of the family.
Drona.
There you go. This mendicant
is the King's friend?
Have you even seen your clothes?
The guard stationed at the
palace should be punished
because he allowed
this person in
otherwise he will allow
every possible creature
to enter the palace.
A relationship like friendship
cannot be weighed
in terms of clothes.
It is about memories.
And my friend Drupad
remembers every moment
that we had spent in the
'gurukul' of Sage Bharadwaj.
What are you rambling
on about, Brahmin?
What friendship are you
talking about?
Friend
what kind of a question is that?
I am Drona. The son
of Sage Bharadwaj, Drona!
You used to learn difficult
weapon movements from me.
Do you not remember?
I remember everything.
I know
you were a fellow student
in the 'gurukul.'
But I do not remember
any friendship.
You do not remember
our friendship?
But friend...
Friend Drupad,
you had befriended me.
Do you remember the night
when we were herding cattle
and I had saved your life by
shooting a lion with an arrow?
Did you forget
that incident as well?
Try to remember, Drupad.
Try to remember that day.
Do you remember your reply?
You had insulted me
by umeashing your arrogance
in the royal court.
My soldiers
save my life every day!
That does not
make them my friends!
In a field
wheat and a grass called
'rajak' grow together.
That does not make 'rajak'
as valuable as wheat.
You had promised
to be my friend forever.
You said, we'd have the right
to each other's properties.
That we'd have the right
to each other's lives.
And that we'll divide
everything we get equally.
But
you forgot everything, Drupad.
It wasn't like I asked you
for half your kingdom, friend.
All I wanted
was two cows from you.
That's it.
Give this Brahmin
ten cows in charity.
I don't want charity!
The son of Bharadwaj
does not accept charity, Drupad.
Give me just one cow
for it is my right.
Your love
will be an example of friendship
to the entire world.
If you seek alms then go ahead.
I can write two villages
in your name
on a gold parchment.
But if you talk about rights
you will be sentenced to death
for insulting me
in my royal court!
Insult?
Drupad
my friendship seems
an insult to you today?
During the examinations,
you'd wait for me outside my hut
in order to gain knowledge from
me and to learn various arts!
Did my friendship not seem
insulting to you then?
Be quiet, Brahmin!
Getting additional aid
from a student in a 'gurukul'
does not establish a friendship
that lasts for ages!
Did you teach me
anything special?
Regardless,
I was the one to learn
the son of Prishata, Drupad!
It was my intellect that
absorbed all the knowledge!
It was not
some miracle of yours!
If you prize your life
then go from here!
- Drupad!
When a friend breaks a promise
it is a more grave crime
than murder itself.
Another name of Sun God is 'Mitra'*
'Friend, partner.'
because He had promised
to illuminate the earth
and He has
never broken his promise.
And today...
Today, the throne that inflates
your arrogance, Drupad...
I promise you
I will have you removed
from that throne.
You have insulted my teaching.
You have insulted my art.
Then hear me!
When I come to take over
your kingdom
I will not do so
by drawing any weapon.
I will train my disciples
who will make you
bow before me.
I will train my disciples
who will make you
bow before me.
And today, I have
fulfilled my promise, Drupad.
Arjun
release Drupad of his shackles.
Drupad himself
will assist Ashwatthama
to the throne.
Drupad himself
will anoint Ashwatthama
with milk.
I had come to you so that you
would give my son milk to drink.
But today, you have
bathed him in milk, Drupad.
Yudhishthir,
your brothers and you
have achieved a great feat.
It has been established
that among the Kuru Princes
you are undoubtedly
the most superior.
Arjun
your valour will immortalise you
till the end of time.
Now, all of you
may return to Hastinapur.
Me and my son Ashwatthama
will stay here for a while
in order to chalk out
his kingdom's governance.
May you live long.
The situation I was once in
I will never let you be in it.
I return half the kingdom
conquered to you.
Go to the city of Kampilya
and rule half the kingdom
of Panchal in peace.
Besides, you have no son.
I return half the
kingdom conquered to you.
Go to the city of Kampilya
and rule half the kingdom
of Panchal in peace.
Besides, you have no son.
So, why don't you consider
my son Ashwatthama as yours
and help him rule
the kingdom, friend?
And forget everything
and become my friend
once again.
'Panchal - City of Kampilya.'
'Hastinapur.'
Where did Duryodhan
and all his brothers go?
They left for Hastinapur
long back, brother.
Maybe they lack the courage
to accompany us to Hastinapur.
How can he fall sleep
on an empty stomach?
That too on a horse.
Brother Arjun
has conquered sleep.
He can go without sleep
for a month.
And he can go to asleep,
irrespective of his environment.
Yes, I know.
People have conquered kingdoms
and my younger brother
has conquered sleep.
Nakul, we should
rest for a while.
I am famished.
Had I known that fighting
in a battle makes one so hungry
I would...
- What?
I would have fought
a battle every day.
One doesn't feel hungry
after a battle, brother Bheem.
One feels hungry
after winning it.
Are you awake?
But you were asleep.
The smaller the time period
between sleeping and waking up
the greater is
the success of man.
This is what our teacher says.
Even I know a person
who is the same, irrespective
of him being asleep or awake.
He keeps dreaming all the time.
Bheem
quit talking about Duryodhan
in this manner.
When one is agitated
trying to calm him
with soothing words
is most appropriate.
Brother, do you truly believe
Duryodhan will ever be at peace?
Will he ever accept his defeat?
Will he ever accept you
as the Crowned Prince?
No one can have
such a weak heart
where righteousness
cannot dwell.