I am going away
to another home to become
its fortune, father.
May fortune always reside
in this abode of yours.
I pray to the Almighty for this.
Bless you!
Bless you.
May you become the valour
and motivation of your husbands.
May you become the basis
of their righteousness.
Bless you, daughter!
I shall always be there
to protect you, Draupadi.
And I shall always pray for
your safety, Dhrishtadyumna.
Deeming the reverence
towards you my wealth
I am leaving this place, Govind.
Keep protecting and testing
my righteousness.
Certainly, dear.
I have firm faith in you.
Do remember
that a husband's love
reflects in his valour
and that of a wife
in her patience.
This also has another meaning.
In testing times,
a husband must be patient
and a wife must display valour.
Go on, dear.
Because of you,
the entire Kuru dynasty
will get cleansed and purified.
If you too would have
accompanied us to Hastinapur
then it would have been
wonderful, Vasudev.
My hands are tied, Yudhishthir.
I must return to Dwaraka.
I look forward
to meeting you, Madhav.
We shall meet soon, friend.
Very soon.
But do remember something.
'Yato Dharma Tato Jaya.'
Victory is
where righteousness prevails.
'This is a difficult path'
'but it is my fate.'
'May I fulfill my vows'
'and that is all I pray for.'
'I am surrounded
by uncertainties'
'but I must remain
firm in my oath.'
'May it be successful'
'and this is what I pray for.'
Greetings, Minister Vidur.
Greetings, Vasudev.
I seek your permission...
Vasudev
a maiden
got married to five men!
Five?
The Pandavas are not five
in number, Minister Vidur.
They are five forms
of the same power
like the five faced Panchamukhi* Hanuman.
*'Five-faced', a metaphorical representation of various traits or characters.
And them staying united
is in the best interest
of everyone.
But Vasudev...
- No.
There is no place for any doubt,
Minister Vidur.
The Pandavas
have the strength
to brave all challenges.
Granted that their life
will not be all that easy
but I can certainly say
that it shall indeed
be successful.
Be patient and follow
the righteous path
to safeguard the throne
of Hastinapur, Minister.
The Aryan region will experience
a great turmoil, Minister
and the throne of Hastinapur
will be at the centre.
'Do you know how far you are
from the throne'
'from where you are standing?'
'51 steps.'
'Do you know how I know this?'
'Because ever since I was born,
my destination'
'has always been this throne.'
'The name of my son will be'
'Duryodhan!'
'My son!
My heir'
'will be invincible, mother!'
'Every first born son
is the heir to his father.'
'In order to inherit
his father's property'
'the son of a shepherd
need not wait to be anointed.'
'Father may have
honoured the throne'
'but to honour its greatness'
'is a right he does not have.'
'Then what is the meaning
of presiding over it, mother?'
'In order to honour
the greatness of the kingdom'
'many Kings have
given up their lives.'
'Then can you'
'not give up your kingdom,
father?'
'Get me anointed, father!'
'I cannot live
with this insult.'
'Today, this sword will
either behead this horse'
'or your son.'
My Lord.
Do you know
what the distance between
you and the throne is, Gandhari?
51 steps, My Lord.
No.
You are
only seven steps away.
And...
And those seven steps
are called Seven Hells,
Gandhari.
While making one's way
to the throne
one experiences seven hells.
But today...
Today, I
saw the seventh hell, Gandhari
when my own son
told me to resort to asceticism.
My...
My own...
My own Duryodhan
told me so, Gandhari.
The fault must
certainly be mine, My Lord.
A mother imparts values
to her children.
And a father is his son's ideal.
So, is it the fault
of his values or his ideal?
I am unable to figure
it out, Gandhari.
You
can still refuse him, My Lord.
That is something
I cannot do, Gandhari.
That is something I cannot do.
In the entire Kuru dynasty,
till date
no son has ever revolted
against his father.
But Duryodhan's ambitions
have inflated so much
that he will break traditions
and revolt against his father
Gandhari.
He...
He will revolt.
He will not revolt, My Lord.
I have firm faith
that he has
love and respect for us
within him.
Gandhari
people ask for the throne
for their sons
but I had asked for a son
for the throne from you.
Duryodhan is certainly my heir
but...
But he could
not become my son,
Gandhari.
He could not become
my son, Gandhari.
He...
He will certainly take to arms
against me, Gandhari.
He will certainly do so.
The poison of my ambitions
also runs through his veins.
The plants that grow
near the ocean
are also salty, Gandhari.
They too are salty.
My Duryodhan wants
me to anoint him.
I have taken a decision,
Gandhari.
Tomorrow
at dawn
I will anoint him, Gandhari.
I shall indeed do so.
Kripacharya
let the anointment ceremony
begin.
Pardon me, Your Highness
but I request you
to wait for the great Bhishma.
Taking such a big decision
in his absence
will be incorrect.
Sometimes, even the incorrect
becomes necessary, Kripacharya.
Do begin the ritual.
That...
That is an order.
As you say, Your Highness.
Stop!