So, Your Highness...
Do you approve of these rules?
I approve of them.
Think once about it,
my darling.
Your might just have to
bet your pride here.
The Emperor has made up his mind
to play till the end
and so must you.
I agree.
Your Excellency
are you contented with this?
I am contented.
Your Excellency
in this game,
neither of the players
must engage in foul play
or break the rules
and to ensure that
you will have to stay
in the court till the end.
You are the only one
whom the entire court trusts.
Now, if the Empress wishes
then she may proceed
to the chamber of Her Highness
so that we may begin the game.
My Lord
something that
man takes pride in
and also has the right to
need not necessarily be
the same thing.
I have firm faith
that only after scrutinizing
both pride and right
will you place the bets.
You have my word.
Your Highness
will you throw the dice
on your own
or do you wish to have it done
by someone else?
Is there not a rule to throw
one's dice on one's own here?
Your Highness,
this is a right
which belongs to the player
and he
can give this right
to someone else.
The way I have given this right
to uncle.
My hands are proficient
in fighting with a mace
but worse than useless
in throwing the dice,
Your Highness.
King of Gandhar,
is it not true
that your dice
dance to your tunes?
His Excellency Bhishma had
compared the dice to fortune
Prince Arjun.
And if I had
the right to my fortune
then Gandhar would
never have met
with any injustice.
Your Highness.
Your Highness
do go ahead and tell us
who will go first.
I have limited property
with me, uncle
but the Emperor has the entire
Aryan region with him!
Hence, the person to go first
should be me,
Your Highness.
I agree,
brother Duryodhan.
Tell me what you would
like to bet first.
I have one lakh
gold coins with me
which I have obtained
with my own efforts.
I have the right to them
and take pride in them as well.
By participating
in various competitions
and emerging victorious
I have procured 5,000 horses.
Then I have my apparels
and jewellery.
My father had
presented me with five villages.
This is
all the property I have with me
to which I have the right
and take pride in as well.
I bet my entire property
in the first round!
The entire property in one go!
If you are defeated
then will you play just once
and put an end to this game?
But if I win this round
then all this property
will become double
beloved Nakul.
So, Your Highness...
Go on.
You also need to bet
objects of equal worth
in the first round.
Brother Duryodhan, the worth
of the objects bet by you
shall be matched
by me by betting
the objects which come
under my possession.
You must be familiar
with the game of dice.
These four pieces
leave their bases
traverse the entire path
and come back to their bases.
Your pieces
can capture those
of the Crown Prince
and remove them from the game.
The player who has
the most number
of pieces in the base
or
the one who captures
all the pieces of the opponent
and removes them from the game
is the winner.
I know the rules,
King of Gandhar.
Though I oppose this game
I am not ignorant of it.
Indeed.
Let the game of dice begin.
Splendid, Your Highness!
Splendid!
In the very first go,
your dice have
rolled out a sum of 12.
In other words,
you get to roll the dice again.
There you go,
Your Highness.
The game has had
a fantastic beginning.
My dice have also rolled out
a sum of 12.
So, I shall roll the dice again.
There you go,
Your Highness.
One of my pieces is
on a castle square.
Over here, neither can
your piece capture mine
nor jump and go beyond it.
Splendid, Your Highness!
Splendid!
You have captured a piece
of my beloved Duryodhan.
Your chances of winning
have increased.
And there is nothing surprising
about it, Your Highness.
I have heard that fortune
is a slave to supreme Emperors.
There you go,
King of Gandhar.
This proves that
fortune is impartial.
Now, I too have
only three pieces left.
You and I are
in the same boat now.
Go on.
It is your turn now.
Look at these,
Empress.
All these apparels and jewellery
will be presented to you
by Hastinapur.
The moment the game of dice ends
the Emperor and Empress
will be honoured
by Hastinapur
by having a gala festival.
Only those people
get such an honour
who have not been
accepted whole-heartedly.
I do not crave presents or
such an honour, Your Highness.
Will the Kuru Princes
accept my husbands
and me as a part
of the Kuru dynasty?
All of you belong
to the Kuru dynasty
and everyone has
accepted that, dear.
Sister-in-law
what Draupadi meant was
that the board of 'chausar'
is not the battlefield.
First and foremost,
they must accept this.
The meaning of a game
is not winning or losing.
Its sole purpose
is entertainment
and they must understand this.
Your Highness
both the players now have
only one piece remaining.
The player whose piece
reaches its base first
will be the winner.
In order to win,
you need just
seven points.
Uncle
I have bet all my dreams here
by putting my trust in you.
If your dice do not
roll in my favour
then there will be
a reversal in my fortune.
My darling
all my plans are made keeping
reversal of fortune in mind.
First, one must put an end
to the suspicions of the enemy
and then his confidence
kills him on its own.
The real game
has begun now.
Your Highness,
let's see
what fortune has in store
for my beloved Duryodhan.
He needs
a score of 12.
Go on, dice...
12.
May His Highness have happiness!
Your Highness,
you have been defeated.
Greetings,
Her Highness.
The Crown Prince had bet
his entire property
but the Emperor has
lost the first round.
But the game is now over,
is it not?
No, Your Highness.
The Crown Prince is about to
place his second bet.
What will he bet this time?
Will you bet your whole property
again, brother Duryodhan?
We are done betting
our properties, Your Highness.
How much pride
can one take in one's property?
True pride
lies in relationships
Your Highness.
I take pride
in my brother Vikarna.
He is an ace archer
and as he is younger to me
I have the right to him.
My younger brother
Vikarna is my next bet.
And if I lose
then his entire life,
Vikarna
will be your servant.
So, Your Highness...
So, which
younger brother of yours
would you like to bet?