There are five steps here,
brother
and the wedding rituals
will be conducted over there.
I can feel the presence
of a lot of people, Pandu.
People from the entire Kuru
empire have come here, brother.
After all, it is the wedding
of their future king.
Many sacrificial altar
have been made here.
The entire place has been
adorned with flowers.
I sensed that, Pandu.
I can smell the tuberoses,
garlands of magnolias.
You are unparalleled, brother!
Sometimes, l close my eyes
and try to identify
the objects around me
but it is futile.
Pandu
the way a blind person cannot
see again with his eyes opened.
Similarly, one cannot close
one's eyes
and become blind.
Flowers have been scattered
from here to the entrance.
The Princess of Gandhar will
come from there for the wedding.
How much longer till the
wedding ceremony, Pandu?
Pandu?
Pandu. - The Kuru Prince
seems impatient to get married.
Do not be so restless, prince.
When the bride
enters this place
you shall definitely hear
the sound of her anklets.
Pardon me, brother.
I had to go receive the aged
and blind Yadav.
I do not need your help.
I can hear pretty well.
I shall hear Gandhari's anklets
when she arrives here.
Before you hear her anklets,
you shall hear the accolades.
But I think, you will hear
only her anklets.
Long live Princess Gandhari!
Pandu
I can hear her anklets.
You were right, Pandu.
I can only hear her anklets.
But..
But why did the other sounds
die out, Pandu?
Pandu
what is happening here?
Why isn't anyone
saying anything?
Stop!
What kind of a joke is this?
Why have you tied a cloth
over your eyes?
Pandu
what is Queen Mother saying?
It is true, brother.
The Princess of Gandhar has
covered her eyes with a cloth.
Pardon my daughter, Queen Mother
but she has taken an oath
of keeping her eyes covered
for the rest of her life.
She will keep her eyes covered
for the rest of her life!
King of Gandhar,
what is the meaning of all this?
She has taken an oath,
Queen Mother.
We tried our best
to dissuade her
but she refuses
to break her oath.
How dare you mock the
descendants of the Kuru dynasty!
We approached you
with a marriage proposal
and in return,
you are insulting us?
We do not intend to mock
or insult you, Queen Mother.
Then what is all this?
Betrayal?
When Bheeshma had come to
Gandhar with the proposal
you never said
that your daughter had decided
to take such an oath.
If the girl cannot become
Dhritarashtra's vision
then she is of no use to us.
Pardon my daughter, Queen Mother
but.. - A woman who mocks
my blindness
can never become my wife!
I reject this woman!
I have left my father's home
behind, my lord
to become your better half.
If you reject me
then I will have to enter
the holy fire.
My child
if you are here to get married
then what is the reason
behind the blindfold?
You should know
that the Kuru prince
needs a wife
who can become his vision.
A true wife is one
who completes her husband.
Accept my greetings,
grandfather.
I do not consider my lord
to be incomplete.
That is why, the question of
completing him does not arise.
To me, my lord is not incomplete
but just a little different
from the rest.
And in order to become
his true mate
I must accept
this different lifestyle.
To me, my lord is not incomplete
but just a little different
from the rest.
And in order to become
his true mate
I must accept
this different lifestyle.
My culture
teaches me, grandfather
that I have no right to see
and be blessed with vision
when my husband cannot..
- The task of
familiarizing your husband
with the scenes of the world
is yours, Gandhari.
Greetings, Queen Mother.
Even a servant
can accomplish this task
but the feelings
of a blind person
can be understood
only by another.
And how can a marital life be
complete if a husband and wife
cannot understand each other's
joy and sorrow.
We only see a serpent
crawl on the ground
but how it is able
to morph its form
is something that we
cannot understand.
Because in the process
of understanding another being
our experiences form
the major obstacle.
I know what it feels like
to be able to see
and as long as my vision
continues to dictate my life
I will not be able to feel
the emotions of my lord.
That is why I have decided
to sacrifice my vision
forever.
Before taking such an oath
you should have given this
more thought, my child.
But thoughts give birth
only to a decision.
An oath is born from the pure
feelings of one's heart.
Thoughts can be
clouded by deceit
but never an oath.
Pardon my impudence, grandfather
but who else can know
more about oaths than you?
Give me your blessings
to help me soak the pain
of my husband's heart
into my own.
Give me the blessing that
whenever my husband is hurt
I feel the pain instead of him.
I pray to you to accept me
as your daughter-in-law
and to bless me
with the opportunity
to bless the Kuru dynasty
with 100 illustrious sons.
And give me the opportunity
to accept the darkness
of my husband's life
and bestow him with the
fruits of my penance.
After hearing all this
what is your decision now,
grandfather?
Long live Princess Gandhari!
Long live Princess Gandhari..
Kripacharya.
This is a very grim situation,
Queen Mother.
This act of Princess Gandhari
is neither in accordance
with our holy scriptures
nor is it traditional.
Even Prince Dhritarashtra
dislikes this act.
Fear will loom in this marriage
because when a husband and wife
do not live in harmony
the offspring does not
turn out well.
To have a good progeny
it is necessary for the couple
to have love for each other.
But even Princess Gandhari
has taken a terrible oath,
my lord!
It is believed by wise sages
that an oath always
goes against traditions
because no oath is required
for what is traditional.
But it is also true that an oath
opens up new horizons
which eventually take
the form of a tradition.
That is why honouring
an oath is desirable.
What Princess Gandhari said
in her favour
reflects her dedication,
great Bheeshma.
In my opinion
Prince Dhritarashtra should
accept Princess Gandhari
wholeheartedly.
And give her the true love
she deserves.
It would be appropriate.
This is in favour of Hastinapur
and the Kuru dynasty.
The marriage is now complete.
Sukta..
This apparel
is improper, Sukta.
Not proper, you say.
This apparel is gorgeous.
It has been adorned with
red rubies, yellow topaz
and sapphires.
In the light of these lamps,
these look like
innumerable suns
in the evening sky.
They look like?
To whom, Sukta?
To my lord,
all these are worthless.
Princess..
And from today, for me as well.
Bring some flowers
for my adornment, Sukta.
Fragrant
and intoxicating.
Attach small bells
to my apparels
that seem like music to my lord.
What good is all this adornment
if it reminds my lord
of his blindness?
Every moment in life
is a moment of decision.
At every step, one has to
decide about the next step.
And the decision..
The decision leaves
a lasting impression.
Decisions taken in the present
bring about happiness
or sadness in the future,
not just for oneself
but for one's family
and the future generations too.
When one is faced with a dilemma
the heart becomes distraught
and is filled with indecision.
The moment of decision
becomes a battle
and the heart becomes
a battlefield.
We take most decisions not to
find a solution to a problem
but to calm one's heart.
But can one eat while running?
No.
Then, can a heart
in a state of battle
take the correct decision?
In reality
when one takes a decision
with a calm mind
he ensures a happy
future for himself.
But
when one takes a decision
to calm his heart
it will invariably cause him
pain and misery in the future.
Think about it.