Greetings, mother.
Today, you have returned
to your mother, son.
No, mother.
Today, I am here to bathe
in your holy water
to wash away my sin.
You are my son, Devavrata.
You cannot commit a sin.
But I have committed
a sin, mother.
To secure the future
of Hastinapur
I have sacrificed
the happiness of a maiden.
I did not even ask her
what she wanted.
Whether Gandhari was ready
to accept a blind husband..
I made no effort
to find out about it.
Did she protest, my child?
Not explicitly
through words but
her oath to keep her eyes
covered for life
is a form of her protest,
mother.
When you had taken an oath,
Devavrata
were you filled with protest
back then?
After so many years..
Why are you asking me
this question, mother?
Look within your heart, son.
There are moments in life
when we are compelled
to engage in retrospection.
This is termed as
bathing in river Ganges.
No, mother.
I can say with
complete authenticity
that while taking the oath,
I had nothing
other than concern
for my father's happiness
and the integrity of Hastinapur
in my heart.
And even today, I feel so.
Had Gandhari objected
to the marriage
would you have attacked
the kingdom of Gandhar?
No, mother.
Your son would never disrespect
the wish of any woman.
Then you are innocent, son.
You have only carried out
your duty.
Sometimes, it is my duty
to breach my banks
to destroy the old
and initiate regeneration.
But when my flood waters recede
the earth becomes more fertile
and nourished.
Similarly in life,
some duties are also agonizing
but they give birth
only to happiness.
I too have just one wish
from the Lord, mother
that may He bless Dhritarashtra
and Gandhari with happiness.
By making such a big sacrifice
Gandhari has undoubtedly
set a new standard
to being a devoted wife.
What Kripacharya said
was absolutely true.
This palace has seen
many instances of sacrifices
being made by wives.
Was our sacrifice not enough?
The question is whether
what Gandhari did is a sacrifice
or a protest.
No.
I do not see this..
- What you and I see in this act
is irrelevant.
The perspective of Dhritarashtra
is what is important.
Gandhari.
I am right here, my Lord.
I know that.
Just by listening
to one's breathing I can know
how many people are present
in a chamber and where.
Come to me, Gandhari.
What?
Alright, my Lord.
If you go in that direction, you
will never be able to reach me.
You will bump into the pillar.
Come here.
Where..
Where are you, my Lord?
Just look at your foolishness.
If you cannot even tell
where I am
how could you cover your eyes?
What did you have in mind?
lnsulting me or making
a mockery of yourself?
I just want to be in the same
situation as you, my Lord.
How could you..
How could you believe..
How could you believe
that by covering your eyes
you could become blind?
I can see with every inch of me.
Gandhari
how could you be so arrogant
about your vision
that you deem the blind
to be helpless?
Not helpless, my Lord.
I consider you different
from the rest.
And I am trying to adapt
to this variation. - Fool!
What do you think?
That I wish for a court
full of blind people?
That after becoming the king
I will order everyone
to cover their eyes forever?
What most people cannot see
with their eyes
is what I can without them.
That is why, quit all this drama
and take off that cloth
from your eyes!
No, my Lord.
Do not say so.
Life becomes hell for a person
who breaks an oath.
If, because of this oath
I refuse to accept you
then will your life
not become a living hell?
To help one's wife
carry out her oath
is the duty of a husband,
my Lord.
And to carry out
the orders of a king
is the duty of every subject.
If, after my coronation,
I order you to uncover your eyes
then will you not do so?
I shall uncover my eyes then,
my Lord.
If I get such an order
I shall uncover my eyes
while stepping into the fire.
This means..
This means
you will not listen to me
under any circumstance.
And what is all this?
Where are you ear-rings?
Where are your bangles?
And why are you
wearing this garland?
M-My lord
I have adorned myself
with flowers
so that you may..
- Enough, Gandhari!
Enough.
Enough of insulting me.
Just because I cannot see
your jewellery
you have gone to this limit
to remind me of my blindness?
Have you forgotten that you are
the daughter-in-law
of the Kuru dynasty?
You will have to grace
the throne of Hastinapur.
Will you do so in the garb
of a female monk?
Has covering your eyes
made you believe
that the people in the court
will not be able to see you?
Or do you wish to keep reminding
the subjects of Hastinapur
that you have
met with injustice?
Is it not so, my Lord.
- It is so, Gandhari.
It is so.
You have come here
only to insult me.
As per the tradition
I had brought this ornament
for your hair, Gandhari.
It is the symbol of privilege
for every woman.
But you are unworthy of it.
You are unworthy.
You are nothing
but my abjection.
Nothing but my abjection!
I
son of King Vichitravirya,
Dhritarashtra
reject you.
The whole of Hastinapur
may consider you its queen
but I
will never accept you
as my wife.
Never!
Never.
From the beginning of time,
one particular question
has always bothered man.
When it comes to relationships,
gaining maximum happiness
and keeping sadness at bay
is the primary motive.
Have all your relationships
given you
complete satisfaction?
Think about it.
Our life is based
on relationships.
Our security is based
That is why, the basis
of all happiness in our life
is also a relationship.
Then why do we meet with grief
when it comes to relationships?
And why are struggles
born from relationships?
Have you ever thought about it?
When a person does not accept
the work or belief of another
and tries to bring about
a change in it
a struggle is born.
In other words,
the more one refuses
greater is the struggle.
And the more one accepts,
greater is the happiness.
Is it not the truth?
If man willingly
restrains his expectations
analyzes his thoughts
and instead of trying to change
another person
tries to bring about change
in oneself
then is achieving
satisfaction in relationships
that difficult a task?
In other words
is acceptance not the true
meaning of relationships?
Think about it.
King Dhritarashtra.
Now, even Dhritarashtra is
getting impatient to hear this.
And this impatience is what
I fear, Queen Mother.
Dhritarashtra has excessive
greed to rule the kingdom.
He dreams of filling his void
of blindness, his inadequacy
by ruling this kingdom.
Who does not go
through this, Bheeshma?
Dhritarashtra is
not at fault here.
Mother, I..
I am empathetic towards
Dhritarashtra's situation
but he has not yet been able
to accept his condition.
And if a person cannot
rise above one's pain
how will he understand the pain
of his subjects as a king?
We have no other alternative,
Bheeshma.
Dhritarashtra is the eldest son
of the Kuru dynasty.
The eldest.
But you should also understand
that he is blind.
If he doesn't become the king,
then what will he do?
He cannot become the General
or the Chief Minister.
His life will be
wasted then, Bheeshma.
As the General,
Pandu will lead the army
and protect him and the kingdom.
Vidur has extensive knowledge.
He will guide Dhritarashtra.
Will Dhritarashtra appoint Vidur
as the Chief Minister,
Queen Mother?
If, after becoming the king
he does not appoint someone
as the Chief Minister, then
neither will I be able to
disobey his orders
nor will you.
After the coronation ceremony,
the orders of a king
become the will of the Almighty.
Then before
the coronation ceremony
I will declare Pandu
as the General
and Vidur as the Chief Minister.
But to keep Hastinapur
as an integrated entity
it is important to coronate
Dhritarashtra as the king.
Bheeshma
my decision to coronate
Dhritarashtra as the king
may not be palatable to you
but it is still
the correct decision.
Listen to me, Bheeshma.
Greetings, sire.
Welcome, Vidur.
Before swearing in
as the Chief Minister
have you come here
to take my blessings?
I have come to ask for
your permission.
Permission?
Regarding what, son?
To release me.
Release me from the duty
of taking
such an oath, sire.
The royal family of Hastinapur
has given the son of a maid
a great deal of love
shown him a lot of respect
and great faith, sire.
Vidur, you are the son
of King Vichitravirya
as are Dhritarashtra and Pandu.
I have never differentiated
among the three of you.
Nevertheless
they are the sons of queens,
sire.
If our reputation
ever gets tarnished
then I will be the first one
to be blamed
not them.
You are my disciple, son.
You would never do anything
to jeopardize our reputation.
After swearing in
as the Chief Minister
when it is time to decide
between righteousness and love
what should I choose,
sire?
Righteousness is like the sun
and love is like the moon.
If you choose love,
you will get comfort
but also the darkness
of the night.
If you choose righteousness,
there will be light
for you, your family
and for the subjects
of our kingdom.
Go on, Vidur.
Go and swear in
as the Chief Minister
and carry out your duties
with righteousness.
As you say, sire.
Goodbye.
May you live long.
Son, may Hastinapur
always be protected by you
and may you
always be victorious.
May your enemies shudder at
the very mention of your name.
May you be immortalized
in history, son.
May the rank of the General
of Hastinapur
shine like its throne.
No other rank has the authority
to shine like the throne.
I know,
yet I shall pray
for your rank to shine on.
For a mother, her child's
success is her only happiness.
I, a descendant
of the Hastin dynasty
the grandson
of King Shantanu
and the son
of King Vichitravirya
take up the reins of
the kingdom of Hastinapur
in my hands today.
I shall extend the boundaries
of Hastinapur
to the very limits
of the region of Arya.
I shall take the reputation
of the Kuru dynasty
beyond the limits of the sky.
Hastinapur will have more wealth
than Lord Kuber himself.
All the kings
of the region of Arya
shall bow before
the throne of Hastinapur.
I.. - 'All hail
King Dhritarashtra!'
'All hail King Dhritarashtra!'
King Dhritarashtra!
Today, I take the oath
that..
Who dares to interrupt
my speech?