Greetings, aunt!
Bless you.
Greetings, Grand sire!
- Bless you, child.
Greetings, Minister!
Bless you, child.
Greetings, Sage Drona.
- Greetings.
[MUSIC]
Greetings, uncle.
Bless you, Krishna.
Greetings, Duryodhan.
Greetings, Krishna.
Welcome, Krishna.
I've arranged for your stay
and refreshments at my palace.
No, Duryodhan.
I am here with a peace treaty.
I am not here to stay.
I can't stay at your palace.
Don't you trust us, Krishna?
If trust is all you wanted
then you could've asked
for my advice
and not a treaty.
I shall stay
at Minister Vidhur's place.
See you at the court tomorrow.
Greetings, Krishna.
Greetings, Karna.
I am impressed
with your archery.
Like Lord Karthikeya* and Lord Ganesha
*Karthikeya, a war god, second son of Shiva and Parvathi, and the younger brother of Ganesha (the remover of obstacles, the patron of arts and sciences and the deva of intellect and wisdom).
you and Parth
bring pride to the Arya clan.
If you both form a nexus
then the reign of righteousness
would prevail among the clan.
Karthikeya and Ganesh
would never stay
in Kailash together.
I hope you're aware of it.
Goddess Parvati
was unfortunate that way.
We are fortunate that we are
not siblings.
I shall fight a battle
with Arjun.
Doesn't this peace treaty
make you happy?
Why do I need to wage
a war to combat Arjun?
I can call him
for a war anytime.
Thwarting such a catastrophe
would be the right thing to do.
I congratulate you.
I can see that you
advocate righteousness.
Why do you emphasize
on warfare then?
Krishna, let's go.
Rashavi, is that all?
What about the sweet meat?
Apologies, Krishna!
After the warfare meeting
we've been eating
such plain food.
Bitter leaves for the bitterness
that's spread around Hastinapur.
Dry bread for the dryness
that's spread around.
I wanted to make sweets for you
but sister stopped me.
Why so, aunt?
I love sweets.
Krishna!
I can almost see
Kuru Dynasty ruin.
On one hand I think
such a warfare must be avoided.
On the other hand I feel
that justice
shouldn't be denied
at any cost.
Keeping calm
under these circumstances
is impossible, Krishna.
One needs to feel
happiness, aunt.
It can never be attained.
One who seeks happiness
out of materialism
seldom attains happiness.
One whose happiness
lies in power and wealth
invites ruin for himself.
Kuru Dynasty
is destined to be ruined.
King Dhritarashtra
never understood
what true happiness is.
His sons too
sought happiness
in power, wealth
and satiating their arrogance.
Will the entire dynasty
be doomed?
Can't you save anyone?
Of course they will be saved.
Justice and righteousness
shall prevail.
Elements that have to be
destroyed will be destroyed.
Ones that have to be saved
shall remain safe.
That's why I said
that happiness
needs to be understood
and it can't be attained.
Here!
Let me relish the sweets
that you've prepared.
Tomorrow at the court
everyone will be rewarded
according to their perspective.
Greetings, Your Highness.
Bless you, Krishna.
I welcome...
The mightiest Yadava
on the land of Hastinapur.
Krishna
the Kuru Dynasty is on
the threshold of ruin.
Like one realises darkness
when night befalls
I can sense Kuru Dynasty's doom
when I see my elders anxious.
Vasudev
only you can show us the way
to stop this battle.
Please, show us a way.
Long live the King!
Your Highness
return the Pandavas'
kingdom to them
and make your sons ready
for repentance and punishment.
I promise you that they
will not lose their lives.
But they will have to let go
of their pride.
If this is acceptable to you
then the battle
can be averted.
Vasudev!
I am the rightful ruler
of Indraprastha
the King isn't.
Under no circumstances
will I return Indraprastha.
And as long as the Pandavas
aren't the rulers
of Indraprastha
they have no right
to battle anyone, Vasudev.
Everyone has the right
to fight against injustice
Prince.
It's the Pandavas' generosity
that they haven't started
a battle with you so far.
They respected the King
at every step.
Actually
the end of a state
is ensured
by its very beginning.
A margosa tree
never yields mangoes.
Your Highness
even this battle
began the very day
that King Pandu died
in that forest
and his sons arrived
at Hastinapur.
Had you announced
Prince Yudhishthir
to be the Crown Prince
that very day
then this circumstance
wouldn't have arisen.
But you were unable to overcome
your attachment
towards the royal throne.
What kind
of language
are you using,
Vasudev?
Have you come
to propose peace
or to declare a battle?
King of Gandhar
only he who benefits from lies
considers the truth an insult.
But the truth is that,
Vasudev...
That only the king's son
becomes the next king.
But you are a temporary king.
The truth is
that your coronation
never took place.
So, how do your sons
have any right to the throne?
What is the point of digging up
the past
Your Highness?
Vasudev
the truth is that at the end
of the game of dice
the Pandavas had accepted
that they will live in
anonymity for one year.
But before the completion
of that one year, Duryodhan
had found Arjun.
We are ready to free
the Pandavas from their exile.
Only if they give up
the idea of a battle.
Even sinning in the courtyard
of a temple
does not convert the sin
into a good deed
King of Gandhar.
That very game of dice
was unlawful.
So, its results are meaningless.
Vasudev
did brother Yudhishthir
not stake his property
his brothers, his wife
and himself, voluntarily?
So, how could it
be unlawful, Vasudev?
By trying to disrobe
a woman at this court
you had turned the whole
proceeding unlawful, Prince.
No one asks which morsel
has poisoned the body.
The whole food is considered
poisonous.
Even I was unarmed
at the court of Indraprastha.
Have you forgotten that,
Vasudev?
When you were unarmed
at that court
why did you not declare
war right then, Prince?
Why did you conspire
to disrobe a woman
at the court,
during the game of dice?
The truth is
that you are incapable
of battling them.
Vasudev, even
His Excellency Bhishma
was present at the game of dice
along with Guru Drona.
Did they sin as well?
Yes, they did.
When the whole house
is crumbling
the gatekeepers cannot
just protect the door
King of Gandhar.
When someone is committing
a crime against society
against humanity
just protecting your own duty
results in a disaster.
I cannot support
this strange
sense of duty.
This is not the time
to have this debate.
Right now, we must
concentrate on trying to avert
this great battle.
And that's why, I have come
as a messenger of peace.
This message
is not acceptable to me.
If you leave this court now, Prince...
I will meet him next
only on the battle field
Your Highness.
Duryodhan.
Wait.
Vasudev
by talking of punishment
you made the message of peace
unacceptable.
How can any warrior
accept punishment?
Which warrior tries to disrobe
a woman from his own family
at the royal court,
Your Highness?
What does fearing punishment
after committing a crime, mean?
But still
I promise you
that if the culprits
touch Draupadi's feet
and ask for forgiveness
then they Pandavas will treat it
as a punishment.