Your Majesty, Prince Duryodhan
seeks your permission to enter.
Prince Duryodhan?
Leave!
What mistake did I make, Prince?
By seeking my permission
to enter
what could be
the reason for hurting me?
Get used to it, friend Karna.
No.
King of Anga, Karna.
Henceforth, I will always
have to seek your permission.
This is the tradition
of royal families.
You will be
senior to me by rank now.
I will always be junior to you
by rank, Prince.
A wheel is meant to travel
but when it is
joined to a chariot
it travels the whole world.
Otherwise
it just lies in the courtyard
of a potter
and is used to make
earthen pots.
I can never
forget the fact, Prince
that all this
prestige and respect
is being given to me
only because of you.
I will devote
the kingdom of Anga to you.
Only your kingdom?
It was never yours.
What else can you give me?
I can give you my life.
A warrior does not deem
his life valuable, King of Anga.
What else can you give me?
Why are you testing
my dedication, Prince?
The person I trusted the most
my own father is about to
renounce me, King of Anga!
Today, for the first time
in my life
I wish to test everyone.
What can you give me?
My mother and father
have already
been renounced by me for you.
Can you renounce righteousness?
Righteousness has always
been an obstacle in my life
King of Anga.
Can you renounce righteousness?
Renouncing righteousness has
never benefited anyone, Prince.
I have got my answer!
However
from this day forth
it will be my duty
to follow every order of yours.
Nothing else shall
lie above it for me.
We can declare a war
against Hastinapur, friend.
We can defeat the Pandavas
in the battle.
What decision have you made?
I have made my decision.
Attention everyone!
King Dhritarashtra
is making his entrance!
Yudhishthir.
- Greetings, uncle.
May you live long.
You should have called me.
Why did you take the pain of
coming to my chamber yourself?
Brother Arjun
I have a really bad feeling
regarding brother Yudhishthir.
You are the epitome
of righteousness.
Just think about it.
If Duryodhan revolts
against Hastinapur
what will be the duty of a King?
You will have to command an army
against Duryodhan.
And that army will be led by
the son of Ganga.
The son of Ganga, who
could not be defeated
even by Lord Parashuram.
Now, in this old age,
do I need to sacrifice my sons?
But Yudhishthir
a person who loses his sons
while he is alive
is left to face hell
before his death
and even after it.
What mistake did I make
that I am to suffer
such a fate, Yudhishthir?
What mistake did I make?
Give me the order, Your Majesty.
Not an order.
No...
Not even a wish.
Only...
It is only hope, dear.
The hope that you will
help your uncle
get over this pain.
To declare you the Crowned
Prince of Hastinapur is my duty.
It is my duty.
But dear
to take a decision that will
make your uncle happy
is also your duty, is it not?
If you yourself
give up your position
as Prince to Duryodhan then...
Then I will not only
perform my duty
but also regain my happiness.
Decide after
meditating over it, dear.
Even Arjun and Sahadev are here.
Take into account
their suggestions as well.
There is no question
of meditating over it, uncle.
Every word uttered by you
is an order
to brother Yudhishthir.
It is an order
to all us brothers.
With your permission
I would like to
clarify a doubt, uncle.
Go ahead.
When the Monsoons begin
the King is the first
to till the land.
This is termed as 'Seet Yajna.'
I never quite understood
its meaning, uncle.
This is not the time to discuss
the 'Shastras,' Arjun.
Still, I will
answer your question.
When tilling the land
a farmer commits the sin
of killing many animals.
By performing the 'Seet Yajna,'
the King
acquires all the sins
of the farmer.
This is the reason why
every King after his death
even for a short period
spends time in hell, Arjun.
Then why does a King
commit a deed
that sends him to hell?
Dear
if a farmer renounces farming
out of the fear of hell
then the entire society
will go hungry.
And it is the duty
of a King to...
Can a King
not assign another person
to the 'Seet Yajna'
and save himself from hell?
Can the rules of righteousness
not be bent?
Yudhishthir
tomorrow at dawn
you will be anointed as
the Crowned Prince in the court.
Here you go, brother.
Sister-in-law
why did you have
these apparels sent to me?
To examine them.
When your son
will be crowned the Prince
one among these apparels
will be placed on his shoulder.
You can choose any you like.
But sister-in-law, this right
belongs to the Queen.
But my eyes are covered.
You are more suited
to this task than me, Kunti.
The question is not about rights
but worthiness.
Sister-in-law, is the victory
of the Princes
making you unhappy?
Kunti, the victory of your sons
does not make me unhappy.
But the defeat of my sons
is certainly causing me pain.
If you want
Duryodhan to be
the Crowned Prince...
No, Kunti.
I am the Queen.
For the welfare of the kingdom
I will do everything
required of me.
But
I am also a mother.
The ambition of my son
will go unfulfilled
and I have the right
to grieve over it.
Let's go, Kunti.
It is almost time for the
anointing of the Crowned Prince.
Why do I feel as though
because of this, you
and I are becoming distant?
When we had
unhappiness in our lives
you and I were close.
Now, you have been blessed
with happiness, Kunti.
Unhappiness brings people close.
And happiness
makes people distant.
Greetings, Your Majesty!
Greetings, grandfather!
May you live long.
Greetings, uncle!
- Bless you.
Greetings, teacher!
- May you live long.
'Om Bhur Bhuvah Svah'
'Tat Savitur Vareniyam'
'Bhargo Devasya Dhimahi'
'Dhiyo Yo Nah Prachodayat.'
'Om Bhur Bhuvah Svah'
'Tat Savitur Vareniyam'
'Bhargo Devasya Dhimahi'
'Dhiyo Yo Nah Prachodayat.'
Be seated.