This is an illusory forest,
Nakul.
Illusory.
Illusory?
Mother, the forest we are
in at the moment
belongs to ogres.
Many years ago
grandsire had defeated
the ogre Hida.
And had instructed all the ogres
never to leave their forest.
And had also made a promise.
'Henceforth, humans and ogres'
'will not trespass
on each other's territories.'
Since then the ogres turned this
forest into an illusory one.
Without the permission
of the King of the ogres
humans can enter this forest
but cannot find a way out.
And our teacher had
told us all about it.
Instead of paying attention to
your reflection in the 'gurukul'
had you paid attention
to teacher's lessons
you would not have
asked all these questions.
I was awaiting
your arrival, sister.
Draupadi, it is almost time
to worship Goddess Annapurna.
It is the tradition
of Panchal that
this veneration is the first
one in the life of a person
right after his birth.
And Dhrishtadyumna and you
have been born just recently.
Let's go.
Why are you smiling, Draupadi?
I was merely wondering
how, right after their birth
children take part
in this veneration.
The child sits on its mother's
lap during the veneration.
And even an elder sister
is like one's mother.
So, will you perform the
veneration with me on your lap?
Me?
Onlookers will laugh at us.
Alright.
I will hold your hand
and sit next to you.
Pardon me, Draupadi
but I need to go
and command the army.
The handmaidens will
take you for the veneration.
This way.
Mother
why are you crying again?
These are tears of joy, Arjun.
Even in these difficult times
seeing all of you laugh
makes me so proud of my sons.
Difficult times?
Mother, time can
never be difficult.
When man forgets to smile
does time seem difficult.
You should rest now, mother.
Today, the five of us
will sleep outside.
How can you even
think of sleeping, Arjun?
We need to defeat
the King of the ogres
and find a way out of here.
Let's go!
- Bheem
we will not be able
to find them in here.
This is an illusory forest.
Illusory.
But we shall
certainly meet them.
That is why, quit worrying
and rest now, brother Bheem.
I do not understand you.
These ogres are
man-eaters, Bheem.
In other words,
they devour us humans.
The way you always find
a way to your 'laddoos'
they are bound to find us.
We are their meal.
But you need not get
frightened, brother Bheem.
I shall protect you.
You?
You are so lean that you would
not make even a morsel of food.
You will not even
reach their stomachs.
How will you protect me?
That ogre is fated to die
at my hands, Nakul!
The biggest human of them all
will die at our hands first.
And the meat from his body
will feed us ogres
for a month.
Today, after so many years
we ogres will get to
consume human meat.
But brother
that human
seems quite strong.
What if
he defeats us instead?
Hidimba
you must use your
power of illusion somehow
and bring them to our village.
After that
they shall not be
able to face us ogres
for even a single moment.
Do remember, Hidimba
that only those
enter this forest of mine
who are
never expected to return.
During my first veneration
will you
not be there with me, sister?
Father has announced
an attack on Drona's city.
And it is my duty
to command the army.
Draupadi, I am
the General of Panchal.
Are you the General, sister?
Yes, Draupadi.
I know that women are
not appointed as Generals
but grandsire Prishat
and father
have raised me
not like a daughter
but like a son.
To me, the greatest happiness
is commanding our army
as the General.
Do you know, Draupadi
that when I behead
the enemies of Panchal
I feel as though the ties of
my previous life are being cut.
I know, Draupadi
that neither is this tradition
nor the accepted norms.
I should be here with you
on such an occasion
but...
- No, sister.
I do not know about traditions
but when it comes to norms
severing the ties of one's
previous life is most apt.
I am proud of father
that he did not differentiate
between men and women.
By respecting your wishes
he appointed you as the General.
You should lead the army
to victory, sister.
You shall indeed be successful.
And when I see the look
of joy on your face then
I too shall be contented.
Army
for the arrival of
the King of Panchal
His Highness, Drupad
be Prepared!
All hail Mahadev!
Did you see, Malini?
In the entire kingdom, my sister
is the most powerful person
after the King.
Princess, the royal priest
awaits you for the veneration.
The veneration is
now complete, Princess.
You may now consume
the sacrament.
Dhrishtadyumna,
I was awaiting you.
Accepting the sacrament of the veneration of Goddess Annapurna*
*"The giver of food and nourishment", an avatar (form) of Parvati, the wife of Shiva.
is the tradition of Panchal.
Father had ordered me to do so.
Hence, I am here
to accept the sacrament.
We were born from the same
'yajna,' Dhrishtadyumna.
But the joy of life
that resides within me
is never visible
on your face, Dhrishtadyumna.
I have no time for joy.
I have been born
to behead guru Drona.
This is what the Gods
have predicted.
Thinking of anything else
is a crime to me.
Someone dying at your hands
is his fate
but to dedicate your entire
life for killing someone
dear brother
is your ill fortune.
You are a fool!
To give advice to men
is not the task of women.
What kind of an argument
is that, Dhrishtadyumna?
If father thought so
then why would he appoint
sister as the General?
Father has replaced Shikhandini
with me as the new General!
Shikhandini gave father
mere defeat.
I shall give him victory.
He dismissed sister
as the General?
In front of the entire army.
And declared me the new General!
Why hurt sister in this manner?
She must have been dejected.
Think of father's hopes,
Draupadi
and not of someone's dejection.
'Who will achieve this task?!
You?!'
'You are a maiden, a woman'
'who accepted defeat
with the first blow.'
'I was a fool'
'to deem you the basis
of my strength!'
'You are of no use to me.'
'Until I get a son'
'I am childless!'
'A father never obtains
anything from his daughter.'
'I have got nothing
to do with a daughter!'