I have always looked
forward to news about you.
But having never seen your face
left me restless.
Father, I've been waiting
for you since birth.
Now, I will always stay with you
and serve you with all my heart.
Surely, my dear.
I am here to take you home.
How did you acquire
such terrific archery skills?
My mother always says that
a peacock is bound to lay
eggs that are either
white or yellow in colour.
But a peacock still bears
multi-coloured feathers.
I am your son.
I was born with your skills.
My uncle reminds me all the
time that I should learn to kill
because killing my father's
enemies is my path to salvation.
My mother reminds me all the
time that I should learn to die.
Dying while avenging my aunt's
libel is my path to salvation.
I knew that your uncle
was a man of intellect.
And that your mother
is such a fool!
Why would you die, my son?
You were born to be immortal.
Where is your mother?
And where is your uncle?
Mother is in her chamber
while uncle is at
the edifice of combat arts.
Uncle Duryodhana
is paying him a visit.
What work
brings Prince Duryodhana here?
Forgive me, master.
Forgive me.
My mind roves.
I see enemies
wherever I look.
Master, all I ever see
are enemies.
There is no joy left
in my life.
Put an end to my misery, master.
Kill me!
Prince Duryodhana.
Whimpering doesn't befit you.
Master
I will be honest
with you.
What frightens me more
than the dark of the night
is the darker period of eclipse.
My honour, my dreams
and my life
have been eclipsed, master.
I feel more pain
than death can cause.
Just like rotten luck itself
the Pandavas
have devoured
all my happiness, master.
Every last bit of it.
What have the Pandavas done?
They have been sentenced
to an exile
while you have spent your life
in the comfort of a palace.
You talk of exile, master?
Am I at fault for their exile?
If they hadn't
participated in gambling
they wouldn't have lost.
But, master
I was born to face injustice.
Why am I not the rightful
heir to my father's empire?
Why?
Why can't my father hand
over his throne to me?
Why?
How can Aryavart* be so unjust to me?
*"Abode of the Vedic India Aryans", the name for North India in classical Sanskrit literature.
The Pandavas insisted
on my kingdom's division.
The woman I was supposed
to get married to...
They abducted her.
Try to recall, master
that I had to return from Dwarka
unwed to that woman.
The whole of Aryavart
mocked me, master.
Master.
I am not blaming you.
Instead I am bringing to light
how the Pandavas have meted
out insults to me all my life.
That's all I wish to disclose.
Now the Pandavas
are turning the entire
Aryavart against me.
So that they may wage
war against me.
How am I at fault?
How have I wronged them, master?
Duryodhana, you disrobed
a woman amidst a gathering.
Does that not qualify
as a wrongful act?
If a slave insults her master
amidst a gathering
punishing her for this act does
not qualify as a wrongful act.
Does it, Vasudev?
But in case
the punishment seems
excessively cruel
I apologise.
I am willing to expiate
for the same.
I will do that, master
but please put an end
to this injustice.
Master.
If a war does take place
it calls for a quid pro quo
action from my end as well.
The Kuru dynasty's entire
wealth will be obliterated.
Master.
Only you
can prevent this war
from taking place.
I? What can I do in this matter,
Prince Duryodhana?
Your support is what
fuels the Pandavas, master.
If you withdraw your support
the Pandavas cannot even
contemplate going to war.
They cannot.
What is it that you
really wish, Duryodhana?
What do want us to do?
Vasudev.
Vasudev, we aren't worthy
of advising yourself
and the all-conquering Balram.
We can only request
that both of you
refrain from
taking sides.
You should not worry
about that, Shakuni.
Such a thing
will never transpire.
Prince Duryodhana
is absolutely right.
The outcome of a game
of gambling cannot act
as a reason for war.
Therefore, I promise you today
that I
Krishna or any other
soldier of the Yadav army
will not pick up a weapon
in support of the Pandavas.
You... Your words are bliss,
all conquering Balram.
that I,
Krishna or any other
soldier of the Yadav army
will not pick up a weapon
in support of the Pandavas.
Elder brother.
What kind of a decision is that?
How can you consider us at fault
without even listening
to our side of the story?
Prince Arjun.
I'm not finding fault
with anyone here.
I am only trying to understand
what the situation demands.
From what I can understand
two groups decided to engage
in a game of gambling.
Both sides agreed to all
the rules of the game.
And your group ended
up on the losing side.
Upon being defeated
you cannot start a great war
as a means of having revenge.
We were cheated,
brother Balaram.
Then you should have
quit the game.
But we were bound
by our promise.
Only when you know
the entire situation
will everything be clear to you.
Prince Arjun!
No truth about this situation
is hidden from me.
Despite your absence,
people have talked about
that game of dice
all these years.
That is why,
I need no information
from either you or anyone else,
Prince Arjun.
Maybe you feel that I have been
influenced by the weeping
of Crown Prince Duryodhan
but it is not so.
Since the beginning, I have
believed in only one truth
and it is
that in the game of dice
Crown Prince Duryodhan
did not act as unrighteously
as Prince Yudhishthir.
He had bet his wife in the game.
He had bet his brothers
in the game!
That is the most
unrighteous act.
Despite all this,
Prince Yudhishthir
did not quit the game.
He had the opportunity to do so.
When he was asked if he
was proud of his decision
to bet his brothers
he could have quit the game
but Prince Yudhishthir
did not do so
because his righteous ways
had made him arrogant.
When one's righteous ways
make a person arrogant
Prince Arjun
one acts solely
in an unrighteous manner.
In an unrighteous manner.
That is why, the promise I made
to Crown Prince Duryodhan
seems correct to me.
Madhav
please persuade brother Balaram
to change his mind
and take our side.
How can I persuade him,
friend?
He is correct.
Arrogance
always makes one commit
the gravest of acts.
It is true
that now,
even I
am bound by
my brother's decision, friend.
On behalf
of the Pandavas
we cannot fight any longer.
He won!
- He has won!
- Charioteer, stop the chariot.
He won...
- He lost!
He lost!
- He has lost!
- Enough!
What is all this?!
Mighty Balaram!
Just look
at all this!
Stop them!
Bhamri, only I have
the sole right to you now!
No!
I will not leave
my husband and family
and go to someone else!
This is what we had decided!
If I knocked him over
then his wife
would belong to me!
Move away!
What is this foolishness?!
By betting a woman
you are tarnishing
the name of wrestling!
End this game
right away!
What loathsome
behaviour is this?!
If one does not bet
something in a game
then the game is no fun.
You cannot stop us,
Mighty Balaram.
Here, you are given the same
respect we give to the King
but you are not the King.
In Dwaraka,
the subjects are the King!
What on earth are you
rambling on about?!
Who are you to stop us?
We will do what we want.
This woman was bet in the game!
Now, she belongs
only to the winner.
First,
you insulted a woman
and now,
you are challenging me!
Do you know
its consequences, fool?!
If you have such strength
then go and ask
the Kauravas and the Pandavas
the same question.
Let him go,
brother.
We shall discuss this with the
subjects and Ministers later.
This is not
the appropriate time.
These maidens will be
safe with Queen Satyabhama
and Queen Rukmini.
If anyone tries to lay
even a finger on them
then I shall punish him myself.
There will be no war!
How is that possible?
What kind of a decision
has uncle taken?
When it is a question
of Mother Draupadi's honour
righteousness-unrighteousness
do not come into the picture!
I shall go and ask uncle
about this right away.
Abhimanyu!
Your father has
not taken this decision
and neither has brother Krishna.
My Lord
nothing that brother says
has one meaning.
Did you forget?
Did you forget that his other name is Ranchhod*?
*Ranchhodrai, one refused to fight the war and fled to Dwarka for the sake of peace.
Sometimes, in order
to defeat the enemy
brother exits
from the battlefield.
He need not take to arms
to emerge victorious.