Indeed, Drona!
Him!
Your disciple
Arjun.
But unfortunately
he died in Varnavrat.
This is what I have heard.
The Pandavas are
my disciples, Drupad.
They have the
capability of escaping
even the fire of a volcano.
Then how can a small
palace fire hurt them?
If they are alive then why
do they not show themselves?
Where are they?
In order to participate
in Draupadi's 'swayamvar'
if I have to send the invites
then where should I send them?
Fate does not require
an invitation, King Drupad.
Go ahead and conduct
the'swayamvar.'
Hold such a
difficult competition
that can be won only by
the best archer of the world.
If it is in the fate
of the Aryan region
then Arjun will be sent here
by the Almighty himself.
All hail Lord Vrikodar!
- All hail Lord Vrikodar!
Apart from that giant man
all of you may devour
the rest of the humans.
Stop...
Stop!
Hidimb
I beg of you.
Do not sacrifice them.
I beg of you!
Be quiet, Hidimba.
Be quiet!
Ogres
my beloved sister
has fallen in love with
that giant and inferior man.
She has forgotten..
She has forgotten
that she is an ogre!
And the arch-enemies of us ogres
are these humans.
She has forgotten
our Lord Vrikodar!
Hidimba
do not talk like a fool.
By sacrificing these
inferior humans today
we will please
our Lord Vrikodar!
Move forth!
Stop!
King Hidimb, how can they
have a meal before you?
W-Why not?
A-All of us always
dine together.
Sahadev.
Y-Yes.
It is a sin.
Yes, it is an insult
to the King.
Ask our eldest brother
if you like.
He never lies.
Brother, is it not a sin?
A sin..
No.
It is not a sin..
- It may not be a sin
but it is tradition.
The King ought to
have his meal first.
It is tradition.
And amongst us, you like
brother Bheem most of all.
So, brother Bheem..
No!
Before you engage
in a duel with him
you will have to kill me.
Hidimba, do not worry.
I do not require the
protection of a woman.
Go ahead, King Hidimb.
No!
No, Hidimb. Listen to me.
Do not kill him!
Listen to me..
Brother Bheem, go on.
The King awaits
to make you his meal.
Arjun..
Sons, all of you
should also aid Bheem.
Do not worry, mother.
Go ahead, King Hidimb.
I await to become your meal.
Stop!
Only I will fight
this giant man.
All hail Lord Vrikodar!
- All hail Lord Vrikodar!
Is Vrikodar
not your name, Bheem?
King Hidimb deems you a God.
Now, go ahead and
offer him some sacrament.
As you say, brother.
Who is Arjun, Govind?
Arjun?
Thank you!
Arjun
is a Prince of Hastinapur.
His father, King Pandu
had renounced the kingdom
and his elder brother,
King Dhritarashtra
had been appointed
the interim King.
And now, Dhritarashtra's
son Duryodhan also
wants to become King.
But ascension to the throne
should be based on competence
and not on desire.
With regard to this
the throne of Hastinapur
rightfully belongs
to the eldest son of King Pandu
Yudhishthir.
And when Yudhishthir was
declared the Crown Prince
surrounded by anger,
envy and dejection
Duryodhan sent the five brothers
to a palace and burnt them.
This is what people say.
Since then there is no news
of the five brothers.
Maybe because of the animosity
their brothers have with them
they may have decided
to stay hidden.
Who can know?
In other words,
if these rumours are true
then the Pandavas let
injustice happen to them?
They did not even protest
and you call them powerful?
Protest is not a proof
of power, Draupadi.
Powerful are those
who tolerate
and the ones who can do so.
But what about justice, Govind?
How can you deem tolerating
injustice to be a power?
When the heart gets expunged
of protest and anger
tolerance becomes the
strength of righteousness.
From anger stems revenge
but from righteousness..
From righteousness
stems justice, Draupadi.
Draupadi
in your life as well
when you meet
with some form of injustice
before you resort to justice
you must curtail your anger.
More?
We shall not be
able to eat more.
We are no longer hungry.
How can you say that we are not
hungry without asking me first?!
You know quite well that I
feel hungrier after a fight!
And this measly amount of fruits
will not suffice me. Bring more.
You need not go.
I shall go bring some.
Do continue eating,
Your Highness.
Your Highness!
King Vrikodar is
getting angry, Nakul.
Apologize!
Pardon me, King Vrikodar.
I beg of you.
Please pardon me.
Fool! You have
committed a crime.
You shall be punished.
You shall be married to an ogre.
Sahadev, Nakul, Arjun
be quiet.
And what is with this
King Vrikodar rant?
Let me eat in peace.
Sure, why not.
Go ahead.
You will now eat in peace
your entire life.
B-But
please do not eat us.
All of us are your brothers,
King Vrikodar.
What are all of you saying?
Brother Bheem
were you not paying attention
when Hidimb's sister
had said all this?
It is the tradition of the ogres
that whoever kills the King
becomes the next King.
In other words, you are now King
of the Ogre region.
Are they telling the truth,
brother Yudhishthir?
Yes, Bheem.
Hidimba did tell us so.
Brother Yudhishthir
will brother Bheem have to
marry an ogre now?
Indeed, brother Arjun.
Sahadev, did you not
have any premonition?
This is an auspicious sign
and I hear jubilation.
And I see brother Bheem
being dressed like ogres.
Could you not
tell me this before?
When Hidimba said
that she would show us
the way out of here
then why did all of you
bring me here?
That is because, brother Bheem
if you had left this forest
then Hidimba's heart
would have been broken.
What do you mean?
The Lord has ordered
you to get married
tomorrow at dawn
to Princess Hidimha.