If I weren't your mother
how do I know what you like?
So what if I didn't
give you birth, son?
Wasn't I the one who raised you?
No, son!
Karna!
My son!
If you didn't give birth to me
who gave me birth,
mother Radha?
Who gave birth to me?
Who gave me birth?
We do not know, son.
We were without a child.
We used to pray to
Goddess Ganga everyday
to bless us with a son.
And one day
Goddess Ganga
heard our prayers.
In a wicker basket
you were found by us.
Just like an offering
from the Goddess Ganga.
Whose son am I, father?
I do not know, son.
All the folks of Hastinapur say
that Krishna is an incarnation
of Lord Vishnu.
If he mentioned a name
it must be the truth, son.
It must be the truth.
This world knows me by the name
Radheya, mother Radha.
Now, which name do I respond to?
Which name do I respond to?
Grant me your leave,
supreme minister.
Forgive me, Krishna.
I gave you the invitation
to bring the peace proposal.
But it became the reason
for such grave insult of you.
It isn't your fault,
supreme minister.
Attempting to avoid
debt, disease and war
is always appropriate
irrespective of its outcome.
I made an attempt.
But as to who shall suffer
because of my failure
shall be evident soon.
The war is on the horizon.
We must soon
decide the venue for battle
and send a summon to Hastinapur
for battle.
Mother.
Being your guest
was a privilege.
And it has also been
the biggest pleasure of my life.
Grant me your leave, aunt.
Before the war, your sons
shall arrive to seek
your blessings.
My five sons have the privilege
of your protection, Krishna.
So, I do not worry about them.
If you ever feel worried
for someone
go tell him in person
to chose the side of justice.
Everyone invokes the clouds.
But it is said
that clouds arrive when called
upon by a peacock or a cuckoo.
Farewell!
'You are not the son of
Adirath and mother Radha.'
'You are the son of
Queen Kunti.'
'So what if I didn't
give you birth, son?'
'Wasn't I the one
who raised you?'
'You are the spawn
of the Sun God himself.'
'You are the son of
Queen Kunti.'
'Karna, King of Anga,
is as good as your brother.'
Son?
'You may think of me
as your mother!'
'Princes who flaunt their
birth status like ornaments!'
'Remember!
In the battlefield'
'everyone shall be faced with
their courage and their lives!'
'And Arjun, if we ever
meet in the battlefield'
'your death shall surely occur
at my hands!'
My dear!
I have heard that
even Krishna has two mothers.
And Krishna respects and loves
both his mothers equally.
Why do you treat this as a blot
on your existence, my dear?
When one craves all his life
to see the other one suffer
and is then told that the other
is a reflection of his own
and that only when he suffers
even that mirror reflection
shall suffer as well
how can that person
stay calm,...
Vrushali?
I struggled all my life
to attain respect
worthy of my capability.
I rivaled against
the entire world.
I faced insults worse than death
at every step.
There was no need
for any of it, Vrushali.
for any of it.
My dear.
Whom...
Whom are you talking about?
Arjun!
I had beheld Arjun as the
personification of my insults.
I told myself repeatedly
that the day I slay Arjun
the entire world will know
on that day
that even the son of charioteer
can be the best warrior
in the world.
But Arjun...
Arjun is my brother, Vrushali.
He is my younger brother.
Even I am the son of Kunti
like him.
I am not the son of Radha.
How do I deal with
this situation, Vrushali?
I am deeply indebted
to my friend Duryodhan.
How do I think of him as my foe?
I harbour nothing but fury
against Arjun.
How can I offer
my alliance to him?
What trickery is this
by Krishna?
When it was the time to get over
all the agony in my life
he has rendered me unarmed.
Those are my brothers, Vrushali!
Those are my brothers!
How can I wield a weapon
against them, Vrushali?
How can I do it?
How can I wield a weapon against
my brothers, Vrushali?
my younger brothers?
My dear!
Only she can answer
all your questions
who is the root cause
of this situation.
My dear! Please...
Please approach Queen Kunti
and question Queen Kunti
if righteousness means
everything.
'Your Majesty Kunti.'
'I wished to welcome you first
to Hastinapur with this lotus.'
'If you stand quietly this way'
'I shall deduce that you haven't
accepted this flower, O' Queen.'
Any saint, any beseecher
any beggar or a wretched one...
Is anybody there
who can accept alms from me
and do me a favour?
Karna my son.
I am a beggar
and a wretched one too.
Here I am, your mother.
I have come here
hoping for charity.
Would you be able to
donate to her?