Your Grace, the minister
has sent this gift for you.
What is this, liege?
- This is a bag of rice.
Did he not send jaggery
and clarified butter along?
I could have made an excellent
'Kheer' if he did.
If you soak the rice overnight,
and fry it in the butter
in the morning and
then add jaggery to it
it makes for an excellent
'Kheer', mother.
Hah! There was a rat
in the bag of rice.
Bhima's 'Kheer' became
impure even before it was made.
Nothing becomes impure
because of an innocent creature,
Sahadev.
Only man can make things impure,
with his deeds.
But
why did uncle send
this rat as a gift?
I don't think he meant
to send us a rat.
The rat must have
stumbled into the bag.
Yes.
I'm sure that rice is not
readily available here
hence, this was sent from
Hastinapur, for the princes.
Is there anything else, leige?
Please keep this is mind,
Your Grace
that even if one grain of
rice falls to the ground
it can manifest itself in
hundreds, in the future.
I take your leave, Your Grace.
Your Highness.
'Even if one grain of
rice falls to the ground'
'it can manifest itself in
hundreds, in the future.'
My child.
Are you looking at this moon?
It was full moon,
some nights past
How luminous it was.
And now, only a part of
its luminousity remains.
Tomorrow,
even this, would be lost.
For tomorrow, is the
night, of the new moon.
Just this way, the luminousity
from lives of the Pandavas
will be extinguished tomorrow.
Uncle, Lord Ram was
victorious on new moon
and the whole world celebrates
that night as 'Diwali'.*
*The "festival of lights", spiritually signifies victory.
The new moon, tomorrow
will be a 'Diwali'
for us as well.
Of course, my child, of course.
But, only if your friend, Karna
doesn't put a
spanner to the works.
Only then, will all our wishes
come to fruition.
Uncle,
I have complete faith in Karna.
My child.
If you have faith in him
than I have nothing
to worry about.
For tomorrow
Purochana will set the
'Lakshagraha' on fire.
Now, there is no escape,
for your enemies.
No one can save them.
Greetings, Your Grace.
Adhiratha,
your charioteer, is here.
Adhiratha? At this time?
Send him in.
- Yes, Your Grace.
What's the matter, Adhirath?
You don't even
bow before me now.
Leave us!
I need to be pure myself
before I bow before you.
I feel
very unclean today.
My soul is stained.
I don't have the right
to bow before you.
I'm here to tell you
that I wish to leave
your services
and Hastinapur.
It's the lay of the land,
Adhiratha
that, a boy endures pain,
because of his friends
an adolescent,
for his lover
a married man,
for his in-laws
and an old man
for his children.
There is no such unction,
which can allay this pain.
I'm certain that
your son is the cause
of your pain, Adhiratha.
Tell me the truth, Adhiratha.
What has your son done?
Don't be silent.
I'm waiting.
Your Grace, Karna is innocent.
If that's true,
then your sorrow is unfounded
Tell me the truth, Adhiratha.
How has Karna hurt you?
Your Grace,
he is bound by
his pledge of friendship.
He hasn't said anything clearly.
But something is amiss
at Varnavart.
Something will come to
pass with the Pandavas
which will be an iniquity,
for even Karna.
But something is amiss
at Varnavart.
Something will come to
pass with the Pandavas
which will be an iniquity,
for even Karna.
And I will not let
that iniquity happen.
Krishna shaved Rukmi's
head with his discus.
Now he won't try to make
alliances with Dwarka.
What's wrong, brother?
Not worried. I was wondering
why uncle sent a rat.
What is he trying to tell us?
I'm sure he's trying
to tell Nakula
that no matter how much
he stand there with the rat
in front of the mirror
he won't be any beautiful.
Leave the mirror alone.
Don't you get tired,
looking at yourself.
What's there to get tired,
brother?
Even you look at yourself in the
mirror, when you have the time.
I look at my arms.
Yes,
one looks at what he possesses.
Now your face is
nothing to look at.
Arjuna face was worth looking at
when he dressed up as a girl.
Our mother will be
saddened to know that
the strongest man in the world
is reduced to being a mere cook.
Just like a beautiful and
graceful wife.
Arjuna!
Bhima! Bhima! Bhima!
Bhima!
Bhima
Bhima, go and see whether
the food is cooked or not.
Even you, brother!
It's nothing like that.
It's time to eat,
that's why I asked you.
Go.
- Come, Sahadeva.
Go, Bhima.
Cook the food.
Uncle.
Brother! Brother!
Grand uncle Bhishma has left
for Varnavart, in a hurry.
How did grand uncle
come to know of this?
The biggest of ships are sunk
because of one hole
in its starboard.
Even your plan has a hole.
Your friend.
I can't believe that
Karna has left our side
and has gone to help
those Pandavas, uncle.
No, this cannot be.
My child, I never said
that he has left your side.
But he can't let go of
his principles as well.
This is his deference.
I'm sure the pain in his heart
is reflecting on
his countenance.
But there is no reason
for alarm.
What has to happen tomorrow
can happen tonight as well.
It seems that Pandavas' lives
are about to be eclipsed.
But how will that happen, uncle?
If we send word to Purochana
then grand uncle will also
come to know of it.
I never found Hastinapur's
traditional ways
of sending messages
to be proper.
The message should
reach discreetly.
Shukra!
My friend.
Will you take a message
to Varnavart?
You have to make haste
because Duryodhana's ill luck
and 'Lakshagraha'
need to be burnt to ashes.
Write the message, my child.
Write the message.
A message from Shakuni?
Brundhari, I have just recieved
word from Shakuni.
We have to set the
mansion on fire tonight.