Stop decorating this 'mandap.'*
*A mandapa is a pillared outdoor hall or pavilion for public rituals.
Dhrishtadyum go tell the domestic help
that no marriage
will take place here.
Let's go, daughter.
Father, Draupadi...
Sister, he was Prince Arjun.
Those five brothers were
the sons of Pandu.
But they have decided
to stay hidden.
That is why,
I cannot tell father about it.
Please do not tell him either,
sister.
Please do not tell him.
Whoever they were, Draupadi...
After what they did
you have no right to think
of their well-being.
Let's go, Draupadi.
One can preach righteousness but
not order its implementation.
Each one of us must determine
what righteousness means to us.
I can only aid all of you
in familiarizing
yourselves with righteousness.
Yudhishthir
if you resort to asceticism
then a powerful kingdom
like Hastinapur
will be devoid of a worthy King.
My sons have renounced the
kingdom on their own, My Lord.
We do not covet the throne.
This must have been your
decision, Kunti.
But while taking this decision
did you think even once
about the welfare
of the subjects?
Did it ever occur to you
that if Duryodhan becomes King
then for generations to come
a great and powerful
kingdom like Hastinapur
will be ruled by selfishness
and unrighteousness?
No, sire.
My heart said that
nipping struggle in the bud
would be appropriate.
Letting your heart
rule your thoughts
and letting your head
govern your likes
is the first stage
of unrighteousness.
What do you feel about
this now, Kunti?
We must stop hiding like this
and return to Hastinapur.
After brother-in-law
descends from the throne
Yudhishthir must become
the next King.
Not for his personal gain
but to provide the subjects
with a worthy King.
Splendid.
Splendid!
But Yudhishthir and Bheem...
If both of them
resort to asceticism
then Duryodhan will
certainly be the next King
because Arjun is younger to him.
He has no right to the throne.
And on the other hand
if, apart from Yudhishthir
the remaining brothers
resort to asceticism
then who will protect
Yudhishthir?
Pardon me, My Lord
but is it necessary to discuss
politics at the moment?
It is unnecessary!
Pardon me, My Lord
but why is the decision
of marriage
being weighed on
the scales of politics?
That too when
it is such a dreadful situation
for Princess Draupadi.
Politics is also a method
of ensuring social welfare.
And it is as vital
as righteousness.
When facing a dreadful situation
if one forgets to think
of social welfare
and thinks only of himself
then is it correct?
Answer me.
No.
But My Lord...
Whenever the thought
of Princess Draupadi
comes into my mind
I fail to console myself,
oh revered one.
Becoming the wife to five men...
How can it be easy?
How can we make a woman
lead such a life?
Draupadi's life
will indeed be difficult...
Then can you five brothers
not make certain sacrifices?
Can you not take certain
difficult decisions
which will ease Draupadi's life?
If the decision to make
such a big sacrifice
was taken by Draupadi herself
then why are all of you
declining it?
Are you afraid of something?
Or does it involve
a selfish motive?
But My Lord, subjects follow
in the King's footsteps.
This will become a tradition.
Many women will be
forced to do so.
Would it be correct?
It would indeed
be incorrect, Prince
but at the moment
a major trouble
surrounds all of you.
The righteousness one resorts to
in times of trouble
can be referred to as
a duty in face of peril.
According to this
many such deeds are committed
which, under
normal circumstances
would be a grave sin.
If another woman will be married
to more than one man
then all those men will be
fated to a life in hell.
But for all of you,
this is not a typical situation.
Then its solution
may also be atypical.
What kind of a path
is this, My Lord?
How can the wife
of my younger brother
be deemed my own?
Instead of revering
the wife of my elder brother
as my own mother
how can I deem her
my wife, My Lord?!
How?
An urn is placed
between three pillars
and the Almighty's idol
is placed below the urn.
The idol is secure
from all five directions.
To whom is that idol
connected, Bheem?
To all of them
yet to none.
Similarly
can you not deem Draupadi
the idol in your life?
Do remember, Bheem.
The temple's idol sanctifies
the urn and the pillars.
The urn and the pillars
do not sanctify the idol.
What is your decision now,
sons of Pandu?
'If you resort to asceticism'
'then a powerful kingdom
like Hastinapur'
'will be devoid
of a worthy King.'
'If Duryodhan becomes King'
'then for generations to come'
'a great and powerful
kingdom like Hastinapur'
'will be ruled by selfishness
and unrighteousness.'
'Then can you five brothers'
'not make certain sacrifices?'
'Can you not take
certain difficult decisions'
'which will ease
Draupadi's life?'
'Can you not deem Draupadi'
'the idol in your life?'
'After brother-in-law
descends from the throne'
'Yudhishthir must become
the next King.'
'Not for his personal gain'
'but to provide the subjects
with a worthy King.'
'If you resort to asceticism...
- After brother-in-law'
'descends from the throne...
- Who will protect Yudhishthir?'
'Yudhishthir must become
the next King.'
'Not for his personal gain...
- If Duryodhan becomes King'
'then for generations to come'
'a great and powerful
kingdom like Hastinapur'
'will be ruled by selfishness
and unrighteousness.'
'Not for his personal gain'
'but to provide the subjects
with a worthy King.'
We must go to Kampilya
and bear the cloak
of asceticism
called life, sage.
And this will establish
righteousness.
Go on, sons of Pandu.
Bless you!
Dhrishtadyumna!
What is your order, father?
Those five 'Brahmins'
are approaching
who have had the nerve to
insult the Princess of Panchal.
Get the troops ready!
Soldiers!
The way throwing away
rotten food
does not result
in committing a sin!
Similarly
killing 'Brahmins'
indulged in unrighteousness
does not result
in committing a sin!
It helps one earn merits!
Today
by killing the five 'Brahmins'
approaching Kampilya
all of you
shall be recipients of merit!
All hail Mahadev!
- All hail Mahadev!
How dare you come here?
Who gave you the right
to enter Kampilya?!
After insulting
my daughter so gravely
forget about Kampilya...
None of you will find a place to
stay in the entire Aryan region!
King Drupad.
These five 'Brahmins'
are none
but the Princes of Hastinapur
the sons of King Pandu.
And that is Arjun
to whom you had dreamt
of having your daughter married.