Why does righteousness
get defeated, brother?
And why does
unrighteousness win?
Getting something is not winning
and losing something
is not being defeated.
It is merely the impact
of time, Subhadra.
Change is ingrained
in its nature.
Uncle
the fortunes have changed.
The flag of the Pandavas
has been lowered!
The fear in my heart
has gone away
forever.
No, my darling!
No!
Just because the reason
of your fear is going away
it does not imply that your
fear is going away as well.
When the reason of your fear
gets annihilated
only then does
the fear in your heart
truly go away.
That is why,
spies will follow the Pandavas
at my order.
Until the five Pandavas
are alive
the fear in your heart
is alive as well.
If something makes man fearful
then he has been defeated.
And despite losing something,
the person
who remains calm and composed
is truly victorious.
Times will change,
Subhadra.
Unrighteous people will
indeed be punished
and the flag of righteousness
will fly once again.
This is not the departure
of defeated soldiers
but the beginning of the journey
of victory of the Pandavas.
The struggles in these 13 years
will indeed
lead them to victory.
'A few days later.'
Panchali,
give me that vessel.
Let me go bring some water.
There must indeed
be a pool nearby.
Why is My Lord Nakul
not back yet?
Let me go check.
I shall come with you,
brother.
Nakul!
Brother Nakul!
- Nakul!
Brother Bheem!
Brother Nakul...
Brother Nakul!
Nakul...
Brother Bheem,
brother Nakul is not breathing.
Get up,
brother Nakul.
Sahadev...
Sahadev!
Brother Yudhishthir
something terrible
must have befallen them.
Let me go check.
Stay here and protect Panchali.
The three of us could
go together, My Lord.
No, Panchali.
We do not know what kind
of trouble they ran into.
You must stay here.
Brother Bheem!
Nakul, Sahadev!
Sahadev!
Brother Bheem!
They do not seem to be hurt.
And neither do they have
the symptoms of being poisoned.
My brothers
must certainly have been killed
by an illusory being.
I know
that you can hear me.
No matter who you are
you must bring
my brothers back to life
otherwise I shall
dry this pool up!
I, son of Pandu, Arjun
warn you--
No matter who you are...
A Yaksh,* demon
*Nature-spirits, usually benevolent, who are caretakers of the natural treasures hidden in the earth and tree roots.
eunuch, ghoul
an illusory being or ogre...
You must bring
my brothers back to life.
Panchali, had it
been a human being
he could not have held Bheem
and Arjun up for this long.
I must go.
I hope you will be able to use
this spear to protect yourself.
Let me come with you,
My Lord.
No, Panchali.
I do not know
what trouble awaits there.
If a trouble befalls
the five of you, My Lord
then it would be the same
for me as well.
Panchali
in the torch of justice
enkindled by Vasudev
you are the fire.
Before justice
reigns supreme again
your life cannot be
extinguished.
If none of us brothers
return alive
then you must go to Dwaraka.
Vasudev will illuminate
the path ahead.
Bheem...
Bheem!
Nakul...
Nakul!
Sahadev...
Sahadev.
Arjun...
Arjun!
What is this illusion?
Who are you
to have killed my brothers
for no reason?
Please show yourself.
Until I know who I am
fighting with and why
I will not take to arms.
I do not fear you.
I do not wish to insult you
unintentionally.
Please show yourself.
I am the King of the Yakshas
the master of this pool!
No human being has the right
to take water from this pool!
Yet your brother Nakul
tried to take water
from this pool
though he had no right!
That is why
I slayed him!
Son of Pandu
your brothers
challenged me to a fight
out of vanity!
That is why,
I taught the four of them
a lesson of my competence
and asserted my right
by slaying them.
Neither did you
create this water
nor the place from where
water can be taken.
Then how can you have the right
to this place, Yaksha King?
Taking water is no crime,
King of the Yakshas.
Then how could you
punish my brothers so?
Justice and righteousness
dictate that
my brothers must be
brought back to life.
Impossible!
However, by answering
my questions
if you are able to
make me contented
then I shall bring one of
your brothers back to life.
After the death of
the four brothers of mine
it is not possible for me
to live any longer, Yaksha King.
However, I wish to keep
one of my brothers alive.
That is why,
I will use my intelligence
to try my best
and make you contented.
Ask the questions,
King of the Yakshas.
Tell me what life
and death are?
Yaksha King, according
to the Rig Veda...
In the heart of
the supreme element
there was the desire to generate
the creation in the beginning.
The rays of that desire
spread all around
and thus were formed
the directions.
The desire of the Almighty led
to the genesis of the creation.
Three realms,
three qualities
and three dimensions of time
were created.
Many beings and elements
were born in the heart
of the Almighty.
Every being and element
is the Almighty himself, sire.
In other words
the Almighty is life.
If the heart of a person
understands this
then he can never be angry with
or envious of someone.
He walks on the path
of righteousness
and respects justice.
This is the essence of life.
And what is death,
Yudhishthir?
Tell me.
Because of love
selfishness and anger man
gets connected to another.
This tie is called attachment.
Because of attachment,
man deems his body to be life
while the disintegration of
the body is deemed to be death.
However, the entire world was
born in the Almighty's heart
and only in the heart
of the Almighty can it end.
Two people travelling
on the same path
can walk with each other
for a while
but then they get separated.
At that moment,
they feel
that the other person
has met with death
but in reality,
both the travellers
are walking down the same path.
Similarly,
what we call death
is merely the distance that
arises between two human beings.
Until the world exists
no being can truly disintegrate.
Then how can one
meet with one's death?
In other words,
King of the Yakshas
the Almighty is the world
and the world is life.
Death is merely a delusion
and an illusion.
Wonderful,
dear Yudhishthir!
You have given satisfactory
answers to my questions.
That is why,
I shall keep my word
and bring one of your brothers
back to life.
Go ahead and ask
for the life of the strongest
person in this world!
If Bheem is alive
no enemy will ever be
able to challenge you.
The mighty Lord Hanuman
will protect your kingdom!
No, Yaksha King.
The greatest enemy of a person
is the grief housed
within his heart.
If three of my brothers are dead
then how will Bheem
be able to protect me
from that enemy called grief?
The truth is,
the grief within Bheem
will defeat him
and leave him weak.
Then ask for Arjun's life.
If the greatest archer
of the world will be alive
then the entire world
will benefit from it!
I know Arjun,
King of the Yakshas.
When he will find out
that the reason of his life
is the death of the
three brothers of his
his courage will wither
strength will leave his body
and his Gandiva will slip
from his hands forever.
If I ask for the life
of either Bheem or Arjun
then my mother will
also be unhappy.
Your mother will be unhappy
to have two of her sons alive!
What kind of an argument
is that, Yudhishthir?!
One of the sons of my
mother is alive, Yaksha King.
I am alive.
Now, the second wife
of King Pandu also has the right
to have one
of her sons to be alive.
My mother Kunti would want this
and I wish for the same as well.
That is why,
King of the Yakshas
if you wish to bring
one of my brothers back to life
then give my brother Nakul
the boon of life.
Wonderful,
dear Yudhishthir!
I am pleased.
I am Dharma Raj.
I had gifted Kunti and Pandu
with you as my blessing.
From that perspective,
I am your biological father
and I am proud
of my biological son.
I shall bring all your brothers
back to life.