Who?
Who dared to help me
when I did not ask for any?
It is me, brother.
Pandu.
I do not require your help!
I do not fear anyone.
Do not keep reminding me
that I am blind.
In this world,
each person has some weakness
or the other.
For instance,
someone cannot run very fast
while another,
cannot lift heavy weights.
While one is afflicted
with a malignant disease
another is unable to recall
the things he has learnt.
There are many such examples.
Do you know a person
who has everything?
And that single weakness of ours
is considered the epicenter
of our lives.
This gives birth to sadness
and discontentment in the heart.
Weakness is either
a congenital defect
or is bestowed by fate
but the same weakness,
by the nous of a person
is assumed to be the bounds
not to be overstepped.
But there are some people
who, through their
righteousness and hard work
defeat their weakness.
What is the difference between
such people and others?
Have you ever thought about it?
There is a very simple answer
to it.
A person who does not
let his weakness defeat him
and houses righteousness
in his heart
is able to move
past his weakness.
In other words,
God may give one weakness
but bounds..
Bounds are determined
only by the nous of a person.
Think about it.
Pandu
you are here.
Are you here to help
your elder brother again
so that no one is able
to forget that I am blind?
Am I right?
A king is offered services,
brother
and not aided.
- But I am
not yet a king.
But you are the heir to the
throne of Hastinapur, brother.
The throne has been awaiting
your presence all these years.
A throne is not meant for a king
but a king is meant for it.
Greetings,
brother Dhritarashtra.
Greetings.
And the heir to the throne
is decided by the capability
of a person, brother Pandu.
I am the eldest of this dynasty.
I have immense strength.
I can fire projectiles
guided by sound.
I am skilled with
every weapon.
I have complete knowledge
of all the 'Shastras' and lores.
Then who are you to judge
my competence?
I cannot that,
brother Dhritarashtra.
Only the Chief Minister
has the right to do so.
When the time is right,
he will take the decision.
All I was telling brother Pandu
that words spoken out of time
are worthless like the fruits
picked before they turn ripe.
Allow me to take your leave,
brother Dhritarashtra.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, brother Pandu.
This is the reason..
This is the reason why
he is envious of us, Pandu
because we are the sons
of King Vichitravirya
but he
is the son of a maid!
Son of a maid.
No, brother.
Do not be so hard-hearted.
The three of us
have the same father
and Vidur is also like family
to grandfather and Queen Mother.
Neither does anyone ever doubt
the depth of his knowledge
nor can his devotion towards
Hastinapur be questioned.
And grandfather adores
a particular virtue of his
that he does not sugar coat
the truth while saying it.
Do not call it a virtue
but vice, Pandu.
Anything said to insult a person
is not candidness but an abuse.
An abuse.
But, brother, the truth
insults only that person
who harbours any
false intentions.
You have nothing but
righteousness in your heart.
Then why would you get insulted?
You should always be gleeful,
brother
because a melancholic heart
can never dispense justice
and it is the duty of a king
to uphold justice.
Being gleeful?
I shall be gleeful only after
I am enthroned as king, Pandu.
I am always skeptical, right?
I have always been doubtful
of my next step.
With every sound I hear,
I am filled with disbelief.
I keep looking
for some hidden meaning
in every word I hear, Pandu.
All my life..
All my life, I have believed
in nothing but disbelief, Pandu.
This disbelief gives birth
to loneliness
and this loneliness will end
only when I am
enthroned as king.
No one will be able
to make a sound near me
without my permission
when I shall be declared
as King Dhritarashtra!
Only then..
- All hail the king!
All hail the king!
A kingdom is for the service
of its subjects, brother
and it cannot be run
for a selfish cause.
Besides, loneliness is cured
not by owning a kingdom
but by embracing love.
You need a wife now, brother
who will become your eyes
to rid you of your loneliness.
I do not have the time
to think about marriage, Pandu.
You need not think about it.
Grandfather and Queen Mother
have already thought about it.
By fixing your marriage
with the princess of Gandhar.
I know.
I have heard
that the princess of Gandhar
is unparalleled in beauty
and virtues, brother.
And she has also been
blessed by Lord Shiva
to beget a 100 sons.
You are extremely fortunate,
brother.
The princess of Gandhar
is the fortunate one, Pandu
who is destined to become
the queen of Hastinapur.
My King
after taking a decision
weakening the heart
by means of pain and worry
is but worthless.
I am not worried or sad,
Sudharma.
My heart is burdened
with the feeling of guilt.
I feel as though l have
a great load on my heart.
My King, when you accepted
the proposal of Bhishma
I was filled with anger
but after pondering over it
I feel
that your decision was correct.
With a person like Bhishma
and the army of Hastinapur
waging a war against them would
spell disaster for our subjects.
This decision was made
by a king, Sudharma
but a father still considers
this decision to be wrong.
My King
a father is bound by affection
and affection makes one weak.
Sudharma
look at our daughter
in the garden.
She is frolicking there.
Like a bird that knits its
dreams on the tree of happiness
she has no idea that the tree
is about to be chopped down.
She is a princess, my King.
If she has to make a sacrifice
for the sake of her subjects
then she will do so
with a smile on her face.
But how will I tell my daughter
about this, Sudharma?
That for the sake of happiness
of the subjects of Gandhar
I have given her sadness
for her entire life.
Not now, my King.
Right now, Gandhari is in
a state of bliss
and I cannot see
this bliss
transform into misery.
Let her fate reveal itself
before her.
But when Shakuni returns
from the hunt
what will happen then, Sudharma?
He is very fond of his sister.
He will never accept the fact
that his sister is being married
to a blind person.
Make haste, sire.
The rope is breaking.
Prince, this rope will break.
It cannot take the weight
of two people.
Then I shall let go
of the rope, soldier.
That will save your life.
- No, Prince. No.
Your life is more precious
than mine.
Then you should
let go of the rope.
Let go.
- No.. No..
Let go!