Eldest brother!
The guards will spot us
if we go that way.
We must take a different path.
This way!
Brother!
There is no other way, Arjun!
Those cowards have
set it ablaze on all sides.
Arjun! You must use
the 'Varunastra'!
The 'Varunastra'...
No!
If the fire is doused, everyone
will know that we are alive.
The walls are starting to melt,
eldest brother!
'They say that Goddess Saraswati
could not flow on this earth'
'holding a divine fire
in her hands.'
'Therefore, she started
flowing under the ground.'
'If you bathe,
recounting this tale'
'you will be blessed, Arjun!'
Eldest brother!
Lord Krishna had narrated to me,
the tale of Goddess Saraswati.
When it became impossible
for the river
to flow over the ground, she
began flowing under the ground.
It was surely an advice
meant for this day.
Even we must find a way
through the ground.
Excellent suggestion!
This way!
Make haste!
Mother!
- Mother!
Bheem!
Brother Bheem!
Mother!
Arjun!
Eldest brother! Take mother
away to a safe place.
No, Yudhisthir! I...
I won't leave without Arjun.
We will wait for you, Arjun!
We cannot go without you!
Mother's safety is more crucial,
brother Bheem!
Arjun!
Take mother away from here!
Make haste, brother Bheem!
Make haste,
the flames are rising!
No, Arjun!
Eldest brother!
Leave this place!
Take mother to a safe place.
Go!
Bheem! Mother!
Mother, have patience!
Arjun must be on his way.
Yudhisthir, Arjun...
Nakul.
Yudhisthir... Take all your
brothers out here and I...
I shall wait for Arjun.
- No!
Brother, we won't leave
without mother.
Sahadev!
- We will all wait, mother!
We lived together.
And we will be together
in death too.
Before any flame
even touches mother
it will have to scorch us first.
Arjun!
My dear Arjun!