The dinner today is
based on a simple rule.
None of you shall bend
your elbows while you eat.
Let's begin.
Why do we need to
fold arms, Duryodhan?
We could feed each other.
Well done!
That's the apt way
to eat, Yudhishtir.
All of you may follow
what Yudhishtir just did.
Your Excellency...
His Highness
has summoned you.
Princes...
This is not the just
the apt way to eat
but a way of life.
As long as siblings
care for each other
it helps the family
stay together
and makes
the kingdom prosper.
All of you must
have meaIs this way.
Duryodhan, it's time
for you to feed us.
I want 'laddoo'.
We must follow the directive.
When one reciprocates
rudely to a kind
gesture of yours
or if someone's gets rewarded
for one's crudeness.
Then one's forced to think that
what does doing good
and being ethical yield?
But one must think what
a crude human being attains.
One who possesses a rude
demeanour is seldom at peace
and never experiences
stability.
Such a human being would
always stay anxious.
Faith makes him
chase after itself forever.
Is that happiness?
But the one who's ethical
the one who's kind
and the one who possesses
a kind demeanour
experiences peace.
Nothing proves as an
obstacle to such a human being.
Such a man always
receives respect
and experiences tranquility.
That proves that a kind gesture
isn't a way to attain
happiness in future.
In fact one who's kind,
is happiness personified.
A bad gesture too
may not yield sorrow.
Iniquity, at that very moment,
springs forth sorrow.
Righteousness doesn't
become happiness
but is happiness
in itself.
Hail Lord Shiva!
For Pandu's soul to
rest in peace
I've arranged to venerate
Lord Kaleshwar.
That's good.
I was about to
suggest you the same.
But why would the
soul of a pious man like Pandu
be not at peace, grandsire?
Religious texts state that until
the son does the final rites
the departed's soul remains
in the netherworld.
I mean to say
the son has to get married
and experience fatherhood.
And that helps his dead
father's soul attain salvation.
You mean, the happiness
of progeny is paramount
to a father, grandsire.
But the subjects of
a kingdom are
like a King's children too.
Their happiness is of
utmost importance to him.
Vidur, don't be diplomatic.
Whenever I talk about my son
you alter your
religious teachings.
That isn't true.
- If that isn't true
then whenever I talk about
my son's coronation
why do you speak against it?
- I am not against Duryodhan.
But it's not yet time
for his coronation.
Bhil women who belong to the
Malanchal mountains in the South
used sandalwood as fuel.
You must be aware of that.
If one's rewarded things
one doesn't deserve
he may not value it.
That may make him irresponsible
towards his duties too.
Mathura's King Kansa has
been killed
by his nephew.
I hope you know of it.
If a King isn't loved
and respected by his subjects
he can't remain a King for long.
Do you want Duryodhan
to be proved
an incompetent ruler?
Then you must put his
abilities to test, grandsire.
Before that, I need
to appoint a teacher
for the princes.
I want all of them to
to attend the seminary.
They've to become
capable enough.
Their abilities can't be tested
before they undergo
rigorous training.
Vidhur, arrange for
the same at the earliest.
But once they undergo training
Duryodhan needs to
be crowned a King.
He needs to be crowned.
After they undergo training
the prince who's eligible
shall be crowned the King.
That's a promise, dear.
But you'll have to judge
all of them as a King.
Not as a father.
Nakul,
Sahadev...
You both are
still awake?
We are unable
to sleep, mother.
Yudhisthir and Bhim
slept before you?
I will punish both of them
tomorrow morning.
Mother, I haven't slept.
We all are still awake.
The forest was calm
and peaceful, mother.
But there is no
peace here.
That's true, son.
Here the soldiers stay awake
all night and guard.
And the attendants in
the kitchen, stay up all night
and make preparations for
the next day's meals.
And brother Bhim is already
hungry again, mother.
It may be because you must
have eaten a lot.
You are not used to
the lunch here.
We haven't had yet.
Grandsire asked us...
What did your
grandsire say?
Nothing, mother.
The attendants here are
still unaware
that brother Bhim is
also called 'Vrikodar'.*
*'One with a wolf's belly'.
They served very little
and brother Bhim was
shy to ask for more.
Nothing else.
I will inform
the attendants tomorrow.
Okay.
Today you all
sleep here with me.
Mother
till when are we going
to stay here?
Nakul
we will now stay
here itself.
This is our home.
Mother, what kind
of a home is this?
Where no one even smiles
on seeing us.
It seems like
that we have refuge here
but no rights.
Who made you feel like this?
Everyone here is
unfamiliar.
Hence they are unpleasant.
The more we get acquainted
their love will increase.
Nakul. Sahadev.
Now, sleep.
It's such a big palace,
brother Bhim.
I have looked in
all the directions
but there is no path
leading to the kitchen.
You are of no use.
Just yesterday we had
been to the kitchen.
Even you had gone.
Do you remember?
You talk a lot.
Even Durbheeksh hasn't
come yet.
Or else he would have
shown me the way.
Greetings, Princes.
- Greetings. - Greetings.
Hey, mister.
Do you work in this palace?
- Yes, Prince.
Then you must be well
aware of this palace, right?
Which path leads
to the kitchen?
The kitchen!
That's very simple.
Go straight from here.
After going straight
turn towards the south.
Take ten steps south.
And then again turn
towards the east.
After turning towards
the east
go down towards
the west again.
After that you can use
your sense of smell
and you will know where
the kitchen is situated.
Greetings.
- Greetings. - Greetings.
Nakul, did you
remember anything?
I feel that if we walk so
much in the forest
we will reach
the nearby village.
What do we do now?
This hunger is
killing me.
What happened?
- Nakul
that attendant has given
a unique solution.
Make use of
your nose.
I can smell raw mangoes.
Let's go.
Nakul
this is like heaven.
The food made by
the attendants
stands no equal to
the food made by God!
We have the rights
on this tree.
Find some other tree.
We have taken possession on
all the trees in this orchard.
Where will he
now find mangoes?
There are mango trees in
Kuntibhoj too!
If you want to eat mangoes, you
will have to travel till there.
I needn't travel!
If I want mangoes
I can take it from
your hands too.
If he wants mangoes he can
take it from our hands too!
You can definitely
take it from our hands.
What's the big deal
in that?
The weak have to beg!
Brother,
let me go.
No, Bhim, we are not
supposed to fight.
Come, I'll arrange lunch
for you.
Of course! The city is very big.
You can beg anywhere.
That's what your ascetic
father must have taught you!
Now they have crossed
all limits, brother.
Forgiveness shouldn't be
to such an extent
that it becomes a sign
of weakness.
That's what father used
to say.
You're absolutely right, Arjun.
It is not appropriate to use
such words for our father.
Listen, everyone
my name is Vrikodar.
The tree that I shake...
All its fruits fall down.
Did you hear that, dear?
He has challenged
you and your brothers.
That when time comes
he can
kill you too.
He spoke about
killing us? - Definitely.
The tree that I shake...
All its fruits
fall down.
The interpretation is
that even if it be a mango tree
or a tree of lineage...
He will ensure all
fruits fall down.
Child!
My dear child!
This is politics.
You know that!
In the forests, whom do
the lion cubs fear most?
The other lions.
Princes too
fear other princes.
What would be an
appropriate solution, uncle?
There is only one
solution, child.
The strategy that
Pandavs have made for you
make the same
strategy for them.