Elder brother.
How could you shackle me?
Elder brother,
please set me free!
Pardon me, Prince!
Pardon me!
Will you imprison me?
Brother Duryodhan?
Friend!
Can you shackle me?
Duryodhan, my lad!
Imprison me if you dare!
Can you bear the weight
of your sins, Duryodhan?
My lad!
Show me your might, lad!
Shackle me!
The arrest must be made
by yourself, son!
Who is in the prison?
Me?
Or you, brother Duryodhan?
Duryodhan!
What happened?
Why are you screaming?
Will someone please tell me
what happened?
I shall grant you sight,
King Dhritarashtra!
See for yourself!
What... What sorcery is this?
What is it that I am seeing?
Take... Take back my sight!
I do not want it!
Forgive me, Krishna!
Forgive me!
My lad!
What happened?
Friend!
What illusion was that, Krishna?
It was not an illusion, Prince.
It was a premonition.
Soon death shall chase you
in the battlefield similarly.
And you shall not
be able to hide.
Because there is no use
running or hiding from death.
The day the spark of justice
shall ignite in the battlefield
right before your very eyes
the entire Kuru clan
will reduce to ashes!
Farewell, King!
General...
Gather the army right away.
Father, I need to avenge
for every insult
that hypocrite
has inflicted on me!
This moment,
we will attack Virat, Father!
We will attack for sure!
Are you still dreaming
about attacking, Prince? - Yes.
The foolish attempt you had made
to incarcerate Vasudev...
That moment...
That very moment,
we became incapacitated.
Forever and ever!
If you still have
some sense left in you, go...
Go and ask Vasudev
for forgiveness.
That’s impossible, Minister!
I...
I can never ask anyone
for forgiveness.
Never can I ask!
Will I get scared
of that devious person
who like a juggler
sets a bewitching trap?
I...
I’ll finish him!
Whether or not he chooses
to fight in the battle
I...
I will for sure
put an end
to that grazier’s life!
I will surely do away with him!
Friend...
Don’t take a decision
out of anxiety, friend.
Be calm and take a decision.
- Keep quiet!
I used to consider
you to be competent and strong!
Is this your strength?
When that cheat
was setting a trap
what were you doing
to protect me?
What were you doing?
It’s the duty
of the chief of army
to protect his king and prince.
But you remained seated
like a helpless woman!
All of you are weak!
Weak is what all of you are!
All of you
are just a bunch of cowards!
Nothing else!
But I don’t need anybody!
Nobody at all!
I’m capable enough
to take my revenge on my own!
Yes, on my own!
I’m capable enough!
Duryodhan...
Duryodhan!
Duryodhan has lost his senses!
Your Highness, Dhritarashtra!
Stop your son
else, he will be the cause
for a catastrophe!
Your Highness,
Vasudev is still in the kingdom.
He will be taking rest
in my chamber for some time.
Your Highness
please walk in,
and ask him for forgiveness.
Brother...
Please do this favour on me
for one last time.
Let it be, Vidhur.
Let it be.
Let this battle take place.
Not my righteousness
not Guru Drona’s teachings
neither the deceit of
the King of Gandhaar
nor the archery skills
of Anga Raj...
No one...
No one can protect
the Kauravas now.
All of us are now
approaching our end.
Krishna...
Did Duryodhan try to incarcerate
you in the court of assembly?
Destiny paves its way.
Humans only play a role
in executing destiny's plan
by using their intelligence
and culture.
Sister-in-law wishes
to apologise to you
on behalf of the sins
her sons have committed.
Greetings, Your Highness!
If you must
then apologise to your sons
to whom you didn't impart
the right teachings
at the right time.
You knew
that His Highness was
empoisoning your sons' minds
with revenge
and futile ambitions.
But still
you let your sons imbibe
the teachings he was imparting.
Now, the situation is such that
Duryodhan has crossed
all his limits.
Don't be resentful
at my sons, Vasudev.
They aren't aware
of the lightning pace at which
they are nearing their death.
No, Your Highness.
Resent is shown on those
who are knowledgeable enough
to make decisions.
Duryodhan's decisions
arise from his ignorance.
How can I be resentful at him?
I only sympathise with him.
Nothing else.
If you sympathise with him
why don't you refrain him
from commencing the battle?
The way fireflies get attracted
to the light of the flame
and get engulfed by it
Duryodhan is facing
a similar situation today.
How can he be stopped?
There must be a way out,
Krishna.
Vasudev, there must be some way
to protect my sons
from self-destruction?
Duryodhan has utmost belief
on Grand sire Bheeshm
Guru Drona
and on the Karna's capability.
Grand sire is helpless
because of his position.
Guru Drona...
He is helpless as he is bound
by the oath he had taken.
But Karna hasn't promised
anything to His Highness.
Karna
is bound by the oath
of friendship with Duryodhan.
Promises made to the king,
Guru, hermit and God
can't be broken at any cost.
But a promise given to a friend
can be broken
if it is
for the friend's well-being.
Please, stop Karna
from taking part in this battle.
I have full faith
that Duryodhan won't
have the courage to go to war.
Nothing is impossible
for you, Vasudev.
As long as a person doesn't...
make a conscious effort
to learn...
it becomes impossible
for even God to enlighten him.
Still...
If Karna's mother makes
an effort, it's possible
that Karna deters
from his decision...
to go to war.