This peace and satisfaction.
I get it only when I am
with you, Satyavati.
The responsibilities
of the kingdom, war
struggle, schemes,
strategies.
The debate about
justice and injustice.
Everything is just lost
to me.
What more could anyone
wish for, Satyavati?
The desire to live,
Your Highness.
During the time of struggles
we realise
that we are alive.
This means you like struggles
and not peace.
The ones who have
all the pleasures
value peace.
The ones with only peace
would desire
for pleasures first.
And peace is attained
only after struggle
isn't it, King Shantanu?
Satyavati!
What are you doing, Satyavati?
Trying to attain pleasure.
Let it go, Satyavati.
That's a very powerful fish.
You wouldn't able to catch it.
Really?
I'm the daughter of Matysaraj.
Stop, Your Highness!
I place you under an oath.
You shouldn't try to help me.
Leave it, Satyavati.
I will order the fishermen.
They will catch
the fish for you.
I cannot wait until then,
Your Highness!
A fish and an opportunity
should be grabbed
once spotted.
Satyavati!
I wasn't aware that these
delicate hands were so powerful.
King Shantanu, you
are a warrior.
You are the king of a great
kingdom like Hastinapur.
You must be aware that
power doesn't lie in our hands
but instead in our hearts.
A desire is the strength
of the heart.
As much as can be gathered
in the cusp of one's palms
desires stay good only in
that measure, Satyavati.
Your Highness,
God has given us such tiny eyes.
But the same eyes
have the power to see
the limitless skies.
Am I not right, Your Highness?
How can I then humiliate God
by having such humble desires?
Desires, hopes
expectations, ambitions
are the driving forces
of a human society.
Aren't they?
If someone asks you
of your identity
what would be your answer?
Think about it.
You will immediately
realise that your desires
define your life.
The success after
achieving something
and the failure after not
describes your identity.
Many people live a life
dying to achieve
many things
but their desires
never do really die.
Desires make them
run around
akin mirages of oasis make
cervids chase them.
But in the very womb
of these desires
lies the light of knowledge.
How?
When the desires are unfulfilled
and they shatter
from the same,
rays of knowledge enter into
the human heart.
No.
This isn't a story about
the battle of desires.
It isn't a story of any horrific
battue born of ambitions.
This story is about
the knowledge which arises
from the womb of desires.
I
Vasudev Krishna
invite all of you join
this journey
which would teach
you the meaning of life.
It will teach you the duty
of a human being.
It would teach you the deeds
to rise and shine from the dirt.
The name of this journey is
Mahabharata.
'A village in Hastinapur.'
Where are you,
King Shantanu!
Protect your subjects!
Hastinapur has been cursed!
The king has no wife.
The king cannot conduct
a 'yajna'* without a wife.
* Sacrificial ritual.
A kingdom which doesn't
conduct 'yajna'
is cursed by the Gods.
Who will now save the
kingdom of Hastinapur?
Pushpak!
Who are you, who has dared
to challenge demon Hida?!
Challenges are thrown
at warriors.
Dacoits are warned, Hida!
Demons like you must
stay at Rakshashvarth.
You are restricted from entering
the realm of the Bharat lineage.
People of the Bharat lineage
chop down forests of our realm.
They attack on our lands.
If that is true
I promise you
hereafter the people of the
Bharat lineage and the demons
wouldn't enter into
each other's lands.
You should free the villagers.
Stop!
How dare you enter into
Shantanu's kingdom, demon?
No demon will be spared now.
Attack!
Stop!
These demons have accepted
our refuge.
Hereafter, they wouldn't
attack the land of Bharat.
And now
no one would attack them.
Who are you to order?
What's the power that
grants you such audacity?
The proof of power
should always be any combat
is not deemed a mandate.
Not with words
but you should prove your
power by your deeds.
How will you protect
the demons?
My army is standing
before them.
There is no way
they could escape.
The river Ganga would
stop flowing.
And the pathway of river Ganga
will become their way.
No one can stop
river Ganga from flowing.
Who are you?
How could Ganga answer
your prayers and stop flowing?
'Because not even Lord Shiva
can decline His child's pleas.'
Greetings, mother.
Is he your son?
Nof mine but ours, King.
25 years ago when I was taking
our child along with me
I had promised you
that I will make Devarath
capable of becoming your heir.
Devarath, my son.
No, son.
Your place is in my heart.
Son, you do not know
I was waiting for you
day and night.
Your son has been trained by Parashuram* himself, King.
*Rama with the Axe (parashu). The sixth incarnation of Vishnu.
I have fulfilled my promise.
Ganga never falters
from her promises.
I was the unfortunate one
to break the promise
that I had given you.
Else
today you would have been
my wife
and the Queen of Hastinapur.
I has asked for such a promise
that you had to
break sometime.
And about being the queen
then a river is the queen of all
the places that are her shores.
Mother.
I am not distancing from you.
Whenever you call me
I will appear before you.
Leave. Now you should
go with your father.
The purpose of your
life is to serve him.
As you command, mother.
Look, King Shantanu
is coming this way!
Your Highness?
King Shantanu
what is Hastinapur
celebrating today?
Satyavati, my son has
returned today.
25 years ago
Ganga had married me in
the form of a woman.
After our son Devarath was born
she took him away.
But she had promised me
that once our son is
capable enough
she would bring him to me.
And today
she has fulfilled the promise,
Satyavati.
Today he will be enthroned
as the crown prince.
Sa...
Satyavati?
Let's go, Satyavati.
I am here to take you.
Why are you staring
at me, Satyavati?
Your Highness, I was looking
at your face.
Every day, you are happy
when you meet me.
But today
you have brought happiness
along with you.
You are right.
I am very happy today.
I will announce Devarath
as the king very soon.
After that
I relieve myself of all
the responsibilities
to spend the rest of
my life happily with you.
Will you keep me happy,
by being my wife?
Sure, Your Highness.
To love someone makes
a woman the most happy.
To achieve someone's love
is her biggest fortune.
I am blessed to have achieved
your love, Your Highness.
I
have no other desires,
Your Highness.
We would have a home
by this riverbank.
You will hunt fishes.
I will go and sell them
in the city.
What makes you laugh,
Your Highness?
I wonder if,
the Queen of Hastinapur
sells fishes on the roads
of Hastinapur
what would the countrymen think?
King, isn't a queen someone
whose son is entitled
to the throne?
Others are considered
as mere maids.
Rather than surviving as a maid
in the palace of Hastinapur
it's better I choose
fishing as my occupation, like
my father and spend our lives.
Your Highness, I hadn't loved
you having any expectations.
But my self-respect
is very dear to me.
Because after becoming your wife
my dignity would be
your dignity, Your Highness.
I tremble by the thought
of our future, Your Highness.
When Devarath's wife
comes to Hastinapur
what would be my plight,
Your Highness?
Here, I am the daughter
of the king of fishermen.
But at Hastinapur
I will be a stepmother
to the King of Hastinapur.
And when a stepson
is given the ruling authority
the state of a stepmother
is worse than a maid.
What would be
the plight of my sons?
They would only be serving
the king of Hastinapur.
Your Highness, let alone
saplings in the shade of trees
even grass is absent.
I cannot seize Devarath's rights
and hand it over to you sons.
But, Your Highness
Devarath has arrived recently.
I had not known about
his existence until now.
But when you promised to make
me the Queen of Hastinapur
my sons were already awarded
the rights to become the prince.
What are you rambling about,
Satyavati?!
Devarath will become
the prince of Hastinapur!
In that case, I would
be helpless, Your Highness.
You should coronate your son
and then you can come here.
But I would stay at Hastinapur
only as the Queen.
The greed for a golden fish
eventually led your hands
to bleed, Satyavati.
This greed
would make your heart bleed.
Hail the King!
- Hail!
Father.
Aren't you keeping well?
I am fine, son.
But your face...
- It's nothing.
Subjects!
Courtiers!
Today, I, Shantanu
announce my son, Devarath
as the prince of Hastinapur!
Hail the Prince!
- Hail him!
'King, isn't a queen someone'
'whose son is entitled
to the throne?'
'Others are considered
as mere maids.'
'Here, I am the daughter
of the king of fishermen.'
'At Hastinapur, I will be a
stepmother to the king.'
'But I would stay at Hastinapur'
'only as the Queen.'
Father.
If a son cannot perceive the
sorrow on his father's face
then he ought to be blind.
What is the cause
of your anguish?
After all...
Father, what is the sorrow that
your son cannot do away with?
Everyone says that
Devarath is very powerful.
But I have surrendered
before your grief.
Everyone says that Devarath
is very knowledgeable.
But, I am unable to find a way
to make my father happy.
Then...
Of what use is then the
power and the knowledge?
Father
until I do not find a
way to make you happy
I would abstain
from food.
No, son.
You shouldn't take such an oath.
Son, my heart is the
reason of my agony.
Your son can fulfil all your
wishes, father.
You should tell me
the worries that have
you so bogged down.
I will free you of
all the worries.
Son, I do not wish
to get rid of this agony.
I just want to learn to
live with this agony.
No, father.
My father be fraught
with worries all his life
is something completely
unacceptable to me.
I will surely find the reason
of your grief
and also find a solution
for the same.
Devarath!
Son...
Where can I find lady Satyavati?
Greetings, lady.
Why have you come here?
I have come to you for alms.
My father's happiness as alms.
My father loves you immensely.
He is unhappy and bereaved
by staying away from you.
Seeing your father unhappy
you shouldn't be unjust
to me, Prince.
I too am unhappy by staying
away from him.
If the separation is
bothering both of you
then what is the cause
for the separation?
If I marry your father
after smothering my desires
then my heart will
grieve forever.
I will never be at peace.
The one who isn't at peace
can never make others happy.
The shadow of a burning tree
does fall on the earth.
But no one can sit
under the shade that is cast.
What does Hastinapur lack
that would cause you unrest?
My happiness comes with respect.
How would I be
respected there?
What place would I be
given at Hastinapur?
What will be my position?
You will be the
Queen of Hastinapur.
You will be the Royal Mother.
Prince, a Royal Mother is
the mother of a prince.
I would accept you as my mother.
I'll honour you and bestow upon
you the rights of a mother.
The one you accept
isn't the truth
but a feeling.
Just like a shadow.
And a shadow
is always on the opposite
side of the light, Prince.
No, Prince.
I would become unfortunate
if I marry your father.
The ones who are looked at
by King Shantanu
become fortunate.
How can you be unfortunate
by attaining the king's love?
No, that will not happen.
It would, Prince.
Not only I
but my children would be
unfortunate also.
Your son will become
the king after you.
What would be the future
of my children?
They wouldn't even posses
the fishing skills.
They have to accept a
lowly position in the army
and be satisfied.
For you and the sake of your son
they would be destined to die
in the war and nothing else.
Are you trying to say, I am the
reason of my father's agony?
For 25 years
I have dreamed about my
father's love for me.
I have yearned for his
love and blessings.
And you...
Are you saying that
I am a misfortune to him?
No, Prince.
You are his fortune.
But, King Shantanu
can get only one
among two joys.
Either to stay with his
son at the palace
or to live with his wife
in this humble home.
Both of the joys together
are impossible for him.
No, lady-
My father will have
both the joys
and together.