'Sons of Pandu, my blessings
are with you!'
'Establish justice.'
'Slay me!'
'May you be victorious!'
Liberate your Grandsire, Arjun!
Put an end to his troubles!
"It is your duty that you all
engage in the battle with honesty!"
"If you have to make
any sacrifice"
"do so, with a smile on your faces."
"Therefore, slaying me
is your duty."
"If any of you step back
from this duty of yours"
"it shall break my heart!"
"You must abide this order
of your Grandsire!"
"Even though your hearts quiver"
"while slaying me"
"your hands should not,
my lads!"
Grant me redemption, Arjun!
Redemption!
"Your family shall punish you!"
"All the sins committed by you"
"shall pierce your body like arrows,
Bheeshma!"
"You shall writhe in agony
lying in an array of arrows!"
"And at that moment I shall
be present there!"
What have we done, Grandsire Bheeshma?
What sin have I committed?
What twist of fate is this?
That I...
...That I was compelled to raise
my arms against you?
Grandsire!
Today... Today I have opened
the gates of hell for myself!
I have betrayed my ancestors!
I have tainted my race!
And...
And I have strangled
my morals, Grandsire!
Why... Why didn't my arms break
before doing this?
Why didn't my arms break?
Why didn't my eyes lose
their sight, Grandsire?
Arjun, my lad!
I am alright!
You have only abided
by my orders!
The lamp that burns
after sunrise...
does not generate illumination.
That lamp...
only creates soot.
The burning of such a lamp
is futile!
No, Grandsire!
It is better to extinguish
that lamp!
No, Grandsire!
Arjun, my lad!
That lamp...
cannot extinguish itself.
And this favour which seems harsh,
has to be committed by someone else.
Even my life...
is futile now, my lad!
It is futile.
No, grandsire.
Your life is not futile.
I am in need of your guidance,
grandsire!
We all are in need of your guidance!
Justice is the path for everyone.
And one's mind is his guide.
Anyone can give you advice...
my lad. But...
No one can offer you guidance.
You all are capable of knowing
the path of truth.
Now do not mourn, my lads!
Do not mourn!
But, Grandsire.
As long as you are alive...
Our childhood shall be alive in our hearts!
After your demise
our laughter shall fade.
Worldly worries shall torment
our hearts, grandsire!
It is our selfishness
That we cannot let you die!
That we cannot let you die, Grandsire!
Our divine medicines,
can heal all of grandsire's
wound before dawn, borther!
Let's take grandsire
to our encampment!
Nakul, my lad!
Do not bind me now!
But, Grandsire. All your oaths
are fulfilled now!
You even laid down your weapons yourself!
Now there are no restraints upon you!
Then why are you adamant,
upon giving up your life?
Because you are adamant upon saving me, Arjun.
Your adamancy shall become
my restraint.
Lord Shri Krishna.
Opened my eyes in a moment!
Seek his guidance, Arjun!
All your restraints shall be undone.
This isn't desire,
Grandsire!
This is love.
Desire tries to restrain others!
And love...
Love binds itself to others.
Even saints have the
right to love, Grandsire!
All your life you have suffered.
The agony of restraints!
Now you have the chance.
To stay alive and enjoy liberty!
No, Krishna!
As long as I was alive I
never let injustice happen.
And justice as well.
I had hindered justice.
And injustice too!
In reality,
I had stubbornly,
halted the progress of time.
Therefore,
I never let time performs its function.
So you killed him!
You killed my Grandsire,
woeful Arjun!
Is this your justice?
Even the one who cuts a
tree is called a criminal!
But you severed the very roots
of my family.
Yudhishtir, you are brute!
Are you so greedy to
acquire the throne?
Brother Duryodhan!
This is time to bid
Grandsire a final farewell.
I can bid my Grandsire
a final farewell in just one way!
I shall lay your severed
head at my Grandsire's feet!
Duryodhan!
The sun has set!
You cannot attack now!
Yes!
The sun has set!
The sun has set upon the
Kuru clan, Bheem!
And this has happened due
to this vile Arjun!
I shall end your life right now, Arjun!
If there is even an inkling
of justice left in your heart.
Then accept the punishment for this crime!
Arjun!