What have you done, uncle?
What kind of a plan is this?
We had come here
to form an alliance
but have become
captives instead!
In both politics and gambling
the dice keep changing
constantly, my darlings!
According to the numbers
being rolled out
one must change one's tactics!
But how can
Jarasandha's Rajsuya 'Yajna'
be of such great value, uncle?
The Pandavas.
Before the Pandavas perform
the Rajsuya 'Yajna'
and become independent from
the kingdom of Hastinapur
it is important
for Jarasandha to perform
the Rajsuya 'Yajna.'
We cannot attack
the city of Dwaraka
because Dwaraka
is our family now.
However
after performing
the Rajsuya 'Yajna'
and declaring himself
the undefeated Emperor
of the Aryan region
if King Jarasandha
orders us to do so
then we will have to,
my darlings!
First of all
despite being guests at Dwaraka
we were insulted by Krishna
for which we must
take revenge from him!
And second
we must snatch from the Pandavas
their beloved city
of Indraprastha!
We will certainly take revenge
from the Yadavas
but
how can we have the city
of the Pandavas, uncle?
Who will fight
on behalf of Hastinapur?
The Pandavas have not yet
become
independent, my darling!
Krishna will be
pitted against Arjun
in the battle.
If that happens
then the Pandavas
will renounce their kingdom.
The annihilation of the Yadavas
and the hold over Indraprastha
will both fall into our laps.
Have you taken a look
at Jarasandha's army, uncle?
His army is a miserable one.
Jarasandha's might
has made him so arrogant
that he has not even assembled
an army of brave warriors.
Then how could he understand the
importance of a Rajsuya 'Yajna?'
Shukra!
My friend
you must deliver
a message for us.
Go on, my friend.
Go on.
Where are you going
at this hour, My Lord?
The Crown Prince
is in danger, Vrushali.
I have to go to Magadha
to help him.
But you had renounced
the kingdom, My Lord.
I had renounced the kingdom
but not my friendship.
Regardless of a rider
on the back of a horse
until the reins are
present in its mouth
it cannot be truly free.
And I shall indeed
be bound by it, Vrushali.
Forever...
My friend has helped me
on numerous occasions.
Protecting him when he is in
danger is my duty.
Pardon me, My Lord!
I do not wish to come
in the way of your duty
but...
But I am exceedingly frightened!
This is the lifestyle of Kings!
They venture out every day
seeking danger.
You have taken to arms
for them today.
If need be, My Lord
will you bear a crown again
for them in the future?
Do not argue
unnecessarily, Vrushali.
This is coming in the way
of carrying out my duty.
Pardon me, My Lord!
I-I am with child!
Your child will be
born very soon.
The entire army of Hastinapur
is there to protect your friend
but the person to safeguard
me and my happiness
is only you, My Lord.
The gates will seem
like a wall to the onlookers
and the wall will seem
like the gates to them.
Areas containing water will seem
like solid ground
to the onlookers
and solid ground will seem
like areas containing water.
Such extraordinary
illusions will be
created by Mayasur for our city.
All the Kings arriving
for the Rajsuya 'Yajna'
will burn with envy
upon seeing our prosperity.
What is the need for such
grandiose construction, Arjun?
Vasudev can never suggest
to construct something
that can give rise
to envy within people.
Madhav just arrived,
brother Yudhishthir.
He will explain us
what his suggestion meant.
How did Vasudev come to know
that we require his suggestion?
It is said that at the time
of his birth, Madhav
had broken his prison cell.
That is why, be it a prison
of bricks or that of a heart
Madhav always comes to know
who the prisoner is.
Punish them!
Punish them, Your Highness!
Punish them... - What kind
of a gamble is this, uncle?
My darling...- Punish them...
life is a game of dice
and
the person who is
acquainted with his dice
can never be defeated.
The King of Anga.
These are not arrows,
Emperor Jarasandha
but the rays
of Lord Surya himself
and no one can stop them!
If you dare
then stop them!
All hail Emperor Jarasandha!
All hail Emperor Jarasandha...
That is Maharathi Karna,
Emperor Jarasandha.
In order to help his friend
he will spend his entire life
shooting at you and leaving you
incapacitated under a net!
Your arrogance will corrode.
You will be robbed
of your strength.
Even your instinct
of self-defense will cave in
but the friendship of
Maharathi Karna never will.
Emperor, your might
and the competence
of Crown Prince Duryodhan
are differentiated
solely by this.
Competence is something
that creates something new
while might is something
that breaks someone's creation.
Both are essential
but the importance
of competence is way higher.
Now that you are going to
perform the Rajsuya 'Yajna'
it is essential
for all the Kings
of the Aryan region
to acknowledge your competence.
That is why
I had suggested you to create
such a grandiose structure.
But Vasudev
the people who see
such a grandiose structure
will certainly
be filled with envy.
Upon seeing any great structure
the subjects of that kingdom
are filled with pride.
When prosperity is apparent
in order to make the kingdom
more prosperous, the subjects
are always prepared.
The competence of a King
lies neither in his army
nor in the strength of his
allies and his sense of control.
The competence of a King
lies in the sense of pride his
subjects have for the kingdom
in the faith of his friends
and in the envy of his enemies.
The competence of a King
lies in his army
in his allies
and in his sense of control.
You have had the entire
Aryan region terrorized
but where is your
sense of control?
Who is the person
who makes certain
that even in far-off places
your orders are
obeyed by people?
That is why
Emperor Jarasandha
you have not yet been
able to kill Vasudev Krishna.
Who is the person who makes certain
that even in far-off places
your orders are
obeyed by people?
That is why
Emperor Jarasandha
you have not yet been
able to kill Vasudev Krishna.
The killing of Jarasandha
will be a demonstration
of your might
and the construction
of a grandiose court
will be a symbol
of your competence.
When you shall accomplish
both these tasks
all the Kings
of the Aryan region
will deem you
the undefeated Emperor.
But without the order
from Hastinapur
we cannot attack Magadha.
We have heard that
the King of Gandhar Shakuni
and Duryodhan have
gone to Magadha
with the proposal
to form an alliance.
But they can form an alliance
only when grandsire
will go to Magadha himself
approach Jarasandha and accept
a lower position in his court.
But brother Yudhishthir
in exchange of accepting
that lower position
when the Kuru flag will be
hoisted on the palace of Magadha
grandsire will
indeed be pleased.
If you allow us then before
we become independent
we shall annex
Magadha to Hastinapur.
Just give us the order
to attack, brother Yudhishthir.
I am getting restless
to put an end to Jarasandha.
People who can make
everyone obey your orders
are warriors
like Maharathi Karna
and you require such people!
He can go to far-off places
and make people
obey yours orders.
That is why
you must become
the undefeated Emperor.
Only then,
Emperor Jarasandha
will you be able to kill
Vasudev Krishna
and annihilate the Yadavas
while we will be able
to take over Indraprastha
and annihilate the Pandavas.
This is the labyrinth
of politics
Emperor Jarasandha
and no one can
navigate through it.
You truly are
very intelligent,
King of Gandhar
Shakuni.
Conducting the Rajsuya 'Yajna'
will be my first step
to attacking Dwaraka
for this is undoubtedly
a splendid opportunity.
100 Kings who are
allies to the Yadavas
will be killed by me first
in order to perform the Narmedha 'Yajna.'*
*Self sacrificing.
And in place of
the 101st sacrifice
will be Vasudev Krishna!
Brother Yudhisthir
your army shall indeed
be victorious.
Putting Jarasandha to an end
will be the beginning
of your Rajsuya 'Yajna.'