I shall bring all your brothers
back to life.
I shall be eternally grateful
to you, Dharma Raj.
I am very pleased
and also quite eager
to bless you
with any boon you ask for.
Go ahead and ask for
power, competence
weapons, wealth, army
or any other thing you like.
By bringing the four brothers
of mine back to life
you have given me
power, competence
and wealth,
Dharma Raj.
The only blessing we wish
to seek, Dharma Raj
is that may we five brothers,
along with our wife
be able to complete our final
year of exile in anonymity.
I shall bless all of you with
the art of disguising yourselves
dear Yudhishthir.
During your final year
of exile in anonymity
the art of disguising yourselves
will aid you in staying hidden.
It is time now,
dear Yudhishthir
for all four of your brothers
to leave to complete
their meditation.
Even the Gods are quite eager
to see righteousness
prevail once again on the earth.
Bless you,
dear.
What danger had befallen
all of you, My Lords?
There was no danger,
Panchali.
It was only a test.
Call it the first test,
Sahadev.
We have to give many more tests
in the next 12 years.
One's meditation is incomplete
without tests.
That is why,
the time has come
for Bheem, Arjun,
Nakul and Sahadev
to leave in order to complete
their respective meditation.
Will everyone
go in different directions
from this place, My Lord?
Yes, Panchali.
One has to revere
the Gods for ages.
Only then do they get pleased.
We have only 12 years
to please them.
You are correct,
My Lord.
The people who know their limits
become truly powerful.
If one remembers this key point
then I am certain
that all of you will
indeed be successful.
My Lord Arjun
I fear that
your meditation will be
the most arduous one
because when
Mahadev tests someone
He shakes up the belief
of that person completely.
However, the faith
of the five of us
will become your might.
You need not be scared.
And neither do you need
to hide from us so, spies.
In order to keep an eye on us,
you have been
travelling with us
all this while.
That is why, you are
like family to us now.
Henceforth,
all your meals
shall be brought by me.
- No, Your Highness.
We cannot have a meal with you.
You most certainly can.
And you need not tell Duryodhan
anything regarding this.
However
you must tell him
that we will not hide
for the next 12 years.
That is why,
sending spies after us
is of no use.
However,
in the thirteenth year
when we shall live
a life of anonymity
all the treachery
of the King of Gandhar
all the competence
of the King of Anga
and even the entire
property of Duryodhan
will not be able to find us.
We shall appear
only when we decide to.
Tell the 100 sons
of King Dhritarashtra
that the son of Pandu,
Vrikodar Bheem, shall arrive
as their death
and one can only await it.
It cannot be stopped.
These many 'laddoos' are
sufficient for Lord Hanuman.
A sacrament is merely
meant to be tasted.
The Almighty feels satiated with
the devotion of the devotee!
I should keep two more
'laddoos' aside for myself.
'Om Anjani Sut Pavan Putra
Tubhyam Namah!'
'Aavaha...'
'Om Anjani Sut Pavan Putra
Tubhyam Namah!'
'Aavaha...'
'Om Hanumate Marute
Tubhyam Namah!'
'Aavaha...'
Go!
Go away!
This sacrament is for Lord Hanuman, son of Pavan Dev.*
*Pavan Dev: a name of Vayu, the god of wind.
You ate the 'laddoo'
meant for the Lord!
I shall be held accountable
for this along with you.
Go away.
Go away from here!
What would the Almighty do
with two 'laddoos?'
One is more than
sufficient for Him.
'Om Hanumate Marute
Tubhyam Namah!'
'Aavaha...'
Get away!
Who are you?!
You seem to be
an illusory being!
I think you have been sent here
to interrupt my meditation
by that wicked Duryodhan!
You seem to be
an adept illusory being
but do not forget
that I have married an ogre!
My son is
an illusory being as well!
Your illusion will not
work before me.
I will kill you.
Markatasur,* just wait a moment!
*Monkey demon.
You are a strange human being.
First, you invoke me
and call me for a meal
and then fight with me
for no apparent reason.
Pardon me, My Lord!
Pardon me!
I had only imagined you
in your titan avatar.
I could not recognize you
in this tiny form of yours.
Upon seeing a tiny being
did you also underestimate
his might, Bheem?
In other words
you do not know
the true form of might.
I seek your refuge to know
precisely that, My Lord.
You are my younger
brother, Bheem.
By praying to my father,
Pavan Dev
your parents had been
blessed with you.
That is why, I shall indeed tell
you about the mystery of might.
First,
you must...
That sacrament
is meant for me,
is it not?
So, go bring it.
You ate all my 'laddoos,'
brother Hanuman.
At least leave that one for me.
So, take it.
Speed should be
in the nature of might.
The might that becomes inactive
gets disintegrated.
That is why, in order
to serve Lord Ram
when Pavan Dev created me
He gave me the form of a monkey.
I shall always remember this.
Please give that to me now,
brother Hanuman!
Then get up.
When did I stop you?
Splendid.
Marvellous.
Composure should be
in the nature of might.
When one has a lively exterior
it is essential
to have a calm mind
otherwise the whole
of might falls apart.
No matter what task is at hand
it can only be successful
when the person executing it
has a lively exterior
and a calm mind.
That is why
in a battlefield
I focus my thoughts
on Lord Ram
in order to stay calm.
Indeed. I shall
always remember this.
But at least give me
that 'laddoo,' brother.
Take it.
You are indeed my
younger brother, Bheem.
No one can learn
the mystery of might
this quickly.
The basis of might is
to assimilate everything.
In other words, to know all
that is happening around
and the capability of
receiving all the information.
What man fails to see or hear
becomes his weakness.
The aim of might is focus.
The Almighty gave man might
only to teach him how to focus.
If one cannot focus one's might
it is of no use.
In other words,
speed
composure
assimilation
focus.
I am exceedingly pleased
with you, brother Bheem.
Whenever you are
in a battle or struggle
I shall be your might.
I shall always remain
around you inconspicuously.
Your mere bellow had killed
numerous ogres of Lanka.
With your blessing
in the great war,
my bellow
will crush the courage
of the sons of Dhritarashtra!
Indeed, Bheem.
When the Almighty himself
is the charioteer
and justice and righteousness
are the wheels of that chariot
the flag atop it
shall always be blessed by me.
May you be victorious.