People of Kuru
this day has ushered a new
beginning to the Kuru kingdom.
Happier times
and new successes
shall begin today, people.
Before man sets out on a journey
he stands at the gate
takes a look at his house
and embraces each memory
that resides within it.
Today, I too
am reminiscing old memories.
I can recall the time
when, in the royal courtyard
my beloved Dhritarashtra,
Pandu and Vidur
would sit next to me
and study their lessons.
Once, on an early morning,
I saw the three Princes
playing a strange game,
In that game, Pandu and Vidur
had climbed to the
highest branches of a tree
and were calling out
to their eldest brother
while jumping off that tree
with great confidence.
And Dhritarashtra ran to them
and caught them in his arms
and did not let them
fall to the ground.
Upon seeing this, I told
the three Princes to stop.
Then I called Pandu
over to me and asked him
as to
what kind of a game
were the three playing.
I said, they could have died
had they fallen to the ground.
On hearing this,
Pandu smiled and said
that
his elder brother
was standing there
and would never
have let him fall.
Upon hearing this, I told Pandu
that Dhritarashtra
could only hear his voice
but could not see him.
Upon hearing this, Pandu said
that
his elder brother
did not require eyesight
to see him.
He said, his brother's love for
him was enough to help him see.
That day, those three boys
my disciples taught me
a new lesson.
The lesson of love and trust.
Your Majesty
when Lord Yama* must have come to take your younger brother away
The god of death.
he would never
have questioned Him
as to
whom he needed to entrust
his sons with while going away.
I can say with complete
confidence, Your Majesty
that he must never have
put forth this question.
Be it jumping off
branches of a tree
or meeting Lord Yama himself
your younger brother had nothing
but faith in you, Your Majesty.
Only in you.
I will not be able to say
anything more, Your Majesty.
At this point of time
may the Lord motivate you!
This is my blessing.
This is what
I was talking about.
Your Majesty
everyone is eagerly waiting
to hear your announcement.
'All my life, I have known
only one warrior'
'who has never accepted defeat.'
'And I have always tried
to become proficient like him.'
'And this is the reason
of my victory.'
'And that warrior
is my biggest motivation.'
'My elder brother
Dhritarashtra.'
People of Kuru
I am faced
with a terrible dilemma.
I have always had the intention
of choosing the most able Prince
during the coronation ceremony.
That is why
this competition was held.
But unfortunately
the outcome of this competition
was such
that one could draw
different conclusions from it.
The decision is a tough one
because uncle's advice
is appropriate.
A King takes the oath
of being righteous.
When it comes to me, this oath
cannot be forgotten either.
That is why
I must look for righteousness
within my heart
for it is very important.
A King takes the oath
of being righteous.
When it comes to me, this oath
cannot be forgotten either.
That is why
I must look for righteousness
within my heart
for it is very important.
Your Majesty
everyone here
awaits your decision.
You have a righteous heart
and no one doubts this.
You must
ask your heart before taking
the decision, Your Majesty.
I, King Dhritarashtra
announce that
the crowned Prince of Hastinapur
is... - May the Lord
bless the King of Kuru!
Your Majesty
I apologize
for interrupting you!
I know that today
you are going to announce
the heir to the throne
and that is why, I have
come to request to you
that out of my disciples
no one ought to be
chosen in the court.
What do you mean?
- Until a sculptor is satisfied
even the Almighty cannot reside
in the idol made by him.
And that idol cannot be deemed
worthy of worship.
I do not understand you.
Your Majesty
Dronacharya has not yet
been paid by the Princes.
That is why, until the Princes
are his disciples
we cannot coronate
any of the Princes.
So, what does the mighty
Dronacharya expect?
I expect my disciples,
Your Majesty
to pay me in the form of
the art I have taught them.
Let me see, who is the most
superior amongst my disciples.
I wish to see, who is
the most capable disciple.
Indeed, sire.
A teacher testing his disciple
is the most apt way
of judging him.
Then no one shall charge us
for being partial.
Pardon me, Your Majesty!
Pardon me.
What is the need of testing
the capabilities time and again?
If one looks at
one's reflection for too long
one sees ugliness in it,
Dronacharya.
Capability is a virtue
of the soul
and not an adornment
of the face, King of Gandhar.
And it does not show
in a reflection.
But was the competition
not held, Minister?
But there was no definitive
outcome of that competition.
Even His Highness
has agreed to this.
That is why, if the capabilities
are now judged
through the medium
of paying Dronacharya
then what problem
do you have with it?
Certainly.
Since the competition
was inconclusive
resorting to this method
seems appropriate.
So, Dronacharya.
Ask for your fee.
The Prince who will be able
to convince you with his might
shall be the most capable one.
But while seeking your fee
what if you become partial
and choose only
one particular Prince as
the most capable one?
Your doubt is an insult to me,
King of Gandhar.
A teacher can never be partial.
And whether my fee
can be paid by one Prince
or all the Princes
for that matter
is a matter of doubt.
What are you asking for,
Dronacharya?
I want revenge
for being insulted.
The King of Panchal, Drupad
needs to be at my feet.
I was insulted gravely
in the court of Panchal once
at the hands
of my friend Drupad.
The hurtful words of an enemy
denote a challenge
but those of a friend
denote an insult.
When a friend insults you
your whole life gets poisoned.
My disciples
I have endured the fire
of this insult within me
and lived for years.
Had I made up my mind,
I could have defeated Drupad
at that very moment
but he
had insulted my art.
That is why, I took an oath
that one day
I will defeat him
at the hands of my disciples!
And today
that moment has come, Princes.
That moment has come, Princes
when you have the opportunity
of fulfilling the vow
of your teacher.
Who will be able
to pay me my fees?
Do you have the capability?
No!
Impossible!
A powerful and experienced
warrior like Drupad
cannot be faced by my sons.
Panchal has more than
two crore soldiers.
And the fort of
the capital city Kampilya
is immense and impenetrable!
No, mighty Drona.
Ask for something else.
This is my fee for teaching,
Your Majesty.
This is not business.
I want either revenge
or nothing else.
If I could not fortify the might
and self-confidence
of my disciples
then it is my misfortune,
Your Majesty.
But you need not feel sad.
I will go to another kingdom
to look for brave men.
I will fortify them with my art
so that they avenge my insult
because, Your Majesty
I shall have my revenge.
Then you must find
the heir to your throne
from another kingdom.
Allow me to leave.
Teacher!