Prince Duryodhana
is standing there!
Remember, Arjun!
The orders to drag Draupadi into
a filled royal court as a slave
were issued by him!
'Dushyasan, bring that
slave Draupadi to this court!'
'If that arrogant woman
dares defy my orders'
'grab her by the hair
and drag her till here!'
Look here, Arjun!
This is your uncle, Shakuni!
Today he wields a sword!
But he always tries
to attack by treachery!
Remember
how he conspired to burn all you
five brothers and your mother
in Varanavrath!
'In the palace of Varanavrath
all five of our foes'
'shall be together!'
'In that very palace'
'your ascension to princehood
shall be decided!'
Now look here, Arjun!
Dushyasan!
These very hands had committed
the audacity
to infringe
upon Panchali's modesty!
Look at Grandsire Bhishma
and Master Drona!
He stayed a mute spectator
as Draupadi was dishonoured!
Look at Ashwatthama over there!
And remember the foul words
he had used!
'The one who nurses
a relationship'
'with five men...'
'l am ashamed to call her
my sister!'
Does your head not crave
for vengeance now, Arjun?
Does your soul not
clamour for justice now?
Does the desire to wield
a weapon does not arise in you?
Does the battle
not seem inevitable now?
Yes, Krishna!
This battle is inevitable!
Now, this battle seems
inevitable to you!
So, look at your Grandsire
once again, Arjun?
And remember
how he provided you with love
and protection at each step!
He sacrificed himself
in an attempt to get justice
for you and your family!
'As long as you hold the throne
of Hastinapur as a king'
'l shall live every moment
to protect you!'
'But today, please grant
the sons of Pandu'
'one chance at solace, son!'
Once again look at Master Drona
and remember how with
immense love and pride
he bestowed upon you
his supreme knowledge!
'You shall be the world's
best archer!'
'l shall make you
the world's best archer!'
'This is my promise, son!'
Just in order to make you
the world's best archer
he burdened himself with sin!
Remember, Arjun!
'If you wish to give me
a souvenir as a disciple'
'grant me the thumb
of your right hand!'
And over there,
look at Vikarna as well.
He was the only one
who dared to oppose
at the royal court that day!
'If a King ever loses in battle,
he has to lay down his arms!'
'But a lady should not be
dishonoured in this manner!'
'There is a difference between'
'disarming an enemy and
dishonouring a woman, brother!'
'And Draupadi is the bride
of the Kuru dynasty!'
'This is the truth!'
ls all this worth killing for,
Arjun?
No, Krishna!
How can I kill them?
Indeed!
But look at the side you are on,
Arjun!
Now look at the side you are on,
Your eldest brother, Yudishtir!
Brother Bheem!
Look at your younger brothers!
Look at your sons
and your nephews!
Many of them shall meet
their demise in this battle!
Doesn't your head feel weakened
by the possibility
of their death, Arjun!
Now also think over
as to what is the fault
of Brother Duryodhana!
If he was greedy for power
and if it is true
if he was conceived earlier...
If Dushyasan committed a crime
by dishonouring Draupadi...
If it is indeed a crime
even you heeded to your
elder brother
and let your wife
be dishonoured!
Wasn't that a crime too?
Grandsire considered his oath
to be more important
and assumed the honour of his
clan's bride as insignificant!
Was that not unfair?
And your eldest brother
Yudishtir
in order to fulfill
his personal obligation
participated in the gamble
in the court!
Was that not unfair?
So, is it appropriate to assume
brother Duryodhana as a foe?
Do you see justice
on your side, Arjun?
You are indeed right, Krishna!
On both sides
I can see justice
and injustice as well!
Therefore
you could never realize
the purpose of the war
nor could you perceive
the form of justice, Arjun!
My mind has gone numb, Krishna!
Every part of me is trembling!
My hands
do not have the strength
to wield a weapon!
My 'Gandiva' bow is repeatedly
slipping of my grasp, Krishna!
I can only foresee
immense destruction!
Only immense destruction!
Why?
What for, Krishna?
What for?
The agony of insult?
The thoughts of injustice
or the oath of vengeance?
I do not have any such reason.
I have no reason, Krishna
to accept such vast catastrophe!
I cannot!
A catastrophe is the foundation
of reformation, Arjun!
If a branch of a tree is cut off
two grow in its place!
Why do you fear
the catastrophe today?
Do you not know the fact that it
shall cause reformation later?
'Do not embrace this impotence,
O' Arjuna!'
'This does not befit you!'
This impotence does not
befit you at all!
It is your duty to wage a war,
Arjun!
Raise your weapon!
How can I raise my weapon,
Krishna?
Serving these people
has been the most fortunate
aspect of life!
Such are my Grandsire,
Master Drona, uncle
and my elder brother!
I do not have the courage to
raise my weapons against them!
Even if I attain Heaven
by slaying them
it is futile, Krishna!
It is futile!
Krishna, a man lives
thinking of his future.
Even when I look
at these soldiers
when I look at these
million soldiers
it reminds me
that post the war
countless women
shall be widowed.
Countless children
shall be orphaned.
Tomorrow, when the rules
of society are broken
there shall be none to teach
the values of tradition!
The knowledge of 'Vedas'
shall go extinct, Krishna!
The Kuru dynasty
shall be destroyed!
The safety of the Arya clan
It shall all be destroyed,
Krishna!
It shall all be destroyed!
You may preach like a wise man!
But in reality
you speak like a fool, Arjun!
What shall be destroyed?
If a tree sheds a few leaves
or grow new ones
it cannot be held as a reason
for joys or sorrows!
The reason for a leafs creation
and the meaning
of their existence
is just to keep the tree alive!
Similarly, the real reason
and purpose for a man's birth
is the society's well-being!
The society is for the world!
And the entire world
is for creation!
And this entire creation
is for God Himself, Arjun!
The one who realises this fact
can always see the path
to justice clearly!
Yes, Arjun!
There shall be destruction
in this war!
There shall indeed be!
Yes, Arjun!
There shall be destruction
in this war!
There shall indeed be!
But bear this in mind too
that new traditions
shall be formed too!
Old traditions have been
rendered poisonous!
Thousands of years ago
the heritage that was
established by the 'Vedas'
now remain as mere words!
The social construct that was
based on a man's intelligence
is now based on a man's birth
and has become a medium
for exploitation, Arjun!
Old constructs shall shatter!
New constructs shall arise!
Old heritage
shall rise again in a new form!
Just as before rainfall
even the cloud strewn skies
look stained
and the land sprawled with
flowers seems tainted as well
the situation is similar today.
And past the rainfall
the skies and the earth
are washed clean!
Similarly, post this war
the society and the world
shall be scourged clean, Arjun!
Post this war
the society and the world
shall be cleansed as well!
Hence give up
your affection, Arjun!
Think of the benefit
of the entire world!
Raise your weapon and wage war!
I can hear your words, Krishna!
But their meanings
do not reach my head!
My mind is clouded by affection!
How do I see through it
and view my duties!
My mind is filled with
thoughts of my dear ones!
How can I think of
the entire world?
Krishna, you had said
that you shall steer my chariot
in the appropriate direction!
Take command of my soul
steer the course of my life
in the right direction, Krishna!
What is it that
after knowing which
I can overcome my weakness?
Rise, Arjun!
Listen, Arjun!
Know the secret of life!
Comprehend the actual form
of creation!
Plunging your fist
into the current of river Ganga
won't give you anything!
But if you dip a cupped palm
into the current of river Ganga
the holy water of Ganga
can be raised to your lips!
Think, Arjun!
Is it a fist of arrogance
or a cupped palm of sacrifice
that you have assumed?
Can you comprehend
this knowledge?