If the society learns
that you bore Karna before
you got married
no one would respect him.
But instead your five sons
would be mocked at.
I do not wish to consider that!
I do not care for anyone!
When he'd have cried as a child
which mother would have
wiped his tears!
I have to wipe the stains
of all his old tears.
I want to run my hands
through my Karna's hair
and pacify him.
Beyond a mother's lap
there exists no childhood,
Priyamvada.
None at all.
Mother, childhood doesn't exist
beyond a mother's lap.
There exists no life.
Even after I get crowned
you'd let me rest my head
in your lap, right?
Dear, you must remove the crown
and place your head on my lap
or it will prick me.
Mother
aren't you happy
about my coronation ceremony?
A person's happiness
is as per his capability.
The coronation, the palace
are beyond me.
The only thing I am happy about
that after several years
the visage of my son radiates
satisfaction and pride.
Radha, take a long look
at this radiance.
It will be soon surrounded by
the dark clouds of regret.
People would say that
the greed to attain pride
provided a lifelong slur
to Karna.
I didn't understand, father.
A gem lying in the coals
is considered as coal, son.
By befriending
King Dhritrashtra's sons
you wouldn't attain respect.
Injustice and humiliation
are but two faces of a coin.
When I had entered the ground
I wasn't friends with anyone.
Was I respected then?
- How would you have been?
You had no place on the ground.
When it comes
to a test of capabilities
every capable person
has a deserving place.
There should be!
Caste and creed are considered
as proof of power and
capabilities by this society.
Wouldn't it become weak
having lost those powers?
But only Prince Duryodhan
realised the truth.
Dhritrashtra's son
displayed that generosity.
He surely has selfish motives.
- He may.
A 'yajna' aimed
at attaining something from God
is still a 'yajna', father.
It's not our duty to think about
Prince Duryodhan's motives.
To accept his favours
and offer love and dedication
in lieu is our duty, father.
Karna, the scriptures say
that charity and favour
if received from good men only
are worth accepting.
But I assume that you
are so disappointed
that you cannot see
righteousness.
Go, son
Fulfill your duties.
Wouldn't you accompany
me, father?
How would I live without
you, mother?
Wouldn't you accompany me?
No, son.
We will stay here.
Someday when you need a house
which has never been
overshadowed by unrighteousness
you must have
a house to return to.
We will keep your house
away from misdeeds, Karna.
You must leave, son.
May you prosper.
Wouldn't you place the crown on
your son's head, mother?
So that its weight reminds me
of what have I lost in my life.
Son.
Son!
A relationship
that is tantamount to a duty
isn't up for choices,
Priyamvada.
I have to now go to my son.
Princess.
Princess, before you leave
you must promise me
that unless you do not
meet Karna
you wouldn't speak anything
about Karna to your five sons.
For the sake of a friend
you must make a promise,
Princess.
Only then would I let you go.
Just give me the promise.
Bheem?
- I am kidnapping you, mother
as I will be the first to
touch your feet.
But to touch her feet, you have
to place her on the ground.
Greetings mother.
Mother.
On seeing all of you
in the ground
I was so elated.
Sahadev
since when have you
become so competent, son?
And what about me?
When the ground trembled at
the blow of your mace
my trembling heart
became stable.
My Bheem.
- But
we were defeated.
I do not know that
but today
you have made your
mother victorious, sons.
Arjun, today all the ancestors
would be showering flowers
on your father.
It means
a bow is the supreme weapon.
I had said that
to brother Bheem.
Arjun, the bow is
perfect for you
and a mace is perfect for Bheem.
How are you, mother?
On our way, we had learned that
you had fainted.
How is your health now, mother?
Yes, actually
at the ground
when...
When I...
- ...saw two archers in a duel
the love for her son made
the Princess fall weak.
She is my childhood friend
Priyamvada.
Greetings!
- Greetings.
Greetings.
I advised the Princess
that when she has
five capable sons
then why should she
be weak at heart?
Priyamvada, it's
a mother's heart.
When a competition
turns out to be a war
between the brothers...
Mother, we are the Pandavas
and they are a hundred Kauravas.
When they do not consider
us as brothers
why should we then be
affectionate towards them?
We are five of us
and are enough for each other.
Mother
we five brothers are like
the five fingers of a hand.
We neither need an extra brother
nor one less would
be sufficient.
And our brother Bheem
is the thumb.
That means if us four
brothers apply ashes on someone
brother Bheem will
do a tilak
and conclude the task.
That was said by Nakul.
Brother.
Sahadev, you have made me happy.
I am sure mother has
made 'laddoos' for me.
I will surely give you
one of those.
No, Bheem.
Now is not the time to eat.
Grandsire, the king
and uncle Vidur
are yet to be met with.
Mother
allow us to leave.
Princess, you must
think once again.
Please keep quiet, Priyamvada.
I have agreed to whatever
you said.
I haven't spoken to my sons
about Karna yet.
Now, please let me go
and meet Karna.