I give my word!
Fall to the feet of Draupadi
and beg for forgiveness
and the Pandavas shall consider
even that as a penance.
Could you do so much, Prince?
Pardon me, Krishna!
Crime, forgiveness,
punishment, war...
All these talks are futile.
If you indeed wish to avoid
this great battle
put forth a proposal
that seems reasonable.
But can you make your friend
comply to it, King of Anga?
I can request my friend.
I cannot order him.
When a dog riding an elephant
barks at the king of the forest
the elephant is the one
who is blamed
for supporting the dog
with its capability.
In fact, it is your ability
that is the base of
the Prince's tyranny.
It is my suggestion to you
that you give up your alliance
to the Prince.
Only that shall make up
for your sins
and grant a new leash of life
to your friend.
I have faith in your virtue.
And my faith is
my virtue, Krishna.
Rather than betraying my friend
I would choose to die.
I respect you, King of Anga!
So I shall make
a final effort.
No forgiveness,
no punishment.
No kingdoms,
no wealth.
Give the Pandavas free reign
over five towns, Your Majesty.
Just five towns!
[TENSE MUSIC]
Friend!
I find this proposal by Krishna
acceptable.
This is deceit, King of Anga.
This is deceit.
Krishna wants to get
the Pandavas
freedom to rule
by getting them five towns.
After attaining
the freedom to rule
the sons of Pandu
can challenge us for battle.
[LAUGHING]
Therefore, Krishna
under any circumstances
wants to pit the hundred
sons of King Dhﬂtarashtra
against the five Pandavas
in the battlefield.
Without any help from
Grandsire Bheeshma
and Grandmaster Drona.
King of Gandhar.
If the sons of Dhritarashtra
are faced with the Pandavas
I shall stand at the forefront
as their shield.
I approve of this peace proposal
only to avoid this great war.
Not to protect myself.
The Pandavas are giving up
authority for peace.
You could at least give up
arrogance, Duryodhan.
Prince.
Krishna speaks wisely.
Accept to the proposal
of five towns.
King Dhritarashtra,
the right is yours!
Please accept it.
Grant the sons of Pandu
free reign over five towns.
Duryodhan, my son.
Accept this peace proposal,
my lad.
Liberate the entire clan
from the gravity
of this battle, son.
Spare your parents
from this pain, son.
Five towns!
Shall I concede my defeat
by giving up five towns?
Shall I accept
that I fear those Pandavas?
- No!
- Father
if a stone
is thrown at a dog and a lion
the dog barks at the stone
and the lion
roars at the ones who threw it!
Will I ever be afraid
of the thought of war?
Will I?
- Impossible!
- No, son...
And this isn't a question
of wealth or authority.
This is a matter of
personal rivalry, father!
As long as the sons of Pandu
are breathing on this earth
the entire atmosphere
seems to be poisoned
to me, father.
I would rather embrace
a foul smelling bull.
But I cannot grant five towns
to the Pandavas.
I can grant an adulterous woman
the status of a wife.
But I cannot grant five towns
to the Pandavas.
I can behead myself before Yam Raj!*
*Yama or Yamaraja, the god of death.
But I cannot grant five towns
to the Pandavas!
Listen, Krishna.
Forget about five towns
I won't give the Pandavas
even a chunk of land
spanning the tip of a needle.
I won't!
Think for the last time before
making a decision, Prince.
Because when you see your
destiny closing in upon you
I hope you do not have to run
to protect yourself.
Prince.
When an owl cannot
compel the sun to set
it closes its eyes
and imagines
that the sun has set.
You are overlooking the gravity
of the situation yet to arise.
Are you not confident about
your abilities, Grandsire?
Braver than you
was King Virat of
that little Piscean nation
who had not waved
his banner of surrender
even before my entire army.
Because the Pandavas
are your rivals.
Not just the Pandavas.
Even the supreme Yadava
Krishna is their ally.
Do not forget it, Duryodhan.
Master Drona.
Does your soul quiver
even looking at an unarmed man?
What greatness is this?
I shall assuage your worry
right this very moment.
[YELLING]
Soldiers!
Soldiers, arrest this shepherd!
Will you arrest me?
Duryodhan, you fool!
Make this attempt as well.
Duryodhan, do not
commit this mistake!
- Dhritarashtra, stop your son!
- Duryodhan! Son!
Wait, son! Wait!
Duryodhan, what injustice
is this?
Duryodhan, you may die
this very moment.
No!
I cannot end his life.
Brother Bheem is the one
who has sworn to slay him!
King of Gandhar,
fulfill your strategy!
Shackle my wrists!
[CHAIN RATTLING]
[SOLDIERS GROANING]
Foolish soldiers!
Get up!
Shackle his wrists!
Soldiers!
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
Your soldiers cannot bear the
weight of your sins, Duryodhan!
Only you have to
commit this deed.
Pick up the shackles!
Let us see how much more burden
of sins can your soul bear?
Flaunt your might!
[YELLING]
Arrest me!
Duryodhan!
Son!
Wait, son!
Wait!
[CHAIN RATTLING]
[DURYODHAN LAUGHS]
[CONTINUE LAUGHING]
Do not do this, friend!
Such behaviour
with a messenger of peace
isn't appropriate.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
D-Duryodhan!
Move, shepherd!