Uncle!
Why did His Highness
imprison my sons, uncle?
What... What crime
have they committed?
I have come here
to find out exactly that.
Do hurry, uncle.
I...
I am not dispensing
advice to you.
If an onion falls into the milk
and is not taken out soon
then the entire milk
reeks of onion.
Same is the case with the
reputation of human beings.
If...
If this news spreads across
the Aryan region then...
Then what will happen
to the reputation of my sons?
Dhritarashtra!
A 'yajna' is performed
to earn merit
and not to wash away one's sins.
One needs to bathe in the Ganges
to wash away one's sins.
This 'yajna' will not
wash away your sins!
Great Bhishma
Why such anger?!
Ask your husband,
Gandhari!
He has imprisoned the Pandavas!
People who dare to take
to arms in the court
get punished, uncle.
You had told me that the culprit
who does not get punished
becomes the source of motivation
to other culprits.
Yes, I did say that.
That is the exact reason
why I cannot let you commit
this crime too, Dhritarashtra!
You cannot imprison
the Pandavas!
Release them!
King Dhritarashtra
cannot be commanded
by you, grandsire.
Respect the polity
of His Highness.
Foolish Duryodhan!
This polity exists
only because of me!
And I can snatch it if I like!
I had told you before.
If I see Hastinapur
succumbing to unrighteousness
then I shall take to arms
against it
and that will not
break my oath either.
You may certainly give a minor
punishment to Arjun, My Lord
but what are you
punishing the rest for?
Release the Pandavas,
My Lord.
Your Highness
I think so too.
Be quiet, uncle!
No, grandsire.
The order of His Highness
cannot be taken back.
And neither will he do so.
Dhritarashtra!
So, is this your
ultimate decision?
Splendid.
Now, I shall take my decision.
Great Bhishma...
Great Bhishma!
Great Bhishma.
That was utter foolishness!
Uncle, but you had said...
I had said so but now
I am going back on my words.
Politics is just like gambling,
my darlings.
If the dice defects
then one must also learn
to change one's tactics.
Do you wish to see Bhishma's
strength and majesty
beloved Duryodhan?
Just like the Almighty
the great Bhishma
can annihilate all your plans.
Do you wish to see this,
beloved Duryodhan?
Come with me.
Stop, soldiers!
The Pandavas will not
retaliate against you
because they are duty bound.
However, I shall
retaliate against you
because I am bound by my oath.
Either fight me
or release the Pandavas.
Grandsire, because of us
you cannot revolt against
the throne of Hastinapur.
We are not as valuable
as your oath.
Dear Yudhishthir
my oath has value
only because of you.
Soldiers
pick up your weapons!
Did you see that,
my darling?
If that old man
is not on your side
then you will be
left with no army.
Even if the Pandavas
leave Hastinapur
then some other King
of the Aryan region
will attack Hastinapur.
That old man's absence
will leave Hastinapur empty
just like Nandi's* absence would leave
Kailash** so.
*, ** An anthropomorphic deity who was one of Shiva’s two door-keepers of Kailash.
Do you understand,
my darling?
Tell His Highness
to apologize
to the great Bhishma.
Tell him to be prepared.
Uncle.
Minister
I have taken the decision
that if His Highness
does not declare
Yudhishthir King
then I shall not stay
in Hastinapur!
Grandsire
please calm down.
Your love and faith mean
more to us than any kingdom.
That is not adequate.
This kingdom has always
housed righteousness
and it will continue to do so.
Uncle
give me the opportunity
to look for another solution.
You need not look for another
solution, Minister Vidur.
His Highness expresses remorse
over his deed.
Prince Arjun
for the crime of taking
to arms in the court
His Highness has ordered
you and all my nephews
to fast for a day
as punishment.
Crown Prince
His Highness apologizes to you.
To all of you.
Will you not pardon
your uncle, Crown Prince?
We do not have the right to
pardon uncle, King of Gandhar.
He pardoned us
and we are glad to hear it.
You are very generous,
Crown Prince.
Your Excellency
by touching your feet,
His Highness
wishes to apologize to you.
If you come by his chamber
then he would be
grateful to you.
Go on.
I will be there.
Thank you,
Your Excellency.
Goodbye, Minister.
You were correct, Vidur.
Water and oil
can never be kept
in the same container.
I feel as though
the division of this kingdom
is the only way out.
Dividing this beloved land
of our ancestors
will leave neither you
nor us happy.
It would be better
if we leave Hastinapur.
Dear Yudhishthir
you may leave Hastinapur
but only as a King
and not a hermit.
Dear Yudhishthir
through the medium of Vidur,
mother Satyavati has ordered me
to declare you King.
I could not help you get
the entire Kuru kingdom
but
by helping you get half of it
I shall have some solace.
But brother Yudhishthir
has the right
to the entire kingdom,
grandsire.
If you tell him to
then uncle will have to declare
brother Yudhishthir the King.
Then why this division?
Dear Bheem
a person sitting in the shade
of a tree seems dark.
The shade of the tree
taints the complexion
of that person.
If you stay with the sons
of Dhritarashtra here
then your righteousness
will get tainted as well.
This is what I fear.
That is why
division is the sole way out.
We know what
righteousness is, grandsire.
But without your guidance
how will we know
what the desired action is?
Dear
I too shall come with you.
I had promised my father
that I shall protect
his throne my entire life.
And his throne is where
there is righteousness.
In other words
in Yudhishthir's kingdom.