Durochan
anyone more skilled than you in
constructing a grand house
won't be found in Hastinapur.
That's why I have summoned
you for this work.
The palace for Kunti
and Pandavas
should stand shorter than
other palaces, Durochan!
But make sure that from
Duryodhan's sleeping chambers
the Pandavas' flag
shouldn't be visible.
Don't worry, Your Highness.
I'll not give anyone a reason
to be unsatisfied.
Disperse!
Duryodhan...
Son
why do you seem so dull?
- I'm not dull
but I'm very furious, father!
Come close to me, son.
What's the problem, dear?
- Problem?
The problem is that
I hail from royalty.
The problem is that my father
is an emperor.
Had I been born in a normal
business family or at sculptor's
or a cowherd's family
I wouldn't have faced
this problem.
What are you saying, son?
Every son is a successor
to his father.
To acquire the livestock
a cowherd's son doesn't have to
wait for coronation.
If the businessman's son
is not competent enough
then his family faces a problem.
But if the king's son
is not competent enough
then the entire kingdom faces
problems, Duryodhan.
Well said.
Even I was trying to explain
the same to Duryodhan
dear Gandhari.
Duryodhan
you've accepted
that you are the successor
to your father
but it's
a disbelief.
Your father is helpless.
Till His Excellency Bhishma
is the de facto authority
His Highness can't take any
decision on his own. - Shakuni!
Forgive me, Your Highness
if I have said
something wrong.
I was just
trying to explain him
that he'll have to prove
his potential
or else
Bhim and Yudhishthir
becoming recluses
can only be prayed for.
Keep quiet, Shakuni!
I've heard enough.
As an emperor
of Hastinapur
only you will be enthroned, son.
It's a promise
by your father.
The coronation ceremony will be
conducted for you shortly.
Shortly.
I'll discuss with grandsire
about this matter.
- But lord...
Buts
are obsolete, Gandhari.
Before speaking
anything contrary
answer my question
and if not me, answer it
to yourself.
Don't you want your son
to be enthroned as
a king of Hastinapur?
Certainly
but I want my son
to be a competent king
who values righteousness.
A golden crown is bejeweled only
after it's moulded, Gandhari
and not before that.
When my son will become a king
he'll prove his competency.
Today I'll order Vidur for
arranging the coronation.
Duryodhan
we'll have
to plan out something
so that the sons of Pandu
leave Hastinapur
and go away forever.
Create such a situation
for them
that Kunti is compelled
to take them
to Kuntibhoj.
I hope
you're getting my point.
But why, uncle?
Father will anyway get
me coronated.
My dear.
You foolish darling!
It's Kuru empire.
Your grandsire Bhishma
will stop you
from being coronated.
But why?
- Because his love for Pandavas
is above all.
He sides with them.
Just for this reason.
If they protest against me
even then
grandsire will favour them.
But those five wouldn't protest
at all, dear Duryodhan.
All the five of them
follow the path
of righteousness
and those who tread that path
can be
meted out injustice
in copious amounts.
Those following the path
of inequity
aren't affected
by righteousness, grandsire.
And Duryodhan
has started on
the path of iniquity.
I have a fear, grandsire
that the future of Kuru lineage
is going to be really dreadful.
There's nothing to be so upset
about, Vidur.
A gardener fastens
a creeper to a pole
and the creeper slowly
learns to climb on the pole.
If a child is given a lesson
on what is just and unjust
then even he can, soon
change his disposition
and mentality.
These 105 kids fostering
love
trust
and respect for each other
is mandatory.
How will we teach them to love
each other, grandsire?
Vidur
persons living together develop
love for each other
just like when the water
and seed come close
a sapling is but inevitable.
Just the ways
of living together
and spending a life
has to be taught.
That has to be taught
with determination.
Hey!
Brother, for whom is this
grand dinner organised?
It's nothing like that, Bhim.
It's a daily routine
in the palace.
For all the attendants, guards,
the ministry
and the royal family,
such food is prepared daily.
Do you remember,
father used to say
the kingdom in which
the attendants are hungry
stays troubled itself.
So that implies I can
eat to my fill daily!
You, anyhow, look for an option
to satisfy your hunger, brother.
We all now could
eat to my fill...
Say like that.
Don't I let you all have food?
Nakul, don't make me angry.
Go and count
the varieties of dishes.
Stop!
What are you doing?
How can you eat
without permission?
Permission? Whose?
Yours?
Behold. These wild men aren't
even aware of royal etiquettes.
This is what happens
when you stay in the forest
with animals for too long.
But they are our brothers.
So are the orders of grandsire.
So we must teach them better.
Look who's seated there.
Who is he?
Minister, may I eat a 'laddoo'?
Go. Seek his permission.
Massage the minister's feet.
Minister, may I eat a 'laddoo'?
Seems like the elder brother
must massage minister's feet.
Come forth, elder brother.
Elder brother.
Let it be.
I do not wish to eat.
You need to eat sometime.
Without the minister's consent
you may never be allowed to eat.
Come forth, elder brother.
Elder brother,
I don't want to eat!
Dear brother Duryodhan.
Kindly allow Bhim
to have a 'laddoo'.
So much malice isn't good.
Let no one be served
prior to meal time.
These are the orders
of the food minister.
Sugdha.
Why is this room
so well decorated?
Queen Gandhari had ordered
that your room be
as well decorated as hers.
I am not a queen.
I'm the wife of a hermit.
I and my sons
sleep on a makeshift
straw mat on the floor.
But the members of
the royal family
must get accustomed to
decorative and ornate things.
Dushala.
Come here.
I was so eager to see you.
Greetings.
Greetings. - Stepmother Kunti,
where are your sons?
Mother had asked me
to greet them too.
They have gone
to have their meals.
My sons are your brothers.
You have
a 105 brothers.
105 brothers?
Aren't you happy to have
so many brothers?
But
brother Duryodhan
wasn't pleased.
But why?
He was saying
that your sons are here
to become the crown princes.
But brother Duryodhan wishes
to be the crown prince.
And he says that your sons
are his foes.
Princes, henceforth, as per
His Excellency Bhishma's orders
there shall be changes in
the seating arrangements.
Prince Duryodhan,
Prince Dushashan
Prince Dussahan,
Prince Dushalan
Prince Jalgranthar
and Prince Shaman.
The six of you,
for the five Pandavas
will have to share seats.
Prince Duryodhan, seats be
arranged for the sons of Pandu.
Right now.
Prince Duryodhan.
Let the meals be served
to the princes.
One more.
Two more.
Glutton.
Today there is
a simple rule to the meal.
No one will bend
their elbow
while having their meals today.
You may now commence
with the meals.