Stop!
Enemies are not premitted
to go near his Excellency!
Go and tell grandsire
that his grandsons
wish to meet him.
We have no weapons on us.
Go
and seek his permision.
His Excellency,
the sons of Pandu are here.
They have no weapons on them
and they seek your permission to meet you.
No,
they do not have my permission.
If they meet me today
then tomorrow in the battlefield
they will not be able to strike at me.
Go and tell the sons of Pandu
that His Excellency Bhishma
cannot meet the enemies.
Stop!
Go and tell them
that they do have my
permission to meet me.
Grandsire,
all of us...
Before you say anything,
you must listen to me.
As long as I am alive
I have no intention of
forsaking my duties.
In other words
neither will I
give up my weapons
nor give up protecting
the sons of Dhristarashtra
It is the duty of all of you
that you must
battle with all your might.
If you need
to make a sacrifice
then you must do so gladly
and obtain victory.
In other words
slaying me is your duty.
If...
If any of you
forsakes this duty
then
it will break my heart.
My death
will become excruciatingly agonizing.
Even after listening to all this
if you still have a question
then go ahead and ask.
- But, grandsire...
- I know, dear.
The very thought of my death
makes your heart shudder.
However
it is a moment of good fortune for me
because the journey of a very
long and unsuccessful life
is drawing to an end.
In my life
I have seen nothing but misery
and now
it is time for my miseries to end.
And
I can have
that good fortune from
all of you.
Until now
you have obeyed all my orders.
Today
you must obey one last order
of your grandsire.
While slaying me
even if your heart shudders
your hands must not tremble!
[MUSIC]
I have only one question
for you, grandsire.
You are illuminating to us
the path to have the kingdom.
But who will dispense sound advice to us
to govern it?
Grandsire.
It was your oath.
That until you help
the throne of Hastinapur
get a king who is both
righteous and competent
you will not leave this world.
With this oath as our basis.
Did we begin this war.
However, after our victory.
If you are not there,
then who will test us?
Who will test us, grandsire?
Grandsire.
Until a judge gives the permission.
No deed can truly be called just.
When the son of Dhritarashtra get slain
by me over here.
Who will assure us
that this is not murder.
But justice?
If you leave, then this battlefield
will be robbed of rightnousness
forever, grandsire.
Forever...
All of you are correct.
A few of my duties have
not been fulfilled yet.
I give you my word.
That before I leave this world.
I shall discharge all my duties.
You must expunge yourselves
of all your suspicions.
And discharge your duties.
Now, this judge shall
award himself a punisment!
He allowed the wife of his grandsons,
and his daughter-in-law
to be humilliated before everyone.
Hence the son of Shantanu.
Devavrat Bhishma is awarded death!
Before sundown tomorrow,
this punishment shall be imposed!
Now, all of you...
All of you should leave.
[MUSIC]
May you live long!
May you be victorious!
Draupadi.
Dear, could you wait for a while?
You may remember this, dear.
You had said during the game of dice...
"Duryodhan will indeed be punished for his sins."
"But before that every person
present in this court"
"will be punished for his silence."
"This is the curse of Yajnaseni Draupadi!"
That curse of yours
is about to yield its results now.
I...
Accept this punishment
of yours, dear.
A culprit...
attains liberation
only after being pardoned.
Will you...
be able to pardon this culprit of yours, dear?
No, Grandsire.
Please do not plead with me.
Dear...
Determining man's age...
in terms of years
is not correct.
His age...
is determined by the number
of sacrifices he makes.
You...
For this dynasty of mine, you...
have made way more sacrifices than me.
You truly are worthy of reverence, dear.
Will you...
be able to pardon me and
grant me liberation, dear?
Your highness.
Is it true?
Will Shikandini, the daughter of Drupad
enter the battlefield tommorow as a man?
She will enter not only as a man but
also as uncle's doom, Vidur!
She will enter not only as uncle's doom...
But also as that of my sons!
N-No...
T-That cannot be.
My sons cannot die.
M-My sons cannot die, Vidur.
Vidur!
Do something, Vidur.
Send a message.
Do something but under any circumstance,
we must stop uncle from entering the battlefield.
We must stop him, Vidur.
In his safety lies
t-that of my sons, Vidur.
Go and send a message at once to
the battlefield, Vidur.
Send a message, that is my order...
That uncle is barred from
entering the battlefield!
That's impossible, your highness.
It is too late to send a message now.
The sun is about to rise, Your highness.
In just a few moments,
the war will begin.
Your excellency
allow me to be of service to you
for one last time.
You are a guru
and a guru
ought not serve others, Guru Drona.
A guru is one who does not
get bound to any tie in life.
The day I coveted the kingdom
I ceased to be a guru.
I merely become
a teacher who educates people.
Your excellency
I am not worthy of reverence.
In this battlefield
you shall attain liberation.
Similarly
after a while
I shall attain liberation too.
That day
it is possible
for me to regain
the title of a guru.
Today,
I am only a teacher.
Only a teacher.
So allow me to be
of service to you today.
Your excellency.
This is an honor to me.
So, do not keep it from me.
Goodbye!
I shall meet you again
in heaven, guru Drona.
May you be victorious sister!
May the Almighty helps you
get the revenge today that
you have seeked
in all your births.
May your heart
finally attains peace.