Draupadi...
Your duties are five times
more difficult
than that of an ordinary woman.
Thus, it would be appropriate
that I hand over...
...my sons to you
and retire.
Henceforth,
only you have the right to
advise my sons, Draupadi.
Greetings, aunt.
May you prosper.
Parents have one great quality...
Patience.
You should be patient too.
I take your leave.
Every man faces a situation
when all his dreams and hopes
are shattered.
All his plans go awry
On the one hand,
there's righteousness
and the other is happiness.
It becomes an impasse.
When righteousness is
behest with problems.
And not being righteous
ensures happiness.
Think about it.
At times, there's a chance
to speak ill about a decent man.
Or get an easy opportunity
to steal when impoverished.
At times the immorality
of a powerful leader
or a king's attendant
comes to light.
Everyone faces such situations.
Most people don't realise
that such a situation
is an impasse.
We don't experience
any struggle.
We are easily attracted
to happiness
Just the way a bee is attracted
to a flower.
In fact, such an impasse...
...is the best time
to get closer to God.
If we don't fear having
to struggle
and are not attracted
towards happiness
and continue to be righteous
we are not too far
from meeting God.
When a leaf falls from a tree
while fighting the breeze
it goes towards the sky.
Whereas the grass that bows to
the breeze remains on land.
In other words,
during an impasse
choosing the easy path
ensures happiness
and an extended life
but doesn't it become
a blot on character?
Does it not darken the soul?
Doesn't it distance us from God?
Think about it
Your Highness!
Your Highness...
Duryodhan has taken
a terrible oath.
It will be disastrous.
It is pure evil,
my dear sister.
What's the matter,
brother Shakuni?
What is Duryodhan up to?
My dear sister, Duryodhan has
lost control over himself.
Your Highness,
at Drupad's kingdom...
The insult that Duryodhan
had to bear
has hurt his feelings badly.
I tried a lot to stop him
but it was no use.
No use at all, Your Highness.
Hastinapur insulted
in Drupad's kingdom?
Yes, Your Highness...
All the kings and princes were
seated near the podium
whereas Hastinapur
was placed at the very end.
Not only that...
My dear sister, even during
the 'Swayamvar'
all the Aryan kings and princes
were called first.
And Hastinapur
was the last.
It felt as if Drupad knew
that Hastinapur is...
...no longer powerful.
The Kuru kingdom
has become weak.
Your crown prince...
...isn't worthy of respect.
That's it!
Because of the hurt caused
by this insult
Duryodhan is about
to sacrifice
the white horse of
the 'Ashwamedha Yagna'.
That's a greater sin than
killing a Brahman, My Lord.
Stop him!
Killing a Brahman!
It is a greater sin than
killing 1,00,000 Brahmans.
But...
It's not
Duryodhan's fault.
Not using your strength
at the right time...
...is a greater sin, isn't it?
This horse is useless,
behead it.
I will bathe in its blood
and atone for
my kingdom's weakness.
Soldier!
Raise your sword!
Stop!
What are you doing, son?
Killing the horse of the
'Ashwamedha Yagna'...
On whose orders?
On the orders of
the King of Panchal Drupad.
Soldier, raise your sword!
What is this foolishness?
The horse of
the 'Ashwamedha Yagna'
symbolises the power and
prestige of the entire nation.
It cannot be killed.
What is the point of
keeping this horse alive
when the reputation of the
Kuru empire is in tatters?
No one considers us powerful.
For the past five generations
this nation
has not had the courage to
perform the 'Ashwamedha Yagna'.
How can you say that
we are powerful, father?
You fool!
Don't insult the nation!
Our strength evokes fear in the
hearts of our enemies even now.
It's just your imagination.
An urn lying on the floor
is not pure.
An idol lying outside
the temple
is not worshipped by anyone.
The urn has to be placed
at the top of a temple
The idol has to be in the
innermost sanctum.
A nation's greatness has
to be proved.
By performing
the 'Ashwamedha Yagna'.
Father, let free the horse of
the 'Ashwamedha'
tomorrow itself.
Any king who tries
to capture it...
I will defeat him and prove
the greatness
of the Kuru empire.
Duryodhan...
- That's impossible, son.
Your father is just
the acting king.
He's only the concierge to
the throne of Hastinapur.
He doesn't have the right
to perform
the 'Ashwamedha Yagna'.
A horse that can't
pull a chariot
or take part in battle.
And can't be the horse
for the 'Ashwamedha Yagna'
is useless, mother.
My father took care of
the throne
but he doesn't have to maintain
its greatness.
So, what's the point in
occupying the throne?
Hold my coronation ceremony
at dawn tomorrow.
And the day after I will
announce to the whole of Aryavat
that I am performing
the 'Ashwamedha Yagna'.
Hold my coronation ceremony
at dawn tomorrow.
And the day after I will
announce to the whole of Aryavat
that I am performing
the 'Ashwamedha Yagna'.
Duryodhan...
calm down, my son.
Grandsire has gone to
Khandavprasth
to quell King Takshak's
rebellion.
After his return,
I will consult him
and definitely take a decision.
Consult him!
Why do we need to consult him?
A flower doesn't consult
anyone before it blooms.
The evening doesn't consult
anyone before it sets in.
Lions don't consult anyone
before they roar!
Why should a nation need to
consult anyone about
showing its strength and beauty?
Father, I have pledged to
perform the 'Ashwamedha Yagna'
and I will have to
fulfil the pledge immediately.
Perform my coronation, father.
Perform your coronation!
Your father and I
will have to renounce everything
and become ascetics, son.
For the greatness of
their nation
kings have been known
to lay down their life.
Can't you lay down
your position, mother?
Father...
I can't live after being
so insulted.
Hear my decision.
Today, this sword will either
behead this horse
or your son.
The third option is
that you perform my
coronation at dawn tomorrow.