Madhav
Have they attacked from both the
East and the West?
This is not a mere attack, friend.
His Excellency has created a battle
formation in the war.
It is called the "Sarvodo Bhadra Vyooh".*
*Sarvatobhadra Vyuha: safe from all sides.
Only when the "Vajra" lies outside
this formation
can it be broken.
Bet our army is almost in the center,
friend.
His Excellency Bhishma
had been awaiting this moment.
He has the capability to break all
our battle formations.
Grandsire will annihilate our entire
army, Madhav.
Sons of Panchali!
I, Ashwatthama, the son of Guru Drona
am your doom!
Get acquainted with me!
Ashwatthama
we are the flames of a terrible fire!
You will not be able to extinguish
us!
King Virat, Dhrishtadyumna and you
need to go to the back of the army.
The army has no protection there!
Charioteer, make haste and move
forth!
But the sons of Panchali are present
in the East.
Bheem!
You need to go and hold off Ashwatthama! You
need to go protect the sons of Panchali!
Arjun, stay with brother Yudhishthir.
Ensure that neither grandsire nor
Duryodhan reach him!
No, Bheem!
Arjun must go and battle with
revered guru!
- But brother Yudhishthir...
- Brother Arjun!
You need to go and protect the army!
If Guru Dronacharya is not stopped
today
then the war will end today itself.
Go on!
Move forth, charioteer!
Arjun and Bheem
had to leave Yudhishthir and go.
Now, Ashwatthama and Guru Drona
will not allow Arjun and Bheem
to return to protect Yudhishthir!
Today, for the first time in life you
have the opportunity of battling me.
Pick up your bow.
You shall strike first.
One more thing.
Ensure that your hands do not
tremble while doing so.
We had pardoned each other a long
time ago, friend!
Then why should I take to arms
against you?!
Help me recall an incident, friend
that will prevent my hands from trembling
while shooting my arrows at you!
"You are like my father."
"Why is such a thing happening with
me?"
I remember, friend Drona!
My daughter...
You had witnessed the daughter of
your friend being disrobed
in a court full of people!
Did the greatest warrior in the world
not have an iota of competence
to protect an aggrieved, a woman,
a daughter?!
That was the gravest crime of my life,
Drupad.
I cannot be pardoned for that crime.
When the time is right I shall willingly
accept the punishment for it.
But by accepting the punishment
you gave me today
my head is at peace.
Now, my hands will not tremble
while discharging my duties, friend.
Even Nakul and Sahadev will have to
leave Yudhishthir now.
Release the orbs of fire!
Yudhishthir is by himself now.
It is time to attack him.
All the foot soldiers
and Atirathis*
*Rathi: a charioteer, ati: extremely skilled.
need to attack Yudhishthir, the son
of Pandu!
Ashwatthama!
Will you keep trying to prove yourself a
good archer by threatening young boys
or do you truly have the competence
to fight?!
Teacher!
Won't you allow your student an
opportunity to combat?
Opportunity is for exhibiting skills
but one's summoned for a war.
What do you want?
I neither need an opportunity or a
summon.
I just need your blessings.
Vikarna, I can't kill you
for Bhima has vowed
to kill you and your brothers.
But I can make you faint for sure.
I can surely kill you, Nakul.
Certainly, Vikarna.
If you could survive armed for a
moment or two before me.
I'll die of embarrassment.
Let the war begin!
Prince Duryodhan
it's time to attack Yudhishthir.
I'll take you to Yudhishthir.
As per the tradition
only a King can capture a King.
In this battlefield
you'd be representing your father.
Be ready to capture Yudhishthir.
Charioteer, move forward.
Hail Lord Mahadev!
The Grandsire has created a
splendid maze.
He has split all the Pandavas
and is taking me to Yudhishthir.
I told you, my child.
That's why even though he's old
he holds a greater significance over
others.
Yudhishthir will soon be captured by
us, brother.
The war would come to an end
and we'd emerge victorious.
Victorious!
Don't hold him captive. No!
No matter what the Grandsire has
asked you to do.
As soon as you see an opportunity
you must...
kill Yudhishthir.
Prince Uttar.
Uncle's life is in danger.
Send a signal to my father.
Madhav, brother is battling all alone.
If he is captured we will lose the
war.
Madhav, take the chariot towards him.
Our face off is not yet complete,
Arjun.
Charioteer, let's move forward.