Tell the Princess of Yadava,
Subhadra
that Prince Arjun
wishes to meet her.
As you say, Prince.
Greetings, Princess of Yadava.
Prince Arjun is here.
Prince Arjun!
Handmaidens, take these away.
And you, prepare the seat.
Tell him to enter!
Wait!
Tell him to enter after a while.
As you say, Princess.
Greetings, son of Pandu!
- Greetings.
Welcome!
Wait...
Walk carefully. I have placed
those clothes there to be dried
because I am to leave
for Dwaraka.
Walk carefully.
Careful!
Now, move forth.
You too are a very
graceful dancer, son of Pandu.
Are you contented now
by making me dance?
I am quite contented!
Did your brother Krishna teach
you to exact revenge like so?
My brother never takes revenge.
When your uncle Kansa
had abducted your parents
then in order to
exact revenge from him
your brother Krishna
had slain him.
And you say that your brother
Krishna does not exact revenge?
He did not exact revenge.
My brother Krishna says
that justice makes
the world go round.
If the culprit isn't punished
then the world will lose
its state of balance.
I don't get it.
Neither do I.
I never understand
any of the things he does.
Peculiar are the things
Krishna does.
He compels one
to meditate over things.
I have come to you
to learn more about him.
So, you've come to me
to learn about him?
Tell me something.
By submitting to Jarasandha
why did your brother Krishna
leave from Mathura?
And when Jarasandha
attacked Dwaraka
your brother defeated him.
He could have done so
in Mathura, couldn't he?
I don't know.
Son of Pandu
I hope you will invite me
to your wedding.
First, brother Yudhishthir and
brother Bheem will get married.
My marriage is
out of the question.
Tell me something...
- I don't know.
You can learn about my brother
by talking to him yourself
when you meet him.
You should leave.
I have to get ready
for the journey.
Handmaiden, pick up the clothes.
But first, answer my question.
I don't know.
You should leave.
Subhadra.
Greetings, mother.
- Greetings.
Subhadra, I just got the news
that the path leading
to Dwaraka from here
has been obstructed by
Demon Kalyavan and his army.
Travelling by that path
is not safe.
Subhadra.
Dear, why are you so scared?
I will send Arjun with you
to protect you.
Now, stop crying-
Arjun
take Subhadra to Dwaraka
safely.
But mother
is it right to leave
Hastinapur now?
Certainly.
There is no question of
a struggle now, Arjun.
Duryodhan has
accepted Yudhishthir
as the Crowned Prince
whole-heartedly.
Righteousness dwells
in his heart.
You can be worry-free and
take Subhadra to Dwaraka.
Get ready to leave
tomorrow at dawn.
Certainly, mother.
'Hastinapur.'
'A Few Days Later.'
We need to let our horses
rest here for a while.
You should freshen up
and have your meal.
Are you certain
Kalyavan is not here?
Are you still scared
despite me being with you?
No...
My brother says that
Kalyavan is very powerful
and that no weapon can kill him.
He is ghostly white
and has yellow hair!
He seems exceedingly scary.
Your brother Krishna comes up
with the most fascinating tales!
I shall not tolerate
my brother's insult!
Hey, where are you going?
I do not require your help.
I can reach Dwaraka
with my handmaidens.
Let's go.
I do not wish to rest here.
You won't reach
Dwaraka this way.
You will have to come back!
And what if you
come across Kalyavan?
Arjun!
What happened?
Did you come across Kalyavan?
Arjun!
Subhadra!
Are you Krishna?
- I am your doom, Kalyavan.
If you are not Krishna
then you are of no use to me
because Jarasandha had said
that if I abduct
Krishna's sister
then Krishna will certainly
come to protect his sister.
And if you are Krishna
then protect her.
Protect her!
Are you alright?
Arjun!
Brother!
Brother Krishna save me!
Save me from this demon!
Brother Krishna!
- Brother Krishna!
Come here
and save
your sister from this demon!
What do you think?
That your brother
can come here and save you?
Hey, Vasudeva!
You shepherd!
By slaying the demon Shankhasura
you seem to be flying too high!
You think you are
a better warrior than me
and Jarasandha,
the King of Magadha!
Then come here
and save your sister!
Come here!
Show yourself, coward!
Show yourself now!