I have lost all my pride.
So, I quit the game.
Emperor Yudhishthir
you are the supreme Emperor.
Hastinapur has taken your refuge
and I am the commander-in-chief
of Hastinapur.
In other words
your words are my command.
Just
order me to release
your younger brothers
and I shall have them freed,
immediately.
And if
you order me to punish anyone
then even that order shall be
executed immediately.
Your Highness...
Your Highness,
I have been defeated.
I have been defeated!
Despite winning the game of dice
I have lost the game of life,
Your Highness.
I have lost the game of life.
Now, I shall accept
any punishment you award me.
You shall not be punished,
uncle.
I pardon you
and brother Duryodhan.
How, Your Highness?
How?
How can you have
such a pardoning heart?
What is the force
that keeps your heart so steady?
Life is nothing
but a war,
Your Highness
and in this war called life
you always remain steady.
How, Your Highness?
How?
Irradiate the way of an ignorant
person like me, Your Highness.
Get up,
King of Gandhar.
It is a simple path,
Everyone knows about
righteousness and truth
and I have never renounced
either of the two.
This is what leaves me
contented.
Contentment?
No, Your Highness.
We do not want contentment.
I
Crown Prince Duryodhan
and King Ashwatthama
do not want contentment,
Your Highness.
We do not want contentment.
We want the society
to look at us
and put its hands together
to treat us with honour
and respect us.
A beggar has his gaze
fixed on the sacrament,
Your Highness
and not on the idol
of the Almighty.
We are destitute from our souls,
Your Highness.
From our souls...
We are not looking
for contentment
but pride and honour instead.
But Your Highness
how can
being righteous be something
to take pride in?
How?
Righteousness is the driver
of actions, King of Gandhar.
One who has not
renounced righteousness
nor given up being truthful
requires nobody's approval
to take pride in oneself.
Mango is sweet by nature,
King of Gandhar.
It does not require sugar.
Your Highness
you never lie, do you?
Despite facing
numerous challenges
you did not renounce
righteousness.
Despite losing all your brothers
you stood by truthfulness.
Since you are a righteous man
with a heart filled
with righteousness
you take pride in yourself
because the truth is
there is no greater pride
than righteousness
in the entire world!
You are correct,
King of Gandhar.
But brother Yudhishthir
you had told brother Bheem that
you were ashamed of yourself
and that there was
no pride in losing us.
Absolutely, Nakul
but a human heart
is not all that simple.
I have never renounced
righteousness
and I take pride in it.
Then be seated,
Your Highness.
The game of dice
has not concluded yet.
Brother...
May the Emperor be happy!
Now, I shall bet
myself against you,
in this round.
May the Empress be happy.
What happened,
maid?
The Emperor has
bet himself this time
and I am afraid
that he will be defeated.
What kind of a treachery
is this?
When a tree
is struck with lightning
the top of the tree
is the first to burn.
Why are men on key positions,
like grandsire and Guru Drona
not getting burnt
with wrath, there?
Why is no one saying anything?
May the Empress be happy.
Vrushali
you...
Your Highness
I... I request you
to leave with the accompanying
army of Indraprastha
to the city of Ahichhatra,* immediately.
*The ancient capital of Northern Panchala taken over by Drona, near Ramnagar village in Uttar Pradesh state. Ahi means snake or Naga (serpent worshippers), khsetra means region.
Your brother Dhrishtadyumna
will certainly
protect you there.
Protect me?
You are a fool!
I am aware of the environment
prevailing here, Your Highness.
All this treachery
is intended to insult you.
If the Emperor gets defeated
then you shall
require protection.
Despite having the five most
competent Aryan warriors
as my husbands
will I have to seek
the protection of my brother?
Pardon me,
Your Highness
but pride defines competence.
When one loses one's pride
how can he be competent?
Uncle!
Slave, take that crown off!
And a slave
does not have the right
to grace a throne of gold.
I am the Lord of Indraprastha!
Now, the supreme Emperor
of the Aryan region
is me!
Me!
Attendant
go to the wife
of these five slaves
and order her to present
herself here!
Go to the wife
of these five slaves
and order her to present
herself here!
Impossible!
If Panchali is
insulted in this court
then there will be
a bloodbath here!
Bheem has
already broken his mace,
slave Arjun
and your Gandiva
belongs to King Karna of Anga.
Then what bloodshed?
Duryodhan!
There are only
two duties in my life!
First is to protect my family
and the other is to obey the
orders of brother Yudhishthir!
So, in order for
a bloodbath to take place
these hands of mine
are more than adequate!
Calm down,
Bheem.
Duryodhan!
A person being enslaved
certainly does not imply
that everyone has
the right to his wife.
This is Hastinapur
and justice reigns supreme here!
Draupadi is the daughter
of my friend.
She is like a daughter to me.
Do not insult her,
Duryodhan
else, with my presence here
for her protection
she need not await the arrival
of anyone from Ahichhatra.
We shall certainly
not insult the Empress.
We shall certainly not do that,
Great Guru Drona.
My darling
do not be foolish.
Had the mere defeat
of Yudhishthir
given you the right
to his family
there would have been no need
to defeat the five brothers
individually, in the game.
We could have defeated
Yudhishthir in the first round.
Right?
You do not have the right
over the Empress, yet.
For that
you'll have to win the Empress
in the game of dice!