All hail Emperor Jarasandha!
You better not leave, cowherd.
My last sacrifice
will be you.
Have faith in me,
Emperor.
I have not come here
to run away this time.
Emperor, do you engage only
in verbal grappling-combat
or do you use
your limbs as well?
All hail Emperor Jarasandha!
Why is this fool
not making the sacrifices
but engaging in a
grappling-combat instead?
Who is Jarasandha
fighting with?
He seems
quite familiar.
And those two
'Brahmins' as well.
All hail Emperor Jarasandha!
That is Vasudev Krishna,
my darling.
I must stop Jarasandha.
All hail Emperor Jarasandha!
So
is this the might
of the son of Pandu?
Had I known this before,
I would have sent my grandson
to engage in a
grappling-combat with you.
All hail Emperor Jarasandha!
All hail Vasudev Krishna!
All hail Prince Arjun!
All hail Prince Bheem!
All hail Vasudev Krishna!
All hail Prince Arjun!
All hail Prince Bheem!
Bless you.
Brother Yudhishthir,
the ogre Jara
had joined the two halves
of a body to create Jarasandha
but I have divided
that body into two again.
The earth has been relieved
of another burden, brother.
Jarasandha didn't stand a chance
against your might, Bheem.
Not only my might
but also my intelligence
is praiseworthy, brother.
Vasudev was playing
with twigs over there.
Upon seeing him,
it struck me
that if I throw
the halves of Jarasandha
in opposite directions
then he will not be able
to become whole again.
I know that it is a lie
but don't you dare try to
oppose my point, Vasudev.
No, brother Bheem.
How can a person
who slayed Jarasandha
ever be opposed by me?
You truly are intelligent!
Greetings, brother Yudhishthir.
Bless you, Arjun.
The first obstacle
that stood in the way
of carrying out mother's order
has been removed
by the three of you.
To add to your joy
let me give you
a piece of news, My Lord.
Very soon, Subhadra will
give birth to your child.
Bless you.
Subhadra
just like his father,
your son will
also be a great warrior.
His fame will be immortalized
till the end of time.
When brother Yudhishthir
becomes King
his heir will be growing
inside Subhadra's womb.
It is not yet the time to be
thinking of an heir, brother.
It is time to take the second
step towards your independence.
The next step now is the Rajsuya
'Yajna,' brother Yudhishthir.
Yes, Nakul.
I will go to Hastinapur soon
and seek grandsire's permission
for the Rajsuya 'Yajna.'
Pardon me,
brother Yudhishthir
but
independence can never be had
through someone's permission.
It is procured through
one's resolution.
The entire Aryan region
is afflicted
with unrighteousness.
The basis of a kingdom
is the happiness of the subjects
and not the prosperity
of the King
but majority of the Kings
are forgetting this key fact.
The task of making them
adhere to righteousness
can be done only by you,
King Yudhishthir.
We must conduct
the Rajsuya 'Yajna' soon.
We must make those Kings
adhere to righteousness
and the ones who refuse
to adhere to it
must be annihilated
otherwise there will
come a time, Your Highness
when, despite wanting
to adhere to righteousness
one will be unable to do so.
Everyone will
take to the path
of unrighteousness.
Vrushali.
It was a question of the
Crown Prince's future, Vrushali.
Had I not accepted
this position again
forming an alliance
with Emperor Jarasandha
would have been impossible
and a crucial plan
would also have fallen through.
That is why, the Crown Prince
requested... - A plan?
Was the plan successful,
Radheya?
No, Vrushali.
Situations have changed now
but the moment I had decided
to become King again
I had only one duty to carry out
which was,
in order to help my friend
to be prepared to make
any sacrifice asked of me.
Is there any circumstance
that never changes?
During the darkness
of a solar eclipse
birds return to their nests
not because it is night
but because
they deem the day to be so
but night-time
follows eventually.
Bearing a crown on the head
does not bring about a change
in one's heart, Vrushali.
I am still the same.
This crown is my duty, Vrushali.
That is why, I am compelled
to bear its burden.
But I assure you,
Vrushali
that I will
never commit an incorrect deed.
Is your
will power your own, Radheya?
If you had that independence
then why would you have to
bear that crown again?