You will sit right here
and mourn, sire.
My conscience curses you!
A curse!
N-No...
No, Vidura.
Vidura...
Gandhari.
G-Gandhari...
Gandhari!
G-Gandhari!
Gandhari...
Mother!
I have turned old.
In one day it feels like I have borne
a decade long pain and turned old.
Mother
all of us feel
burdened today.
What kind of a strange
situation this is, mother?
We knew the consequences
for which grandsire himself
has prepared us.
But when we were faced
with that situation
the head was unable
to bear it, mother.
You're right, son.
The very thought of pain
scares a person.
But the experience
crushes his head.
Like every part of you
is experiencing pain.
One can overcome fear
through determination
but he cannot get rid
of the pain, son.
Mother-in-law
duty always causes pain.
That's why people try to escape
from performing their duties.
This battle is our duty.
All those who die
in this battle...
We'll mourn their deaths
together
once the battle ends
for the rest of our lives.
But now
is not the time to mourn,
mother-in-law.
Panchali is right, mother.
If a warrior
mourns his troubles all night
then the next day
at the battlefield
he does not have
the courage to even stand.
And the battle is not over yet.
We have to focus on our strategy
for tomorrow.
So that our patience
is not shattered
grandsire is still
holding on to his breath.
We will serve grandsire
continuously.
We will take care of his needs
day and night.
Turn by turn, each of us
will serve grandsire.
Panchali
give me food and water
for grandsire.
I will serve him today.
Grandsire, I have brought
some medicines for you.
Some food and water too.
Please have them.
Son Arjun
what benefit can
this body of mine gain
from food, medicines,
water, et cetera?
But, grandsire, if your
pain is reduced
only then will the pain
in our heads reduce.
You may have ordered us
to go fight the battle
but if you're going to be
in this state
then how will we get
the strength to fight?
How will we be able
to fight?
Do us a favour,
grandsire.
Answer a question of mine.
Can a person
remain disease free
with medicines?
No, grandsire.
The body heaIs itself.
Medicines only lend support
You are right, Arjun.
This body of mine also
does not need these
medicines any more.
My body does not
want to heal.
Until 'Uttarayana'*
*"Uttara" (North) and "ayana" (movement), the northward movement of the Sun on the celestial sphere, between January 14 and July 16.
I will hold on
to this body
I don't need anything more
than this, Arjun.
Have some water at least.
I am the son of Ganga.
This water will not be able
to quench my thirst, son.
Every part of me
desires for the water
in which my body
is destined to be immersed.
You have the strength
to unite
my mother and I, son.
But
this battlefield of Kurukshetra
has turned harsh
because of the blood
it drank.
And harshness, be it
of the land or of the head
doesn't have place for purity.
Make enough place in this land
so that my mother
can get in, son.
Please do so, dear.
That is more than enough for me.
Forgive me, mother.
Today
I will not be
able to
stand to bow down
in your respect.
A father feels delighted
with such respect, son.
A mother feels real
happiness only
when her child places his head
on her lap.
Son of Pandu, Arjun
I will reside here
from now on
and take care of my son.
You're free of this
responsibility, dear.
Don't feel sad
because of his agony.
Fortunate are those
who in old age
get an opportunity
to be a child once more.
Go
and carry out your duties.
May you prosper.
Though I am your son
I have committed grave crimes.
The ones
whose welfare was my priority
were also welled up with tears
due to me.
Why so, mother?
Son.
You are able to distinguish
what is righteous
just as the rays of the Sun.
Hence, the ones
who cannot see righteousness
cannot have their minds
read by you.
You have been hard
on yourself your whole life, son.
Any person who is hard
on himself
cannot behave tenderly
towards others, son.
You were never bound
to attachments.
Hence the ones
blinded by attachments
were only punished, by you.
You haven't taught them
a lesson.
Yes, mother.
If I had been able to accept
others' weaknesses
then perhaps I would have
found a solution for it.
This is my error.
It is not your fault, son.
Instead, it is my fault.
I have not passed down
any unholiness or weakness
to you.
To know others' weaknesses
it is necessary for
some weakness to exist
in oneself.
Only the one who battles
with his weakness
can impart knowledge
about it.
You are the epitome of purity
in this world, mother.
Then how
did this son of yours
turn into an unholy person?
How so, mother?
You are not unholy, Devavrata.
You have lived as the epitome
of holiness, my son.
Then why
do I not receive salvation,
mother?
I am here for that
very purpose, son.
Your tasks in life that
you have considered as
your virtues
and all that you have considered
as your sins
need to be renunciated, my dear.
Let those toils be washed away
with these droplets of blood
from your body.
Become the epitome
of knowledge, my son.
When a person capable enough
comes to you for that knowledge
then renunciate even that.
At that moment I shall
engulf you in my tides.
Till that moment
I shall stay near you, son.
Subsequent to your death
on earth
I shall wait for
the time of your rebirth
in the Heavens, son.
Today
the thirst of my life
has subsided, mother.
It is now quenched.
Oh, great warriors!
Grandsire Bhishma's defeat
is no reason for us
to be frustrated.
The Pandavas
have not defeated him.
Due to his oath
he gave up his weapons.
Neither has this
added to the valour
of our adversaries
nor has it increased
their chances of victory.
Do not forget, my great warriors
that in eight directions
eight gigantic elephants
jointly bear the weight
of the sky.
They are called legends.
The fall of one legend
would not let the sky collapse.
Grandsire Bhishma was
certainly a great warrior.
But we do possess
other undefeated warriors
as him.
It is hard for even Lord Indra
to retribute to his arrows.
He has immense power
and owns divine weapons.
Similar to Grandsire Bhishma
he is also the disciple
of Lord Parashuram.
Oh, great warriors!
Going forward,
in the battle-field
you shall be lead
by your commander-in-chief.
Disciple of Lord Parashuram
and a great warrior
Karna, the king of Anga.
Oh, great Karna!
The time to demonstrate
your valour has come.
Dear friend, Karna.
I have complete faith in you.
You do not have any reason
to be biased
towards the Pandavas.
Neither are you related
to the Pandavas
nor are they your disciples.
Dear, Karna.
You and only you
shall annihilate those Pandavas.