I will certainly emerge
victorious in this battle.
I will become the emperor
of all the kingdoms.
After me, my son Laxman...*
*"Auspicious."
After him, his son
will become the emperor.
If the last survivor
of the Pandavas' lineage
is being nurtured
in anyone's womb
he will be killed,
before he is even born.
Listen carefully, mother.
I will die and the five Pandavas
will survive...
Don't you even think
of such a scenario.
Until I receive the news
of the death
of those five brothers
my soul will not leave my body.
It won't.
I take that vow!
The King of Panchal Dhrupad,
Commander Shikhandini
and Prince Dhrishtadyumna
are entering!
Stay blessed.
Father
where are my sons?
Can a child stay away
from his mother's love?
Mother, my life revolves
around the inspiration
of my father Yudhisthir's
righteousness.
Bless me
that in the coming battle
I am able to live up
to everyone's expectations.
Prativindhya
*Prativindya means Drupadi's son. Other name: Shrutavindha "related to the Buddhi (righteousness)."
may you have a very long life.
Greetings, mother.
I am the heir to my father
Bheem's strength.
Bless me, mother
so that I am able to crush
the heads of my enemies.
So be it, Sutasom.*
"Manifestation of the mind", because he was born after Bhima had performed a thousand Soma** sacrifices.)**A Vedic ritual drink, juice extract of Ephedra sinica stalk.
Mother, bless me so that I can
make my father Arjun's powers
my achievements.
Every arrow you shoot
will be reinforced with my blessings, Sutakarma.*
*Action taken by his son.
May you have a very long life.
Mother, bless me so
that I become as effective
as the sharp sword
of my father Nakul
against our enemies.
Satanika*
*Named after a famous king in the Kuru lineage who had that name and he was considered to be an avatar of Visvadevas (various Vedic gods).
all your ambitions
will be fulfilled.
You have my blessings.
Mother, bless me
so that like my father Sahadev
even my insight always
helps our side.
Srutasena,* it will certainly be so.
*With a famous army.
You will always
have my blessings.
Mother
we will face every attack
meant for our fathers.
You are my sons.
You are impossible to defeat
on the battlefield.
And I will act
as my brothers' shield.
Give me such a blessing.
May you be immortal,
Abhimanyu.
Go.
Take blessings from
your fathers.
Your Majesty
Uttara is fortunate
that she is getting married
to Prince Abhimanyu.
When Uttara's son
will rule Indraprastha
sitting on the royal throne
he will be protected
by five uncles.
Abhimanyu's son?
The greatest of the Yadavs,
Krishna, has promised me
that Uttara will give birth
to the emperor who will
rule over the entire nation.
Abhimanyu will be the reason
behind the change of an epoch
and his son
will take the first step
towards that change.
Govind.
Govind
what is going to happen
in the battle
between the Kauravas
and the Pandavas?
I need to know.
Why such a question suddenly,
my friend?
In this battle, Bheem and Arjun
shall fulfil their oaths.
Sinners shall be punished.
Righteousness shall win.
Who all will die, Govind?
Who all will survive?
Who can know the result
of a battle?
You can.
Tell me.
Why did the sacred thread
tied by me, break?
You said that Abhimanyu shall
be the reason behind the change
but his son will take the first
step towards that change.
You said that Abhimanyu's son
shall be the ruler of the nation
But my elder son Prativindhya
has the foremost right
to the throne of Hastinapur.
Why will his son
not become the emperor?
Why will Abhimanyu
not become the emperor himself?
There is some deep meaning
in your words, Govind.
But I want a clear answer.
The sorrow of the future destroys
the joys of the present.
The joys of the future
cannot erase
the grief of the future.
Don't try to know the future.
It won't help you
in any manner.
Learn to live in the present.
Perform your duties.
And don't try to find out the
Almighty's plans for the future.
That means...
Will Abhimanyu
die?
And my five sons...
Govind!
Will they also...
Will they die as well?