All hail son of Pandu, Arjun!
All hail son of Pandu, Arjun...
Prince Arjun has bound
Prince Duryodhan with ice.
All hail son of Pandu, Arjun!
Greetings, teacher!
- May you live long.
Arjun.
I am proud of you.
You are nonpareil.
The winner of today's
competition is undoubtedly you.
No other warrior has
the competence or adroitness
to defeat you.
Arjun is not only the most
superior among the Kuru Princes
but also no warrior in the world
can match up to him.
Subjects of Hastinapur!
My disciple
and your Prince Arjun
in reality, is truly
the best archer of the world.
All hail son of Pandu, Arjun!
Arjun, release him
from this bond.
All hail...
All hail son of Pandu, Arjun!
Karna...
Who are you?
With whose permission did you
dare to shoot an arrow like so?
When one makes a sound
between two mountains, sire
the sound is bound to echo!
A mountain waits
for no one's permission!
Sanjay.
What is happening here?
- Your Majesty
some archer has released
Prince Duryodhan from his bond.
Now, he is making
his way to the arena
maybe, to challenge Arjun.
Namely, we also have such
brave men among our subjects.
You are challenging Arjun, lad!
Do you not know
that this competition is
only between the Kuru Princes?
It was, sire.
And until this competition
was between the Kuru Princes
I was silent.
But upon seeing a few stunts by
Arjun, your excitement soared so
that you challenged
the entire world?
You declared Arjun
the world's best archer?
I too am a part
of the world, sire.
So, the dignity of millions
of archers of the world
and preserving it
is resting upon my shoulders.
That is why, you must either say
that Arjun is the best
only among the Kuru Princes
or order him
to accept my challenge and
add further glory
to your teachings.
Do you even have
a weapon in your hands
or just in your tongue?
Kripacharya,
this is a major crisis.
In the presence of
so many distinguished guests
the dynasty of Kuru
has been insulted.
To say that Arjun will win
might be an overstatement
but how can a Kuru Prince
accept a common man's challenge?
And if he loses
the Kuru kingdom will be forever
labelled a weak one, Vidur.
What are you pondering, sire?
Do you not have faith
in your disciple or
in your teaching?
What are you pondering, sire?
Do you not have faith
in your disciple or
in your teaching?
'I am Karna.'
'I seek to learn the art
of archery from you.'
'My father is the charioteer
of the great Bhishma.'
'I shall return
but let me assure you'
'that I shall return as the
most skilled archer of India.'
'And I will be superior
to all your disciples.'
I know you.
Are you not the one
who had come to become
my disciple? - No, sire.
The one you had seen that day
had died the very instant
you had refused to accept him
as your disciple.
You were fortunate, lad!
You were fortunate.
Otherwise you would have
lost your right hand's thumb.
People choose different paths
in order to become great!
Some choose effort
and some choose deception.
Similarly, a warrior
engages in battle
while a murderer poisons people.
Is this not what you wish
to say uncle?
That is exactly
what I wish to say, Arjun.
That is what I wish to say.
To decline the challenge
is an insult to your teacher.
Accept it.
- I had accepted it the moment
it had been made to me.
Now, I only await
the competition to begin.
Stop, Prince!
Before the competition begins,
it is crucial to know
as to who the challenger is.
According to the norms
of religion and traditions
a king can fight only with
another king or a prince.
And a prince
can fight only with another
prince or a chief minister.
And a chief minister
can fight only with another
chief minister or a general.
In other words, a warrior
can challenge someone
equal to his rank
or a person who is of
a higher rank than him.
Who are you, lad?
You did not introduce yourself.
Before challenging anyone
to a fight
introduce yourself, lad.
Who are you?
You do not seem like a prince.
To which clan of Kshatriya
do you belong?
Do not ask him
that question, Kripacharya.
A warrior who bears such courage
does not deserve to be insulted.
Insult?
Telling about
my lineage and clan
is not insulting to me, sire.
I am
the great Bhishma's charioteer,
Adhirath Sushain's son.
Shudra!
So, you are the son
of a charioteer!
Despite being the son
of a charioteer
how did you even dare
to learn the art of weaponry?
Yes, I am a charioteer's son!
And I am proud of my father
who provided service to Bhishma
with complete devotion.
I am proud of my mother
who has fortified every inch
of me with her love.
Even today, because
of my mother Radha
when people call me Radheya
my heart becomes ecstatic.
I condemn every person
who is ashamed to be associated
with his parents' identity
and finds it an insult!
The son of a charioteer
cannot compete with a prince.
Why can he not?
How is my capability
related to my caste?
No one questions a waterfall
that cleaves through mountains
as to where its source is!
Its strength is its identity!
No one asks the lotus
that is offered to Lord Shiva
as to where it originated!
Its beauty is its clan!
Then why do you ask me?
Why?
No one asks the lotus
that is offered to Lord Shiva
as to where it originated.
Its beauty is its clan.
Then why do you ask me?
Why?
Pardon him, Kripacharya.
Let us go, son.
No, father.
Today, I must prove
my capabilities in this arena.
I am undoubtedly a better
archer than Prince Arjun.
Be quiet, Radhe!
And let us leave!
It is your father's order
that you will not
compete in this!
Go away, son of a charioteer!
Listen to your father
because he knows that your kind
has no capabilities!
Go away, son of a charioteer!
Go away!
Did I not tell you?
To make a place here
and to garner respect
are two things destiny
will never bless us with.
Let us go, Karna.
Karna!
Let us go from here!
Go away, son of a charioteer!
Go away!
Son.
L-Let us go from here.
Let us go.
Stop, archer!
I wish to ask royal teacher
Kripacharya a question.
When Ravan, a Brahmin,
put forth a challenge
then why did Lord Ram,
a Kshatriya, accept it?
When challenged by a descendant
of the demon clan
why did our ancestor Dushyant
decide to fight him?
Because they both were kings.
It is tradition that...
- That
if this archer were to be
the king of a region
then he can challenge Arjun.
Then from this moment
this archer is a king.
I declare him king!