Arjun!
Stop, Duryodhan.
Dusk sets is not because of a person.
But because of time.
Hence, don't get angry, dear.
Because tomorrow morning.
You will need both anger and courage.
Grandsire...
Soldiers!
Grandsire's head needs support.
Go and get some pillows.
No, dear.
I don't need any kind of comfort.
It isn't nice to wish
for any kind of comfort,
during one's last journey.
The less the burden of comforts are,
the easier the journey gets.
Dear,
don't give my head any comfort.
Just keep it in an upright position.
Arjun!
If a warrior gets...
the support of arrows,
after his death he goes to heaven.
Grandsire
I have hurt you a lot.
I even insulted you, Grandsire.
But the respect my heart holds
for you has never reduced.
I have always seen you as the
leader of Hastinapur, Grandsire.
The leader who stopped you from
reaching the limit of skies.
Today...
Now, the leader is going
to go away from all of you.
I hold no anger against you.
If you seek forgiveness from me today
I will definitely forgive you, dear.
F- Forgive... Forgive me, Grandsire.
Forgive me, Grandsire.
And bless me, so that I
attain victory, Grandsire.
- Bless me.
- No, dear.
I cannot grant your wish.
Because I have already blessed
Yudhisthir to be victorious.
I cannot do politics anymore.
But...
Even you have right
on my blessings, dear.
I...
bless you,
that while breathing your last,
your face will have a
smile of contentment.
If...
you achieve contentment
out of righteous deeds,
you will go to heaven.
But if you achieve contentment
out of unrighteous deeds,
you will go to the nether world.
Now, the decision is up to you, dear.
Grandsire, even while dying you
couldn't give up on your inclinations.
I had thought that in your last moments,
you would show some generosity.
But no...
you have always been against me, Grandsire.
Look, Grandsire...
The sun is moving towards the south now.
It is believed
that the sun moving towards the north,
leads one to heaven.
And the sun that heads towards the south,
takes one to the nether world.
This is your punishment, Grandsire.
It is the punishment for your partiality.
You will have to suffer in
the nether world, Grandsire.
You have to suffer.
Duryodhan,
what kind of a misdeed
you have committed?
How could you curse Grandsire?
All these are pointless, Bheem.
One paves the way to heaven
or hell by one's actions.
The movement of sun has
nothing to do with it.
Grandsire Bhisma had found
himself a place in heaven.
The minute he sacrificed traditions
and recognised the true
form of righteousness.
Hence
you don't need to worry, Bheem.
You are blessed with the
boon of self willed death.
Free yourself from this pain.
No, dear.
Pain
sacred the soul.
Pain cleanses the soul, dear.
All of you
should stop worrying about my pain.
I have
decided
that I
will lie down on this bed of arrows
and await my death every moment.
My lifelong deeds
will continue to hurt me
in the form of arrows, Vasudev.
The way
even elderly person is followed
by deeds of his lifetime.
When Yudhistir receives knowledge,
Bheem receives justice,
Arjun receives prestige, and Nakul and Sahadev receives happiness and contentment.
Only then will I be able
to let go of this body.
When the throne of Hastinapur
sees justice and courage together.
Only then will the
subjects of the Kuru dynasty
experience heaven on earth.
Only then
will I accept my departure to heaven.
Now
I wish to be left alone, Pandavas.
I want to bear this pain
all alone.
All of you should now depart.
That's an order.
Your highness,
Hastinapur's flag has been destroyed.
And the pillar that held it
high, too has been brought down.
Hastinapur's flag...
has been destroyed.
I know everything, Vidura.
I know everything.
I know that the Pandavas have brutally
attacked Hastinapur's dignity and prestige.
All the five had together attacked, Vidura.
Grandsire's pious body,
was tarnished with arrows by them, Vidura.
With arrows!
Pandavas, Your Highness?
Your sons were the one who
made the attack.
An old man, who has the rights on all the comforts in the world. He was handed weapons...
And taken to the battlefield,
by your sons.
The one who should be
respected and honored...
The eldest member of such a family...
has been injured with various
humiliations and poisonous...
allegations by your son.
Whose death-bed...
deserves to be as soft
as a mother's heart.
That old man.
is lying on a death-bed
made of arrows
because of your sons.
Even when the birds
leave their nest,
they don't destroy it.
But your sons...
Your sons set the roof under
which this family lives on fire.
- Prime Minister!
- Not Prime Minister, Your Highness!
I have renounced that position,
the day this battle began.
If you want to punish me,
then lift the sword,
and kill me, beheaded me.
But I will not be able
to stay quiet today.
Instead of letting such
children live,
why didn't you kill them
at the time of their birth?
Vidura!
Are you watching?
Look, my hands lost
their strength.
My feet...
My feet cannot take the burden
of my body!
In such circumstances,
don't wound my heart, my dear.
Don't leave me in times like this.
It's your sons that have
wounded many hearts, sire.
The place of the coal is in the stove.
You cannot place it on the throne.
Your son is the coal of
this lineage, sire.
And you,
tried to give that son
the throne!
That is Kuru dynasty's and
your misfortune, sire.
I have renounced you, sire.
I will not see you even at the
time of your death.
Even your shadows seems
like fire to me.
Yes.
Till King Yudhistira's arrival,
I will continue to protect
the throne and the nation,
to the best of my ability.
And keep in mind, sire.
This battle will not continue
for as long as it has been,
going on.
All your 100 sons will be killed.
And soon the Pandavas,
will be victorious and succesfull.
And you...
You will sit here,
and mourn, sire.
My concsience will cursed you!
Cursed!