Kunti!
Arjun!
Yudhishthir, Bheem,
Nakul, Sahadev!
No!
Mother
Bhagirath had brought you
to the earth from heaven
so that his subjects could
offer the ashes of their
beloved deceased in your waters
and pray for their salvation.
Have you ever seen
an unfortunate event
when a person came
to offer his own ashes?
Today, I am here, mother
to offer you my own ashes
and pray for my salvation.
These are my ashes, mother.
The way the skeletons
are the basis of a body
the sons of Pandu
were the basis of my life.
They were the basis
of all my hopes.
They were the basis of the
future of my kingdom's subjects.
The leaves of a tree
may fall off
but its roots can
never attain liberation.
You are the root of the
tree of righteousness, uncle.
How can you attain liberation?
The tree has fallen, Vidur.
Hastinapur's tree
of righteousness fell today.
It fell.
Every inch of me is burning
with anger and dejection.
I feel like following
Lord Parashuram's example
by drawing my weapons
and destroying the entire
Kuru dynasty!
I feel like punishing
Duryodhan and his brothers
in such a manner
that they repent
for their sins
till the end of time!
I feel like following
Lord Parashuram's example
and punishing Duryodhan
and his brothers
in such a manner
that they repent
for their sins
till the end of time!
But I...
But I cannot do so, Vidur.
I...
I am helpless.
Even if one's child is a sinner
one cannot kill it
with one's hands.
Now, my heart
hopes for nothing in this world.
My end must be near.
No, uncle!
I have faith
in your merits and in that
of my ancestors.
The tree of righteousness
can never fall.
But just for a little while
it has been clouded by
the mist of unrighteousness.
But when the time is right
that mist will certainly
clear up, uncle
and that tree will be
visible once again.
How?
How, Vidur?
I had a suspicion, uncle
that Duryodhan and
the King of Gandhar, Shakuni
had hatched a conspiracy
in Varnavrat.
I had informed Yudhishthir
about the same, uncle.
Does this mean
that the sons of Pandu
are alive?
They must certainly be, uncle.
Rahu can swallow the sun
only for a few moments
but not forever.
They must certainly
be alive, uncle.
And when the time is right,
they will show themselves.
Arjun
we cannot look like
Princes any longer.
If the news of our survival
reaches Hastinapur
then a search party
will be sent for us.
Brother Yudhishthir
we should give up
our kingly clothes
and dress up as ascetics.
That's a sensible idea.
We will dress up
as 'Brahmins' and sages
and proceed to the West.
After travelling for a few days
we will reach the place
where father and mother Madri
have been commemorated.
The place where
our lives had begun.