In spite of you not being a king
my father sends you
his greetings.
And now, let me greet you.
I am sorry to hear that your
father died in the forest.
When the sun distances
itself from the earth
the earth is covered
with darkness.
When a father is away
from a son
the son's life is covered
with darkness.
Thus, intelligent people keep
a part of the sun
which is a lamp, they
always keep it with them.
Sir, I too have kept a part
of my father with me.
The dices.
They have been made from
the ashes of my late father.
When alive
my father agreed with me
most of the times.
And now, he agrees
to everything I say.
Five.
The son of Bharadwaj
the great teacher Dronacharya
arrives!
Greetings, Sire.
We welcome you, Dronacharya.
- Thank you.
The king wishes to know
what progress the princess have
made at your hermitage?
The king would also like to know
what is the capability
of each prince.
May king Dhritarashtra prosper.
My great father
the great sage Bharadwaj
would feel proud
such is the knowledge I have
imparted to the princes, O King.
The souls of your departed
ancestors would be pleased
such is the knowledge
derived by the princes.
I am sure my son Duryodhan
is the best of all.
Isn't he?
Why are you quiet,
O great teacher Dronacharya?
Your Majesty, I am quiet
as I wonder whether I should
sing the praises of my students
or should my students
exhibit the knowledge
I imparted them and thus
earn praises for my teaching.
What would be appropriate?
The teacher is right.
It's a tradition.
When the princes return
on completing their studies
before the subjects
of the kingdom
and before the special
guests invited
they should exhibit
their skills.
Exhibition!
We have a different
tradition at Gandhar.
Hastinapur follows its
traditions, prince of Gandhar!
Sir, it's the king of Gandhar.
King of Gandhar.
Thanks to your blessings
and favors
I am now the king of Gandhar.
I am informing the fine
traditions of my kingdom
to the king of Hastinapur.
Your majesty, in my kingdom
it is believed
that two people can
make similar swords
but no two swordsmen
can be alike.
Thus, your majesty, we hold a
competition at our kingdom
especially so that, when the
winner is hailed
the entire world learns
who has acquired how much
competence.
Now if the princes of Hastinapur
wish to exhibit their skills
like dancers
his highness would know better.
- King of Gandhar!
Hastinapur... - Has a great
tradition, Sire!
It's an excellent tradition.
The pleasure that lies
in a competition
doesn't lie in an exhibition.
We will hold a competition
among the princes.
Besides
I wouldn't be able to see them
exhibit their skills, Sire.
But on hearing the people
hail my sons
my heart would feel content.
Dronacharya
organize a competition that
you find appropriate.
The princes would mock fight
each other in the competition.
I would like to know
which prince is eligible to be
heir to the throne
of Hastinapur.
A competition!
Vidur, why are we
talking about a competition?
My elder brother
is eager to prove that Duryodhan
is the most eligible one, Sire.
I am apprehensive,
before all the invited guests
and the subjects
if there develops an animosity
between the princes
it would have dire
consequences, Sire.
In any situation
this competition shouldn't
become a duel, Vidur.
We have to supervise
it all the time.
Greetings, Sire.
- May you live long, dear.
I will not let the arrival of
the princes turn into politics.
I promise you.
Kunti.
Once I had asked you
to trust me and you did.
Today, what has suddenly
happened
for you to not have faith in me?
But Sire, the test
of the princes.
It would be appropriate
that my sons
don't take part
in this competition.
I hope people do not consider
their capabilities as ambitions
and be enemies with them.
I fear of that, Sire.
Who are you scared of,
sister-in-law?
Are you scared of Shakuni,
the king of Gandhar?
Don't have any kind of fear,
Kunti.
The snake whose venom
is extracted once
the next time it gives up its
venom very easily.
Because its previous experience
stops it from opposing.
Don't fear Shakuni.
Besides
he can no longer conspire.
He too would understand the
burden of responsibilities.
He is now the king of a state.
The great Bheeshma had made
a grave mistake by expelling me.
Pardon me, your majesty.
But my status will always
be less than the great Bheeshma.
Thus, before becoming a part
of your scheme
I would have to think
a hundred times.
An ant doesn't get trampled
under the feet of
an elephant, Purochan.
You are a man of low stature.
The great Bheeshma won't
be watching you.
Think about it.
If you help me in my plans
you will be enormously
prosperous.
And if you do not...
What are you planning,
your majesty?
Leave us alone!
The king wishes
to hear the people hail Prince
Duryodhan at the playground
and not anyone else.
Thus, the entrance door that you
will build for the playground
should collapse at
the right time.
With just one arrow.
The king wishes
to hear the people hail Prince
Duryodhan at the playground
and not anyone else.
Thus, the entrance door that you
build for the playground
should collapse at
the right time.
With just an arrow.
When it collapses, the person
standing beneath it
should reach kingdom come.
Will you be able
to fulfill the plan?
Who is this meant for,
king of Gandhar?
For the one
who Duryodhan may
not be able to defeat.
Are you making arrangements for
the test, son? - No, father.
I am making arrangements to
make my friend Duryodhan win.
You would have benefited, had
you befriended Arjun, son.
The scriptures say
one should always befriend
someone who is more intelligent
or more powerful than you.
Such friendship ends
in animosity.
There is one more
important thing.
The one who is the best
never needs anyone.
Thus, he's merciful
and doesn't befriend anyone.
I and Duryodhan
need each other.
He needs my help to attain
the throne of Hastinapur.
That's impossible.
The heir of Hastinapur
will be appointed
based on eligibility.
And eligibility
cannot be proven with
somebody's help.
To me, this is an opportunity
to make my friendship
with Duryodhan stronger.
So that, when I become
a king in the future
Hastinapur should
stand to protect me.
Father.
I have spent my life considering
a mixture of flour as milk.
I never asked for anything.
I never objected to anything.
But today, I ask of you.
Whatever happens in the
competition held for the princes
let it happen the way it is.
Son...
I cannot be unrighteous for you.
But you can at least keep quiet.
I need your assurance
that you will keep quiet.
And you will let
things happen the way they are.
Long live king Dhritarashtra!
Attention!
King Dhritarashtra
is on his way!
I was waiting for this day
since the last twelve
years, Your Majesty.
And you have promised
that this day
will be the most happiest day
of my life, Shakuni.
I am sure there is nothing
lacking in your arrangements.
If my nephews are hailed
by the people
only then this day would be
the happiest day for me, O king.
And I never make mistakes
for the sake of my happiness.
Greetings, sister.
- Come Kunti, sit here
next to me.
Today, I want to see my
sons with your eyes.
I mean, your sons too.
Greetings, aunt Kunti.
Bless you, Dushala.
Aren't you anxious to watch
the prowess of your brothers?
I am really excited.
Long live king Dhritarashtra!
Subjects!
Today many brave Aryan kings
and princes have arrived
in Hastinapur
to witness the strength of the
new generation of the Kurus.
To get introduced to the
strength of the Kuru dynasty
I welcome everyone
to Hastinapur.
Today on this playground
bravery and potential
would be exhibited.
And it shall reverberate in all
corners of the earth.
The praises would be heard
till the end of time!
Today, on this playground
a new history would begin.
The future of the
divine nation established
by the great Kuru ancestors
shall be decided.
Long live king Dhritarashtra!
To begin the competition
the one to arrive on
the playground
would be the son of the great
sage Bharadwaj
the disciple of Parshuram
the one as radiant as fire
the great teacher Drona!
Long live the great teacher
Dronacharya!
May the great king of
the Kuru dynasty
Dhritarashtra prosper.
Over there on the device
the names of all the princes
have been inscribed.
My son, Ashwathama
will shoot an arrow
at the device.
The name of the prince that
is highlighted on the device
will arrive at the playground
and fight a duel against
the winning prince.
The prince
who would stand as a winner
on the ground until sunset
that prince will be considered
the most capable.
Long live the great teacher
Dronacharya!
A rule has been decided
for the competition.
No prince can make
another prince bleed.
If that happens
the prince will be disqualified
from the competition.
The competition is a game taking
place between brothers
and no prince has the right
to turn it into war.
You can now begin
the competition.
Long live the great Bheeshma!