Brother
bowing before the wind does not
rob a tree of its strength.
Sailing with
the current of the ocean
does not insult a sea vessel.
Surrendering my weapons to you
is not an insult to me.
In fact, it is an honour
brother Yudhishthir.
I have a feeling that
when it comes to strength
and military strategies
you are superior to me.
Regarding the decision to crown
you as the Prince of Hastinapur
me
and my brothers
accept it.
All hail Prince Yudhishthir!
Brother Bheem,
what are you doing?
I had soaked these bitter gourds
overnight in a sugar solution,
Sahadev
but they still taste bitter.
If you soak them
for a year then maybe
they won't taste bitter,
brother.
If Duryodhan can change then
bitter gourds stand no chance.
Even if you soak them for life
there won't be any change
in them, Nakul
because bitter gourds are
defined by their bitterness.
Think positively, Bheem.
All of you should
try to think positively.
No one can have
such a weak heart
where righteousness
cannot dwell.
My heart isn't that weak, uncle
that righteousness
can dwell within it.
Five!
Do not say so, son.
Righteousness is
the basis of this world.
You cannot resort to
unrighteousness, son.
What is righteousness, mother?
What is it?
Righteousness is for
the solace of incompetent
and weak people.
The Almighty gave us a heart
and desires along with it.
Then how can
fulfilling those desires
be deemed unrighteous by anyone?
No, mother.
I know what righteousness is.
I have been taught enough
about it in the 'gurukul'
but pardon me, mother
I cannot live by it.
I have just one goal.
To have the throne
of Hastinapur.
Mother, the blessed event
I had been awaiting since birth
is drawing closer now.
Which blessed event
were you awaiting, son?
Greetings, mother.
At the time of my birth
when I had asked the great sage Vashishtha*
*One of the Saptarishis (seven great Rishis) in the seventh, i.e. the present Manvantara, or age of Manu.
about the path to my
enlightenment, he had said
that after fulfilling
all my duties on this earth
if, on the day
of the summer solstice
I leave this
earthly vessel of mine
then the Lord of the Sun
will take me northward
and show me the way to heaven.
Mother
Yudhishthir was crowned
as the Prince today.
Today, the royal court
of Hastinapur
was blessed with righteousness.
Today...
Today, I accomplished
the goal of my life, mother.
Are you certain
that Duryodhan has curbed
his ambitions?
But after the crowning
ceremony of the Prince
Yudhishthir and his brothers
will be able to protect
themselves from Duryodhan.
That is why...
That is why, today
my purpose was served, mother.
How can just one incident
fulfill the purpose
of someone's life, Bhishma?
The purpose
of one's life is served
only when he is free of
all ties and relationships.
But mother
I have no ties.
I was merely
carrying out my duties.
Even a duty is a tie, son.
Until you find the way
to free yourself from this tie
you will not be completely free.
Do not say so, mother.
Even after leading
a righteous life
how can I not be free?
Mother
how can I finally be free?
I cannot tell you that
but very soon
someone will arrive
who will make you realize
your true duty.
Not only you, son
but also the entire world
will learn about
its true duties.
When you will
attain that knowledge
you will finally find yourself
to be free.
Righteousness.
Everyone meditates over it.
Some discuss their own
and some, about that of others.
People keep discussing
someone else's unrighteousness.
There is no one who has never
meditated over righteousness.
But in true terms
what does righteousness mean?
Has anyone ever been
able to understand it?
Righteousness
teaches man how to
live with others
and to live with
the entire creation in peace.
This is the reason why
in the presence of righteousness
man always feels at peace.
Have you not experienced it?
In other words, righteousness
ends all of man's struggles.
But how can it be possible
for a man to not have
any struggle with another?
Think about it.
Does struggle also exist
in the presence of love?
Your answer to this
would be 'yes'
but if you think a little more
about it, you will know
that when one struggles
with something
one forgets about love.
And then
desires come to the forefront
arrogance and anger come
to the forefront but love?
No.
Love does not
come to the forefront
because when love
comes to the forefront
all arguments, all struggles
and all fights
come to an end.
What if such a love develops
for the entire world?
Not only for mankind
but also for flora and fauna
and even a blade of grass
if one has love in one's heart
then can anger ever exist in it?
Certainly not.
The feeling of love that exists
in one person for another
if that same love is
extended to the entire creation
then it is termed as compassion.
Compassion, in other words
to accept the entire world.
To have nothing
but love for everyone.
To not protest against anyone.
Compassion is truly
the essence of righteousness.
If righteousness is a tree,
compassion is its basis
and its root.
But there are instances
in life when man
completely forgets
the basis of righteousness.
He clings to a few rules
and traditions.
But compassion?
He forgets all about it.
And the world gets
permeated with struggles
with jealousies
with exploitation, with anger,
with hatred!
In other words,
with unrighteousness.
And then
the Almighty is required
to take an avatar
to impart the right knowledge
to man.
The epic of Mahabharat
is a tale of a time
when some people would deem
traditions to be righteous
while others were unrighteous
and were stuck in the vortex
of anger, hatred and ambitions
thus leading to the destruction
of righteousness.
Back then, people loved others
but they lacked love
for the entire world.
There was no compassion
back then.
That is why, I
took an avatar.
'Paﬂtranaya Sadhunam.'
For the upliftment
of the good and virtuous.
'Vinashaya Cha Dushkritam!'
For the destruction of evil
and evil-doers!
'Dharma Sansthapanarthaya!'
For the re-establishment
of righteousness
I, Vasudeva Krishna,
am going to arrive
in the epic of Mahabharat!