Govind!
Draupadi.
Draupadi!
Don't touch me,
Queen Mother Kunti.
I'll get besmirched.
I'm no longer
your daughter-in-law.
I'm not your sons' wife.
Neither am I the bride
of the Kuru dynasty.
Dear!
Now, I'm without a husband
a name
or a dynasty.
Just like a flame
burning in the hearth
of a forest dweller far away.
I am pure
but I am thriving
on what is impure.
Today, in this court
I alone have shed tears
equivalent to that of all
the women in this world.
Queen Mother Kunti
Queen Gandhari
if you wish to save yourselves
then renounce
this court and leave.
Because this whole court
will drown today.
I'm not a human being
but death!
Only death!
I'm the death
of all the wicked men
present
in this unrighteous court.
And it's my curse
that right now,
at this very moment...
No, Draupadi!
Please don't curse,
Draupadi.
Forgive them.
Please forgive them.
My curse is forgiveness
in itself, Your Highness.
If I have to punish
then it shall be
in this lifetime.
Every moment,
they'll experience hell.
There will be no end
to their suffering.
No.
The woman who gives life
can't give death.
These men have almost
committed suicide in this court.
If someone destroys
their physical being
it is called self-annihilation.
But suicide takes place
when they destroy their souls.
Out of rage
don't do something
similar to these men.
It's a woman's task
to keep the house clean.
And it's a woman's task as well
to keep the society clean.
I curse that...
- Stop, Panchali.
Today, the sons of Pandu
have endured
a great disgrace, Panchali.
Give us a chance
to redeem ourselves.
Let us avenge your dishonour.
How will you take revenge?
You are now the slaves
of these wicked people.
And I no longer
consider you my husband.
Henceforth
I shall never bind my hair.
I shall not wear a tiara
on my head!
Henceforth
I will never tie my hair.
I will not adorn
my forehead with any ornaments.
I accept it.
But only you...
Only you can guard
our souls, Draupadi.
If you don't give us
a chance
to repent for our sins
then till the end of time
we will reside
in the netherworld, Draupadi.
I'm not saying this
as a husband
but as a friend.
Don't lose your patience,
Draupadi.
Don't lose your patience.
'Sometimes the deeds
of others terrify us'
'and give us a chance
to lose our patience.'
'But continue
to be patient.'
'It is very important
to control one's heart.'
Patience?
Patience!
Patience...
My dear...
That's enough, my dear.
King Dhritarashtra
your younger brother,
Pandu's family
has once again done
you a favour.
Go and live happily!
But until you're leading
a content life
keep in mind
that the day my sons...
The day my sons
attain freedom
will be the last day
of your happiness.
Your sons will
attain freedom?
Keep quiet, my dear.
Keep quiet.
Let him speak, Shakuni.
This is his arrogance speaking!
You wanted to disrobe Draupadi,
isn't it, Duryodhan?
Look!
Look around this court!
Even the skin of a poisonous
snake
deserts it.
All those who quietly
witnessed this unrighteous act...
Look at how they have been
disrobed
like a snake!
Look around this court!
Listen carefully, Duryodhan
I will soon go to Dwarka
and bring Krishna's
Narayani army to Hastinapur.
And I will request
Krishna and Balrama
to defeat
the Kuru dynasty!
Help my sons gain freedom!
But not to kill any of you
because the responsibility
of taking revenge
for my daughter-in-law's
humiliation
lies only with my sons.
And this task
will be done
only by my sons.
No, Kunti.
No.
Don't give us such
a severe punishment.
If the Kuru dynasty is
destroyed
at my hands
then the souls of my ancestors
will never rest in peace.
No.
I seek your forgiveness
Draupadi.
You can ask for any wish
you want.
Yes.
But forgive my sons.
If it's possible for you
erase the memories
of today's game.
Nothing else
can subside my pain.
The stain on our characters
will never be erased, my dear.
But so that our sadness
decreases to some extent
ask for a wish, my dear.
Do His Highness a favour.
Ask for a wish.
Ask, my dear.
Give the Pandavas
their freedom.
Return their weapons.
Their powers had been
snatched through treachery
in this court.
Return their powers to them.