Son Karna,
your mother is here.
Hoping to get something
in charity from you.
Will you be able
to make her an offering?
Queen Mother.
No, son.
Just mother.
Your mother.
It took tremendous courage
to come to you.
Tremendous courage...
It took so long
for a Warrior's mother
to gather courage?
At the time
of your birth
I didn't have
the courage.
I had to face
the entire society.
I could have accepted
my character being questioned
but
what about my father's honour?
How could've
I tarnished that, son?
Definitely your father's dignity
must have been more valuable
than your son's life.
No, son.
I have committed
a big mistake.
I lacked the sense
to understand
the result that
my mistake would yield.
I am the result of your mistake.
My entire life is the result
of your mistake.
I...
I'm here to rectify
that mistake, son.
I'm here to be
your mother.
Now you come
to be my mother?
Now you come?
What do I do
about that mother of mine
who has stayed up
for many nights, weeping
whenever I slept hungry?
Whenever someone ridiculed me
upon seeing a bow in my hand
she held my hand
and taught me tolerance.
What do I do
about that mother
who is weeping
right now
because now people will
no more address me as her son
but as someone
else's son?
What do I do
about that mother
who embraced me
when you abandoned me?
What do I do
about that mother?
Abandoning you
was my mistake.
Please forgive me, son.
Forgive me.
But
I am here now
as your mother.
We can change
the circumstances, son.
We can change everything.
How can one change
the past, Queen Mother?
You had abandoned me.
Can you change that?
I was always in front of you
but you never accepted me.
Can you change
this situation?
My younger brothers
are my enemies, today.
Can you change
this situation?
A fruit fallen
off a tree
cannot be put back
on the tree, Queen Mother.
No one can change
the past.
Neither you, nor me...
No one.
Your son has drowned
in the tide of misfortune
in which you had
abandoned him.
Queen Mother.
Please
help me find
my son, Karna.
Where will you
look for him?
Even after the inferno
has calmed down
you can feel the heat
in the ashes.
In the same manner
even your son
is burning
in the flames
of pain and humiliation.
Don't try to find him now,
Queen Mother.
We can end this complexity,
this bitterness, son.
Now, you will no more
receive pain
insult or tears.
You will now be called
a Pandava.
You'll be referred to
as the eldest of my sons.
Abandon Duryodhana's side, son.
Come to the side of your
brothers and guide them.
Abandon my friend?
The hand that helped me gain
foot during troubled times...
You want me
to leave that hand?
If this is how I repay for all
the favours bestowed on me
will that make you
proud of me?
Duryodhana has always been
unrighteous.
Why are you taking his side,
son? - Because he had once
committed a righteous deed.
In the arena, that day
he kept aside
caste, creed
social classes, position
and everything
and offered his friendship
to me.
The righteous grandsire Bhishma
never did any such thing.
The knowledgeable mentor Drona
never did this.
Even the person who gave
birth to me
did not lend her support.
During those dark times
only one hand
offered support.
And for that one
righteous deed
I can sacrifice a hundred lives
for Prince Duryodhana.
My weapons will forever
be indebted to
Prince Duryodhana, Queen Mother.
Will you wield arms
against your own brothers, son?
And that will be the most
disastrous result
of the mistake
you've committed.
Even after I surrendered
to Duryodhana
why did you not accept me?
Had you done so, mother
then today, I would have
been known as your son.
I would have stood
in your favour.
But now...
Now, the time has changed.
I am...
I am bound today.
I witness immorality
and atrocity at every step.
My soul dies
at every step, but I...
I am bound by a promise.
Buried under favours bestowed.
I cannot sacrifice the prince.
I cannot give up on my promise.
I would lose
my self-respect, then.
Whenever my arrows
would injure my brothers
my heart would bleed too.
I would have to live
through this anguish.
But, I...
I cannot break my vows
and go against my duties.
Then do not participate
in the war, son.
Even that encompasses creed.
Vrushali has a question
for you, Queen Mother.
Is it reasonable for one's
pride to be their creed?
Or is one being proud
of their creed
appropriate?
One's creed turning
into their pride
is legitimate.
I am aware of my creed.
I cannot renounce it.
Neither my creed
nor Prince Duryodhana.
Farewell, Queen Mother.
You chose to remain silent
throughout your life.
But the pain
was borne by me alone.
I am accustomed
to living in anguish.
But by breaking your silence
please do not hurt everyone.
Do not tell my five brothers
about this truth.
I am well aware
that they are firm
in their creed.
They would surrender
immediately.
And I...
I would slay their competence
and dedicate it
to Prince Duryodhana.
Let the war materialise, mother.
Do not inform them
of my torment.
Their joy lies
in their ignorance.
I have...
I have always lived
as the son of Radha
and that will be my identity
till death.
How can I help it, son?
My own sons
slaying each other...
How can I be an audience to it?
How can the consequences
of one error of mine
be so dreadful?
How is it fair, son?
How can it be so?
How?
How could it be so?
Weren't you here to ask
for a grant, mother?
Let me accord you with one.
You would need to mourn
the death of only one son.
I wouldn't slay the remaining
four sons of yours.
Only Arjuna and I
would combat to vanquish
the other.
If I die
at the hands of Arjuna
all five sons of yours
would remain alive.
But if Arjuna dies
at my hands
even then five sons of yours
would remain alive.
Because then...
I would address you as 'mother'.
This is my promise,
Queen Mother.
And this is my grant to you.
Karna...
Madhav has sent a message.
Hastinapur has rejected
our peace treaty.
I will direct all of our troops
to leave for the river route.
- They don't want peace
but don't mind facing
total obliteration.
Don't say that, Your Highness.
You can term this as the first
step of a new beginning.
You are right.
Arjuna... Bhima... Send a message
across to all our allies.
Request all of their armies
to assemble with ours.
My dear sons, take note
of your weapons and courage.
Get ready for war!