She had stripped us
of our weapons in the court.
We will strip her of her clothes
before the entire court.
Empress Draupadi
will be disrobed by you!
Maid Draupadi will be
disrobed by me, uncle!
Only then will
the fire of being insulted
get extinguished
within me, uncle!
Splendid, my darling!
Splendid!
A woman having five husbands
has no dignity and this truth
will be revealed
before the entire world.
Look.
The Great Guru Drona
is making his entrance.
All hail Guru Dronacharya!
He has come here to see
the glory and respect
of his beloved disciples
but
he will get to see something
which has not been
witnessed by the world
until this day.
May His Highness have happiness!
No, Guru.
A disciple does not have
the right to bless his guru.
A river always flows downwards
from its source after all.
Despite garnering such success
you have not let arrogance
cloud your thoughts
and this makes me
exceedingly glad.
But do remember
that the virtues
of a successful person
do not lessen
the envy of others
but increase it instead.
The envy people had
towards Jarasandha
was not substantial.
However, the envy
people have towards you
is quite substantial.
That is why,
this game of dice
is going to be
played here today, Guru.
I am aware of that.
I am certain that none of you
will resort to unrighteousness
but you must
promise me something.
If you see something
unrighteous happening
then you must not pardon it.
Friend Karna
you must stay prepared.
I do not have faith
in Bheem and Nakul.
If they lose at the game of dice
then they might
draw their weapons.
I am always prepared
to protect you, friend.
But
the General of Hastinapur
is His Excellency Bhishma.
Before we draw our weapons
we will require his permission.
Grandsire is subservient
to the throne of Hastinapur
because he is its servant.
If the Pandavas
do draw their weapons
grandsire will have to
fight them.
Dear Duryodhan.
Greetings, grandsire.
Greetings,
His Excellency.
His Excellency!
Listen to me very carefully.
Do not attempt
to taint this ceremony.
You are aware
that I am a servant
to the throne of Hastinapur.
And now
Hastinapur has
willingly accepted the reign of
the supreme King Yudhishthir.
In other words
I am also a servant
to the supreme
King Yudhishthir now.
If Emperor Yudhishthir
meets with improper behaviour
or is made to face injustice
or any form of treachery
I will have to draw my weapon
in order to protect him.
I hope
you understand.
Indeed, grandsire.
But I am conducting
this ceremony
to forget the past
and bury the hatchet.
I had misbehaved
with Empress Draupadi
and this is its penance,
grandsire.
All I have in my heart
for the Pandavas
is love.
And may it stay the same.
That is in the best
interest of everyone.
Uncle.
This is what I had feared,
my darling.
For some reason or the other
that old geyser
always starts to preach
about righteousness
but
you need not worry, my darling.
I will find such a cure
for that old geyser
that the very definition
of righteousness
will have to be changed by him.
May His Highness have happiness!
With the permission
of His Highness
let the game of dice begin!
Grace the seat.
Come here,
brother Duryodhan.
Let's begin the game.
Greetings,
Your Highness.
With your permission
uncle would like
to say something.
Certainly.
Your Highness
in the world,
the game of dice
has a very bad reputation.
The thing is,
all the games
which have unclear rules
tend to be bad in general terms.
Even a life without rules
tends to be painful.
Your Highness
that is why,
before beginning the game
the rules of this game
need to be clarified.
Tell me,
King of Gandhar.
What are the rules?
Me?
No, Your Highness.
In order to come up
with the rules
one needs to have deep knowledge
of righteousness.
One needs to be fair-minded.
One needs to be experienced.
And righteousness,
fair-mindedness and experience
are embodied by none other
than His Excellency Bhishma.
His Excellency
I request you
to explain the rules
of this game
so that when the game begins
you have
nothing to say against it.
Do I have the permission
of His Highness?
Certainly.
Grandsire explaining
the rules of the game
would be best.
Pardon me,
Your Highness.
The game of dice
does not honour
the labour and competence
of a person.
It is a slave to fortune.
That is why
I do not approve of
this game.
But Your Highness
wise people say that something
orchestrated by the Almighty
for us is called fortune.
King of Gandhar!
Fortune is not something
that is unrighteous!
However, toying with
one's fortune certainly is.
And Your Highness
what rules
can be made for
such an unrighteous deed?
Come up with such rules,
grandsire
which can restrain
unrighteousness.
Come up with such rules,
grandsire
which can restrain
unrighteousness.
Then lend an ear to me.
First and foremost,
Your Highness
the ones to be most hurt
by unrighteousness in the world
are women.
And the recipients
of grave injustice
are again women.
That is why,
until this game of dice is over
none of the women
will be present in the court.
How is this correct,
grandsire?
All these arrangements
have been made
to honour the Empress after all.
Her presence in the court
is essential, grandsire.
Then this game of dice shall
not be played, Crown Prince.
Because I have firm faith
that the Empress
would appreciate music
more than a game of dice.
Oh no,
Your Excellency!
Her Highness has made
arrangements for the Empress
to see a host of apparels
and jewellery.
Besides, my darling!
Apart from their husbands
and maids, women of royalty
do not play a game of dice
with anyone else!
Your Excellency,
that is a valid rule.
But
the Emperor would require
some light meal during the game
for which the maids
ought to have permission
to enter the court.
This is what I request of you.
That sounds fair.
When called for
maids will have permission
to enter the court.
Your Highness,
the second rule will be
that both the players
in each of the turns
must only bet
objects of equal worth
in the game.
When one bets jewellery
only jewellery of equal worth
can be bet by the other.
That sounds fair, grandsire.
The third rule will be
that both the players
can only bet
those objects or items
to which
they have a right.
But the Emperor has the right
to the entire Aryan region,
grandsire.
But you do not have the right
to even a single village.
I am the Crown Prince
of Hastinapur, grandsire
and the throne of Hastinapur
rightfully belongs to me.
- In time.
And when it is time
we shall invite the Emperor
for a game of dice again.
But at the moment
you can only bet
Your apparels
jewellery
and gold coins in the game.
Objects of equal worth
will be bet by
the Emperor as well.
But grandsire
because of this rule,
winning and losing at this game
will have absolutely no meaning.
The game will be over
in just a few turns, grandsire.
Then what is
incorrect about it,
Crown Prince?
Do you not want
this game to take place?
I do not, Duryodhan.
Stop the game.
I
apologise to Yudhishthir
on behalf of Hastinapur.
That is impossible!
I will not let this ceremony
get ruined, grandsire.
Do you have some sort of a plan,
brother Duryodhan
which is being obstructed
by these rules?
It is our plan
to please the Emperor
Prince Bheem.
And no rule
is an obstruction here.
Your Highness
with your permission
I would like to make a request.
Certainly.
Your Highness
be it a battle
a competition
or the game of dice
to a competent person,
these are nothing but games.
Then why do we play these games?
For wealth or for an empire?
No, King of Gandhar.
Upon being victorious
one garners glory, fame
and praise from the world.
The Emperor is correct.
No one is more intelligent
than the Emperor.
When man wins, there is
an appreciation in his pride
but when he loses, there is
a reduction in his pride.
The true property of man
is his pride.
Did I say something incorrect,
Your Highness?
You are correct,
King of Gandhar.
Pride is everything.
Then I request,
Your Highness
both the players
to bet their pride in the game.
But only to which they have
a right, Your Excellency.
And along with the right to it,
they ought to take pride in it.
Your Highness, such an object
can be bet in the game.
And out of the two players
when one of them
has no object in his possession
which he can take pride in
the game will be
deemed complete.
Brother Yudhishthir
what exactly does
brother Duryodhan possess
which fulfill
both these criteria?
We are aware of no such thing.
But we are well aware
of what the Emperor possesses,
Prince Sahadev.
The Emperor possesses
the entire Aryan region
in which he takes pride.
And whether beloved Duryodhan
can have possession
of even a handful of land
is certainly a question.
So, Your Highness...
Do you approve of these rules?
I approve of them.