Princess of Panchal
what is the meaning
of coming here?
I wanted to ask you a question.
I am not obligated
to answer any of your questions.
Is resolving the issues
of sinners
by showing them
how to purify themselves
not the duty of great men?
You...
The sin committed
by all of you...
What path do I show
all of you to atone for it?
Now, even
the water I give as an offering
is not being accepted
by Surya Dev.
After slipping
through my fingers
the water does not mix
with that of mother Ganga.
Princess
all of you
have committed a grave sin
and Hastinapur is being
punished for it.
Now
what path should I
show all of you?
I can only
show you the path to
the God of Death, Yama.
We are ready to follow
any path you show us
but I have a doubt.
What will Lord Yama
be able to do?
Yama will be able
to purify your tainted souls.
In other words
even after committing
such a grave sin
it is possible for us
to be pure once again?
Do I have the permission
to ask another question?
Is the other name of Lord Yama
not Dharmaraj?*
*Lord of righteousness.
Then is the righteous path
not that of Lord Yama?
You are arguing
with me, Princess.
Had you known righteousness
you would never have
resorted to unrighteousness.
When one does not know
what righteousness is
how can he follow the path
of righteousness then?
That is the solution
I wish to seek from you.
If a soul gets purified
after death
then what is the point?
There must be a way
to follow Lord Yama's path
when one is still alive.
The way Savitri had...
She had brought back
her husband from Lord Yama.
The way Sage Udalak's son
Nachiketa had been
offered to Death
but had returned from
the abode of Lord Yama.
There must be a solution.
The principles followed by Yama
are rules on this earth.
A lotus is born in the mud
but there are
no branches on its stem.
Hence, it does not move sideward
but grows straight up
towards the sky.
This is what rules mean.
One must abide by rules
all his life.
One must deem it sacred.
And how could you believe
that we chose not to
abide by certain rules?
That we did not take an oath
to make our lives sacred?
You may not have faith
in the values imparted to me
and I accept that.
But you could have had faith
in that of the Kuru dynasty.
It is easy for a tree
to grow on a river bank.
However, a desert
is devoid of water
and has the blazing sun.
For a tree to grow there
is its true test.
And my husbands and me
have followed the righteous path
even in such a grave situation.
You say
that because of our
unrighteous deed
your offering is being rejected.
But what if
by doubting the purity
of the sons of Pandu
you have committed
an unrighteous deed?
If my husbands and me
are entirely guiltless,
oh Lord Surya
then do accept this offering.
I have a request, grandsire.
Do not keep the sons of Pandu
deprived of your blessings.
Hear all!
The sons of Pandu
are making their entrance!
Greetings, His Highness.
Greetings, grandsire.
May you live long.
Greetings, uncle.
Bless you!
Your Highness
a while ago, as the palace
in Varnavrat had caught fire
we had to flee from there.
That is why, we had decided
to stay away from Hastinapur.
And deeming us dead
you decided to coronate
brother Duryodhan as Prince.
But now, I am here
to serve you
and the entire kingdom.
Uncle
when an old building
is still standing
a new building cannot be
constructed in its place.
Until one harvests
the current crops
one cannot sow
news crops in the field.
That is why, uncle
when the former Crown Prince
is still present
a new Crown Prince
cannot take his place.
I request you
to declare brother Duryodhan's
coronation as Prince
null and void.
I... - Certainly,
brother Yudhishthir.
The truth is,
the moment you returned
my coronation as Prince
became null and void on its own.
For you, I shall give up
this throne of mine.
Greetings, brother Yudhishthir.
Be seated, brother Yudhishthir.
But
answer a question of mine,
Crown Prince.
Despite having a husband
when a woman has
relationships with other men
she is called amoral.
In the other kingdoms
of the Arya region
such a woman gets imprisoned.
If you face this question
in the future
then how will you
uphold justice, Crown Prince?
I have another question.
In our kingdom
no matter how gallant
the General is
if he is proved to be amoral
then he gets punished!
If the judge is amoral
then the King punishes him too!
If the Crown Prince
or his wife is amoral
then would punishing them
be correct
or not?
No amoral person is ever given a
position in the state politics!
The position of a Crown Prince
is a sacred
and stately one.
So, would letting
an amoral person
preside over it be correct?
Answer my questions,
Crown Prince.
And Your Highness
you must then
let justice prevail.
I can answer your questions,
brother Duryodhan.
No need to do that, Yudhishthir!
I banish you and your family
from the kingdom this instant!