When the Almighty himself
is the charioteer
and justice and righteousness
are the wheels of that chariot
the flag atop it
shall always be blessed by me.
May you be victorious.
There is another
basis of might, Bheem.
And that is
a tail
which you do not have.
I am on my way,
Duryodhan
with the might of Lord Hanuman,
son of Pavan Dev, in my arms.
I am on my way!
Splendid, my darling!
Splendid! - Uncle!
Brother! I have some bad news,
brother Duryodhan!
I have heard from various sages
that Bheem has pleased
Lord Hanuman!
And being pleased with him,
Lord Hanuman
has provided him with His might,
brother Duryodhan.
I do not fear Bheem one bit!
I do not!
My darling!
I have heard that Arjun seeks
to acquire the Pashupatastra
brother Duryodhan.
And the Pandavas are gathering
an army of competent people.
The Pandavas
will engage in a battle
only when they are successful
in their life of anonymity.
At the dawn
of their life of anonymity
the Pandavas
will be standing before us
and we shall
send them back on an exile.
Uncle, why would the Pandavas
come and stand before us?
To protect their wife.
If you lift a trident
by its shaft
then the three of its prongs
come along with it.
Just a day before
their life of anonymity begins
Draupadi will be
abducted by us!
The method to heal
the wounds of our army quickly
was taught to us
by the Ashwini Kumaras.
And not only that.
They also taught us how
to heal horses and elephants.
When the battle comes
to a halt at sunset
the soldiers who are wounded
will not die
because of the wounds.
We shall heal them
by the crack of dawn.
After pleasing Lord Shiva,
when Arjun
will acquire the Pashupatastra
we will never get defeated
by grandsire and guru Drona.
Panchali, all the sages
and guests
have left after having a meal.
I hope you have kept
food aside for yourself.
There is sufficient
food for me, My Lord.
I have set aside
extra food for you.
Enough"
I do not want more.
If it is too much for you
then let me have some.
Panchali
you should begin
your meal as well.
This is enough for all of us.
Yes, Panchali.
Let me serve
the entire contents of this pot
on your plate.
If it is too much for you,
you may give me some.
Is there a householder
in this hut
who can give a meal to us sages
or has the entire world
fallen prey to unrighteousness?!
Great sage Durvasa!
Greetings!
Welcome.
- Prince
sweet talk does not
satiate a person.
Since you are a householder now
you must provide
us sages with a meal.
My disciples and I shall
have a meal at your residence.
Princes, arrange for
a place to sit for us
and you
must tell your wife
to arrange for a meal for us.
As you say,
great sage.
Bheem, Sahadev, arrange for
a place to sit for the sages.
Nakul, go and place clean
plantain leaves for the meal.
Let me go aid Panchali.
Alright.
Great sage Durvasa is here!
At this time?
- Panchali, guests
always arrive unannounced.
We must offer them a meal.
Vasudev made us take a vow
to ensure that sages
leave this place contented
so that we can earn merit.
Upon hearing of this vow
of ours, great sage Durvasa
must have come here to test us.
But all the food that we had
has already been
served by me, My Lord.
I even served food on my plate.
Now, how can we serve him a
meal which was intended for us?
That amount would not have
sufficed anyhow, Panchali.
More than 100 disciples have
accompanied the great sage.
You must prepare something.
I do not even have
enough grains with me
that I can prepare
something, My Lord.
The one who takes a test
comes with the intention
of leaving discontented.
No one can ever make the tester
leave feeling utterly contented.
And everyone is familiar with
the wrath of great sage Durvasa.
If he is not contented
then he will certainly curse us.
How will we ever be able
to give him a satisfactory meal?
Prince!
- Yes?
Tell the daughter of Drupad
that after being seated
for a meal, great sage Durvasa
does not have
the habit of waiting.
Tell her to serve
our meaIs this instant
otherwise we shall leave
on an empty stomach.
Such a situation
will never arise, great sage.
Your meal will be here
in just a while.
Do not interrupt me,
impudent man!
Tell her
that if great sage Durvasa
is not contented
then the future of the Pandavas
will get incinerated
with his wrath!
What do I offer
great sage Durvasa now?
What do I do now?
The curse of great sage Durvasa
has the power to turn all our
plans upside down, My Lord.
What will become of us now?
Disciple...
I do not think we will get
a meal from this residence.
Let's leave!
No, great sage.
No.
Just wait for
a little while longer.
Panchali!
Brother Yudhishthir,
the great sage is very angry.
He is about to leave
on an empty stomach.
The duties of a householder have
been tarnished by Pandu's sons!
I cannot wait any longer.
Let's leave!
Just a little while longer,
great sage.
Just wait for
a little while longer.
Insolent men!
Do you not know
that the longer hunger
and the enemies wait
the stronger they get?!
They become more powerful!
Get up!
Patience and herbs
become weaker
with the passage of time!
And listen!
I shall wait only until I am
done reciting the Gayatri Mantra
101 times and
not a moment longer!
Not a moment longer!
Why is he testing us
in this manner?
This exile is a time of tests
for all of us, Panchali.
In order to help us
know our limits
the Almighty has blessed us with
this opportunity of an exile.
I have realized what
my limits are, My Lord.
I lack in providing nourishment.
I shall go to the great sage
and apologize for this.
Stop, Panchali.
If the great sage
vents his anger out on you
then it would be a defeat
for us five brothers.
Wait here.
I shall go tell him.
- Stop, Sahadev.
Panchali lacking grains
in her kitchen
denotes my limit.
You need not worry,
Panchali.
Ensuring that one has enough
grains for a guest at home
is the duty of a householder.
It is my defeat
as a householder.
That is why, I must
apologize to the great sage.
Whenever one undergoes a test
there is always a way
to succeed in it.
How do I succeed in this?
How are you,
friend?
Are you happy?
Govind!
How do you do it,
Govind?
Whenever I require your aid
you always come to me.
Aid!
This is a deliberate attempt
on your part, friend.
Whenever I come visit all of you
you always make me do
some task or the other.
What seems to be the problem?
Great sage Durvasa
and his disciples
have come over for a meal
but there is no food
in any of the vessels.
Let me think of a way
to make the great sage
understand.
This is a grave problem.
A grain of rice
is still there, friend.
However, this single
grain of rice
would not leave
those sages contented.
Am I correct?
How would it,
Govind?
I think great sage Durvasa
is almost done
reciting the mantra as well.
Govind, I will have to serve him
and the 100 disciples of his
a meal very soon.
In such a situation
saving this single grain
for them is of no use.
Let me have it.
'Om Bhur Bhuvah...'
Prince Bheem!
I am certain that the
treacherous Vasudev Krishna
is inside your hut.
Pardon me,
great sage Durvasa.
Why have I done,
great sage?
You are an illusory being,
Vasudev
but the person
you have sided with
is on the side of righteousness
and there is no doubt about it.
And
the daughter of Drupad
we are leaving your home
feeling contented.
You have
truly been blessed by Goddess Annapurna.*
*Annapurna Devi: the goddess of nourishment.
You are too kind,
great sage.
Great sage Durvasa
and his disciples
burped as though
they had just eaten.
The courage to cast an illusion
on great sage Durvasa
can reside only
within you, Vasudev.
What did I do?
The son of Pavan Dev,
Lord Hanuman
was pleased by brother Bheem.
I believe
that the great sage burped
because of something
that brother Bheem did.
Will you come
to aid us again, Govind?
Indeed
but
I will not be able
to aid all of you
in the place where
you must go now.