I am nothing.
But I am also everything.
This has happened in every age
and will happen in future,
as well.
When you reflect on your own being.
You will find that your own self is
also connected to me.
And then, like me,
you'll find that you are also within the avatar
of the Almighty.
But to reach that stage,
it is important for you to
wholly submit to me.
What do you mean with
'submit', Madhav?
It is a state of mind
where one surrenders all one's desires.
Not making any expectations for oneself.
And not taking any oath
for anyone according to
what is requested from him.
In short, submitting yourself to someone,
willingly.
Your mind,
your thought, your knowledge,
your wish, your desire, your emotion,
and all that you have,
to someone.
That commitment is called submission.
A wife committed to her husband.
A soldier committed to his general.
A student committed to his teacher.
Isn't all these submissions the same?
Isn't all of them reaching God?
No, Arjuna.
When one committed to something
or someone,
it's according to its circumstances.
One that leaves no room for doubts
or questions.
Commitment to someone evil,
can make one to slander.
King of Anga, Karna, even when
he knows what is right,
slanders Panchali in the
game of dice.
'A woman that has relations to five men'
'is no better than a harlot.'
And because of
King of Anga's committment
to brother Duryodhana,
he will get punishment in this war.
Is that so?
No. But because of his loyalty
to an evil person.
That's why, Arjuna,
it is important to commit oneself
to what is right.
That will make a human righteous.
Otherwise one is like a criminal that's
bound with an iron chains.
Like a temple lamp bound by
a brass chains.
Like a gold chains around our neck,
just as ornament.
Loyalty to a husband,
loyalty to a teacher,
loyalty to friends, they are but
some forms of loyalty.
But the true loyalty of all,
is your loyalty to God.
But is dedication to God
must be fulfilled with "sankhya yoga"
or "karma yoga"?
Because of "sankhya yoga"
human knows that they are
only souls.
And because of 'karma yoga'
they can liberate themselves
from the bind.
And that's because through dedication
human knows the real manifestation
of the Almighty,
and knows about the Almighty.
A human is in the circle of life and death.
To reach bliss and knowledge,
a human dedicate itself to the Almighty,
and becomes the Almighty.
Just like water falls into a river,
and becomes the river itself.
So do you mean,
that this human body has
no value, Madhav?
It surely has value, Arjuna.
A human body is a medium
for human to meet the Almighty.
Between death and reincarnation,
with soul's knowledge is still active,
with experience, thoughts,
and learnings from the previous life,
the soul becomes part of a new body.
The soul growth and its commitment,
it only happens when it becomes part of
a human body.
But, Madhav, by killing people that
are present here,
do we not destroy their
chance of liberation?
Your enemies have gone past the limits
of righteousness.
Evil had become their second nature.
Liberation for them is not possible.
Sinners only given chance
to reform to a certain time.
I had given Sishupala 99 offences,
but it becomes necessary to punish him,
for his 100th offence.
If we let sinners do evils,
they will do more and more.
Righteousness is stopping them
committing sins.
These souls will not meet their ends,
but leave their bodies that had been
corrupted with evils.
And become part of a new human body.
And there are more opportunities to reform
in their new bodies.
If you fight this war with this logic,
it would be justifed.
A human body, to a human, is its wealth.
As bhakti,* as dignity.
*Dedication.
Those who tread the path of truth,
will purify their bodies.
And, through that path,
they will meet their souls.
This is the relation between 'kshetra'* and 'kshetragna'.*
*Field, area, tract of land. **The fielder.
I don't understand, Madhav.
When one knows,
that one's body is like this dirt,
meaning, only a 'kshetra', a place.
And one who's aware of a land,
and standing on top of it is 'kshetragna'.
Then through his body,
one can measure one's progress.
A soul in the body balancing
the 3 righteousness,
annihilates darkness,
and opening path for righteousness.
And with dedication to God,
it becomes one with the Almighty.
But the worshipper
is devoting but not dedicating?
No, Arjuna.
That is the first step to dedication.
In reality, dedication is not a duty.
It is a meditated state of mind.
It is important for human
to purify its soul.
Through prayers, repentaces,
'yogna', ritual,
'yoga' dan self learnings.
And remain devoted to the Almighty.
Devoting all his actions,
all moments,
each breath,
to the Almighty.
If dedication is only a state of mind,
then what use is prayers, repentances,
and all of these others?
They are only means to
cleanse your self.
Cause it will be soiled again.
Human mind needs
to be repeatedly reminded of the Almighty.
That's why it is important
to pray, repent, self development,
and others.
One needs to remind oneself,
all the time,
that one's life is to serve the Almighty.
It's not important to know which river,
what's important is that you dive in it.
There's only one dedication in 'bhakti yoga',
that by surrendering one's life
to the Almighty,
one will keep one's dedication
and one will do good deeds in one's lives.
What is righteousness and kindness, Madhav?
Violence without reason or necessity,
is not right, Arjuna.
In reality, nonviolence is a supreme decision.
And along with it, truth,
refrain from anger, sacrifice,
peace of mind, refrain from mocking,
generous,
actions without expecting rewards,
greatness, compassion, patience,
do not indulge in self praise, not egoistic,
all these qualities is called
the cardinal possession.
Only with help from these, a human becomes
my true worshiper.
Fullfill their duties in life.
Establish truth.
And live without attachment to the fruit
of his deeds.
I will certainly,
grant happiness in his life,
and absorb him into my self
after his death.
What is your true form, Madhav?
Through 'sankya yoga',
I know if my soul (atma),
is eternal.
And that it is in this temporal body only
for a certain time.
I know how, through actions without
expecting rewards,
sacrificing the desire for rewards,
and fullfill one's duties,
one attains peace of mind and
happiness in life.
Through spiritual discipline,
I know how important is
submittance to you.
But, Madhav, you say
that to the Almighty
no humans are standing here,
or all place,
but
I still see humans standing here.
All humans, Madhav.
I want to have a glimpse of your
true being, Madhav.
Your power, glory, knowledge,
in all majesty,
divine form.
I want to see it, Madhav.
Display your devastating being
to me, Madhav,
to quash all doubts in my heart.
Show your self, Madhav.
Behold, Arjuna.
Through the knowledge of divinity (sankya yoga), one attains discipline in altruistic deeds.
Through that discipline (karma yoga),
one attains spirituality.
And through spirituality (bhakti yoga),
one attains knowledge.
Behold that my 'murti'* form
*An image in which the Divine Spirit is expressed ('murta').
is the knowldge of the truth, Arjuna.
This is the supreme knowledge.
This form is the base of all
knowledge and sciences.
This knowledge bestows salvation.
Even the gods can't see this form easily.
This form I manifested for you, Arjuna.
I reside in each and every particle
of this universe.
And earth, sun, moon,
galaxy, and constellations reside in me.