'A Few Days Later.
Hastinapur.'
After many years,
we have been blessed
with a suitable reward for our
labour throughout the year.
And this time, we have also
had a good amount of rain.
People are obtaining
more money these days.
Hence, they are becoming
more prosperous.
No wonder they are buying grains
from us at a higher price.
Ever since the son of Pandu,
Yudhishthir
became the Crown Prince even
the Gods are pleased with him.
The ogres used to cause
nuisance near the borders
but Prince Arjun has
put an end to it.
Friend, the entire
kingdom is safe.
What more could
the subjects ask for?
Just safety and prosperity.
It's nothing but the majesty of
the Crown Prince, Yudhishthir.
You are correct.
Greetings, uncle.
May glory be yours.
Greetings, brother Yudhishthir.
Bless you.
To see the Kuru Princes
become fond of each other
gives me immense
happiness, Minister.
Had the King of Gandhar
not been in Hastinapur
I too would have
thought so, Kripacharya.
He must certainly be scheming
to disrupt Hastinapur's peace.
'The spider shown in this scene'
'has been generated
through computer graphics.'
A spider works very hard
to spin a web.
How does it aid the spider?
Have you ever thought
about it, Dusshasan?
No, uncle.
The enemy submits before it
on his own free will.
He moves slowly
towards his death.
He becomes utterly helpless.
He squirms about.
But he is
unable to do anything.
In the end
he gives up his life.
This gives one unparalleled joy,
beloved Dusshasan.
The day our enemies
decide to go to Varnavrat* themselves
*A forest, present day Barnava.
that day I too
shall experience
such contentment.
Purochan has made
all the arrangements
as per your plan.
The Pandavas will
certainly go to Varnavrat
but they will
never return, uncle.
But
what if the Pandavas refuse
to go to Varnavrat?
The Crown Prince can be given
such an order
only by His Highness.
There won't be any need
to give such an order.
Yudhishthir himself
will ask for the permission
or he will have to see
with his precious eyes
the supremacy of Hastinapur
get crumbled into dust.
I do not understand, brother.
- Dusshasan!
My beloved!
When you strike at
the flat end of a nail
the pointed end
sinks into the earth.
When it comes to the cornerstone
of righteousness in Hastinapur
your grandsire Bhishma
is like a nail's flat end
while the pointed end is
Crown Prince Yudhishthir.
If you strike at your grandsire
then Yudhishthir will be
forced to sink into the earth.
Insult that old geyser
and keep at it,
my beloved nephews!
That is our plan's second stage.
And the first stage
of this insult
involves Dushala's marriage.
Sukta, I was awaiting you.
You are my eyes.
Just look at these ornaments.
Aren't they beautiful?
I had these made for
Dushala's 'swayamvar.'
'Swayamvar?'
Princess Dushala cannot have
a 'swayamvar,' Her Highness.
Why?
Do you not know?
Everyone in the palace
is discussing this.
Prince Duryodhan has announced
Princess Dushala's marriage
to Jayadratha,
the King of Sindhu.
How can that be possible?
Sindhu has had enmity
with Hastinapur for ages.
His Highness and uncle Bhishma
will never agree to it.
That is impossible,
brother Duryodhan.
Dushala cannot be married to
Jayadratha, the King of Sindhu.
Without even seeking permission
how could you propose this
marriage to the King of Sindhu?
The decision to have
my sister married
is my personal matter.
Mulling over Princess Dushala's
marriage and its consequences
is the duty of the Ministers,
Prince Duryodhan.
You are well aware
that only those kings are
invited to a 'swayamvar'
with whom forming
personal relationships
does not adversely
affect the kingdom.
I do not wish to turn
my sister's marriage
into politics, Minister.
Prince Duryodhan
we shall forge no relationship
with either Magadha or Sindhu.
And this has always been
the policy of our kingdom.
The duty of carrying out
the policies of the kingdom
is that of brother Yudhishthir.
He is the Crown Prince.
Not me.
To me,
the happiness of my sister
is above all else.
Princess Dushala
is not only your sister
but also the daughter
of His Highness.
Water is water
whether is it found
in a river or a pitcher.
However, only river water
is worshipped
and not the water in a pitcher.
The values and duties
of a person
are determined
based on his rank.
It is essential
to have a Princess
married through the mode
of a 'swayamvar.'
Sage Vashishtha was married
to the Princess of Vidarbha,
Lopamudra, Bhishma
because it was Lopamudra's wish.
Then why can't beloved Dushala
marry the King of Sindhu
out of her free will?
But of course
you have always used
your sense of duty
to crush the desires and wishes
of everyone around you.
- King of Gandhar!
Watch what you are saying.
Insulting grandsire
was not uncle's intentions,
uncle Vidur.
The sense of duty
is the most supreme
and toughest in the world.
But we ordinary people
cannot execute such
a tough task, Minister.
The Prince is correct, Minister.
The Lord of Sun burns himself
in order to
illuminate the world.
The moon does not have
the power to burn.
Hence, it cannot
illuminate the earth.
It can only provide coolness.
A person who did not marry
cannot be expected to
understand the affection
for one's family.
A person who did not marry
cannot be expected to
understand the affection
for one's family.
I did not get married
because the sons and
grandsons of my brother
are my family, King of Gandhar.
And King Dhritarashtra knows it.
The heart pumps blood
through the body.
And the heart beats
because of the blood.
The way the heart and the blood
cannot be separated.
Similarly
the progeny of the Kuru dynasty
and I are not different.
King of Gandhar
do remember.
The sense of duty is borne of
affection and compassion.
And Prince Duryodhan
it is the love of the Sun God
that makes him burn himself in
order to illuminate the world.
Indeed, uncle Vidur.
But it is also true
that the light of the sun
gives birth to vegetation
while that of the moon
gives birth to herbs.
In other words
that which is valuable
stems from the sense of duty
or love?
Brother Duryodhan
there is no point
to a discussion now.
Grandsire has said that
Dushala will have a 'swayamvar'
and his words are
like an order to us!
It may be an order
to you, Crown Prince
and to the Ministers of the
royal court of Hastinapur
but not to me.
The truth is, we have
a major dilemma at hand.
But it is not a dilemma for me
because I am
not the Crown Prince.
It is a dilemma for you
but I am the son
of His Highness!
You cannot curtail
any of my actions.
But I can curtail your actions.
A waterfall erodes the earth.
The earth can never be
an obstacle to a waterfall.
Grandsire.
Beloved Yudhishthir
once, Goddess Parvati had closed
Lord Shiva's eyes
out of playfulness.
And at that moment
the entire creation had
plunged into darkness.
And from that darkness
was born a demon called Andhak.
And he began tormenting
the entire creation.
It was a grim situation
for the Gods.
The son of Lord Shiva
and Goddess Parvati
could be killed only by
Lord Shiva and Goddess Parvati.
We are in a similar situation.
Back then, Lord Shiva had
salvaged the world, grandsire.
Dhritarashtra cannot
curtail his son's actions.
Or maybe
he does not have
the desire to do so.
There is only one solution
to this situation, grandsire.
You must take a decision,
grandsire.
You must ask me to step down
as the Crown Prince
and declare Duryodhan
as the new Crown Prince.
Otherwise he will
keep doing such things.
He will approach the Kings
who are not the allies of Kuru
and befriend them.
And he will forge an enmity
with the Kings
who are our allies.
He will keep posing such
problems for us, grandsire.
Are you scared of
such problems, Yudhishthir?
I did not expect this from you.
Your insult scares me,
grandsire.
And Duryodhan will
keep posing situations
where you will be insulted.
And do you believe, you stepping
down as the Crown Prince
will add to my respect?
Yudhishthir
I had promised my father
that until the kingdom
of Hastinapur
would find a righteous
and brave king
I would continue
this struggle of mine.
And if
you step down
as the Crown Prince
and despite your presence
I have to declare Duryodhan
as the Crown Prince
then my promise
will go unfulfilled.
My lifelong struggle
will go in vain.
And this...
This will be
the biggest insult to me.
Until you are alive
you cannot forsake Hastinapur.