Goodbye, Your Majesty.
Bless you.
Goodbye, grandfather.
May you live long.
Goodbye, father.
May you be victorious, son.
May you be victorious.
Goodbye, uncle.
Bless you.
- Goodbye, teacher.
May you be victorious.
Goodbye, grandfather.
Goodbye.
May you be victorious.
Princes
this is the first battle
of your lives.
All the art and knowledge
taught by me
and even your might
will seem scant in this battle
because your opponent
is my friend Drupad.
From my revered father
the great sage Bharadwaj
Drupad learnt the same art
which all of you
have learnt from me.
Me and my son Ashwatthama
will not take part
in this battle
because Drupad had told me
that if I am proud of my art
then I needed
to generate a warrior
who could defeat him.
And I have
accepted his challenge.
All of you
must uphold the honour
of your teacher.
If anyone is fearful
of this battle then
I release that person
from the duty
of Paying my fee.
Is there anyone
who doubts my teachings
or has no faith
in his own ability?
Is there anyone?
We have faith, teacher!
Splendid.
All of you may proceed
for the battle.
But the sons of Dhritarashtra
must go back.
Father, what are you saying?
What kind of partiality is this?
It is not partiality.
It is not partiality at all!
One who doubts my teachings
and has no faith
in his own capability
cannot be accepted by me
as my disciple.
I cannot ask for my fee
from such a person, Ashwatthama.
If I had to defeat Drupad
by any means possible
then I would have approached
the King of Hastinapur
as a trader intent on
making a business deal.
I would not have meditated
and waited all these years.
But we have
complete faith, teacher.
In order to protect oneself, if
one is accompanied by a warrior
who is not my disciple
I do not deem it faith, Prince.
I have no faith in his archery
because I did not
teach him that.
I do not know from where
he learnt the art.
Hence, if you lose
because of him
I will be the one
to be humiliated.
And even if you win
because of him
I will still be humiliated.
'The Region of Arya.'
'North, North-East,
East, South-East'
'South, South-West,
West, North-West.'
'Vidarbh, Kunti,
Hastinapur.'
'Ganges,
Panchal
City of Kampilya.'
Is Drupad really that illusory
brother Arjun?
Those who
do not trust their eyesight
their vision cannot be
restrained by anything.
The biggest victory is
to gain victory
over one's senses.
Learn to control your senses
like me, Sahadev.
One who does not seek
any happiness in his life
cannot be defeated by anyone.
Would you like to have
a 'laddoo,' brother Bheem?
'Laddoo!'
Where is it?
Do you have one?
Could I have it?
This is my brother
who seeks no happiness
in this world.
I have taken the oath of
not eating 'laddoos,' brother.
I shall not even
think about them.
I might think about them
but I won't eat any
until we defeat Drupad
and have you
coronated as the Prince.
'Panchal.'
We shall make use
of the spiral formation.
We shall divide ourselves
into three battalions.
The first battalion,
comprising me, shall lead.
Dusshasan
you shall lead
the second battalion.
Your battalion will be behind
mine in the southern direction.
Vikarna
your battalion shall be
in the north
and will attack
from that direction.
In order to navigate
through any labyrinth
the 'Sharvyooh'* is the most efficient one.
*Chakravyuh or Padmavyuh, is a multi-tier defensive formation that looks like a blooming lotus (padma, पद्म) or disc (chakra, चक्र).
Drupad will certainly be
at the center of his army.
I
need to reach him.
Friend Duryodhan
before we defeat Drupad,
we must defeat his General.
I have heard
that Drupad's General
is immortal.
No one is immortal.
But Drupad's General cannot die.
It is due to an oath
taken in his past life.
And until he fulfills it
he won't die.
And that is why
Drupad has made him his General.
No matter how many times
the enemies kill him
he rises up every single time.
And upon seeing this miracle
their enemies run away
out of fright.
Friend, if we tie him up with a 'Paashastra'*
Snare tactic.
then defeating Drupad
will not be impossible.
Vikarna, do you know
how to use a 'Paashastra'?
I do know, brother
but I have no faith in me.
But Arjun knows.
To win with the help of Arjun
is to be defeated, friend.
Do remember, Dusshasan.
Under all circumstances
Drupad must be defeated
only at my hands.
This is mandatory.
But how will you
achieve this, friend?
Yudhishthir is the eldest.
He will also be
the General of your army.
And you will have to fight
according to his strategies.
In other words,
under all circumstances
Yudhishthir is bound to win.
Did you hear, General?
Drona is arriving here
with the Princes of Hastinapur.
They are only 105 princes
but you have
two limitless armies with you.
Take them in as prisoners.
Then Bhishma will come
to save them.
The aim of your life
will be fulfilled
and Panchal will take over
the kingdom of Hastinapur.
'I am here as the representative
of the kingdom of Hastinapur.'
'I have come here on behalf
of Prince Vichitravirya'
'to ask for the hands
of your daughters in marriage.'
'If any of the Kings
present here disagree with me'
'then that King has the right
to challenge me.'
'A true warrior
can never pass up'
'an opportunity for a combat,
son of Ganga!'
'I have accepted King Shalv!
as my husband with my heart.'
'That I'll choose King Shalv as
my husband in this 'swayamvar'
'had already been decided.'
'You have won me in the court
by displaying your might.'
'Now, if I am to be married'
'it will be only with you,
son of Ganga, Bhishma!'
'But this is not possible.'
'I have taken
a vow of celibacy.'
'And I am here to break
that very vow, Bhishma.'
'You should seek the help
of my teacher, Lord Parashuram'
'and if I am guilty'
'then only one person
is capable of punishing me'
'namely, my teacher
Lord Parashuram.'
'Until the solution
to my problem is found'
'Lord Parashuram
must continue this battle.'
'My Lord,
fulfill this wish of mine.'
'I wish to see him dead,
Mahadev.'
'I wish to be
the reason of his death.'
'Aiming at a higher goal'
'or more a noble deed'
'when you wish
the death of Bhishma'
'you will certainly become
the reason of his demise.'
'Then I do not wish to live'
'but I shall return
in my next life'
'after 25 years.'
'This girl will take revenge
for my insult.'
'And this girl shall be
called Shikhandini.'
'And when your soul
will be fatigued and aged'
'I shall be born with
the purpose of killing you.'
Bhishma!