Did Queen Gandhari
give birth to a lump of flesh?
Yes, Madri.
A lump of flesh
has been delivered.
But why, Lord?
Why is brother-in-law and
sister-in-law's life filled with
so much of
sorrows and grievances?
Not just them
the whole of Hastinapur
and the entire Kuru clan
is a victim of this misfortune.
Even your son
Yudhisthir, Kunti.
Yudhisthir's misfortune!
My father used to say...
Only an unfortunate king
lacks a brother or a kin
for his protection.
A lone tree gets uprooted
easily during a storm.
If it is in a group,
it doesn't get uprooted.
Kunti
I've thought over
what Madri said.
Madri is absolutely right.
Now that Yudhisthir
is the future of Hastinapur
four brothers are also required
for his protection.
You have to invoke the deities
again with the help of mantras.
The Kuru clan wants
four more heirs from you.
Hail Lord Mahadev!
Let's go, Sanjay.
Why did you stop, Sanjay?
Who has obstructed my way?
- It's sire Bheeshma, King.
King, I've learnt that
you've set up an army
to attack someone.
- Yes.
I am going to
conquer everything!
East, West, North, South!
I've taken an oath
to extend my kingdom all over!
I can't give you
permission for this.
I don't need
anybody's permission!
I've had enough of obeying
orders and commands!
I kept following
these obligations so far!
But to no avail.
Now, I'll take my own decisions.
Disperse!
Do take your own decisions.
But the river which flows
with violent speed and current...
The water of such a river
is not fit for drinking.
When someone is enraged
he loses control
over his mind.
Take a decision
when you calm down.
I don't want to calm down!
What did I gain by taking
decisions while staying calm?
Except humiliation, disgrace
and indignity!
The Queen Mother got me married
to the Princess of Gandhar.
It was a wise decision,
wasn't it?
But what did I gain?
What?
Gandhari insulted me
by blindfolding herself!
But still, I accepted her
at your behest.
What did I gain from that,
sire?
What did I gain?
What and when has
Dhritarashtra ever gained?
But, Your Majesty...
Brother, what will you gain by
following the path of warfare?
I will...
I definitely will...
When the fever
is too high
villagers burn their hands.
That pain...
That pain fetches the heat out
of their bodies.
Vidur, I am also in search
of one such pain.
I want to feel the pain of
wounds caused by swords.
So that, I don't get to hear
the lament of my heart.
I don't want to hear that.
I don't want to hear that...
I don't have any son.
My wife has delivered
a lump of flesh.
What sort of irony
is this?
Because of being blind
I have always been at
the mercy of people.
Now, am I supposed to face
their tongue-lashing as well?
What will they think of me?
What sort of a man am I
who is incapable of giving
a child to his wife?
I couldn't
give her a child.
Don't insult Mahadev
by using such words.
To expect a child from Gandhari
was our mistake.
It was my mistake.
I should have understood earlier
that it's not possible
for a woman to give birth
to a 100 children
in a single lifetime.
God's blessing never
goes in vain.
Actually, she has not given
birth to a lump of flesh.
She has delivered the source
of a 100 babies.
Your 100 children have taken
birth in the form of seeds.
Now, the person
who can bring them
to life is my son...
Sage Vedvyas.
Shakuni, what is the sage doing?
He has prepared
an underground cave
and named it 'Kshiti Garbha'.*
*"Earth Womb"
Vedvyas has said that
inside this cave
Gandhari's sons will get formed.
If he can really
perform miracles
then why doesn't he
cast some spell
and give life to my children?
Vedvyas doesn't
perform miracles
his knowledge does.
He is the son-in-law
of Sage Jabal*
Vedvyas' father-in-law.
an expert on the Atharva Veda.
Have faith in him.
He will keep his word.
Vedvyas has summoned
Queen Gandhari and all of you
to the 'Kshiti Garbha'.
Greetings, mother.
The 100 embryos
that Gandhari has blessed
the royal family with...
I have embedded them
in these 100 urns. Mother
they are all
floating in clarified butter
that has been specially treated.
And they are being
nurtured with
many unique miraculous
herbs.
When the right time comes,
in these urns
Gandhari's 100 children
will take birth.
And, Gandhari
when Lord Shiv blessed you
and gave you this boon
you must have had a desire
for a daughter too.
The Lord has also answered
this unspoken desire of yours.
A daughter will be born
from the 101st urn.
The first feature of a king
is his strength.
Yudhisthir will be known for
his good and just deeds.
And I know that.
But a king's deeds and
justness receive respect
only when he has the strength
to protect that justice.
I want a son, Kunti
who has the strength of
a 1000 elephants in his arms.
He should be like the wind,
when it comes to strength.
Just like when the Lord of Wind
gets angry
he destructs the forests,
brings about cyclones
he destructs mountains and
converts them to dust.
The same strength should be
possessed by my son, Kunti.
Chant the mantra and
invite the Lord of Wind, Kunti.
Tell me, Shakuni.
What does the sight
look like?
Is there...
Is there any flutter
in any of the urns?
Is there...
Is there any sign of
life visible?
This cave
is filled with the lives of my
nephews, Your Highness.
There's a flutter in
each of these urns.
Just like the one in your
brother Pandu's heart.
The same kind of
flutter.
Pandu!
Fluttering, in Pandu's heart?
Of course! Don't you
feel it, Your Highness?
Not just flutter but a quake.
There's a quake in his
heart, Your Highness.
His son, in spite of being
the oldest in the royal family
is helpless in front
of these 100 sons.
Just watch.
My 100 sons will be
his strength, Shakuni.
Strength!
Your 100 sons
will be the strength of Pandu's
son, Your Highness?
Then you will do
the right thing.
My dear sister
has deceived you,
Your Highness.
Instead of giving you
a 100 princes
she has given you a 100 ordinary
soldiers, Your Highness.
Who will be Pandu's son's
bodyguards.
One of them will carry
his sword for him.
One will hold his
fan for him.
And one of them will also
have to pick up his slippers,
Your Highness.
My dear sister is very evil,
Or else, you are
deceiving my dear sister,
Your Highness.
She went through so much pain
and gave you a 100 princes.
And you...
You wish
to bring them up
as a 100 ordinary soldiers?
Who has cheated whom?
I'm unable to understand it,
Your Highness.
This is a very complex question.
But
when the time comes
you only will have to
answer it.
At your invitation
I have appeared, Kunti.
I am here to fulfil the boon
of Sage Durvasa.
Then bless me with a son as
powerful as you, Lord.
Half the body of
your son
is made of adamantine, Kunti.
I will myself reside
in his arms.
His enemies will shiver on
hearing of his achievements.
He will be very powerful.
The whole world will know him
by the name of Vrikodar Bheem.*
*Vrikodar: 'one with a wolf's belly'.
Bheem: 'terrible', 'awful'.
My Bheem.
I will go and get
milk for him.
Bheem!
Bheem...
My son.