Tomorrow herein
I shall step onto
the battlefield
as an undeterred warrior.
With only triumph,
clenching my mind.
Sanjay, today grandsire
shall obliterate the Pandavas' army.
Assume that today,
is the final day of the war.
My sons
shall emerge victorious
while the Pandavas
will concede defeat.
Tell me. What is
happening on the battlefield?
The Pandava warriors are cooking
up a battle formation, my King.
Commander Dhrishtadyumna.
You, along with elder brother
shall confront Duryodhan
at the centerfield
of the battlefield.
Bhima, Nakula, Sahadev.
Attack the forces
of the Kaurava, from the west.
It's your foremost
responsibility
to rebuff Lord Dronacharya.
King Virat, Abhimanyu and I
shall entice grandsire
into battle.
Brother, attack Duryodhan
the moment is vulnerable.
Soldiers, get to your
respective positions
at the earliest.
The battle formation
is about to commence.
Praise the lord!
Grandsire, declare
the battle formations to begin.
You had urged that you would
decimate the Pandava's army.
Incentives are not
achieved by formations
but by a sense of purpose,
Prince Duryodhan.
Why hasn't grandsire
created a formation, yet?
What if, like the first day
he is planning to attack
our army from both sides?
No, Arjun.
Grandsire is a
distinguished General.
The formations,
which his enemies can comprehend
he will never put up with the
same strategy again.
Moreover
war needs a formation
decimate doesn't have one.
Lord Dronacharya, you will stay
at the end of the battlefield.
And shall protect
Prince Duryodhan.
Prince Duryodhan!
You had questioned
my sense of duty.
Today, you shall view
with your own eyes
how I carry through,
my obligation.
Let's move, my friend.
Grandsire!
It's not your Grandsire,
Arjun.
It's Kaurava's accomplished general.
The proficient follower of duty.
The saviour of traditions.
Lord Bhishma!
Pandava!
Get ready,
to engage with Bhishma.
Your army,
will not be allowed to surrender
nor could they take off
from the battlefield.
On this battlefield
the only thing they
could partake in, is death.
'The third day of war.'
Lord Bhishma had
caused us great many casualties.
With just nine attacks
he annihilated two
battalions of our soldiers.
I could feel for a while
that we weren't facing off
against the grandsire
rather the Lord of Death,
was present.
Pertaining yesterdays'
involvement, I thought
Grandsire was
against the Kauravas.
I thought he would
hold off our onslaught.
But wouldn't attack
us in return.
What could have
changed his mind?
His perception has changed,
Sahadev.
Fingers were raised against his
sense of duty.
Henceforth,
he is ready to embrace death
or embark upon, to take up ours.
Hereafter, from today,
our only objective
is the death of grandsire.
[MUSIC]
'Fourth day of the war.'
Your Grace, we just have four
battalions of soldiers left.
In just a day, Lord Bhishma
had thumped our forces.
And this is just the
fourth day of war.
It is impossible to
defeat grandsire.
Every potent individual
has tried his best.
But grandsire
has always triumphed.
If we do not stop grandsire
then he will
obliterate our armies.
Run!
'Fifth Day of the War.'
The funeral pyres of the enemies
are burning till the horizon
Your Highness.
The wailing of widowed women
is driving a stake through
the hearts of the sons of Pandu.
It seems as though
the torches in their camp
are spreading
darkness instead of light
today, Your Highness.
This very darkness will engulf
their fortune as well, Sanjay.
The power to revolt
against uncle
does not reside
in Lord Indra himself.
'Sixth Day of the War.'
Your Excellency
the Pandava army has been
reduced to three 'akshauhini.'
If you annihilate them
then the war will be over.
No,
Guru Drona.
This war
will not end
until Yudhishthir gets slain
and I must slay him.
'Seventh Day of the War.'
Seven days ago, we had
seven 'akshauhini' army with us
but now, we merely have
two 'akshauhini' army.
However, they still have nine
'akshauhini' army with them.
We tried to attack
grandsire numerous times
but were unsuccessful.
Can no one
revolt against grandsire,
Vasudev?
Every question has an answer,
brother Yudhishthir.
However, it is mandatory
to ask the right question
at the right time.
Vasudev, by the time
we await the right time
we will have no army with us.
We must slay grandsire
at any cost.
"Eighth Day of the War"
The valour of His Excellency
has left everyone perplexed
Your Highness.
For all these days,
neither has he eaten
nor slept a wink.
Then how can such power
get generated in his aged self,
Your Highness?
This is not a war
but my uncle's meditation,
Sanjay.
Its fruits shall be reaped
by my sons.
Mother-in-law
why is great grandsire Bhishma
standing in the battlefield?
Does he not require food,
water and rest?
Grandsire is facing the
punishment of his actions, dear.
In this battlefield
each time he will slay someone
he too will experience death.
But why, mother-in-law?
What did he do?
His Excellency Bhishma
is the sentinel of the
Kuru dynasty in terms of
its memories, power
and righteousness.
However,
blinded by attachment
he allowed unrighteousness,
lies
and deception
to enter Hastinapur.
That is why, he is facing
this punishment today.
As long as
His Excellency is alive
neither will he be
able to sleep
nor take rest.
"Ninth Day of the War."
Renounce your weapons,
dear.
I do not wish to slay you!
Great grandsire,
I leave the camp each day
with the wish to die!
You may certainly slay me!
I am prepared.
Fight me, grandsire!
Give me the opportunity as well
to showcase my competence!
I am not here in the battlefield
This war is my duty and
not my valour, dear!
I am helpless, Arjun!
Irrespective of
who attacks Hastinapur
I must slay him!