Mother, Vasuki told me
to crush the heads of my enemies
in a similar way on
the battlefield.
Nakul, I hope you
understand crushing.
Powder!
Which on being consumed
cleanses the stomach.
Brother Bheem...
How can you laugh in such
an alarming situation?
Doesn't your blood boil
with anger?
Anger?
I am so angry that my
palms may emit fire
that is why I was
laughing, brother.
The sinners aren't aware
that Bheem has become stronger than Hanuman* himself.
*A central character in the epic Ramayana. Vayu is the spiritual father of Hanuman.
I have taken an oath.
I would be the one
to kill the hundred brothers.
Quiet, Bheem.
It isn't appropriate for us to
talk about killing our brothers.
Have you forgotten
father's words?
Bravery lies in being merciful
and not in seeking vengeance.
Yudhistir, don't tell him
to be quiet today.
One can forgive his enemies
but not his family members.
Plants come to life from water.
That's why wood
doesn't submerge in water.
The day wood
submerges in water
it will be doomsday.
And when a family deceives
there arises a calamity
in the family.
There's no longer any place
for us in Hastinapur.
We will now got to your
grandfather's place
to Kuntibhoj.
Kunti, don't punish the
Kuru dynasty so severely.
The daughter-in-law who at
her husband's house
doesn't get happiness, comfort
and respect
not only the family
but the entire dynasty
is disgraced.
The ancestors in heaven
feel humiliated.
But, sire...
I have collected all
the information
from my spies.
The way when a part of
a body is wounded
the brain feels the pain.
I'm enduring the pain
of this incident.
I have decided to find a
solution to this dilemma.
Dear, I request you
please stay back.
Believe me, Kunti.
Don't you trust me, dear?
Yes, sire.
Your majesty, couldn't you hear
my footsteps today?
I...
Greetings, sire.
You shouldn't greet me
sitting on the throne!
Aren't you conscious
about that today?
Your majesty, what were you
listening to with such
concentration that you didn't
hear my footsteps today?
I...
- You were probably listening to
the thundering sound of the
anarchy previaling in Hastinapur
Or were you hearing the
cries of our august
ancestors in heaven,
your majesty!
Why are your words so harsh?
- Because I had become tough
and taken an oath to protect
this throne and its glory.
What is the problem
that makes you... - Problem?
Your majesty, the problem
is that you haven't
called the justice committee.
Justice?
For what?
My son is innocent.
If you were confident
that he is innocent
then that could be heard
in your voice, your majesty.
Duryodhana is just a kid.
When you had decided to
make him the crown prince
hadn't you realized then
that he is a kid.
King, you have to do justice!
Pardon me, sire.
What judgment shall I rule out?
The love for my son
weakens me.
I was born blind.
Distrust is my sole asset.
So apart from my son
I am unable to trust
anyone else.
Dear, several people in
this world are blind.
You are not the first.
But they lead their life
respectfully and independently.
The don't plead for mercy.
They have made trust
the basis of their life
and not discontent
like you have.
Please forgive my son.
Let me assure you
I take an oath that
when the time comes
whoever you think is eligible
I will declare him as
the crown prince.
I will not argue.
But please pardon my
son for now.
If an innocent child kicks, no
one considers it a humiliation.
I will be agonized to
punish him.
I will be heartbroken.
If you tell me,
I will touch Kunti's feet
and apologise to her.
But do not order me
to judge Duryodhana.
Do not order me
to judge my Duryodhan.
Alright.
I have one adequate verdict
for the both of you.
You have to distance
yourself from him.
That would mean
the way Pandu's son
don't have the protection
of their father
in the same way
you have to stop
protecting your sons.
At Guru Drona's academic
institution
all your sons would study
for twelve years.
And in the twelve years
you will not try to contact
your sons in anyway.
Dear, you will be the one to
take the decision
today itself.
Kripi! Ashwathama!
I have taken my first step
towards my dream.
The burden of my past that
I carry within
I will soon be relieved of it.
Ashwathama!
Ashwathama.
Son, till now you were
destined to be impoverished.
Now...
I will see to it that you
become the king of a state.
With the help of these princes.
That's surprising!
The soldiers from
Gandhar are here.
With so many things
What has father sent
from Gandhar?
These are my belongings.
Who has loaded them
on the chariots?
These are arrangements
made for your journey
King Shakuni.
Greetings, Sir Bheeshma.
King Shakuni!
Why are you mocking me?
I am not mocking you.
Your father
the king of Gandhar, king
Subala has decided that
he will renounce his throne
and become an ascetic.
Thus, I addressed
you as the king.
Is father embracing anchorite?
Who gave you this information?
No one did.
Actually, I was the one
to send him a message
that it's time for him
to be an ascetic.
Thus...
He will declare his son
which means you,
as the king.
And Gandhar cannot dare
to disobey my orders.
Thus, you have finally
become a king.
And
do you have any reason
for being
so kind to me, Sir Bheeshma?
King of Gandhar,
the reason is
that it's right for a king
to stay at his capital.
Your team of bodyguards
are ready
to take you to Gandhar.
Please proceed.
Let me seek king
Dhritarashtra's permission...
That isn't needed.
I have taken the
king's permission.
Let me seek Gandhari's
permission...
I have taken the queen's
permission
on your behalf.
Please come.
Are you
throwing me
out of Hastinapur, Sire?
That there's no opportunity
to expel you
and you don't lose respect
that's what I'm trying to do.
Proceed.
Proceed!