May God bless you.
Greetings, sister.
Greetings, Dhrishtadyumna.
Vasudeva
this Brahman
who has sworn never
to ride a chariot
are you sure
that he will one day
sit on the throne?
Your daughter will definitely
sit on a throne, Your Highness.
You're
worried about
your daughter's future.
But every day
and every moment
of the future
has been decided.
Your Highness, future
is nothing but
the result of our present
decisions and deeds.
If you're happy with the
decisions you took today
then have faith
you will definitely be blessed
with a happy future.
A difficult competition
of archery
was won by a Brahman, Vidur.
Yes, sir.
Even the message
of our spy reads the same.
That when no prince
could triumph
the princess was married
to a young Brahman.
Then, Vidur
you will have to leave
for Kampilya, immediately
in order to get
that young Brahman
his four brothers
and mother
to Hastinapur.
But no one should learn that
the five Pandavas are alive.
Before Shakuni formulates
another conspiracy
get all the five Pandavas
and their mother to Hastinapur.
Definitely, grandsire.
Brahman Batukeshwar
isn't it necessary during
a marriage to know the names
of the bride and the groom?
Uh!
I didn't ask this young Brahman
his name.
What's your name?
V-Vateshwar.
Vateshwar!
And what's your lineage?
Lineage?
Why do you want to know
about my lineage?
I should know your lineage in
order to get you two married.
Hey!
Someshwar...
Someshwar!
Someshwar.
Som...
Someshwar!
Your elder brother acted smart.
Your
secret was not revealed.
Secret...
What secret?
How am I to know that?
But there's
definitely some secret.
You don't reveal
your lineage.
You can't remember your name.
You are the world's best archer
yet, you don't wield a bow!
I have learnt archery
that's why I'm good.
I don't aim
to be the best.
I'm a Brahman.
Hence I don't wield a bow.
What is the secrecy in it?
Brother Someshwar!
Why did you halt?
He says that the princess
is not married.
Hence she cannot be left
alone with you.
Hey...
Someshwar, I want to see
Vateshwar's face.
Show me his face.
Come on, quick!
Tell me your lineage.
You are to be married.
Brahman Batukeshwar
will you get us married
on the way?
The marriage will take place
in the society
in everyone's presence.
I'm just recollecting
the marital chants.
But
are these the marital chants?
Being a Brahman,
don't you know
what the marital chants are?
- Brother Someshwar
the marital chants at your
wedding were different.
Yes.
Those chants were...
What is he reciting?
Are you married to a demoness?
You made a very big mistake,
Brahman Batukeshwar.
Now, brother Someshwar is angry.
You call my wife a demoness!
No one has the courage
to marry a demoness.
Princess.
Princess, protect me.
You're right, sir.
But if you kill the demoness'
brother, Hidimb
then you have to marry Hidimba.
How do you know this, princess?
The king's spies give him
all the information.
But, sir
only demons can win
against the demons, right?
Other than Lord Parashuram
and Guru Dronacharya
no ordinary Brahman
can defeat them.
This means
a...
A demon has won me?
I definitely have
been won by a demon.
Do I look as terrifying
as a demon to you?
What?
Are demons terrifying?
No, brother.
That's not what I meant.
I was just saying that
I am in a Brahman's attire.
You...
You please stop crying.
Brother Someshwar, would
sister-in-law too cry like this?
Yes, sometimes.
Now go and persuade
the princess.
How, brother?
- Apologise!
Apologise for what?
If you want to have
a peaceful married life
then keep apologising.
I am saying this
out of experience. Go.
Go.
Princess, stop crying.
Forgive me.
I lied to you.
I am not a Brahman.
I am a Kshatriya.
My name is Arjun.
And he is brother Bheem.
We have given up
our kingdom.
Hence we are disguised
as Brahmans.
I knew that.
I just wanted to
hear it from you.
Let's go.
You're not a Brahman!
You're a Kshatriya!
I had never imagined
that someone would
deceive me like this!
Leave, all of you.
Wait, sir.
At least accept the offering.
If he has renounced
all ornaments
then how can I wear them?
Give them.
It will benefit
the Brahman.
Other than those that are
the symbol of auspiciousness
give me all your ornaments.
Why did you make
me a part of this
I couldn't understand.
Brother
the minute we entered
into the 'Swayamvar'
I knew
that brother Arjun
will be victorious.
Your intuition is always
true, Sahadev.
But, why aren't they
here yet?
Brother
here they are.
Greetings, brother.
Bheem
what happened?
What took you so long?
I could see
a brilliant opportunity
hence I was waiting for it.
But I couldn't get
that opportunity, brother.
What do you mean?
It was His Highness, Shakuni
who provoked all the kings
for a battle.
I thought Duryodhan
will step forward
and I'll kill him.
But they left without fighting.
Maybe they were scared.
Don't be unjust to Karna,
brother Bheem.
He doesn't possess
the trait of fear.
Brother Sumangal
why are you referring
to brother Someshwar
as Bheem?
But why are you
referring to Vateshwar
as Sumangal?
Isn't that the name you told me?
I am sure Arjun has told
Princess Draupadi
who we really are.
What you did was right, Arjun.
The one who is capable
of being a life partner
nothing should be
hidden from her.
Brother, hadn't I told you
that I had an intuition?
Welcome, princess Draupadi.
Hold on, princess.
You're not married yet.
You're the princess of Panchal.
You touching anyone's feet
is not apt.
But I have vowed to
complete this journey
with your brother.
Yet, princess
you should first seek
mother's blessings.
Parents have the right to bestow
an identity upon any relation.
Arjun
let's go.
Take princess Draupadi
and go ahead.
Mother must be waiting.
- As you say.
Mother was about
to perform some ritual.
She must be done by now.
You're welcome, Princess.
Brother Arjun!
Mother
look what I got as alms.
Look, mother
how lucky brother Arjun has
become with just the alm.
You shouldn't say that, son.
Since childhood
I have taught you
be it alms or punishment
all five brothers will always
have equal rights on it
and not just one brother.
Mother...
- It's my order, Yudhishthira
that whatever Arjun
has received
should be shared among
all you brothers.