It is being announced to
the entire Kuru dynasty
that the daughter-in-law
of the Kuru family Kunti
has given birth to the
heir of the Kuru family.
The one who displays
auspicious characteristics
the one with numerous
positive qualities...
Such a son has been born
in the family of
Emperor Shantanu.
On this happy occasion
King Dhritarashtra himself
will announce the celebrations
in the kingdom.
Subjects of the kingdom
and people present
in the court!
By the grace of God
today, the ancestors
of the Kuru family
would be pleased.
An heir to take forward
the lineage
has been born
into the Kuru family.
I am extremely happy that
my younger brother,
my dear Pandu
got this opportunity to
please the ancestors.
On behalf of the royal family
there should be offerings,
sacraments
and prayers in all
of the kingdom.
There should be abundant
charity and offerings.
Like the sunrise
lights up the world
with happiness
in the same way, may the new
member of the Kuru family
fill the hearts of our subjects
with happiness and bliss...
Such should be
the arrangements.
This is the order of the
Kuru king Dhritarashtra!
Hail King Dhritarashtra!
Where is the princess
of Gandhar?
Where is the woman who has
brought misfortune to me?
Your Majesty...
The Queen is sleeping.
She has fallen asleep
with great difficulty.
Then, wake her up!
How can the one who made
my fortune sleep forever
sleep peacefully?
Gandhari!
Lord.
You!
Hundred!
You had promised me a 100
majestic sons, Gandhari!
Where are my 100 children?
Where is the heir to my throne?
The one who would make
my heart content
the one to redeem
me from desperation...
Where is my son?
Where is he, Gandhari?
Lord, I am confident.
The blessings of Lord Shankar*
cannot go in vain.
*A manifestation of meditative Shiva.
But what kind of blessing
has God given you?
A 100 sons who would
win over kingdoms
or a 100 sons who
would serve others?
They would lead
a life of humiliation
their father would lead
a life of humiliation.
Is that the boon
you got?
Had you really got
a boon
or is all of it fabricated?
Why haven't you
delivered yet, Gandhari?
No one can predict
birth and death.
I am not convinced with
the answer, Gandhari.
I have always been
disappointed by you.
Always disappointed!
You mocked me by
blindfolding yourself.
Yet, I didn't remarry.
Look at Kunti!
Pandu married another woman
but still, she gifted
him with a son.
And me?
I gave your respect.
I was considerate
towards your feelings.
I made you the Queen.
Yet, you didn't give me
a son at the right time.
That's why... You haven't gifted
a son at the right time
because...
I have honoured you
more than you deserve.
That was my mistake.
If you had a competitor
you would have delivered
a child by now.
Yes, it was my mistake.
But, Gandhari, I will correct
my mistake very soon.
The way you have hurt me by not
delivering the baby on time
in the same way,
I will do something
which will hurt you
all your life, at each step.
It will hurt you at every step!
It will hurt you at every step.
Lord!
Gandhari.
It isn't good to cry in
such a condition, sister.
What else shall I do, brother?
When the clouds of misfortune
are hovering on me
I will obviously have to cry!
- No, Gandhari!
No!
Don't you think like
that, Gandhari.
You will give birth to a baby,
a blessing of Lord Shiva.
You shouldn't insult God by
addressing it as a misfortune.
Consider it as meditation.
- How long should I meditate?
How long should I wait?
How much more pain
do I have to bear?
The more a tree
stands under the sun
the sweeter its fruits are.
But my husband is
getting impatient.
He cannot be blamed for it.
I have always disappointed
him as a wife.
Only disappointment.
After a long wait
I had attained my
husband's love.
That priceless possession is
slipping out of my hands.
No, Gandhari!
You shouldn't worry
about the king.
He has no control
over his anger.
But he wouldn't dare
to be unjust with you.
Because he knows
that you will be the one to
carry his 100 sons.
And no son
can love and respect a father
who is unjust to his mother.
The king must be aware of it.
Greetings, Queen.
Queen, a guard is here with
a message from the King.
What is the message?
The king has commanded
to go to his room.
But I have taken an oath.
I will not leave the temple
until... - Not you, my Queen.
The order...
What? - The order is for
your head maid.
Is it for Sugadha?
- Yes, Queen.
The King has asked Sugadha
to beautify herself
and come to his room.
The King has ordered Sugadha
to come to his room.
Me?
Why?
Queen, I won't go.
I will not go, Queen.
Is this the idea
the King has come up with
to hurt me all my life?
What are you raving, maid?
Sugadha will not go.
Sugadha will go, brother.
If my husband has
decided to punish me
then, I accept his decision.
But, Gandhari...
- Please leave, Sugadha.
Follow the King's order.
Go, Sugadha.
Sugadha, leave!
Brother, you too should leave.
I need to be alone.
Gandhari, let me
talk to the King.
You shouldn't decide
anything in a rush.
Brother, you should leave!
When someone loses hope
and his desires are shattered
his heart is full of anger.
He tries to punish the person
who he thinks, has
offended him.
But whenever we lose hope and
our desires are shattered
should we always blame
someone else for it?
There can be many reasons why
desires are left unfulfilled.
Some are unfulfilled
due to our fate
and some due to our destiny.
And sometimes, the
desires are such
that they cannot be fulfilled.
Without considering the
circumstances
it isn't right to blame someone.
Instead, it's vengeance.
The basis of justice is mercy
Pity.
And the basis of vengeance
is anger and pride.
It means...
Dealing with someone's offence
without being merciful
or to punish someone...
Isn't that being unfair?
Think for yourself.
What kind of a son are you?
You shouldn't torment
your mother.
What crime are you
punishing me for?
Why have you turned me helpless?
Why have you turned me into
a culprit before my husband?
I have waited for your
birth every moment.
I dreamt about you all the time!
I observed several fasts
for your happiness!
Either take birth
or be the cause of my death!
Be the cause!
Either take birth
or be the cause of my death!
Be the cause!
Move aside!
Has Gandhari delivered a baby?
What has she delivered?
Is it a son or a daughter?
Answer me!
Has Gandhari delivered a baby?
What has she delivered?
Is it a son or a daughter?
Answer me!
Aryavati. Rambha.
Where is my son?
How is he?
Why can't I hear him cry?
Is he alright?
Where is he?
Answer me!
Why isn't my son next to me?
Take me to my son...
Queen!
My son...
Where is my son?
Son?
Not a son
you have given birth
to a lump of flesh.