But do remember, Arjun.
This task will be exceedingly
difficult for you.
The truth is, this task will be
quite gruesome for you.
If you wish, you may test me.
- Test you?
Alright.
Then let's go.
We will move northward first
and then proceed to the East.
Subhadra
you should proceed
to the palace now.
'Murli Manohar'
'Mohan Murari.'
'In every form of yours'
'the things you do are lovely.'
'Murli Manohar'
'Mohan Murari.'
'In every form of yours'
'the things you do are lovely.'
'Whenever He breaks
a pot full of butter'
'Kanhaiya* is reminded of Yashoda, his mother.'
*Krishna
'Whenever He breaks
a pot full of butter'
'Kanhaiya is reminded of
Yashoda, his mother.'
'Though He is the
entire world's creator'
'Murari can't give up
his love for butter.'
'Murli Manohar'
'Mohan Murari.'
'In every form of yours'
'the things you do are lovely.'
'When with friends,
Kanhaiya is quite frisky'
'but this flute playing darling
can also be very naughty.'
'When with friends,
Kanhaiya is quite frisky'
'but this flute playing darling
can also be very naughty.'
'The one who pesters
the maidens of Bra") is He'
'and hence, the maidens
chase Girdhar Murari.'
'Murli Manohar'
'Mohan Murari.'
'In every form of yours'
'the things you do are lovely.'
'Kanhaiya is kind...'
'Kanhaiya is a kind buddy,
unparalleled in the world'
'never oblivious to agony.'
'To help man, he is ever ready.'
'Wondrous are
the deeds of Murari.'
Labour seems to have
magnified my strength, Madhav.
No, friend.
Helping that man has
magnified your strength.
Helping people always
magnifies one's strength.
Let's go, friend.
- 'Murli Manohar'
'Mohan Murari.'
'In every form of yours'
'the things you do are lovely.'
So, this is Kundanpur.
It is far more prosperous
than I had heard of.
Indeed, friend.
This is the capital of Vidarbha.
And over there you can see
the palace of
the King of Vidarbha.
The main entrance is over there.
Then why have we come here?
Friend, we have
come here because
we need to enter the city.
But we cannot take
the main entrance
because it will be guarded
by the soldiers of Vidarbha.
But Madhav, you said
you were invited to the wedding.
I wasn't invited to be
a part of the wedding, friend.
I have been invited here
as the groom.
The marriage
of Princess Rukmini
has been arranged with
the Prince of Chedi, Shishupal.
The entire region of Arya
know about it.
But Rukmini will be
married to me
but you are fortunate
because only you know about it
in the entire Aryan region.
What do you mean?
What do I mean?
Read it, friend.
'Srutva Gunan Bhuvana-Sundara'
'Srinvatam Te.'
What is this?
A letter, friend.
A love letter.
Who wrote it?
The Princess of Vidarbha,
Rukmini.
'Bhuvana-Sundara!'
The most beautiful in the world!
Who, Madhav?
Me, friend.
Who else?
'Tan Me Bhavan Khalu
Vritah Patir Anga Jayam.'
I... I have accepted you
as my husband!
'Vidarbhan Guptah Sametya.'
She asks you to come
to Vidarbha secretly.
Is this why you have
brought me here
instead of the main entrance?
We need to enter
the city secretly, friend
for the purpose of marriage.
We need to enter
the city secretly, friend
for the purpose of marriage.
But...
If a father has not
organized a 'swayamvar'
is it right to abduct
his daughter, Madhav?
Whether a 'swayamvar'
is organized or not
abducting a woman
against her wishes
is always wrong, friend.
The truth is, every living being
has the freedom to live his life
on his own terms
and it's a God-given right.
And snatching this freedom
is indeed wrong, friend.
And today, this wrong deed
is being committed
by Rukmini's brother.
I am merely going to save a
woman from this misdeed, friend.
Then give me the order, Madhav.
The mere sound
of my bow being plucked
will shatter the fortress
of Vidarbha!
This is what I was
afraid of, Arjun.
This is what I fear.
Rukmini has instructed
clearly in the letter
that her family members
should not get hurt.
We cannot engage
in a battle with them.
Besides, friend.
When eloping is easier
why engage in violence
unnecessarily?
You need to meet Rukmini
secretly and tell her
that as mentioned in the letter
I will wait for her in
the temple of Goddess Parvati.
Meet her secretly, Madhav?
What disguise will we be in?
Yes!
Disguise...
I will dress up as a cowherd.
I have quite the practice
in being one.
And what about me, Madhav?
Stop!
What have you got there?
Some 'kheer.'
It's a sacrament.
Who are you?
I am Gopal.
The one who raises cows.
No one is allowed
to enter this place.
People are not allowed to enter?
Yes.
Alright.
Sire, I have got it now.
That Yadava...
Krishna!
He has tarnished the reputation
of us cowherds.
He has committed such deeds
that even heavily armoured
soldiers like you
are afraid of us cowherds.
It's alright.
- We are not afraid.
Then may I g-go
and deliver this 'kheer?'
To Prince Shishupal.
Alright.
You can enter.
But you need to be back soon.
As you say, sire.
Thank you.
As you say.
Come here!
Brihannala!
Who is she?
She is my sister, sire.
Her name is Brihannala.
She is taller and bigger
than most women.
Hence, our mother
named her Brihannala.
Let's go.
Madhav.
What kind of a disguise
is this, Madhav?
I had told you, friend
this task is going to be
quite gruesome for you.
Better get used to it.
Who knows when it might just
come in handy to you.
And even the name of Brihannala.
Friend
that is Rukmi.
Rukmini's elder brother.
The Crown Prince of Vidarbha.
We should ask him as to where
Rukmini's chamber is.
What are you saying, Madhav?
He will find out about
your true identity.
Even you don't know
my true identity, friend.
Then he has no chance
of knowing it.
Hold this.
Prince! Give me
your blessings, Prince!
Bless you.
Who are you?
Prince, the great sage Durvasa
has sent this sacrament.
As he is busy
with another undertaking
he will be unable
to attend the wedding.
So, he has sent this sacrament
for the groom and the bride.
Alright. Give that to me.
- N-No, Prince.
He had said that only the groom
and the bride can touch it
otherwise it will
get unsanctified.
Alright.
Deliver it yourself.
Deliver it myself, Prince?
Prince, my sister Brihannala.
She can deliver the sacrament
to the Princess
but only if you permit it.
Alright but not right away.
She can deliver it to the
chamber upstairs after a while.
To that chamber?
As you say, Prince!
Madhav, you touched his feet!
Friend, he is Rukmini's
elder brother.
So, I had to touch his feet.
Besides, who knows
whether in the future,
we will get his blessings
or not.
Was that sacrament really sent
by the great sage Durvasa?
Are you doubting me, friend?
It was indeed sent by him.
His hermitage is very
close-by to Dwaraka.
I had asked for it for the groom
and the bride myself.
Hold this.
Friend, I am the groom.
Hence, I was bound
to consume this sacrament.
Now, you must go.
Bring Rukmini to the temple
of the Goddess in three hours.
I shall be waiting for you.
- 'Murli Manohar'
'Mohan Murari.'
'In every form of yours'
'the things you do are lovely.'