My life is more precious.
Dear Prince. Why are we
at such a desolate place?
You will know
soon enough, Ullok.
Fireflies.
They twinkle like my beloved
sister's eyes.
Now Gandhari shall never have to
fear darkness, Ullok.
Catch them all.
Shukra.
My friend.
So you've brought news
from the capital.
Dhritarashtra?
Dhritarashtra!
I heard that Bheeshma,
the son of Ganga
had been to lay siege
on Vidarbha.
Not Vidarbha,
he'd been to Gandhar instead.
Have the Kuru's ever
attacked anyone?
Bheeshma had been there
with a marriage proposal.
Greetings, grandfather. - May
you live long, Dhritarashtra.
Greetings, grandfather.
- Vidur.
- Pandu.
Greetings, mother.
What do I even bless you,
my prodigal son?
A blessing for a long life
is futile
for you have a boon,
to choose your death at will.
A mother always
blesses for happiness.
As long as the throne of
Hastinapur lies vacant
how can I ever
be truly happy?
An orchard
full of fruit laden trees
And a derelict throne,
without a king
suffer the same
ill fate, Bheeshma.
The one who bears the duty
of guarding either of these two
shall forever be sleepless.
I'd sent you to find the path
to our happiness, Bheeshma.
Has the king of Gandhar arrived
with Gandhari? - Mother.
They couldn't come along.
King Subal pleaded with me,
that he wishes to conduct
Gandhari's wedding with great
pomp and splendour.
He shall bring his entire family
along with Gandhari
and arrive in Hastinapur, before
the eve of 'Akshaytritiya'
Besides, after so many years
this would be the first wedding
in our clan too.
Even we shall have to invite
Kings from other kingdoms.
If you'd brought them along,
I'd be even happier.
But I hope you did
what you felt was right.
Ambika.
Commence with the
preparations for the wedding
of your eldest son,
Dhritarashtra.
Daughter-in-law, before
king Subal arrives here
have a token of ornaments and
other gifts sent to Gandhar.
As you say,
mother-in-law.
I'm feeling very glad today,
elder brother.
Even I am very glad,
Bheeshma.
Now the throne of Hastinapur
shall forever be secured.
The promise I had made to your
father, shall be fulfilled now.
Gandhari's hundred sons
shall brighten the Kuru clan's
future for eternity.
Pandu. Convey the good news to
the royal teacher Kripacharya.
Also command the announcer Uttam
to announce across the kingdom.
On the eve of 'Akshaytritiya'
prince Dhritarashtra's wedding
to princess Gandhari,
shall be solemnised.
Soon thereafter
Dhritarashtra
shall be crowned and enthroned
as the king of
Hastinapur.
'Long live the king!'
Pandu.
- Greetings, elder brother.
Do you know how many steps
you need to take
to reach the throne
from where you're standing?
No, brother.
Fifty-one.
One, two, three..
four, five.
I have measured the distance
to the throne
from every door
within this room.
Six, seven, eight..
Nine, ten.
Do you know why?
Because right since birth, I had
been heading to this throne.
20, 21, 22..
46, 47, 48
49, 50, 51.
But how far is it now?
Tell me.
Fifty-one steps?
- No. lt's one.
Just one.
And the name of that one step
is wedding.
Then I shall be seated there,
upon my throne.
The biggest dream of my life
shall come true, Pandu.
And then, she shall sit there
as my eyes.
My Queen.
A token of ornaments and drapes
have arrived from Hastinapur
for you, princess.
Look at them, princess. They're
such beautiful ornaments.
Yes, they're very beautiful
indeed.
They truly befit the status
of the queen of Hastinapur.
When you shall wear this and sit
upon the throne of Hastinapur
your beauty shall be celestial,
princess.
I'm a royal princess.
Someday I had to be a queen.
But you have no experience
with ruling, princess.
Then how shall you rule?
It's very simple.
Where there's no experience,
affection comes in handy.
With my devout affection
I shall win the hearts of
the subjects of Hastinapur.
Right now, l'm not concerned for
Hastinapur's subjects.
I wish to rule the heart
of my beloved husband.
Winning the subjects' heart
is easier, princess.
But winning the heart
of your husband
especially when
he's a king himself
is a little difficult.
All the beautiful damsels
in the world
must be flocking
around him.
I'm not afraid
of that competition.
If that were the case,
Hastinapur wouldn't travel here
all the way to Gandhar,
to choose me.
I shall get him so spell bound
with my beauty
that the Kuru prince's eyes
shall only look at me.
Then through her eyes,
l shall look at the royal court.
Even when a person
is quiet
he says a lot through the
expressions on his face, Pandu.
My wife shall be my eyes,
and read the expressions
on the faces of the courtiers.
I'm glad, elder brother, that
you shall soon get your eyes.
Anyway, you do not trust
your younger brother.
No, brother.
lt's not so.
I trust you completely.
But, you shall not be
with me always.
Sometimes you shall be at war,
as the commander-in-chief.
And sometimes, you shall
be off for leisurely travel.
And l need eyes that shall
stay with me always, brother.
Incessantly.
A husband needs a wife
at every step, elder brother.
A wife heeds her husband
in transactional matters.
She stands by him
during religious deeds.
And shows him the path
to redemption.
A wife's arrival fulfils
a husband's life, elder brother.
These are all useless talks,
Pandu.
Power.
Power is supreme
in transactional matters.
That is the foundation
for religion.
And the path to redemption.
That's all.
There is no need
for a wife, for that.
For me, the significance
of my wife is just that
she shall fulfill this
one thing l lack.
That's all.
There shall be nothing
more precious than me
for my husband,
Sugdha.
The way father consults mother
regarding every matter
my husband too shall consult me
regarding every decision.
We shall teach our sons about
good values and happiness.
My husband shall show me
around his entire kingdom.
He shall hold my hand
and walk ahead.
And I shall lay my every step
upon his shadow.
As the eldest brother and
his beloved wife
the journey of our lives
shall be truly successful.
The foundation of all human
relationships
is expectation.
A husband, who could fill
life with joy and prosperity.
A wife, who is always
dedicated and loyal.
Children, who shall always serve
and obey.
Human being.
An individual usually
loves the person
who meets his expectations.
But expectations are destined
to be broken.
How?
Because expectations
originate from the human mind.
No one else ever learns
of those expectations.
In spite of all intentions
to fulfill them
one can never fulfill
another's expectations.
And that is the root
of conflict.
All relationships
turn into conflict.
If humans stop building
their relationships
based on expectations
and accept relationships
solely for what they are
won't this life be full of
peace and happiness?
Think about it.
Shukra.
Look, Sugdha. We just spoke
about brother Shakuni.
And he's already sent
a message.
So many fireflies?
You see, Sugdha?
Brother Shakuni went through
so much of trouble for me.
Just so that my chamber
shouldn't get dark.
Even brother Shakuni must
have surely arrived.
Shakuni. Son, we were
waiting for you.
What is the use of waiting now,
mother?
Son, control your anger.
A huge army had arrived from
Hastinapur, with the proposal.
And Bheeshma himself
was supervising them.
We had no other choice
than to accept the proposal.
Son, your father shall
explain the situation.
Who shall explain?
A father or a king?
Shakuni. A king cannot ignore
his royal obligations.
You said it right, father.
lt was your royal obligation.
To marry beloved Gandhari
to Dhritarashtra.
It was only your
royal obligation.
She's a daughter who gave you
so much of love and respect.
And you are being
unjust to her..
It's only your
royal obligation.
You are darkening the future
of my beloved sister.
It's only your
royal obligation.
What use is
a royal obligation
where you need to sacrifice
the royal family?
Where is your
greatness now?
Where is your strength,
king Subal?
Or are you consumed by the greed
to expand your kingdom
with the aid of
Hastinapur?
And has that greed overpowered
your love for your daughter?
Answer me.
I love my daughter Gandhari
too, son.
And I had to come to that
decision with a heavy heart.
Because emotions
make you blind.
You must give up emotions and
think about the circumstances.
Tomorrow you shall be
the king of Gandhar.
And as the king of Gandhar
you cannot be blind
to Gandhar's future.
I do not fear Bheeshma.
Father, when might fails
one must use deception.
I shall attack the kingdom
of Hastinapur so cleverly
that the entire kingdom
shall be reduced to a rubble.
I do not respect
any such obligation
that is a hindrance in
my beloved sister's future.
Even if I have to do the
most disgusting deeds
for the sake of Gandhari,
I'm willing to do it.
I will gladly accept hell.
But I shall not let my beloved
sister's future be darkened.
I will never allow Gandhari
to marry a man who is
blind since birth.
Never.
Gandhari