Friend!
'The fishes shown in this scene'
'were generated
using computer graphics.'
Is the son of a blind man
blind as well?
Be quiet!
Quit babbling!
Brother Duryodhan,
please calm down!
Go away,
Dusshasan.
Only this fire can extinguish
that burning in my heart.
Go away!
'Please order
brother-in-law Duryodhan'
'to lay down his weapons.'
'Take the weapons away from
Duryodhan and the King of Anga.'
'Is the son of a blind man
blind as well?'
'Is the son of a blind...
- Duryodhan and King of Anga.'
- Please order brother-in-law...'
'Duryodhan and the King of Anga.
- To lay down their weapons.'
Father, brother Duryodhan
has set his entire room on fire!
What!
Set his room on fire!
Why, Dusshasan?!
What caused him to do this?!
Upon seeing the court
of the Pandavas
brother had become
exceedingly agitated, father.
You must come with me
at once, father!
Let's go, father.
Friend, the reply
to an insult is revenge
and not killing oneself!
The Pandavas will have to
set themselves on fire, friend!
You need not
set yourself on fire.
You...
You need to calm down.
Please calm down.
Go away,
friend Karna!
Living on this earth now
cannot give me any peace!
My heart is burning
like the bed of the ocean!
Go away!
Duryodhan!
The fire of the ocean
does not burn itself up, son!
That fire is blanketed in water!
Have the strength
to be patient, Duryodhan.
How can I possibly
be patient, father?
The wood of this room
is not burning here!
My respect,
my pride
and the emotions of my heart
are burning here!
That daughter of Drupad
had snatched the weapons
from your son
in the court before everyone!
The insult a woman feels
when being disrobed
is nothing compared
to the insult
experienced by a warrior
when his weapons
are snatched from him!
Karna...
My friend Maharathi Karna
had requested them
not to take away our weapons
but to sentence us
to death instead!
However, those Pandavas
paid no heed, father!
With the intent of insulting us
in some way or the other
they had conducted
the Rajsuya 'Yajna!'
And despite being disgraced
I was a part of that 'yajna.'
I was cursing my fate
during that ceremony.
Apart from killing myself
those Pandavas have left me
with no other alternative,
father!
No other alternative...
Son, killing oneself is not
the solution to any problem.
We will discuss
this matter calmly
but please,
let's go from here!
No, father!
No!
- Karna...
Karna, say something
to your friend!
Your Highness
I cannot bear to see
my friend in pain.
The solution to this problem
lies solely with you.
More than the sons of Pandu
you are chaser to him, Karna.
When it comes to your
dedication and competence
I have never questioned
their sincerity, dear.
Please guide us
to extinguish the fire
in Duryodhan's heart!
Blinded by the arrogance
in creating Indraprastha
the Pandavas have insulted
my friend, Your Highness!
Just give me the order.
I will defeat the Pandavas
and annex Indraprastha
to Hastinapur!
Go ahead and attack.
Dear Duryodhan,
I give the order
to go ahead and
attack Indraprastha
but please give up the thought
of setting yourself on fire.
Extinguish this fire.
Extinguish...
- No, father!
The question is no longer about
Indraprastha and Hastinapur!
It is not about two empires!
It is a personal matter now.
The excruciating pain
in my heart will subside
only when I will make
those five brothers
go through the same agony!
I do not wish to
merely defeat them, father.
I wish to insult them.
A tiny spark
on a pillow made of cotton
eventually
reduces it to ashes.
That fire cannot be extinguished
despite numerous efforts.
It burns every particle
of that cotton pillow!
This is the kind of insult
that should set
their bodies, hearts
and lives on fire,
father!
It should set them on fire!
Without laying
a finger on someone
the act of draining that being
completely of blood
can be achieved only by uncle,
brother Duryodhan.
But you insulted him.
That is why,
he returned to Gandhar.
Uncle
are you forsaking me?
When baby birds
are old enough to fly
their parents stop feeding them.
You are capable enough.
You can shove me
out of your way.
Now, to me
returning to Gandhar
is the only alternative.
Move forth,
charioteer.
Uncle
I had shoved you with this arm
and now,
I shall cut it off!
But you cannot leave today.
Please pardon me,
uncle
and let us proceed
towards Hastinapur
otherwise...
- Let it be, dear.
Let it be.
You have learnt the art
of shedding crocodile tears
from me after all
and it will have
no effect on me.
Uncle
then go ahead and punish me.
Any mode of atonement you say
shall be honoured by me.
If you tell me
to serve the Pandavas for a year
I will certainly do it
but uncle
you cannot leave.
I need you.
Not just for a year
but even if I ask you
to serve them your entire life
the punishment
will be inadequate
for you
and that would
not be a punishment
for insulting me.
It would only be one
for your foolishness.
Uncle
when the wheel of a chariot
attempts to outrun it
it is bound to fall.
The chariot may get
another wheel
but the wheel does not
get another chariot.
This is the kind of foolishness
I have exhibited, uncle.
Uncle
I join my hands before you
and take the oath
that henceforth,
if I disobey you
it will be an invitation
to my death.
Uncle
I join my hands before you
and take the oath
that henceforth,
if I ever disobey you
it will be an invitation
to my death.
I hope, unlike your
foolish friend Karna
you will not speak of
engaging in a war.
I have always felt
that wars are worthless.
You know quite well
that a plan should be such
where we must not
end up getting hurt
but the enemy
should end up losing everything.
Uncle!
Uncle
I am not asking for
a war this time.
I wish to insult them.
Insult!
If you snatch everything
from a person
but not his pride
then it will not benefit you.
Every year,
the winter season
snatches the leaves
from the trees
but foolish is the season
which does not
chop the roots off.
That is why,
every year
new leaves grow on the trees.
The way
the roots of a tree
give nourishment to it
similarly
the pride of people
strengthens them.
If you wish
to insult the Pandavas
then do you have the desire of
breaking their pride, darling?
Then take all that anger out
not on the Pandavas
but on their wife
Panchali
by channelling it towards her.
is the pride of the Pandavas.
She signifies their dignity.
When Panchali's respect shatters
the life of the Pandavas
will be in ruins!
Uncle, that laugh of Panchali
is still resonating in my ears!
I wish to obliterate
that joy from her face!
Forever...