Krishna not having a plan
at the back of his mind
is an impossibility.
He has a dangerous mind.
Is he
looking at me?
Yes, uncle.
Even at Draupadi's 'swayamvar'
he had done such a thing.
He is calling you, uncle.
Will you go?
Yes.
Krishna has again made
a plan this time
and I must find out what it is.
Subhadra.
On behalf of Queen Gandhari
I have brought these items
for your adornment, dear.
These are items of good fortune
for the bride-to-be, dear.
Subhadra!
Calm down, dear.
Are these items
of my good fortune
or symbols of my ill-fortune?
Why are you getting me married
to Prince Duryodhan, aunt?
Dear
this...
This marriage,
this alliance
was approved by your
brother Balaram himself.
If you refuse to it now
then it will be an insult
to King Dhritarashtra
and the Kuru dynasty.
Enmity will stem between Dwarka
and Hastinapur.
But what about my feelings?
The fortune of a woman
is like the water
held in the palms
during a benediction.
If the person making
the benediction
does not consume it
then the water
falls to the earth.
But I have deemed your son
my husband a long time ago.
I am the water
in Prince Arjun's palms
during a benediction, aunt.
What...
What are you saying, dear?
This is
a complete disaster, dear.
Why do you not order your son
to come here and marry me?
This will not be an insult
to the Kuru dynasty
and I will be saved
from my ill-fortune as well.
Ar...
Arjun is bound by his oath
at the moment.
His...
His whereabouts are...
His whereabouts are
unknown to me, dear.
Then...
Then what will
become of me, aunt?
Despite having two able brothers
do I not have the right
to choose my own life partner?
Will politics be my life now?
The alliance between
the Kurus and the Yadavas
was approved by
Krishna himself, dear.
Have faith in him.
Krishna will never let
unrighteousness prevail.
This is what Arjun had said.
And I believe him as well.
Krishna will do
what he deems correct.
Princess
Vasudev Krishna has asked you
to go to
the Somnath Temple at once.
A holy man is present there
at the moment
and he has asked you
to invite him to Dwarka.
I do not wish to go anywhere.
Vasudev Krishna has said
that if the holy man comes here
then your life will be
filled with happiness.
You should go, dear.
Krishna must certainly have
put some thought into it
before asking you to do so.
Run...
Welcome, King of Gandhar!
Greetings, King of Gandhar!
Bless...
- Oh!
Be careful!
Bless you.
Welcome, King of Gandhar.
Hastinapur and Gandhar
do not have a view of the ocean.
So, enjoy the sea-shore
in Dwarka.
Uh!
Boy, be careful.
Pardon them.
No, Vasudev.
No.
We are mountain folk.
We are scared of the ocean.
All we know is
that be it man's life
or the mountains
the one who keeps
climbing the slope undeterred
eventually reaches the summit...
Be careful, child.
Pardon them.
King of Gandhar,
we Yadavas only know
that be it the ocean
or the world
the one who builds
a boat of righteousness
sails right through.
Father, the ball.
This is my son Pradyumna.
Dear, go and seek the blessings
of the King of Gandhar.
Greetings.
May happiness fill your life!
Father, the ball.
King of Gandhar,
will you play this game with us?
It is one of the games I adore!
Here you go.
Let's go.
Greetings, holy man.
Our Princess is to be married.
Do give her your blessings.
Bless you.
Are you asking for material
happiness from an ascetic?
Give me the blessing
that may my marriage
not take place today.
With whose order
are you getting married?
With that of my elder brother.
Then you should obey his order.
If Madhav wants
the Yadavas to be
on Hastinapur's side
then it must be correct.
Do you know my brother?
He must indeed,
Princess.
Holy men like him
can see even the future.
Nothing is hidden from them.
Brother Krishna has
invited you to Dwarka.
I am engaged
in a penance, maiden.
I cannot go.
But brother Krishna says
that one's penance ends
in the Somnath Temple.
And he has personally
asked you to come.
Then let's go.
Even I wish to see
what your brother has planned.
Vasudev
listen very carefully to me.
I love my nephews a lot.
I endeavour
for their happiness
but you are interfering in it.
You are foiling all my plans.
What is your plan?
The throne of Hastinapur
rightfully belongs
to my beloved sister.
The Kurus have given her
a life of darkness.
So, she should at least
have the joy of the throne
and the kingdom.
That is it!
This is my plan.
That is a splendid plan,
King of Gandhar.
But how am I interfering in it?
Vasudev
if the city of Indraprastha
successfully conducts
the Rajsuya yajna
then it will become independent
and that would be
unjust to my sister
and nephews.
The entire Kuru kingdom
must once again
become united.
And it shall indeed be so,
King of Gandhar.
And that kingdom
ought to be ruled by Duryodhan.
And for this task, I require
the aid of the Yadavas.
That is why, I wish to have
beloved Duryodhan
and Princess Subhadra married
and I have even convinced
your elder brother to it.
And I did not interfere in it
either, King of Gandhar.
An alliance between
the Kurus and the Yadavas
is something
I approve of as well.
So, tell me your plan now.
My plan is very simple,
King of Gandhar.
The presence of righteousness
includes my presence too.
I shall aid in making
the Kuru kingdom united again.
King of Gandhar!
I shall aid the Kurus
and the Yadavas
in forming an alliance.
Now you must tell me
where I am interfering.
Then at this most inopportune
time, how could Arjun
reach the Somnath Temple,
Vasudev?
I am certain
that Arjun must have been
ordered to travel from
the North to the South
by you.
I did not order him.
I had merely told him
that visiting the Somnath Temple
would benefit him immensely
and that his penance
would be complete.
But I assure you,
King of Gandhar
that Arjun being at
the Somnath Temple at the moment
is not a part of my plans.
Vasudev
I have seen Arjun at
the Somnath Temple myself.
I warn you
that if Arjun is at
the Somnath Temple
because of a plan of yours
then Hastinapur and Dwarka
will become enemies.
If Arjun is at
the Somnath Temple
then Hastinapur and Dwarka
will become enemies.
A warning!
You are quite the comedian,
King of Gandhar!
But I do not lie.
However, if you
do not believe me
you may go to the Somnath Temple
and confirm
whether Arjun is present there
or not.
Boys!
Surely Arjun
has gone to Dwarka.
Subhadra.
Greetings, brother.
Bless you!
Are you angry
with your own brother?
It looks as though
even my friend is very angry.