Greetings, teacher.
May you be victorious.
Are you prepared for the battle?
Certainly, teacher.
This is the first battle
of your life.
Are you scared?
Do you not trust me, teacher?
I can trust no one
but you, Arjun.
What is this?
It is a riddle, teacher.
And I am trying
to figure it out.
Greetings.
Do not let
any of the Princes die.
Take all of them in
as prisoners!
Only then will Bhishma
come here
to die at your hands.
All hail Mahadev!
Greetings, teacher.
May you be victorious.
Yudhishthir
there's quite the responsibility
on your shoulders
because you are the eldest.
The respect garnered
from the victory
will be yours.
And even the insult
of the defeat
will be attributed to you.
Be it a battle or politics,
teacher
victory belongs to every person
but defeat belongs
only to the King.
If we are successful
in paying you your fee
then it will be the success
of the 105 disciples of yours.
But the throne of Hastinapur
cannot have 105 Kings,
brother Yudhishthir!
You must have understood
the meaning by now.
This battle is
not being fought only
to pay our teacher his fee.
The truth is, this battle
is not between the Kuru Princes
and King Drupad.
It is between you and me.
Answer my question, teacher.
When our capabilities were being
weighed in terms of your fee
did you have no knowledge then
that all this was being done
in the favour of Yudhishthir?
The test of your capabilities
was not devised by me, Prince.
You should ask this question
to your father.
In the name of righteousness,
my father
has always been the recipient
of deception, teacher.
But I do not wish
to discuss this with you.
If I use my might
to pay you your fee, teacher
then you cannot object to it.
What do you mean?
It means, brother Yudhishthir
that in this battle
the help of you or your brothers
will not be required by me.
In this battle, only
the Kauravas will participate.
How can that be?
If only the Kauravas
fight in this battle
brother won't get an opportunity
to prove his capability.
There is no other alternative,
brother Bheem.
Anyone older than me
cannot participate
in this battle.
We 100 brothers
shall have
the fruits of our valour
and you five
getting a share in it
is an injustice I cannot allow.
Arjun, Nakul, Sahadev
can participate in the battle.
But I shall be the General.
And the victory
shall be attributed to me.
We cannot accept that.
That was not my request!
The duty and right to pay
our teacher his fee
belong to all the disciples.
I shall also deem you a partner
in paying the fee, Arjun.
I give you my word.
Then why do you worry?
Besides, our teacher
wants us to pay his fee
by defeating Drupad.
But the participance
of all the Princes
was not something
he explicitly mentioned.
And what if we
do not accept this?
Then, in the battle, you will
either keep an eye
on Drupad's army
or on the weapons
of my brothers.
We Kuru Princes are
on the borders of Panchal
and us fighting in this manner
is inappropriate, Duryodhan.
This is an insult to our
dynasty and kingdom.
I give you
the first opportunity.
Go on.
May you be victorious!
Brother Yudhishthir
what did you do?
If we do not even
participate in the battle
then we will have no chance
to win, brother Yudhishthir.
Sahadev, why don't you
say something?
I feel, this is an apt strategy.
The enemy is approaching!
Order the first unit of cavalry
to march forth!
The Princes must not
get hurt, General!
They are to be taken in
only as prisoners.
None of the Princes should be
able to leave the battlefield!
I want all the Princes alive!
Soldiers!
Take your positions!
The enemy is approaching!
Attack!
Dusshasan, Vikarna
the army approaching us
is not an army
but a horde of rats!
Hastinapur has defeated them
countless times.
We shall chop Drupad's head off
and hang it on his castle,
brother Duryodhan!
Attack!
Brother Duryodhan,
just look at Drupad's army!
It is easier to defeat them than
harvesting grains from fields!
We are the Kauravas!
No one can defeat us!
Keep attacking.
Drupad must
certainly be at the center
of his army.
Soldiers, change your positions!
Get back to the positions
allocated to all of you!
Do remember!
The Kuru Princes
need to be captured alive!
What are they doing now,
brother Duryodhan?
They must be getting ready
to form a labyrinth.
But you need not worry!
A 'Sharvyooh' can help navigate
through any type of labyrinth!
Organize yourselves
in the form of an arrow!
And keep your weapons
facing outward!
Allow the Princes
to come inside!
Open the second gate
and close the first one!
Your Majesty
the first gate has been closed
and we have surrounded
the enemy on all the sides.
Splendid. Keep opening
the gates in this manner
and once the enemy is inside
close all the gates behind them!
This is the labyrinth
of King Drupad!
King Drupad's labyrinth!
They will be caught in it
like a fly in a spider web
these ignorant Princes.
Close all the gates one by one!
Our strategy was a success,
Shikhandini.
Take all the Princes in
as prisoners!
None of the Princes
should escape!
W-What is happening,
brother Duryodhan?
We were winning the battle
but how did we end up
becoming prisoners?
They have sealed the exits,
Dusshasan.
Never did I imagine that
Drupad would construct
such a labyrinth.
Even I do not know how to
navigate through this labyrinth.
What do we do now,
brother Duryodhan?
I must now make
my way to Drupad.
Two of the Princes
are still fighting.
I will capture them,
Your Majesty.
In order to defeat these boys
if I have to employ
the Five Gems of mine
then it will be
your defeat, Shikhandini.
I will not let that happen,
father.
I will not let that happen!
You?
Will you fight me?
Does Panchal now
live under the protection
of maidens?
You need to protect
yourself first, Prince.
I am your doom!
Is this what you call
might, King Drupad?
What were you thinking when
making a woman your General?
I have defeated her
with just one blow.
And because of her, even you
got defeated this easily.
Are you absolutely certain
that I am the King of Panchal
Drupad?
Or am I?
Or maybe it's me.
Or am I the real
King of Panchal, Drupad?
Who is the real