Allow me to leave.
Teacher!
Every word uttered by my teacher
is an order to me!
I take the oath
that you will have
either Drupad at your feet
or my severed head
in your hands!
Arjun
your vow shall
indeed be fulfilled
but at my hands.
Father, His Highness
give the order
to launch an attack.
Give the order to launch
an attack, Your Majesty.
an attack, Your Majesty!
Give the order to launch
'Drupad.'
'The Region of Arya.'
'North, North-East,
East, South-East'
'South, South-West,
West, North-West.'
'Vidarbh, Kunti, Hastinapur.'
'Ganges,
Panchal - City of Kampilya.'
Where is King Drupad?
Land is life.
From land originates life.
What news do you bring,
messenger?
All hail King Drupad.
Your Majesty, Dronacharya
has sent the message
that he is getting ready
to attack Panchal very soon.
He had attempted to usurp
only nine miles of my land!
And with these hands of mine
I buried him in the land here!
A person who eyes
the land of Panchal
does not have the right
to reside here.
Messenger
go and send Drona the message
that a stone which is
cast at the ocean
lands directly
in the Netherworld!
Cover his body with soil.
Prince Dusshasan.
Yes.
- Pay attention, friend.
While sharpening the swords,
make sure the soldiers
do not file them too much else
the shaft will lose its weight.
Certainly, King of Anga.
Prince Vikarna.
Make sure the shafts
of the swords and arrows
are as small as possible.
- Alright.
Otherwise they won't travel far.
- Certainly, King of Anga.
Carry them away properly.
I do not require
such a heavy armour.
Go and give it to the Pandavas.
The armour of
my friend Duryodhan
is me.
- In other words, I have
the best armour in the world
friend Karna.
- Undoubtedly, friend.
By agreeing to take part
in this war
you have magnified
my self-confidence, friend.
I was waiting for you.
We must go to my uncle now
to chalk out the strategies
for the war.
Let's proceed.
- Alright.
What is he doing?
Bheem!
What are you doing?
Oh!
Brother Duryodhan!
Do you wish to have your idol
built on the shoulders of mine?
So, I thought of coming here
and seeing how much it weighs.
If it is not too heavy,
I can hold it in my hands.
May I have a look?
It broke.
I am certain that while
making the idol, the sculptor
must have used arrogance
and not self-confidence.
They might look similar
but are vastly different.
Now, pray to the Almighty,
beloved brother Duryodhan
that may your capability
be stronger than your idol.
Do remember.
Drupad will
not go this easy on you.
Careful!
Do not step on
those illusory circles
else you will land
in the Netherworld.
From there.
Hey!
Not there!
There.
Now, to your left.
No!
Careful!
Careful.
Now, come from that way.
And now, from there.
This way.
What were you doing?
Teaching you how to dance.
You dance quite well.
In other words,
these are not illusory circles?
No.
I was devising formations
for the war.
I was meditating
on how to create them
and how to navigate
through them.
What is this?
Discus formation.
Could you explain it to me?
It is not your cup of tea.
It will bore you.
My brother Krishna says,
only a person who is afraid
devises an Illusory Labyrinth
but only an able person
can navigate through it.
Does your brother Krishna deem
himself highly knowledgeable?
No. Other people deem him
highly knowledgeable.
What brings you here?
I wanted to ask you the name
of the melody you had played
the other day.
Why?
- It was beautiful.
It is still resonating
in my ears.
It was a very soothing melody
at least, to me.
It was more like war music
than a soothing melody.
Uh!
It is not always necessary
for a melody to be soothing.
Sometimes, the psyche
of a person deems it so.
Were you thinking of a lad
you are in love with?
Is that all?
Do you not wish to learn
war music for your love?
Brother Krishna has
sent this for you.
What is it?
I do not know.
Brother Krishna said,
if you keep this with you
it will be of use to you.
Listen.
- Yes.
Are you going to be
at the front of the army?
Certainly.
I shall be at the front.
At the very front.
I shall indeed be at the front.
Sons
while filling a bowl
with a liquid
ensure that it is
properly filled
and that nothing spills over.
Mother, we shall ensure that our
valour pleases Dronacharya.
Have faith.
Our strength
will not be used to torture the
Panchal army or King Drupad.
May you be victorious!
Goodbye, mother.
Goodbye, father.
My son
I could not keep the promise
I made to you.
This is what
I was afraid of, father.
You fail to grasp the tricks
of grandfather and the Minister
because you are
a righteous man.
Uncle often says
that a righteous person
can be treated
quite unrighteously.
I have something more to say.
Your grandfather Bhishma
is reminded of righteousness
only when
he has to resort to
something unrighteous.
Hence, even when poisoning
the life of a maiden,
there was no
feeling of remorse within him.
What are you saying, brother?
Have you heard about
the King of Kashi
and the woeful tale of his
daughter Amba, beloved sister?
I have heard
that the elder sister
of your mothers, Amba
has been born again
to slay the great Bhishma.
Impossible!
It is impossible to slay uncle!
He has the boon
of dying at will.
And a person who cannot die
cannot be defeated.
These are mere rumours!
He has spread these rumours
only to scare people.
But you need not be afraid of
grandfather any longer, father.
The strength of
the 100 sons of yours
is enough to defeat anyone.
We are certain, son,
that by proving your might
you will make
your parents proud.
But do remember, son
that more than your victory
your life is
more precious to me.
Have faith, father.
Drupad does not have the might
to defeat your son.
I shall certainly make him bow
before our teacher.
Why do you not behead him and
place it at your teacher's feet?
Dronacharya will be
held guilty for this
while you shall earn
all the virtues.
Chopping the thorns off a tree
is a wise thing to do,
Duryodhan.
Goodbye.
- May you be victorious!
May you be victorious!