Sire.
How... How did you
achieve this, sire?
Did this question
arise out of amazement
or from the desire
to learn the art?
Can I also perform
such a wondrous deed?
Your grandsire
will answer that question.
Show this ball
to him with the stick I made
using blades of grass.
Attention!
King Dhritarashtra
is making his entrance!
Your Highness
there are seven vital topics
to be discussed in the court.
In the northern region,
there is severe water shortage
and in the south...
- The most vital topic
is the punishment
given to the princes.
Excluding the revered teacher
Kripacharya
all the other court members
need to vacate the court.
Your Highness
seeing their impudence, I felt
that it was necessary
to punish them.
Indeed, grandsire.
The question does not pertain
to your decision.
The question is as to
what was the reason
that led to friction between
Pandu's sons and mine.
In what manner
do Pandu's sons behave
that Duryodhan's anger
knows no bounds?
Your Highness!
Character is truly tested
when one has relationships
with unfamiliar people.
Until now, Kunti
and Queen Gandhari's sons
were unfamiliar with one another
but now that they are living
under the same roof
then how one acts
is reflective
of one's character.
In other words,
only my sons are flawed here!
Is this what you mean,
grandsire?
Dhritarashtra!
Your Highness...
Love for family is apt only when
it acts as an armour.
If that love becomes a weapon
then problems may arise.
Your Highness, perhaps
the familial love has made
the princes impudent.
The scriptures and traditions
instruct us, Your Highness
that princes should gain wisdom
by residing in seminaries.
The capability
of testing my sons
lies with which 'Brahmin',
Vidur?
There should be
a capable 'Brahmin'
or a knower of
scriptures and weaponry
who can leave the court of Kuru
in awe with his capabilities.
Arjun.
Why did you enter the court
without permission?
Pardon me, sire.
I wished to show this
to grandsire.
Brother Bhim.
Where are brother Yudhishthir,
Arjun and our other brothers?
Brother Yudhishthir
is practising 'yoga'.
Nakul and Sahadev
have gone with him.
Arjun has gone
to the royal court.
You need just me
if you wish to duel.
No, no. We have not come here
to engage in a duel.
We have brought some fruits
for the five of you.
There is a beautiful place
just a few yards from here.
It is called Praman Koti.*
*Pramanakoti was a beautiful spot on the banks of Ganges, north of Hastinapura.
The fruits that grow
in the jungle there
are extremely sweet.
We have brought some for you.
Delicious.
Did I not tell you,
brother Bhim?
Let us go.
Today we have organised
a feast for all of you
in Praman Koti.
For us?
- Yes.
We did not welcome you
the right way.
That was our mistake,
brother Bhim.
You all are our brothers.
To give you respect and love
is our duty.
It took you quite some time
to learn this, Duryodhan.
One learns only with time,
brother Bhim.
It would be better if we make up
for our past mistakes.
Today, we 105 brothers
will jubilate in Praman Koti.
Indeed. Let me go call
brother Yudhishthir and Arjun.
Brother Bhim,
Dushashan will go and call them.
Dushashan, when Arjun
returns from the royal court
and when brothers Yudhishthir,
Nakul and Sahadev
are done with the yoga
bring them to Praman Koti
with you.
Shall we go, brother Bhim?
If you are fearful
of going alone with me...
Even then, no matter.
We shall leave after some time.
Fear?
Of what?
Let us go.
This way.
Attention!
The great son of Ganga, Bhishma
is making his entrance!
The eminent son
of the great sage Bharadwaj!*
*The author of Ayurveda.
The great Bhishma.
Greetings.
Greetings, Dronacharya.*
*Acharya: Brahmin head guide or a highly learned man.
What crime
has Hastinapur committed
that without even receiving
a proper and apt welcome
you are leaving the palace?
If a proper and apt welcome
gave solace to the heart
then I would have resided in
the woods practicing the Vedas
great Bhishma.
In order to satiate a desert,
a few clouds are not enough.
Only a few rivers
can achieve this task.
Great Drona
your heart has burnt
with the fire of this enmity
and become arid like a desert.
And I know this.
Maybe this is the reason
why the news of your arrival
was not conveyed to me
by Kripacharya.
A true Brahmin is one
whose heart never dries up
and who does not let enmity
become the mantra of his life.
The courage and ability to argue
with one's wife's brother
is not something Lord Parashuram
blessed me with.
That is why I accept
what Kripacharya said.
I may not be a true Brahmin
but am certainly
a great warrior.
I'm a knower of
scriptures and weaponry
and a great teacher too.
And Hastinapur was awaiting
such a teacher.
This way, Drona.
Greetings.
May you live long.
Take this and feed it
to the son of Pandu.
With this approach
the five thorns
in the path of Duryodhan
will be gotten rid of
one by one.
When it comes
to gaining something
deception is more potent
than strength, Kark.
When it comes
to the struggles of life
and when man does not
deem himself adequate
and loses faith
in his own strength
then he renounces virtues
and embraces vices.
In reality, villainy is
born in man's life only
when his psyche
loses self-confidence.
Only self-confidence
can bear righteousness.
What is self-confidence?
When man considers
that the struggles of life
make him weak
then he loses faith in himself.
Instead of braving the struggle
he looks for ways
to free himself of it.
But when he believes that
struggles will make him stronger
in a way a body
is strengthened with exercise
then with each struggle,
his enthusiasm magnifies.
In other words,
self-confidence is nothing but
a state of mind.
It is merely a way
of looking at life.
And the way of looking at life
is in the hands of man.
Give it a thought.
This is Praman Koti,
brother Bhim.
Many snakes and serpents
reside in this river.
They are extremely venomous.
But they bear no enmity
with the people of Kuru.
Are you listening,
brother Bhim?
Indeed. Did you not
say something about a feast?
I did.
- Yes.
Let us proceed.
Please come this way.
Do come, brother Bhim.
This way.
Look at all this.
Such varied dishes.
Our chefs
have prepared all this.
Especially for you.
When the rest of the brothers
are here, we shall begin eating.
That is alright but
brothers Yudhishthir, Arjun
Nakul, Sahadev and the rest
are not here yet.
Dushashan must be
on his way here with them.
And it would be inappropriate
to begin without them.
No, no.
We shall wait.
Brother Bhim, how about
we taste a little of everything?
That way we will know if we
need to alter the taste or not.
Indeed.
That is a good suggestion.
But we must not eat a lot.
- No, no!
We shall only taste these.
And you have a special interest
in food.
Indeed.
I am a great cook myself.
Then, brother, only you
should taste the dishes.
I too shall taste but I shall
not be able to comprehend much.
No, no.
Pay respect to food, Duryodhan.
First, you must get a whiff.
Then you must take in the aroma.
Wow!
Let herbs, saffron, fruits
and flower's aromas
satiate your heart.
This is food and not a battle.
One must not attack it.
Take a look.
Do taste this 'kheer,'*
brother Bhim.
*Rice pudding.
Our chefs make
the tastiest of 'kheer'.
No, no.
Then what will the rest
of the brothers eat?
If you insist so much
then I shall taste it a bit.
Pardon me, 'laddoos'.
I shall eat you after a while.
Duryodhan.
You are younger to me.
You should taste it first.
Me?
No, brother Bhim.
You are elder to me.
You should taste it first.
Have some.
No, I cannot eat this.
Why not?
What is wrong with this 'kheer'?
Nothing.
I was just ribbing you.
Give that to me.
It is delicious.