When one's pride
is wounded
it reflects on the face first.
Show me
this imperious woman's face.
Your Highness
what kind of practice
is being conducted
at Hastinapur's
royal court?
I am the daughter-in-law
of the Kuru lineage.
I am the prestige
of the Kuru dynasty.
I had entered this city
as the pride of Hastinapur
Your Highness.
And I am being brought here
like some animal!
Why!
Grandsire
you're the most glorious one
in the whole of this kingdom.
You're Lady Ganga's son.
How can you remain silent
on seeing this kind of behaviour
being conducted
right in front of your eyes?
Guru Drona
you're a father figure to me.
Why am I being
treated like this?
Your Highness
your sons are defiling
and this is bringing
dishonour to you!
Why don't you stop them?
A maid
has to carry out
her master's orders.
Maid?
Am I a maid?
What makes me a maid?
My question has still not
been answered by Yudhisthira.
By losing himself in the game
he had lost his rights
on me.
Then how could he put
me at stake?
I question everyone
at this court...
What kind of
righteousness is this?
Why are you questioning
the court?
Ask your husband!
Slave Yudhisthira
answer her.
Answer me.
The rights with which
you put your brothers at stake
did you exercise the same rights
to put me at stake?
Yes, Draupadi.
Family members have a right
on each other.
A wife is not
a mere family member!
Wife is the better half.
On a man's death
his family definitely
feels sad.
But it's only his wife
who becomes a widow.
Do pearls kept in a bowl
share the same relationship
as two pearls woven together
in an ornament?
Then how could you exercise
such rights on me
that you have
on your brothers?
Answer!
Don't be silent!
Minister Vidura
your kingdom is ruled
by justice.
You answer me.
Does your kingdom
give one's brothers
the right on his property?
If the person gives the right
to his brothers...
Then, yes.
Then the right
of the brother
is accepted.
It's the society that gives
a wife the right
on her husband's property.
The kingdom's law
gives her that right.
She receives those rights
as soon as she's married.
So, tell me, Minister.
When Yudhisthira
put his property at stake
I too had a right on it.
Then, why didn't he take
my permission?
Answer me!
- Maid Draupadi
when all of you came to
Hastinapur to play this game
had you bound your five husbands
with any kind of restrictions?
No?
Then you have yourself
given your husbands the right
to lose all the property.
Now, stop rambling
for no reason.
This means
since I didn't bind my husbands
with any restrictions
it was my fault?
I trusted my husbands.
Was that a crime?
Answer me, Pandavas!
All of you have to answer
to all my questions
in this court
of unrighteousness.
Arjun
You answer me.
Had Yudhisthira taken
your permission
before losing me
in this gamble?
Did all of you
give the permission?
Have all of you together
made me a maid from an empress?
Answer!
You had taken the seven vows
of marriage from me
and in return
you had vowed
to protect me.
Did you forget all about that,
Pandavas?
For the sake
of your family's happiness...
So that four of you don't
have to lead an ascetic life
I have converted
my whole life into a penance.
And in return
why am I receiving
such a disgusting reward?
Why?
Forgive us, Draupadi.
Forgive us.
We
never go against our
elder brother's orders.
And brother Yudhisthira had to
give in to Duryodhan's orders.
Forgive us.
This means
you were being righteous.
Yudhisthira
was not unrighteous either.
Every person present
in this court
has abided by
righteousness.
So does righteousness means
dishonouring a woman?
Does righteousness give you men
the right to exploit a woman?
What was my fault
that I was brought here
in this manner?
Everybody did think about
being righteous in their own way
but no one thought
about my honour
My right
and my emotions.
No, they didn't
because your husbands
are not man enough.
Why are you relying
on such righteousness,
maid Draupadi
which makes these warriors
incompetent?
Come
and establish a relationship
with me.
Come
and establish a relationship
with me.
It will give me happiness
and you...
Protection.
Come, maid Draupadi
be seated on my lap.
Come on!
Duryodhan
I will give you a death,
looking at which
the whole of earth
will tremble.
I will break your thighs
and take your life!
It's a promise!
It's a promise.
It's my promise!
And until I don't
destroy all of you
I will add mud
to the food I have.
So that it keeps reminding me
that I'm not a human
but an earthworm.
An earthworm!
Don't ramble.
Come, maid Draupadi
and obey the orders
of your master.
Foolish Duryodhan!
I have taken birth from
the holy fire of Yajna.
And fire can
never be bound by anything.
You cannot make
me your slave
because that is not
acceptable to me.
I detest it!
Your Highness
in your court, a maid
is leaving
by dishonouring
her master's orders.
Wait, Draupadi!
Obey your master's orders.
Let her go, Your Highness.
Let her go.
For the sake of peace
we have tolerated
many an injustice.
Ignore this one too,
Your Highness.
Let her go.
Your Highness
a soldier who dares to stop
the wind forgets
that if the wind
forgot its limits
then the weapons
will be compelled to break.
It was decided to keep
unrighteousness in its limits.
Now, don't let unrighteousness
gain prominence.
Has it not been proved
in this court
that now, only Duryodhan
has the rights on Draupadi?
It was, Your Highness, but...
- There's no question
of an argument, Prime Minister.
If I give credibility to a
maid dishonouring her master
then all the maids and slaves
of this kingdom
will begin to insult
their masters.
On the mere basis
of a washer man's allegations
Lord Ram had asked Lady Sita
to take up an ordeal.
While here, there are many maids
and slaves who will protest.
It will upset the administration
of Hastinapur, Minister.
No.
Maid Draupadi will have
to obey
all of Duryodhan's orders.
Maid Draupadi will have
to obey
all of Duryodhan's
orders.
Maid
I order you
to come back.
Independence lies
within oneself, Duryodhan.
It's not a piece of clothing
that one can snatch.
You're so arrogant,
maid Draupadi
that you won't obey
your master's orders!
Independence cannot
be snatched
but clothes can certainly be.
Dushasana
The way she had us disarmed
at the court in Indrapastha
in front of the entire
Aryan lineage...
In the same manner
in this court
disrobe her!
Duryodhan!
Stay in your limits!
The way
this court has immersed
in darkness
similarly
Emperor Dhritarashtra
we will fill your life
with darkness!
We will fill it