Grandfather used to worship
Lord Indra every year, Uncle.
But why did you decide against
worshipping him for once?
Abhimanyu, my lad.
All injustice that prevails
in the world is one.
Because all injustice
arise out of one or the other
form of fear.
I did not mean to oppose
the veneration for Lord Indra.
But he was being venerated
solely out of fear.
In fact, no one was
venerating Lord Indra, lad.
Everyone was just venerating
the fear in their hearts.
But isn't the prevalence of fear
obvious, uncle?
No, lad.
In fact, there is no greater
foe in the world than fear.
You better know
the consequences of fear.
In order to be free of fear
a human accepts injustice.
That is where evil is born.
Ought to fear, a human mind
is filled with worry
and conflict.
He loses his ability to think.
The mind or the soul
is destroyed.
Due to fear, a human mind
is filled with bitterness.
His entire life is filled
with bitterness.
The joy of living is lost.
Soulful joy.
Sachiddanand* is the incarnation of the almighty, lad.
*The three qualities of God. Sat is truth. Chit is universal consciousness. Anand is Bliss.
Ought to fear, a human
drifts away from the almighty.
[MUSIC]
But Indra's veneration wasn't
so grave an injustice, uncle.
Prativindh, my lad.
No power is so great
that it cannot be defeated.
And no injustice is so minor
that it need not be defeated.
Because a minor injustice
with the passage of time
can attain a catastrophic form.
Am I right, my good lady?
[MUSIC]
Revered clown!
After destroying
Indra's arrogance
what did Lord Krishna do?
My Prince!
The glorious tales of
Lord Krishna are endless.
If you all permit, could we end
this tale narration right here?
It shall be sunrise soon.
And as dawn breaks
the wedding rituals
will commence too.
No, dear clown.
After tempting one with food
and describing the taste
of every morsel
you cannot deprive one
from food.
You have to tell us the tale
of the end of Kansa,
the Lord of Mathura.
[MUSIC]
[LAUGHING]
Very well, listen.
Darkness encroached into Mathura
and nested within Kansa's mind.
Kansa's despicable heart
lost all love and compassion.
'Fear gripped his mind
and arrogance corrupted him.'
'When his final moments
closed in, he lost all wit.'
Vasudev!
Is the head of Gokul's Yadavas
your friend?
What do you wish to know,
Kansa?
His son has lifted
Mt. Govardhan!
How could he be so powerful?
Who is he?
Are you suspicious,
elder brother
that he is my son?
But the eight child
my womb bore was a girl.
She was an illusion!
[MUSIC]
Your womb had borne an illusion
in order to deceive me!
Vasudev had surely transferred
your eighth son to his friend's
home to safety.
No, elder brother!
You had all the infants
born during that time killed.
Then how could that infant
still be alive?
Tell me!
Calm down, Devaki.
The time has come
that Kansa braces himself
for his death.
Listen, Kansa.
The monsters that you had sent
have met their death.
Even demoness Putna* has met her death.
*Putana, a foster-mother of Krishna as she breast-fed him, though it was with the motive of killing Krishna by poisoned milk. She was killed by the infant-god Krishna.
Yet you did not understand.
Firstly, let me tell you
about Devaki's seventh child.
Devaki's seventh child
in the seventh month
was transferred by the Gods
to the womb of
my second wife, Rohini.
His name is Sankarshan.*
*Meaning a spirit transferred between two wombs.
Since he is mighty, he is also known as Balram.*
*"Strong Rama".
He is safe at
my friend Nanda's home.
And my eighth son's name is
Krishna!
[ECHOING]
[MUSIC]
Son of Nanda, Krishna!
He has even defeated
the serpent Kalia
and has lifted Mt. Govardhan
on a single finger.
My lord, my brother is further
blinded by arrogance.
He shall kill our son!
My lord!
If it were possible
to kill your son
it would have happened
years ago.
Even the King of Heaven
couldn't defeat him.
So how can the King of Mathura
defeat him?
You are a fool, Vasudev!
A fool!
I shall soon compel
both your sons
to arrive to Mathura!
And they shall die
before your very eyes.
Revered Akroor!
Head to Brindavan soon
and fetch both those lads
to Mathura.
You are inviting
your own death, Kansa.
My death?
My death, Akroor?
As long as Vasudev
and Devaki are alive
I shall be protected
by these two.
Their sons
ought to the fear of their death
will willingly give up
their lives.
Go on!
Bring Krishna and Balram
to Mathura.
No, revered Nanda!
Stepping on this holy land
has sanctified my life.
Gods dwell within idols.
But even the temple yard
is considered holy.
Similarly, all of Brindavan
is holy.
The ones to liberate Yadavas
from Kansa's atrocities...
These celestial lads
were raised on this holy land.
Son, the king of Mathura,
Kansa, has sent an invitation
for you.
I am ready, sire.
Last night father Nanda
narrated us the tales
of the sacrifice of mother
Devaki and father Vasudev.
Their sacrifices have not
yet borne fruit, my boy.
The clouds have to shower
until their existence
is obliterated.
Maybe Kansa shall use
your parents as shields
and try to attack you.
If the moon hides
behind a hill
isn't it obscured, sire?
If a deer hides behind a bush,
does a lion not devour it?
The sacrifices that my parents
made...
I won't let it be in vain.
If I have your permission
- may I gain my mother Yashoda's consent?
- Sure.
Even I shall bid farewell
to mother Rohini.
Sire Akroor, now the son
of Yashoda
will be the son of Vasudev.
So far...
So far, I kept him safe here
as long as I could.
Now, in Mathura please
watch over him.
Your son will protect
the whole world.
I needn't protect him.
For the sacrifices you have
made for Krishna
the entire world shall
forever be in your debt.
[MUSIC]
S-Son. How could you
abandon your mother
and leave from here?
Brindavan shall wither away
waiting for you.
The shepherdesses
will be grieved by
your departure.
And your mother...
- Your mother shall die...
- No, mother!
My soul dwells within your body.
And I am taking your soul
along with me.
If the soul leaves your body
I shall die instead, mother.
But why, son?
Why do you need to go?
My life's sole purpose
is to think of
protecting the entire creation.
And uncle Kansa
is just the beginning.
The end...
The end is still very far away,
mother.
I have to wander this
way incessantly for years.
And that life of a wanderer
begins today, mother.
Son.
Will you never ever return?
How can I return, mother?
I am leaving the Krishna
of Brindavan here
as I leave this place.
And the Krishna who is
going to Mathura
isn't the one you think he is,
mother.
When the river Ganga
flows down from the skies
she undergoes a lot of change.
She not just purifies earth
but get rendered polluted
by earth too.
She cannot return to Heaven,
mother.
Therefore...
[STUTTER]
Won't you remain
to be my son?
Will you be now
known as Devaki's son?
Mother Devaki gave me birth.
So some shall call me
the son of Devaki.
But I am fully confident
when I meet mother Devaki
for the first time
she shall surely address me
as the son of Yashoda.
And whoever shall know me
by your name
will know the true meaning
of duty and sacrifice.
Mother, bless me.
[MUSIC]
Krishna!
Mother!
[sesame]
Won't you feed me butter
for one last time
before I leave?
Please feed me, mother!
Krishna!
[MUSIC]