So, this is
the new-born.
It is time
to sacrifice him, Devaki.
No, brother!
What crime did this
boy child commit?
It has committed
the crime of being born!
Your child is my doom.
Him being born
is a crime, Devaki.
But our first child
will not kill you.
Our eighth child
is meant to slay you.
This is what the voice
from the sky had said.
Every fruit of a poisonous tree
is poisonous, Vasudev.
I will not spare
a single child of yours.
Along with Mathura,
the entire nation should know
that if a person even
dreams of revolting against me
then he will die
right after his birth!
Devaki
give me your child.
Give him to me!
No, brother!
I will not give my son to you!
What is his crime?
- Let me go!
He is soft and fragile.
If you see his face,
your heart will melt.
Just look at him,
brother.
Just look at his face.
- Foolish Devaki!
Even a lion cub
is defenseless and fragile
like a kitten!
But when it grows up, it becomes
the King of the Jungle!
That is why, I will not let
any of your children live.
No!
Give me your child!
Give him to me!
Give him!
No, brother!
- No, Kansa!
No!
Brother,
let my child go.
My Lord...
You are my doom?
- No!
No! - Take my life instead
but please let him live!
Let him go,
brother!
Will you kill me?
My Lord...
Let me go...
- My Lord...
My Lord...
- No...
Kansa!
If you kill him
then do remember!
We will sacrifice
seven children of ours
even if it kills our souls!
But our eighth son meant
to slay you will indeed be born!
If you have the competence
then go ahead
and kill him as well!
No, brother!
- No...
No, Kansa.
No!
Uncle
were all the children
born before you
killed by King Kansa of Mathura?
Yes, dear.
Both sins and merits
are like a pearl necklace.
The way the first pearl
attracts the second
and the second
attracts the third
similarly
one good deed leads to another
while one sin leads to another.
Sin fuels the arrogance
of a person.
A person can stop himself
from committing another sin
only when he sees the grave
consequence of that sin.
But a person
blinded by arrogance
is unable to see
that consequence.
The tradition of
unrighteousness and crime
keeps getting augmented by him.
The number of treacherous
and deceitful acts
and crimes
a society can tolerate
and the number of crimes
it can pardon
is decided
by the society itself.
In a society, the one who has
the power to punish the wrong
needs to take that decision.
But uncle,
how were Mother Devaki
and grandsire Vasudev
able to make so many sacrifices?
Did their hearts not break
when a new-born child
was sacrificed each time?
Dear Prativindhya
after the death
of their first son
mother Devaki and father Vasudev
were robbed
of their happiness for life.
The truth is
those children
were not sacrificed, dear.
In that war against
unrighteousness
they were the brave martyrs.
The happiness
of my parents
had been sacrificed.
But why did they have to make
such a grave sacrifice, uncle?
Dear Srutakarman
do you know what is the limit
of the sacrifices for the people
trying to establish
righteousness?
The limit of the sins
of the sinners
is the limit
of their sacrifices.
In other words
until the sinners and their sins
get annihilated
the sacrifices
to be made by the righteous
cannot come to an end.
Am I correct,
friend?
Dhundhumali
please tell my sons now
how my brother Shri Krishna
was able to survive.
In this manner,
the wicked Kansa
killed all the children
of Devaki and Vasudev.
It was then the time
for the eighth son to be born.
My Lord...
My Lord,
are these thunders
a sign...
A sign of death
of our eighth son?
I am exceedingly frightened,
My Lord.
Each time a child
of mine was killed
I too died along with them,
My Lord.
But I remembered,
My Lord
that giving birth
to our eighth son
is my duty.
That is why...
That is why,
I am alive until now.
If brother
kills our eighth son
before our eyes
then I will not be able to live!
I will not be able to live!
If that happens,
Devaki
then I too shall embrace death.
But I have firm faith,
Devaki
that in order to salvage
the entire world
our eighth son
will indeed be born.
And this time, Kansa will
not be able to kill him.
The power to thwart
the wish of the Almighty
does not reside in Kansa.
Guard!
What is this
sinister environment?
What is this illusion?
Guard!
Greetings,
Your Highness.
Go to the prison
and examine the situation.
The moment you hear the cry
of Devaki's eighth son
inform me at once!
If you delay even by a moment
then the way a potter
removes a pot from the wheel
I shall have you beheaded!
Go! - As you say,
Your Highness.
Tonight
Devaki's eighth son
will indeed be born.
My Lord!
Do not be frightened
Vasudev, the eldest
of the Yadavas.
Devaki,
the daughter of Devak
bless you!
When Hiranyaksh had submerged
the earth in the cosmic ocean
I had assumed the Varaha Avatar
and salvaged the earth.
In my Narasimha Avatar
I had slain Hiranyakashipu.
In my Vaman Avatar
I had established King Bali
in the netherworld.
Each time human beings
forget the essence
of righteousness
each time their hearts
are robbed of virtues
when competition
takes the place of love
and arrogance
takes the place of kindness
and a King begins to exploit
his own subjects
and begins to covet
polity and power
more than the truth
I am born on this earth.
Today,
once again
I must assume
another avatar of mine.
The two of you
have made numerous sacrifices
in the name of righteousness.
Upon seeing your agony
even the Gods in the heavens
are overwhelmed with sorrow.
But through your medium
the world
will receive
righteousness and peace
as sacraments.
I will be born as your son
and play in your lap,
mother.
In this auspicious hour
I shall enter your womb
with all my skills and powers.
I, Vishnu,
bless the entire world
but now, I seek your blessings
for this endeavour.
Do accept me
as your son, mother.