Sacrifice and truth
run through the veins of this dynasty.
With all due respect, Your Highness
in order to avenge the insult
my husband and children are ready to take weapon in the war.
I have the right to ask this question.
So that everybody is going to fight for you
without selfish motives in mind.
Wait.
I'll greet them first, My Lord.
Before you come in, give me an answer,
who you really are?
Panchali,
he is the sister-in-law Subhadra's son
Abhimanyu.
I know his name, My Lord.
I even know what is his relation to us.
But I want to know who is he truly is?
Sister-in-law!
Son Abhimanyu.
Panchali do not ask what all people know.
There are various types of clouds.
Some drift without producing rain.
Some carry flood.
Some bring beautiful bath.
While some just rumble.
Who you really are Abhimanyu?
Tell that to mother.
I...
I am my father arrows.
I need a blood bath.
But the glory will go to my father.
I shield my brothers.
I will stand in front of them at the moment of struggle.
And behind them in peace time.
But above all,
above all, I am kohl* for the eyes of Mother Panchali,
*Ancient eye cosmetic, traditionally made by grinding galena (lead sulfide) and other ingredients.
Each time there are tears in those eyes,
I could wipe the entire existense.
These are my tears,
Queen Mother, do you want me to die before...
Why you, Subhadra.
Why you
gave birth to such a child?
Gems may be born out of sister-in-law's story
but it is intended to be ornament of the Empress.
He is your son.
He is surely mine.
And until the end of time
the child's name will be immortalized!
New era
always begins with the destruction, Majesty.
The alignment of heavenly bodies
indicates the major changes.
Every war causes great destruction.
Tell me what will be destroyed.
What will happen to my children?
Majesty, try to remember the story of Matsya* avatar.
*Matsya ("Fish") is the first avatar of Vishnu that rescued the first man, Manu.
When the Almighty has submerged the entire
world in water.
Who have seeked refuge
to the Almighty?
As a result, only he is still alive.
Similarly, even in this war
people who are destined to
be destroyed
are those who has not been in the path
of refuge in the Almighty.
If your children,
have left the Almighty,
and embraced luxury.
Then they are bound to be destroyed, Majesty.
But there is no deficit of competence on my side,
Great Sage.
His Majesty Bisma, great teacher Dorna,
and because maharathi Karna is a great warrior
who will keep my sons safe on the battlefield.
Mars, Mercury, Venus, Saturn
Rahu, Ketu,* Sun and Moon
*Rahu is a severed head of an asura, that swallows the sun causing eclipses. Ketu is said to be the body of Rahu, after the head of the asura was cut off by Vishnu.
are much stronger
than any warriors from each side, Majesty.
When it's time for someone to die
no man can keep it from him.
However, you may
strengthen your heart.
Survive the blow, Majesty.
That's all.
What do you mean?
Are all my children
will die in the war?
The entire Kuru dynasty will disappear,
only those people will live,
which has the protection of the Almighty.
Which have the protection of the Most Powerful?
Answer me, O' Great Sage.
Do my children
do not have the protection of the Most Powerful?
It has been so
to my fear and worry
but do not let it weighed you down, Majesty.
My children...
will die...
No...
Why did Great Sage Vyas has given life to my children?
There must be a way
to keep my children alive, O' Great Sage!
You have
the power to save a son.
You can save any of your sons' life, Majesty.
One son!
God has blessed me with a hundred sons.
A hundred children.
They were supposed to build my husband's empire.
And you say
that
I could only keep one of them living.
Your Excellency, it is also not an easy task
however
there are ways
using one of which, an heir to a Kuru dynasty
can stay alive.
Who can stay alive?
Who can I give a ride to?
How do I...
This is your decision to choose.
Do you want him to stay alive, Majesty?
You have to think of ways
to keep the child alive.
I can not even say
if this arrangement will benefit your children,
or Kunti's side.
All I can say is
that only one lamp of the Kuru dynasty
that will continues to burn.
Remember
the burning of lights at the foot of the Almighty
is one of the beneficial.
Kuru dynasty would disappear
only those people will live
who have protection from the Almighty.
I can not even say
if this arrangement
will benefit your children
or Kunti's side.
The burning of lights at the foot of the Almighty
is one of the beneficial.
Queen Sudeshna
even in all regions of the Aryan
you do not find a decent young man
for such a beautiful girl?
We will arrange a Swayamvar
for this year Vasudev.
But you have declared war.
Who knows how many princes
who will live until the end of the war.
So how do we
have Uttara married before the war?
Being recorded for the alignment of the object
of the heavenly bodies.
We still have some time before
war begins.
We still have four months with us,
Queen Sudeshna.
But how can that be Swayamvar
held in just four months?
What needs to arrange a Swayamvar?
Here, there Uttara herself
and even the groom.
There you go.
It is a Swayamvar.
King Virat,
if you think it's alright,
shouldn't we marry Uttara and Abhimanyu
at the earliest possible?
In Abhimanyu
running blood from both the Kurus and Yadavas.
And Uttara
is the great Matsya dynasty descendant.
Their marriage
will merge
the three major dynasties, King Virat.
Impossible!
Your Majesty, how can you
make such a major decision without
discussing it first with me?
Sudeshna, this is Uttara's good fortune
that she will become daughter-in-law of Pandu's sons.
She will be Krishna student's wife.
Abhimanyu is a great warrior.
Kshatriya's daughters are married in a Swayamvar, Majesty.
Don't let the war ruin everything.
What if Pandu's sons defeated in this war?
How about the future of our Uttara?
Queen Sudeshna
do you have a firm conviction
that you can shape the future of Uttara
in accordance to your plan?
Do you
have a certain right to time?
I'm sorry, Vasudev.
But even you
do not have right to time.
Of course
I have
no right to time.
However, I have faith
in the generosity of time.
I promise you, Queen Sudeshna
that Uttara would give birth
to the greatest empire of the entire nation.
Abhimanyu
will become the one to usher in a new era.
While his son
will begin the first phase in the transformation.
Your daughter Uttara
would take away the whole Aryan region out of war
to peace and tranquility.