Come closer...
What is the problem, Hidimba?
Why are you taking so long
to lure these humans?
There is no problem, brother.
I am about to lure them.
Do not try to fool me.
You have done this before.
But you have taken almost
ten hours to lure them.
Why so long?
Never has it taken you
so long, Hidimba.
These...
These humans
are very intelligent.
They refuse to listen to me.
They refuse to listen to you
or do you not want
to take them there?
Have you fallen in love
with that tall human?
If you fall in love with a human
Lord Vrikodar will become angry.
And in order to appease him
I will have to
sacrifice you myself.
You are bound to die
but even these humans
will not stay alive.
So, be prepared
and lure them at any cost
by using your illusion
and bring them to the village.
Understood?!
What happened, Arjun?
Did you find something?
I just saw the
King of the Ogres, Hidimb.
'If you fall in love
with a human'
'Lord Vrikodar
will become angry.'
'And in order to appease him'
'I will have to'
'sacrifice you myself.'
'You are bound to die'
'but even these humans
will not stay alive.'
'Lure them at any cost'
'by using your illusion'
'and bring them to the village.'
'Understood?!'
I can smell food being cooked.
There is certainly a village
in that direction.
Look! I can see light
coming from over there.
We should proceed that way.
Brother Bheem is correct.
We should proceed
in that direction.
Shall we go?
'You are bound to die'
'but even these humans
will not stay alive.'
'Lure them at any cost'
'by using your illusion'
'and bring them to the village.'
Stop!
We cannot go there.
That is the village
of the ogres.
We should leave
this place at once.
Please come.
You brought us here
with so much effort.
Then why ask us to leave now?
She brought us here,
brother Yudhishthir?
What do you mean?
She is an ogre, Bheem.
An Ogre?
You are an ogre?
I...
A woman who competes
with you in eating
cannot be a human being.
You are an ogre?
Yes.
I am the sister of Hidimb,
the King of the Ogres
Hidimba.
My brother had told me
to bring all of you here.
We trusted you
but you betrayed us?
You had trusted her,
brother Bheem.
Brother Yudhishthir and I
knew of this from the start.
All of you should leave.
Your lives are in danger here.
I will show you the way
out of this forest.
Please come.
- Be quiet!
Now, no one will believe you.
Please believe me!
Hidimb is the King of the Ogres.
He is very strong.
He will certainly
kill all of you.
I do not want to hear anything!
Brother Yudhishthir,
what are your orders for me?
Please believe me!
Whoever kills the King of
the Ogres becomes the new King.
This is the tradition.
That is why, many people
tried to kill Hidimb
but no one can kill him.
Please come with me.
I will take all of you
outside this forest.
Then will he not punish you?
You need not worry for me.
I shall brave the punishment.
Please come with me.
You need not worry.
Since we have come here
we shall make this forest
safe for all human beings.
What are your orders, mother?
How can I disbelieve
the might of my sons?
And it is the duty of Princes
to provide people
with protection.
Let's go, brother Bheem.
Stop!
If all of you go there
you will be sacrificed
to Lord Vrikodar.
All hail Princess Draupadi!
All hail Vasudev Shri Krishna!
'I did not ask for you!'
'The Gods have sent you
because of their intransigence!'
'The truth is that you are
a symbol of my weakness!'
All hail Vasudev Shri Krishna!
'This maiden has been banished
from the city of Kampilya!'
All hail Princess Draupadi!
Bless you, daughter.
Pardon the crimes
of your father, daughter.
The haves of
a marge tree are bitter
but the fruits are sweet.
However, the leaves
are more beneficial.
In the bitter words of a father
must certainly lie
crucial lessons of life.
That is why, I can never
be angry with you, father.
You are truly my good fortune.
I asked for lifelong struggle
for you without thinking.
But the capability of
braving those struggles
and even values like
having a pure character
will also be given
by you, father.
And a family that can
offer protection for life
is what Draupadi
needs in her life.
So, make the necessary
arrangements, King Drupad.
Very soon
for Draupadi
you need to have
a 'swayamvar' organized.
Invite the finest royal families
in the whole of the Aryan region
to this ceremony.
The day Draupadi gets married
will be the dawn of
a new era for the world.
You are correct, Vasudev.
The Almighty has placed enemies
sandwiched between rocks.
He has blessed them
with the armour of rocks.
He has blessed a pearl
with the armour of a shell.
The Almighty has given an armour
to every precious entity.
For my daughter,
I wish to find a person
who can become her armour.
One who is the most superior
warrior of the world.
And I have seen only
one such warrior, Vasudev.
He has the glow of righteousness
on his forehead.
He has the determination
of values on his face.
He does not insult an enemy
even when he is defeated.
'Accept your defeat,
King Drupad.'
Are you not talking
about him, Drupad?
Indeed, Drona!
Him!
Your disciple
Arjun.