If marrying Karna
is not what Draupadi wants
then she can
certainly say no to it.
The Crown Prince
of Hastinapur, Duryodhan
is making his entrance
for the competition!
Greetings, King Drupad.
To take part in this competition
instead of me,
I call upon my friend
the King of Anga, Karna
who has dedicated his competence
to our friendship.
This way, King Karna of Anga.
Where are you, Prince Arjun?
Where are you headed,
'Brahmins'?
Greetings, revered one.
Greetings.
All of us are on our way
to seek alms.
To seek alms here?
Kampilya is like Lord Kuber's* treasury at the moment
*The Lord of Wealth.
and you have come here
to seek alms?
It is just like,
despite having a river nearby
a rodent is licking
the dry earth.
We do not wish to go
to Kampilya, revered one.
We need to proceed towards
Naimisharanya shortly.
If you can offer us some alms
we would be grateful
to you, revered one.
What can I give you?
I am sitting here with the hope
of reaching Kampilya myself.
But I am a cripple.
If I could walk then I would
have certainly gone there.
One would get to have
novel dishes there
and would get gold coins.
And I suggest that you
should go there as well
and take me there
on your shoulders.
Pardon us, revered one
but we do not wish to go there.
Listen
you need not worry
about how I return.
I shall arrange for it.
But just take me there.
I would be grateful for it.
Why would all of you serve me
when my own sons
have forsaken me?
A cripple has no one
in this world.
No one...
This way.
Pardon us, King of Anga!
But you cannot be allowed
to do that.
The person who marries my sister
will have to demonstrate
his competence himself.
But this is not a fair
competition, Prince.
Competence cannot be judged
solely by one's archery skills.
Crown Prince Duryodhan
is a competent warrior.
When it comes to
fighting with a mace
he is superior than all
the Princes present here.
Had this competition
involved fighting with a mace
Crown Prince Duryodhan
would certainly
have emerged
as the superior one.
But to have my sister married
to the most superior
archer of the world
is our decision.
Nevertheless
on behalf of Crown
Prince Duryodhan
I have the right to take part
in this competition.
The competence of
a King's trusted soldier
is deemed that of the King.
And I
have dedicated myself
to Crown Prince Duryodhan.
That is why,
when I achieve the goal
my victory will be deemed
that of Crown Prince Duryodhan.
This is the prevalent tradition
of the Aryan region.
This may be a tradition
of Hastinapur, King of Anga
but not of Panchal!
I do not give you
the permission.
Please go back to your place.
This time,
you have been defeated
in the name of tradition,
my dear.
What will you do now?
In the name of tradition,
you have insulted
the competence of a person,
King Drupad!
I, the Crown Prince
of Hastinapur
ask you
what you intend to do.
If you wanted to insult
so many King and Princes
then for the Ashvamedha 'Yajna,'* you could have let the horses
*Releasing a horse to roam for a year, and if it wanders into neighbouring provinces hostile to the sacrificer, they must be subjugated.
run freely in the
entire Aryan region!
That way, your competence would
have been proved before all.
Your Highness.
Crown Prince Duryodhan
to worry for
his daughter's future
is not only
the right of a father
but also his responsibility.
That is why, a 'swayamvar'
is deemed a noble deed.
And to deem the defeat
in a 'swayamvar' an insult
is not correct.
King Karna of Anga
has no fear of defeat.
Snatching the right to
take part in the competition
is what I deem an insult,
Vasudev Krishna.
A tree can be nourished
only by water.
Milk cannot do what water can.
Similarly
the proof of your competence
cannot be given
by another person, Prince.
But my friend certainly can
prove his competence.
Friend Karna
pick up that bow
and achieve the goal.
Friend Karna pick
up that bow
and achieve the goal.
That is a splendid decision,
my dear!
A splendid decision!
Listen, King Drupad.
My friend is the King of Anga.
He has every right to take part
in this competition.
He shall marry your daughter.
Draupadi
King Karna of Anga
may win the competition.
'In the entire Aryan region,
this competition can be won'
'by two people, Your Highness.'
'The son of Pandu, Arjun'
'and
the King of Anga, Karna.'
'If marrying Karna
is not what Draupadi wants'
'then she can certainly
say no to it.'
Stop!
I will not marry the
son of a charioteer.