In other words, in three days
from now will begin
the Mahabharat.
And very soon
the sons of Pandu
will meet their doom
in this very battlefield.
The Kurukshetra
after all these years
will be satiated by drinking
the blood of my enemies.
Crown Prince
who can ever know
the result of a war?
I know,
Vasudev.
You may be a great trickster
but I have unparalleled might
fighting from my side.
Take a good look at us.
General Bhishma
who has been blessed
with the boon to die at will.
Guru Drona, who cannot
be slain by anyone.
My friend Maharathi Karna
whose armour can withstand
the blow of any weapon.
When a side has
three exceptional warriors
who cannot be slain
how can that side ever meet
with defeat, Vasudev?
Crown Prince Duryodhan!
The answer to your friend Karna
is Prince Arjun.
The armour of Maharathi Karna
can certainly withstand
the blow of many weapons
but not that of the Gandiva Bow
of Prince Arjun.
My brother Dhrishtadyumna
was born to slay Guru Drona.
And His Excellency Bhishma
has made me a promise
that whenever I confront him
in a battlefield
he will not resort to arms!
And what will your role be
in this battlefield
Princess Shikhandini?
As the General of the army of
the Pandavas, King of Gandhar.
In other words,
on the very first day of the war
your General,
His Excellency Bhishma
will be stripped of his weapons.
Am I correct,
Your Excellency Bhishma?!
You are correct,
Princess Shikhandini.
Uncle
did you know that
grandsire would never take to
arms before Drupad's daughter?
Yes,
my darling.
The entire Aryan region
resonates of such tales.
In other words, on the
very first day of the war
will the General of my army
refuse to take to arms?
So, will we get defeated
even before the war begins,
uncle?
My darling
before a war begins
in the battlefield
one needs to come up
with certain plans.
This war is not yours,
my darling.
The truth is
this war
is between me
and Vasudev Krishna.
This is a web of treachery
woven by him.
That is why,
a woman
has been made the General.
However, the ethics
and rules of this war
are yet to be discussed
by both the sides.
The war will begin
after three days.
However, in order to change
the circumstances
I require merely three moments.
Only three moments.
Do not worry,
my darling.
Righteousness will aid you
win this war.
Righteousness?
How can righteousness
aid me win this war, uncle?
The righteousness of
Yudhishthir, the son of Pandu
will aid you win this war.
You.
'Three days before the war.'
Uncle Shakuni
will weave another web
of treachery, My Lords.
The ethics of the war
are yet to be discussed.
He will certainly use treachery
in the discussion
and use it to their advantage.
Do not worry,
Panchali.
Uncle has never had
any faith in wars.
He has always used treachery
to avert a war.
In a war,
his mind stops working
before cowards give up fighting.
But right before a war
in order to protect oneself
even the mind of cowards
becomes quite sharp.
Panchali's fear is not baseless.
Uncle will certainly weave
a web of treachery.
But this time,
we will not get caught in it
brother Yudhishthir.
Even if the question
of righteousness arises
we will not get caught in it,
brother Yudhishthir.
Righteousness is not a tie,
Sahadev.
Righteousness is
the other term for liberation.
When it comes to righteousness
one cannot compromise with it.
Only copper
turns green,
yellow
and white under
different circumstances.
However, gold does not
change its colour.
That is why,
gold is so precious.
Let's go.
It is time for the discussion.
Greetings, Vasudev.
Greetings.
Greetings,
Your Excellency Bhishma.
Greetings.
In the entire Aryan region
the rules of a war
have already been defined.
However, in the discussions
held before a war
those rules are merely
recollected by everyone
so that no person
in either of the sides
has a doubt in his heart.
With the permission
of everyone present here
I wish to put forth
these rules before all
in this session.
Certainly.
Thank you.
It is a tradition
of the Aryan region
that a war begins at dawn
and ends at dusk.
However,
dusk or sundown
shall not be deemed
the end of the day.
Only when it is
impossible to see
in the absence of torches
will it be deemed
the end of the day.
Impossible!
It is deemed the end of the day
when the sunrays
are no longer visible.
The argument over
precisely that point
has given rise to this war,
brother Bheem.
Regarding this point
our decision is crystal clear.
We accept your first rule,
Crown Prince Duryodhan.
But do remember...
If the inability to see
marks the end of a day
then you may stop
fighting for that day
but I shall continue fighting.
If the inability to see
marks the end of a day
then you may stop
fighting for that day
but I shall continue fighting.
I can shoot arrows
even in complete darkness.
You have seen it,
have you not?
Then I suggest
that dawn and dusk
should be determined
by the sound of a conch shell.
The Maharathis
of both the armies
shall begin and end the day
by sounding a conch shell.
That sounds fair,
Your Excellency Bhishma.
We have firm faith
in your justice.
My darling...
Your Excellency...
Let us discuss the rest
of the rules as well, Vasudev.
Only one warrior shall fight
with another warrior.
Each warrior shall fight
with a warrior of his category.
A warrior who is
injured, defenseless
or has come to seek shelter
shall not be harmed by anyone.
People who serve
and treat other people
shall not be harmed by anyone.
A warrior who is not present
in the battlefield
shall also not be harmed
by anyone.
A warrior who breaks these rules
shall be sentenced to death
by the General of that warrior.
Since these rules are in
accordance with the traditions
there is no scope
for any argument.
Splendid.
Marvellous.
Now, before ending
this session
I wish to ask one last question.
Vasudev Krishna has
called this region
a righteous one.
So, will all the warriors
participating in this war
act righteously?
Indeed.
Splendid.
Marvellous.
In other words
we have decided
that each warrior
will fight with a warrior
of the same category.
A warrior proficient in archery
will not challenge a warrior
proficient in mace-fighting.
A Maharathi
cannot challenge
a Commander.
However
according to the 'shastras'
and traditions
even the categories
of men and women
are deemed to be different.
If a woman is a mother,
she is revered.
If she is a wife,
she is dear.
If she is a daughter,
she is one's good fortune.
If she is a daughter-in-law,
she is worthy of respect.
Even when one has
an argument with a woman
striking at a woman
is like paving one's way
straight to hell.
In order to appease Maha Kali
Lord Shiva
had lied down defenseless
in the path of the Goddess.
However, He did not employ
might against the Goddess.
So, even when a woman
takes to arms in the battlefield
can any man
ever strike at her?
Only a woman
can fight against another...
So, would it not be correct
to come up with such a rule?
Yudhishthir,
son of Pandu
you are the most
knowledgeable person
when it comes to righteousness.
If you say that in this war
it is appropriate
to strike at a woman
then you would be doing
an unrighteous deed.
And if you say
that it is inappropriate
to strike at a woman
then you would be
making this war
an unrighteous one.
What kind of a question is that?
When I have given everyone
the freedom to strike at me
how does righteousness
come into the picture?
Righteousness and traditions
do not function according to the
will of a single person, Lady.
Yudhishthir,
son of Pandu...
So, what does your
righteousness say?
Have you thought of defeating us
even without engaging in a war?
Because when confronted
with your General
no warrior from our army
will strike at her.
You have upheld righteousness
all your life.
So, in order to be victorious
will you let go
of your righteous ways?
Women will not be able
to participate in this war.
We accept it.
I had told you,
my darling...
The righteousness of Yudhishthir
will become the reason
of your victory.