Lord...
Don't say anything
instead, just hear
me out, Gandhari.
Emotions are really peculiar.
They flow like water and then
cannot stop, just like
the flow of water.
In the same way, my
heart kept running
on the paths of hatred,
sorrow, anger and sadness.
It kept stumbling.
The way a dam stops
water from flowing
in the same way,
one's thought process
can be stopped due to
a single incident.
When there was no news of
Pandu from the battlefield
my thought process stopped
as is due to a dam.
The negative thoughts stopped.
My worry for Pandu
stopped my mind from travelling
the path of hatred and anger.
I understood that
I was unfortunate
and no one has
conspired against me.
I was unjust with
Pandu, Gandhari.
When I understood that,
I realized
that I was unjust to you too.
I had rejected you, Gandhari.
If I realize my mistake
would you accept me?
My heart is overflowing
with happiness today.
Now that I have shown
my weaknesses to you
I feel relived.
So what if I couldn't
become the king?
Here, I am respected and
honoured more than a king.
When you gift me with
a son in the future
he will be the eldest in the
next generation of the Kurus.
He will become the king.
He will become the heir to
the throne after Pandu.
I will feel like I was
enthroned, Gandhari.
Will you gift me with
such an able son?
Yes, Lord.
To fulfil your wishes
I can even go
to the God of death.
When it's time
we will together go to
the God of death, Gandhari.
We still have to lead
a happy life, don't we?
Stop!
Lord, look at that.
It's such a beautiful animal.
It's absolutely unusual.
Please bring me its skin
for my throne.
No! We cannot kill a deer
for no reason.
If the deer has fawns
they may turn into orphans.
Its usual for fawns
to turn into orphans.
What's so unusual
about it, Lord?
I want the animal.
Lord, wouldn't you fulfil
your wife's simple wish?
I'm not asking you
to crown me the queen.
I'm just asking for a deer.
Madri, you should open your
mouth to speak good things
not bitter things.
I will bring the deer for you.
All of you, wait here.
Madri.
To kill an animal for no reason
isn't right.
Kshatriyas are used
to killing animals.
But you may not understand that.
Weren't you born into
the Yadav clan, sister?
And the Yadavs are
shepherds, aren't they?
No!
Sage Kindam! Was that you?
Had you taken
the form of a deer?
What have you done?
You shot the arrow
without recognizing me.
I was dallying with my wife
in the form of a deer.
Fool!
In spite of seeing the deer's
appearance and grace
didn't you realize that it was
an unusual deer?
Please forgive me, sage.
I have made
a grave mistake.
It isn't a mistake but a crime!
Imbecile! How could you
forget Dasharath's* fate?
*Father of Rama who killed a boy, mistaking him to be a deer, and cursed by the boy's blind parents.
Did you forget
that he had made
the same mistake?
He had to repent
for it all his life.
What kind of
a human being are you?
What kind of a king are you?
How will a cruel king like you
bring welfare to his subjects?
You too have to
suffer a punishment.
You have disturbed the intimacy
between a man and his wife.
I curse you!
If you cohabit with a woman...
If you establish a conjugal
relationship with her
you will be dead!
"Greetings!"
"I greet the King!"
"May there be happiness"
"with the queen mother,
Bhishma and the ministers!"
"Greetings!"
"Dhundhumali the imbecile has
many doubts in his heart."
"The doubts dance on
my head like spirits."
"Dhundhumali, what is
your question? Ask us."
"Should I?
Answer this."
"He is the master
and also the slave."
"He rests and also travels."
"He is freedom
and restriction too."
"All are fascinated by him."
"Tell me. Who is it?"
"Come on, tell me.
- Life!"
"There is no rest in life.
- A wife!"
"There is no freedom
from a wife."
"A son."
"Perfect!
Well done, sire."
"Now, the second question."
"What is superior to knowledge?
It is always constant."
"The experts surrender
before it."
"All the pleasures
accumulated together."
"Come on, tell me.
Speak up!"
"What is it?"
"Devotion."
"Experience."
"Foolishness."
"No!"
" Love . "
"Wonderful!
That was perfect, sire!"
"And now, the third question."
"A forehead like the sun,
his shoulders broad enough"
"he has strong insights"
"he is an epitome
of righteousness."
"Tell me."
"Come on, tell me.
Who is it?"
"My elder brother,
prince Dhritarashtra!"
"Perfect, minister."
"And now, the last question."
"The one who answers it,
will be proven intelligent."
"In the four answers"
"lies some good news."
"If you answer the question,
I would agree"
"this a court of brilliant men."
"What happened, Vidur?"
"What is the clown saying?"
"Brother"
"I have three answers."
"Son, love and
prince Dhritarashtra!"
"It means, he is trying to say"
"that you will achieve the love
of a son very soon, brother!"
The king has arrived on
a very auspicious occasion.
Greetings, Queen Mother.
Welcome, Pandu.
Look at the games
played by time.
To be a part of a happy
event in our family
you have returned before time.
Gandhari is expecting.
Dhritarashtra's first son
will be born very soon.
'I curse you!'
'If you establish a conjugal
relationship with a woman'
'you will be dead!'
Pandu
I hope you have understood
the news.
You don't look pleased at all.
Yes, Queen Mother.
Just like grief, happiness
also stops the brain
from functioning at times.
Brother, I am
extremely happy.
Brother, my hearty
congratulations to you!
'What kind of a king are you?'
'How will a cruel king like you
bring welfare to his subjects?'
Queen Mother, I have to announce
something important.
I killed sage Kindam
in the forest!
I am no longer worthy of
ruling a kingdom, Queen Mother.
I have killed sage Kindam!
I am no longer worthy of
ruling a kingdom, Queen Mother.
So, I have decided
that from this very moment
I renounce the throne
of Hastinapur!
Greetings, uncle.
- May you live long.
Lord Vishnu
made eight elephants stand
facing the eight directions
and gave them the responsibility
of all the three realms
the sky, the earth
and the heavens.
I hope you know that.
It was a very honourable
thing for them.
And they are restricted
by the same.
Pandu, think about this.
If one of the eight elephants
filled with grief and remorse,
like you
decides to withdraw from his
responsibilities
what would happen?
The entire creation would
be destroyed.
No, uncle.
Lord Vishnu will appoint some
other animal to bear the burden
of the three worlds.
The universe cannot be destroyed
because of one entity
and neither would the
kingdom of Hastinapur
be destroyed if I left.
Hastinapur will
not be destroyed.
But the happiness
of your Queen Mother
and your uncle's peace would
surely be destroyed, dear.
The Queen Mother has waited
for 25 years.
It's her right to see
a worthy king seated
on the throne of Hastinapur.
But, uncle. I am no
longer worthy.
I am no longer worthy.
I have committed
a grave sin, uncle.
Kripacharya and Vidur have
given you a remedy to it.
Donate cows,
offer prayers.
You should fast and abstain.
Uncle, that would be deceit.
It would be like
deceiving myself.
When Lord Indra killed a sage
he had renounced his kingdom.
He had renounced heaven.
He had meditated for several
years on a lotus stem.
When the King of Gods couldn't
wash his sins away so easily...
I am a mere human being.
How would my sins
be washed away
through charity and abstinence?
But, dear...
- Don't stop me, uncle.
The one who holds the sceptre
is called the king.
To give justice to everyone
and do justice with everyone
is the duty of a king, uncle.
If a king commits a crime
who will mete out
his punishment, uncle?