Arjun.
Uncle
that is Arjun.
My dear
those four young 'Brahmins...'
They are his brothers.
My dear
h-how are those
five people alive?
Today, your fate
stands at a very
dangerous point.
Bheem
if the five of us
are seen together
then everyone will know
who we are.
But brother Yudhishthir
is it not the time
to reveal ourselves?
That decision can be taken
only by mother, Sahadev
and not us.
Bheem.
- Yes.
You must stay with Arjun.
The rest of us shall leave.
We shall wait for you
outside the city.
On my behalf,
you must bless Arjun
and the Princess.
- Do wait for a while, brother.
Just look at how excited
the 'Brahmins' are.
And Nakul might just get married
to one of their daughters.
Yes, Bheem.
That too is one of the fears.
And Nakul might just
not be able to refuse
a marriage proposal like you.
Bless you.
Father
allow your daughter
to leave with her good fortune.
My dear, if a swan enters
the territory of crows
then all the crows
peck that swan to death.
What do you mean?
With the help of all the Kings
and 'Kshatriyas' present here
we need to have
Arjun killed today.
What kind of
a mockery is this?!
an insult is it, Kings?
Can the might of the
'Kshatriyas' of the Aryan region
be insulted in this manner
in the city of Panchal?!
We are 'Kshatriyas!'
We are protectors of the land.
We are nourishers
of the subjects!
The maiden who was
gifted to us by the Gods
will be taken by that
destitute 'Brahmin?'
Destitute 'Brahmin.'
If a mouse steals a gem
from an elephant's crown
then that does not denote
the greatness of the rodent!
The elephant...
The elephant!
It is the elephant's insult!
Today, as the Princess
got married
to that destitute 'Brahmin'
all the Princesses
of the Aryan region
and the 'Kshatriya' maidens
will henceforth,
renounce all the Kings
and marry such
destitute 'Brahmins.'
How many times
should we be insulted?!
Pick them up!
Pick up your weapons!
And put an end to this 'Brahmin'
and his family.
And punish
the impudent Princess!
Kill that 'Brahmin!'
And throw the maiden
into the fire!
Friend.
Do not fight with
Arjun today, friend.
What are you saying,
King of Anga?
The enemy is standing
right before us!
And the enemy has displayed
great valour today, friend.
When lightning strikes
even Chandra Dev hides behind
the clouds momentarily
to honour it.
If we do not honour
someone's competence
then how will we
take pride in ours, friend?
If you ask me to
then I shall take to arms
but I will not be able
to kill Arjun today, friend.
'Kshatriyas'
we must kill this
'Brahmin' today!
If so many 'Kshatriya' Kings
kill us 'Brahmins'
then they will commit
the sin of killing 'Brahmins.'
You have taken to arms!
To fight you and kill you...
...is our right!
Quit talking, Kings! Attack!
- Attack!
Patukeshwar
why do you not challenge
the King of Gandhar to a fight?
King of Gandhar, where are you?!
Show yourself! I will
behead him this instant!
King of Gandhar!
Patukeshwar, this way.
This way...
King of Gandhar!
You want to fight, correct?
Come here!
You must fight me first.
Make haste!
My dear
go and kill Arjun and Bheem.
The rest of them
will perish on their own.
Do not ponder, my dear.
This is your opportunity.
Pick up your weapon.
Not today...
Today, you may
savour your victory.
You will certainly get to meet
Lord Yama someday.
Let that
'Brahmin' know this.
Crown Prince Dhrishtadyumna
when one invites people
to a ceremony
one must never draw
a weapon on them.
Calm down
Crown Prince.
Kings, Crown Princes
and 'Kshatriyas'
I request all of you
to bless this young man
and the Princess
and leave for your
respective kingdoms.
Now, you too should leave,
young 'Brahmin.'
The Crown Prince
will arrange for a chariot
and a palanquin for you two.
Indeed! Arrange for
a palanquin for me as well.
I am from the groom's side.
Pardon us, sire
but we will not
take the chariot.
We have taken an oath to walk.
Goodbye.
Stop...
I will complete the rituals
of your marriage.
And you have got that maiden
only because of me.
Do not forget that.
But before the marriage
I must seek the blessings
of my mother.
Then let's proceed.
I shall accompany you.
After all, I was the first
to stand up to protect you.
In other words,
I took the initiative.
Someshwar
carry me now.
Turn around, Someshwar.
Turn around.
Now, all the 'Brahmins'
may leave.
This right belongs solely to me.
Bless you.
Allow me to leave, father.
You are allowed to leave,
daughter.
After seeking the blessings
of the 'Brahmin's' mother
you must return soon.
We shall conduct
your marriage here.
Bless you, friend.
The look of joy on your face
gives me great contentment.
I would
like to gift you something.
These five stones.
The gems of
knowledge and patience
are to the right of the stone.
Those of love and dedication
are to the left.
And justice...
Justice is right in the center.
These are the fives bases
of righteousness, Draupadi.
What
do I do with them, Govind?
There are many instances
in one's life, Draupadi
when one is unable
to see the path.
In order to remind oneself
of righteousness
one requires an object.
The decision will always
be yours, Draupadi.
But taking a decision bearing
righteousness in mind
will be easier.