You are very beautiful.
More beautiful than
this doll of mine.
I shall have her married to
a good and handsome Prince.
And you should marry a
handsome Prince too, Princess.
Nakul
in which direction
should we proceed?
There is a very thick forest
towards the South, brother.
Some birds are flying
from the West.
They seem to have
found some wheat.
Hence, there must be villages
and fields in that direction.
We should proceed
in that direction then.
Let's go.
Mother
brother Yudhishthir
there is a village nearby.
We may live there for a while.
But would it be right
to go to a village, Arjun?
What will happen
if someone recognizes us?
We are outside the borders
of the Kuru kingdom, Bheem.
This is the kingdom of Ahichhatra.*
*The ancient capital of Northern Panchala, near Ramnagar village in Uttar Pradesh state.
Apart from guru Drona
and Ashwatthama
who else can recognize us here?
Sages, we shall offer you
security till the next village.
Bless you!
This way, please.
Stop, sages.
Greetings.
- Bless you.
You have no protector
or weapons with you.
Where are the five of you
headed towards?
We are not five.
We have...
We were...
- This is my land
and it is my duty
to protect all of you.
Let's go.
Let me drop all of you
to the next village safely.
This way, please.
But there were
six more people with us.
Five young men and their mother.
We must wait for them.
Five young men and their mother?
Where?
Where are they?
We have to kill him now.
Brother Bheem
mother has ordered us
to stay in hiding.
Besides, we cannot kill
the son of our teacher.
We need to proceed
towards the forest.
Soldiers, look for
those six people!
Where did they go?!
Look for them!
Let's go.
Soldiers, those people
must be trying to hide.
And to look for a person
who is hiding
is the prime duty of a King.
Look for them.
Brother Yudhishthir
proceed to the forest
with mother.
Until all of you
make it to the forest
I shall stay here to keep
an eye on Ashwatthama.
Nakul, Sahadev, make haste.
Arjun, be careful.
Let's go, mother.
Let's go, Bheem.
Soldier, what are you
waiting for?!
Go after them! - We cannot
go beyond this, Your Highness.
That is the forest
of the ogre, Hidimb.
A person who enters it
does not come out alive.
But those people
have entered it.
Maybe they do not know,
Your Highness
that even sunlight does not
penetrate this illusory forest.
They are bound to become
Hidimb's meal, Your Highness.
But it is vital to know
why they were
hiding in this manner.
Who were those six people?
Arjun
are you alright?
Sahadev, that way.
Brother, we are back to
where we started from.
How odd!
Sunlight does not penetrate
this place even during the day.
I think, Ashwatthama
must have left by now.
Now, we should leave
this forest as well.
How odd!
I had ripped a tree out
to clear the path.
But did I
rip a tree out from here
or from somewhere else?
From where did we
enter this forest?
Mother, this way.
Brother Bheem,
we should rest for a while.
Mother must also be tired.
But would it not be safer for us
to leave this forest first?
Would resting here be right,
Yudhishthir?
We can certainly
rest here, mother.
After entering this forest
leaving this place
or resting here
makes no difference.
Besides, now we
cannot leave this forest.
What do you mean?
This is an illusory forest,
Nakul.
Illusory.
Illusory?