'My son is innocent.'
'Had you been confident
about his innocence'
'that would have been heard
in your voice, your majesty!'
'You have to do justice,
your majesty.'
'The way Pandu's sons don't have
the protection of their father
'in the same way'
'you will have to stop
protecting your sons.'
'Your sons will study
at Drona's hermitage
for 12 years.'
'And in these twelve years'
'you will not try to contact
your sons in anyway.'
Father.
Father!
What is this I hear?
I have been ordered to go
to the hermitage... - Quiet!
Learn to seek my permission
before entering my chambers.
Father?
Yes, I order you to go
and stay at Guru Drona's
hermitage along with
your brothers.
On the banks of the
river Rishabh
miles away from Hastinapur.
There you will concentrate
on your studies.
You will follow the
orders of your Guru.
And you will be kind to
Pandu's sons.
But why are you abandoning
me like this?
At least tell me the reason.
Because that is a
tradition, son.
Your arrogance
and to bring your contemptuous
behaviour back to the
path of righteousness
this is the only solution
I have, son.
But father, what arrogance
have I shown?
I always try to fulfill
your wishes.
And don't you want
me to be your heir?
That someday I should become
the king of the Kuru dynasty.
How dare you question me!
Whatever you did to
Pandu's son Bheem
was that my wish?
But, he is an enemy, father.
All of them have come here to
stop your wishes
from being fulfilled.
This is the way one should
behave with his enemies.
Enemy?
Had I told you that Pandu's
sons are your enemies?
Father, you were the
one to say that.
You had said
that life means ambitions.
Our dreams are the
assets of our life.
Whoever becomes an obstacle in
the path of achieving
our desires
it's our duty to eliminate them.
Father, I did as you said.
How am I at fault then?
Fault...
I do not know
what is your fault.
I only know that
I may have given you
wrong advise.
To proceed towards the hermitage
is the only choice
you have, son.
So you must go.
Thus, go there
and use all your competence
to become worthy.
Go!
But, father...
- Go!
Leave.
Every child coming
into the world
is totally uncivilized.
His inner self has no
good values
nor vices.
It means, by birth
a child possesses no good
qualities or vices.
Then how do they attain
good qualities or vices?
Have we ever thought about it?
What they repeatedly
hear from their parents
children accept the
same as values.
Like
a road is formed to reach
the village river
only because people have been
repeatedly walking on it.
It means, the desires
of the parents
can develop as vices or good
qualities of their children.
Isn't that true?
Yet, when they see
vices in their children
the parents are astonished
and unhappy.
The parents ask themselves
where did their children
learn such immorality!
The truth is that, the
parents unknowingly
sow seeds of immorality
in their children
which develops
into a tree
of depravity in their heart.
It means, the parents
who desire to make
their children
virtuous and righteous
have to first
control their own desires.
Isn't it necessary?
All parents should
think about this.
Subjects present in the court
the new generation of
the Kuru dynasty
are today heading towards
the most important
phase of their life.
Among the four phases
mentioned in the scriptures
the most important is
the student life.
In the coming times
the happiness of the subjects
and peace
both depends on
the love for knowledge
of the students today
and their uprightness.
After twelve years
when the princes come back
after finishing their studies
they would be capable of
giving the great nation
administration, security
and justice.
They will return after
having gained such knowledge
and I believe in that.
Long live the princes of the
Kuru dynasty!
Prince Duryodhan.
Prince Yudhistir.
On behalf of all the princes
you will ask the king for
permission and advise.
The rest of the princes
will bid goodbye to
their respective mothers.
It's time to leave.
Goodbye.
Bless you, dear.
Study well, dear.
Value the orders of
your Guru
more than you value
the orders of God.
You are wise, so I don't have
much to advise you.
Goodbye, father.
Bless you, son.
I have several ambitions
and dreams for you, my son.
Acquire knowledge
and come back soon to
prove your capability.
Hastinapur will be
waiting for you, son.
Goodbye.
- May you live long.
Your majesty...
Send off the children
with happiness and enthusiasm.
The children are leaving today.
They will return as radiant and
strong young men soon.
I am eagerly waiting
for the day
when my son, instead of
being guided by others
can determine a path for others.
The curd will make it
a happy journey
and the sugar will make
your journey sweet.
Bheem, extend your hand.
Mother, give it to my
younger brothers first.
Just a bit.
All three are kids.
It's not right for them
to eat too much.
It isn't right to waste
sweet curd.
Bheem.
Arjun.
Protecting your
younger brothers
is your responsibility.
Trust me, mother.
Now, I am stronger than Hanuman.
I will protect Nakul
and Sahadev.
But the question is
At times, Nakul talks a lot.
Who will protect me from him?
Bheem, my brother,
you will do that.
Yes, it's true.
I can protect myself from you.
It is a bit difficult.
I am very strong.
My sons, it's time to leave.
Be successful
is your mothers blessing.
I will be worried for you.
Mother.
Father always said
whatever we do, we
should give it our best.
I will always follow his advise.
I will surely acquire the
best of knowledge.
And with my archery skills
I will always protect
my brothers.
Son, I have full faith in you.
Go.
Look!
Looks like uncle
has made arrangements
for us to rest.
Come.