Greetings, Prince Balaram!
You are welcome.
Excuse me,
King Shakuni
my intent wasn't to insult my
dear disciple Duryodhana or you.
No, Prince Balaram
we have no spite against you.
If you have to apologise
please do so
to your dear sister Subhadra.
I didn't quite catch your drift.
Prince Balaram
if a flower, instead of
adorning a deity's feet
graces the locks of a dancer
the happing
doesn't insult the deity.
It's but
the flower's misfortune.
King Shakuni!
Don't be angry with me,
Prince Balaram.
I am innocent.
Do you know?
When Drupad's daughter
had to marry the five Pandavas
she had taken a vow
from these brothers
that they can surely marry
a second time
but can't get their second wife
to Indraprastha.
There's just one queen
in Indraprastha.
High Queen Draupadi.
No one else.
Now you can
decide for yourself.
Your dear sister Subhadra
will spend her entire life here.
But, yes, whenever Arjun wishes
he will surely come to meet
your dear sister.
What dignity
will she be left with?
The entire Aryan nation
will mock at you.
You are my friend
and the guru
of dear Duryodhana.
That's why I say so.
If you doubt my words
ask him yourself.
So hang, Prince Balaram.
Vasudev.
King Shakuni.
Prince Arjun, if what
King Shakuni said is true
I can't put my sister in
such an unfortunate situation.
Neither will I tolerate
such insult to the Yadavs.
You have two options
in front of you.
Either stay in Dwarka forever
or else, my sister
shall start off for Indraprastha
right now, along with you.
Greetings, High Queen.
Prince Arjun is returning
after completing his penance.
His Highness has ordered
to be present at the town gates
to welcome him.
For the sake of the welcome
of the new bride
he has also asked to bring
along the veneration platter.
New bride?
Prince Arjun is arriving
with his wife
Princess Subhadra.
Prince!
You have broken the marital vow!
You have shattered my trust.
You and your wife
don't have the rights
to enter the town!
Panchali!
Greetings, brother Yudhisthir.
Be blessed, Arjun.
You have hurt Panchali.
I was helpless, brother.
Brother-in-law Balaram
ordered me
that post the wedding
either I take Subhadra
along with me
or reside in Dwarka forever.
And mother had ordered me
to return to Indraprastha
and help you in
the Rajsuya Yajna.
But what is the solution now,
brother Yudhisthir?
Draupadi's words are apt.
Arjun's quandary
is as legitimate.
Brother Yudhisthir, we must try
to convince Panchali.
Come, Arjun.
I believe Panchali will
surely heed to us.
'No matter where we live,
there will be just one queen.'
'And that
will be Princess Draupadi.'
'That's our vow.'
'We pledge that we shall
always bide by our vow.'
Panchali.
Your orders, Your Highness.
Not an order,
rather it's a request, Panchali.
Please think on the situation
that has come up.
Stopping Arjun
from entering the town
will be unfair to the town.
The town will remain incomplete
without Arjun.
Without Arjun,
my very life is incomplete.
Just for the sake of a vow
I have made my very life,
a penance.
We all have.
That Indraprastha will have
no other wife of you brothers...
It was the vow
that you had taken.
Arjun can't break that vow
and nullify our penance.
If Arjun
wishes to live with
his second wife
he will have to
forsake Indraprastha forever.
If Arjun
wishes to live with
his second wife
he will have to
forsake Indraprastha forever.
But, Panchali
how can the Rajsuya Yajna
be done without Arjun?
How can we ever be independent?
The dream of a great kingdom
will remain unfulfilled.
Does our penance
cause the kingdom
or the desire to have a kingdom
cause our penance?
You have to decide
whether if sweetness
causes sugar to have a value
or if just because it carries
a value
does sugar taste sweet.
If a kingdom is that important
then you all are capable enough
just attack Hastinapur.
It will be unrighteous
but unrighteousness is the cause
of polity in the Aryan empire.
Why should we be any different?
Bear in mind though.
From underneath massive rocks
if a bit of soil is swept away
those rocks tumble down
from their mountains.
A violation of penance
is even easier.
Thus, if Arjun wishes to live
with his second wife
he shall have to forsake
Indraprastha forever!
Prince
won't sister-in-law come
to welcome me?
Subhadra
we might not be able
to even enter the town.
Subhadra, where are you going?
To get you forgiveness.
High Queen
this has been sent
to you
with a request
to keep them safe.
Who sent them?
She says she's a woman
from Dwarka.
This has also been sent by her.
She said
that you can keep it safe.
Tell the High Queen
that it's a request from me
to keep this keepsake safe.
You must be Subhadra.
Greetings, High Queen.
When I had started from Dwarka
brother Krishna had given me
these gifts.
All that he had got
from Mathura and Vrindavan.
All those souvenirs.
Brother Krishna had told me
to keep these very safe.
But, High Queen
I feel
I have made a terrible mistake.
I won't be able
to keep them safe.
How would they not be safe?
Your husband is the world's
best archer!
Anything that comes
under his protection
can never be harmed.
I beg your pardon, High Queen
but brother Krishna said
that these are no royal borders
that protection can be given
through weapons.
To keep souvenirs pure
and protected
love and dedication
are required.
Just look at my husband!
He forgot his very vow!
How can he protect
these invaluable souvenirs?
Subhadra!
Arjun is my husband too.
I can't bear to hear
a word in his insult.
The vow that he'd given me
is my concern.
You need not concern yourself
about it.
No, High Queen
I was mentioning about
the vow he had made to me.
He had said that
I'd hold the supreme position
at Indraprastha.
That I'd have power over all.
You wish to become
the High Queen of Indraprastha?
No, High Queen!
A High Queen
has many responsibilities!
She never finds a moment's rest.
I want to have power over
the High Queen of Indraprastha.
And Arjun had said
that it'd surely be so.
Don't speak lies, Subhadra.
I know Arjun.
He can never teach anyone
such a grave ploy.
Surely Govind
has taught you this.
Yes, High Queen.
Brother had said that if I was
to be the cause of your spite
I should have the words
to soothe you as well.
Brother had said
that wherever force
doesn't work
love always conquers.
He had said that if I remain
my simple self
I'd be able to queen over
the High Queen.
That's what brother had said,
High Queen.