The King of Magadh, Jarasandh
by having his daughter married
to the Prince of Mathura, Kans
has surrounded us.
Now between Magadh
and our kingdom
there is just one
big kingdom, Panchal.
Its neighbouring kingdoms
are Virat, Kashi and Kaushal
and their kings do not have
the might to stop Jarasandh.
But we have
our allies in the South.
The most powerful kingdom
in the south is Vidarbha.
But Vidarbha is an ally
of Magadh.
- Pandu
when you set out
on your victory march
you shall face hostility
from many kings.
If you do not do so
Jarasandh will
deem you powerless
and attack our kingdom
some day or the other.
Greetings, grandsire.
May you live long.
Greetings, Kripacharya.
- May you live long.
Greetings, Queen Mother.
All of you are discussing
a very serious topic.
To dispense sound advice
to the king
the entire assembly
is present here.
Greetings, brother.
We have a pressing problem
at hand, brother.
We need your assistance.
In other words, does
the king require my services?
Then what was the need to have
grandsire call me here?
I would have been here
even if you had summoned me
Your Highness.
I can only request to you,
brother
but never order you.
Irrespective of when
the skies thunder
animals are bound
to run for cover.
Similarly, the request of a king
is like an order.
So, tell me, Your Highness.
Have you sentenced me
to the gallows
or given me life imprisonment?
Son, what are you saying?
Why would you be punished?
For my crime of being
the elder brother, Queen Mother.
Being the elder brother
to a king
is no less than a crime.
Listen to me, brother.
Expunge your heart
of bitterness and anger.
Vidur and I feel...
And even grandsire
and Queen Mother agree
to make you the Prime Adviser
of Hastinapur.
This rank will be above
that of a Chief Minister.
But no such rank exists,
Your Highness.
Will such a rank be formed
only for me?
Even if it is, it is pointless.
What advice can
a blind man dispense?
The darkness of his vision
clouds his intellect as well.
Am I right, Chief Minister?
Brother...
- Let it be, Pandu.
Let it be.
When I was a child
I would cry to see the moon.
Then mother Ambika would place
a jaggery 'laddoo' in my hand
and tell me that the 'laddoo'
was better than the moon.
She would say that people
could only see the moon
but I was fortunate enough
to be able to eat the sweet.
I am not a child anymore.
So, I do not
require this 'laddoo'.
But I do have question
in my mind.
The coronation ceremony is
like a 'yajna'* in the 'shastras'**
* Sacrificial offering.
** Sacred texts.
and righteousness dictates
such a 'yajna'
to be performed
only by a married man.
Grandsire
I was denied my right
based on righteousness.
So... - But brother,
'Shandilya Samhita' says...
Let it be, Chief Minister.
According to you, righteousness
changes according to situations.
You will quote an unknown
'shastra' to us all now.
But for me,
tradition is righteousness
and not just the'shastras'.
It is tradition
that one gets one's right
but only after
proving one's competence.
And in our family, we all
have enlisted our competencies
and Pandu has even proven
the same.
Do you understand all this,
Chief Minister?
Even I did not
understand anything.
I shall definitely
prove my competence, brother.
If you like you may test me.
Only time tests a person, Pandu.
And I am not time
but only a person
who has to it.
Before performing your duties
as the king, get married
to a maiden, Pandu,
who's progeny
will provide security
to Hastinapur in the future.
Just like the progeny of
the Princess of Gandhar.
Is a devoted wife not
a part of a king's competence
Chief Minster?
Goodbye.
Dhritarashtra has raised a doubt
regarding righteousness.
What should I answer him?
For the injustice done to him
will he exact revenge
at every step of the way?
Righteousness can never
lead to injustice, Queen Mother.
But in Dhritarashtra's
perspective
what happened to him was unjust.
And even Gandhari's brother
has stayed back.
He seems deceitful
and devious to me, Bhishma.
He is bound to
instigate Dhritarashtra
and make him a rebel.
If two walls are at loggerheads
then the ceiling
is bound to collapse.
If Pandu and Dhritarashtra
go against each other
then the Kuru dynasty
wall fall apart.
I cannot let this happen.
To keep King Shantanu's kingdom
as an integrated entity
I have gone
through a lot of pain.
Bhishma, we must put an end
to Dhritarashtra's doubt.
Then we should get Pandu
married at the earliest.
Where will we find a maiden
who will bless Hastinapur
with eminent heirs?
Whose sons will secure
the future of Hastinapur.
Whose presence will magnify
the strengths of Pandu.
Where can we find such a maiden?
Princess, why did you
break our arrows?
Did we make a mistake,
Princess Kunti?
It was not a mistake
but a crime.
That deer has a baby.
Did none of you see it?
To snatch its mother
from a child
is the gravest crime.
A child separated
from its mother is not
surrounded by the world
but only fear.
All around it...
The King has sent you a message.
He has asked you to return
to the palace at once.
Why?
The day of your 'swayamvar'
has been decided.
'Swayamvar?'
Greetings, father.
You are back.
Come here.
Father
have you announced
my 'swayamvar' already?
Yes, dear.
With great pride,
I have made this announcement.
You will see,
this 'swayamvar' of yours
will be celebrated
like a festival.
But father...
- No, Kunti.
If the term 'but' is applied
to the beginning of a question
then its answer
is always doubtful.
A good task is never begun with
terms like 'ifs' and 'buts'.
But what if
the heart is filled with fear
while executing that task?
Even then the task
cannot be executed, father.
This is what you had said.
Are you afraid
of the 'swayamvar'?
Why, dear?
With your purity and devotion
you had pleased sage Durvasa.*
Incarnation of Shiva.
Then what are you afraid of,
Kunti?
There...
There is something, father
that keeps
tormenting my heart.
What is it, Kunti?
Only crime
can torment the heart.
And I have complete faith
that my daughter
can never commit a crime.
Something that would
tarnish my reputation
is not something my daughter
is capable of.
Then what keeps tormenting you?
Father...
I had...
After I leave
who will take care of you?
My brother is still a child.
- My dear.
You have taken
enough care of me.
Now you shall worry
only for your husband.
Be calm.
Dream of happier times ahead.
I have complete faith
that the most able man
of this world
the very finest of them all,
will become your husband.
That is why only the best
kingdoms in the region of Arya
have been invited
to the 'swayamvar'.
It is an invitation from
King Kuntibhoj, Queen Mother.
He is organising a 'swayamvar'
for his daughter Kunti.
I think, Queen Mother,
we should accept his invitation.
She is not even
the daughter of King Kuntibhoj.
She is the daughter of
Shurasen of the Yadavas.
King Kuntibhoj has adopted her.
If she is not even a princess
then how can she become
the Queen of Hastinapur?
Queen Mother
a mango sapling is taken
from where it was sown
to another piece of land.
And the new piece of land
makes the mango even sweeter.
This maiden belongs to both
the Yadava and Kunti dynasties
and has their virtues too.
And Queen Mother,
with this marriage
our relations with the kingdoms
of Kunti and Yadava
will get strengthened.
Chief Minister Vidur.
Right now, I have no interest in
strengthening our relations.
Right now, I am
in search of a maiden
who has the competence
of becoming Hastinapur's Queen.
I have heard that
this maiden had served
Sage Durvasa for months
and her service was such that
even a short-tempered sage like
Durvasa was pleased with her.
A maiden who can perform
such a difficult task
must have the virtues
of patience and righteousness
inside her, Queen Mother.
Princess
what were you about to tell
to His Highness?
That
the daughter whom he
deems to be pure and chaste
has an
unspeakable secret inside her.
It is a secret which, before
the kings of the region of Arya
can humiliate you
and ruin your reputation.
His Highness has
boundless faith in you.
What will you achieve
by breaking that faith?
That was a mistake in your past.
There is no point
in remembering it.
Please forget about it.
How can I forget about it?
How do I forget about it,
Priyamvada?
Even today, that memory
sends chills down my spine.
I am very pleased with
your service, Princess Kunti.
Before I release you
from my service
I, sage Durvasa,
give you a mantra
with which you will be
able to invoke any God
and call him to you
and shall be blessed with a son
by that God.
Thank you, sire.
I accept your invitation, Kunti.
Are...
Are you Lord Surya himself?
- Yes, Kunti.
Greetings.
This mantra is the order
of Sage Durvasa himself.
When you chant this mantra
while taking the name of a God
that God will be
compelled to appear before you.
Then how did I not get burnt?
I have regulated my temperature
according to you, Kunti.
The son you are
about to conceive
will similarly have
my energy and luminescence.
Son?