Along with lac,
this palace is made
with dried grass,
clarified butter and cotton.
If this palace catches fire
everything will get burnt
within six hours.
This is a scheme to burn
us alive in the palace.
Father
the remaining Pandavas
have figured out
that the entire palace
is made of lac.
Purandiri, seek permission
from Her Highness
to go and get more food
from the kitchen.
You have my permission.
You may go and get it.
But we have already given them
all the food, My Lord.
Be quiet.
Our plan has been foiled.
We must torch this place.
We must get out of here at once!
Let's go.
We need to discuss
this with mother.
But I do not understand,
brother Yudhishthir.
What must have Duryodhan
thought about this place?
If this place is torched,
will we not be able to escape?
Is he a fool?
Brother Arjun can extinguish
an entire forest fire
using a single 'Varunastra'.*
*The water weapon (a storm) incepted by Varuna--the god of the water and of the celestial ocean, as well as a god of law of the underwater world.
He might not have
thought about it.
He did.
He has put quite a bit
of thought into it, brother.
The mouse died
upon eating the 'kheer'.
Mother, begin eating.
They must be on their way.
No, let them arrive.
At least, allow me to feed you
some 'kheer', mother.
No, Bheem.
You may have it.
Besides, a mother eats only when
her children are done eating.
No, mother. You must allow me
to feed you some 'kheer'.
Alright.
Go ahead.
But I have a fear, mother.
When you feed me,
I feel satiated.
What if I feel satiated
upon feeding you?
That is impossible,
my Vrikodar.
If that happens, I shall not be
able to eat when you feed me.
And I have committed no sin
that the Almighty will
punish me that harshly.
Now, feed me.
Open your mouth.
That 'kheer' has been
poisoned, mother!
Yes, mother.
The mouse died upon eating it.
Mother, get up. This palace
might get torched any moment.
I do not understand.
Brother, this palace
is made with lac.
Poisoning all of us first
and then torching this place
were all part of a scheme!
That way, everyone would think
that we died in an accident.
But... - This is not the time
to talk, brother Bheem.
We must first catch
that Purochan!
And then we will
take him to Hastinapur.
Let's go.
Let's go, mother.
Never did I imagine
that brother Duryodhan
would try to kill us!
Couldn't you imagine
such a thing, Sahadev?
Then your power of imagination
is very weak!
Did you forget?
He had poisoned me.
But we were children back then.
Children do many things
without thinking straight.
How could he do it now?
- I will crush Duryodhan's head
brother Yudhishthir!
I have heard that
when death approaches
a deer makes its way
to a lion's den on its own.
I think, Duryodhan's doom
is calling out to him.
'Taste this 'kheer',
brother Bheem.'
'You 5 brothers will touch
the feet of us 100 brothers.'
'Right now!'
'And forever after.'
'Mother, what kind
of a place is this?'
'No one seems happy
upon our arrival here.'
'It seems like
we are refugees here'
'and have no right
to this place.'
'Certainly.
This is a big kingdom.'
'You can ask for food
from anyone.'
'That is what your mendicant of
a father must have taught you.'
'Yudhishthir'
'the blood of which dynasty
runs through your veins?'
'From whom did your
characterless mother'
'conceive you?'
'Very soon'
'the reason of your worry'
'will come to an end,
brother Bheem.'
'You 5 brothers will touch
the feet of us 100 brothers.'
'Right now!
- It seems like...'
'And forever after.
-...we are refugees here...'
'Mother, what kind
of a place is this?'
'Certainly.
This is a big kingdom.'
'You can ask for food
from anyone.'
'That is what your mendicant of
a father must have taught you.'
'Very soon,
the reason of your worry'
'will come to an end,
brother Bheem.'
Brother Bheem is correct,
brother Yudhishthir.
If we do not draw
our weapons even now
we will be termed
as cowards and weaklings.
Just give me the order,
brother Yudhishthir!
I await it!
Do not give them any order,
Yudhishthir.
What are you saying, mother?
How can we calm down?
Duryodhan has schemed
to burn us alive.
He schemed to burn you,
our mother!
If that is the case, sons
then all of us
shall burn to ashes here.
They conspired to kill my sons!
Such hatred...
Such animosity harbours in them!
No, sons.
Going to Hastinapur now
is not an option any longer.
The gates of that kingdom
are closed for us now.
What are you saying, mother?
Why should we not go there?
It is our home.
A home is made up
of a family, son.
A place filled with enemies
is not a home
but a camp in a war.
Death looms in such a place.
Anger pervades such a place.
Doubt infests
such a place.
It feels like hell
in such a place, son.
We cannot live
in a place like that.
But, mother, brother Yudhishthir
is the Crown Prince
and he has the right
to the throne.
We have no greed for polity.
We do not want any throne!
Your father had
renounced polity himself
and resided in a forest.
Did you forget that?
You were even born
in a forest.
It was a forest
where sages would meditate.
There was no misery.
We did not go to Hastinapur
asking for our rights.
We had gone there
asking for a family.
We had gone there seeking the
love and respect of that family.
If we do not have
any right to their love
then what is the point
of the right to the throne?
Yudhishthir
if Duryodhan wants polity
then let go of it, son.
But, mother,
what about justice?
Duryodhan tried
to kill you, mother!
Right now, my blood is boiling
like an erupting volcano!
I would be a disgrace if I
do not punish Duryodhan!
What punishment will you
give Duryodhan?
When Bheem was poisoned
what punishment was
given to Duryodhan?
King Dhritarashtra has
forgotten at the moment
that a King is the father
of all his subjects.
Right now, he is just a father
of his 100 sons.
Duryodhan will receive
no punishment, Arjun.
He will receive no punishment.
The one to be punished
will be me.
I will be punished, son.
All of you are capable.
You can revolt
against Hastinapur.
But if that happens
then my husband's soul
will grieve in heaven.
And if you do not revolt
against Hastinapur
then we will have to live
with such conspiracies.
Day and night
I will be plagued with doubts.
The only property I have with me
are the five sons of mine.
Among the five of you
the mere possibility of
any of you dying will be like
going through hell to me.
Do you wish to see me
face the atrocities of hell
in every moment
of the rest of my life?
And son
Duryodhan...
Duryodhan needs to succeed
just once, son.
Just once.
We will never let him
succeed, mother!
Never!
- They will succeed!
They certainly will!
If you stay there, you will
lose your peace of mind!
Duryodhan will compel you
to conspire against him.
He will extinguish
your righteousness!
In other words, you will
either lose your life or morals.
But, I
will lose in both the cases.
Now, you decide, sons
if the news of all of you dying
will award me misery for life
or righteousness dying within
you will award me the same.
What kind of a punishment
have all of you chosen for me?
Answer me.
Answer me!
When your tears
are that of joy, mother
it is like a plunge
into the Holy Ganges to us.
But when they are
that of sorrow
it is like a plunge
into the fire to us, mother.
Mother, this is
such a big world.
Why would we choose a place
where our mother
would neither be in peace
nor be contented?
Why would we
do such a thing, mother?
Why would we?
If it is your order
then we shall certainly
not return to Hastinapur.
No one will even know
that we are alive.