Princess, this feast
is for family only.
Apart from family
and the guests invited
no one else can be
a part of this. - Mother Kunti!
Mother Kunti!
Greetings! Just look at
who is here to meet you!
This is my friend Subhadra.
She used to practice with me
at the students' dwelling.
She is the daughter of Vasudeva.*
Kunti's brother, also father of Krishna (Vaasudeva, with long 'a').
Subhadra!
The daughter
of my brother Vasudeva?
When starting from Dwaraka,
brother Krishna told me
that Queen Kunti is our aunt.
He said that if I
served you whole-heartedly
fortune would smile upon me.
Greetings!
Subhadra!
I hope, the health of
my younger brother Vasudeva
and that of the daughter
of Ugrasena, Devaki, is well.
And what about
the two brothers of yours?
Balaram and Krishna...
How are they?
All of them are doing well.
Hearing the heroic tales
of Krishna
always pleases my heart.
He is truly divine, Subhadra.
I would really like
to meet Krishna.
Brother Krishna says
that when the temperatures soar
the ocean is required to meet
the mountain at its crown.
If the circumstances
continue to be so
both of you shall meet soon.
What do you mean?
The meaning
of brother Krishna's words
cannot be comprehended
even by brother Balaram.
I merely listen to his words.
Subhadra, a few musicians
are present over there and
are playing some instruments.
Let's go listen to them.
Let's go.
Greetings, mother.
Greetings.
Bheem
your seat is over there.
Why are you seated
amongst the women here?
It has been years since
you have fed me, mother.
Today, you will have to feed me.
Everyone will laugh at you.
Greetings, mother.
Greetings.
You should feed him today.
The moment you feed him,
brother Bheem feels satiated.
Then all of us will be able
to have a hearty meal too.
Alright.
I shall go sit over there.
I shall be here when
we are having our meals
so that you can feed me.
Greetings, brother Yudhishthir!
Greetings. - This is my friend
from the student's inn.
She is the sister of Krishna
Subhadra.
Greetings!
- May you be prosperous!
Krishna has transformed the
politics of the Aryan region.
Brother Krishna says
transformation in politics
of the Aryan region
will be brought by you.
Dushala, I have heard that you
have completed your course
at the student's inn.
Yes, brother Yudhishthir.
I have learnt
all the arts necessary
but I could not learn
to play any musical instrument.
But Subhadra plays the veena* very well.
*String instrument from which sitar is derived.
Greetings.
- Greetings.
Brother Arjun can play
all musical instruments.
Nakul, this is no occasion
to play a musical instrument.
Do play the veena,
brother Arjun!
Even father is not here yet.
Go on.
Play it, Arjun.
Go on and play it, brother.
Even Princess Subhadra
is eager to hear you play it.
Wonderful.
You played the veena
wonderfully, brother Arjun.
Go on and reward the other
musicians as well, Dusshasan.
Friend Karna
do you play
a musical instrument too?
Me?
Had someone else asked me
this question, friend
I would have considered it
to be my insult.
To a true archer
the sound of his bow's string
is real music.
Very rightly said, friend.
The valour of the Kuru dynasty
is being tarnished by him.
Duryodhan!
Yesterday, Arjun had you pinned
to the ground with his arrows.
Did you forget about that?
Arjun had me pinned
with his arrows
but my friend Karna
had used just one arrow
to free me from my bond.
Did you forget about that,
brother Bheem?
Even a mouse can cleave
through a bond with its teeth.
This makes him useful
and not a warrior.
King of Anga Pradesh!
You may be a skilled archer
but when it comes to debating
you cannot beat
the sons of Pandu.
Some pluck a bow's string,
while some blow a gasket.
If he displays such a temper
on the battlefield
then his enemies
even before picking up
their weapons
will faint.
Go on and play, Prince.
To entertain the maidens
you would not only
play musical instruments
but also
be ready to become a dancer.
King of Anga Pradesh!
Arjun!
Restrain yourself!
What are you doing,
Prince Arjun?
Let me tell you,
Your Excellency.
Prince Arjun
is insulting a royal guest.
A king
who is an ally of
the kingdom of Hastinapur.
By drawing a weapon on him
he is jeopardizing
that alliance.
Now, maybe Prince Arjun
will draw a weapon on
the King of Gandhar as well.
Attention everyone!
King Dhritarashtra
is making his entrance!
Sanjay.
What is happening here?
- Your Majesty.
The very righteous,
the very knowledgeable
Chief Minister Vidur
is about to do justice here.
Justice?
Prince Arjun has drawn a weapon
on the King of Anga Pradesh.
Without the permission
of the king
he has jeopardized
an alliance of the kingdom
and this is the crime
of Prince Arjun.
Arjun must be just jesting.
But dear Gandhari
the King of Anga Pradesh, Karna
is neither a friend
of Prince Arjun
nor his brother.
To jest with the King
of Anga Pradesh, Karna
is a right he does not have.
This is
a very grave crime that you
have committed, Arjun.
But uncle...
- Be quiet!
Be quiet.
You decided to forge an enmity
with Anga Pradesh?
You have given Hastinapur
an invitation to a war!
I request the King of Anga
Pradesh to pardon Hastinapur.
Because of just one person
I cannot forget the benevolence
of the king, Your Majesty.
But Arjun ought to be
punished, father.
There is just one punishment
for this crime.
To be banished from
the entire kingdom of Kuru!