Vrushali.
You need not worry, dear.
Even though I cannot go
to Indraprastha
it is alright.
I will request Her Highness
to ensure that you
get your freedom.
I know
that the day
I plead to sister-in-law
will be the last day of my life.
But I
am the mother of the Pandavas.
The promise I made you
cannot be broken by me.
All hail Queen Mother!
King Karna of Anga
seeks permission to enter.
Allow him to enter.
Greetings,
Queen Mother!
Bless you!
I have ensured
Vrushali's freedom.
Let's go,
Vrushali.
I shall take you to the borders
of Indraprastha safely.
I...
Pardon me.
But
I can go there by myself.
You need not bother
yourself with it.
Why?
Do you doubt my character?
No!
No, Your Highness.
I do not doubt your character.
But...
Pardon me.
I have travelled
with the royalty once.
Your Highness
when an elephant
comes to pluck lotuses
it does not crush the flowers.
It crushes the leaves
and the stems.
When a predicament approaches
it is the subjects that suffer.
I am not a King
anymore, Vrushali.
I have renounced the kingdom.
Now, I am just like you.
I am merely an ordinary
son of a charioteer.
You shall be safe with me.
Seek the permission to leave
from the Queen Mother.
Go on,
Vrushali.
Maharathi Karna
I would like you
to give my sons this...
Could you kindly
deliver this message
to my sons?
A written message,
Queen Mother!
You must certainly
have faith in me.
My mother has renounced me
but I have not yet
renounced her.
The values and righteousness
imparted to me
have not been forgotten by me.
Let me tell you
what the message is, Karna.
Tell my sons that...
- But think once
before telling me what
the message is, Queen Mother.
I have not yet renounced
my friendship.
Undying dedication to my friend
is still a part of my values.
I have faith
that whatever you do
will be in accordance
with righteousness.
Tell my sons
that a true kingdom
is an independent one.
Only when a gem
emerges from a rock
does it truly shine.
If you seek the refuge
of Hastinapur
you will always be a part
of unrighteousness.
That is why,
you must
earn a flag of your own
kingdom at the earliest.
Only when your kingdom
is independent
will your mother
enter Indraprastha.
If any 'Brahmin'
traveller or requester
requires money
then I, son of Adhiratha
Karna, request him
to accept this charity
from me for which
I will be very grateful.
Revered 'Brahmins'
will you not accept
charity from me today?
We cannot accept charity
from you, Radheya.
One is prohibited to accept
charity from a 'Shudra.'
But yesterday, you had accepted
charity from this very 'Shudra'
revered 'Brahmins.'
Until yesterday,
you were a King, Radheya.
Being a King is regardless
of one's competence.
A tiger and a cat look similar
but we behave differently
with both of them.
In other words
you were afraid of me.
That if you did not
accept charity from me
I would punish you.
Did you accept the charity
out of this fear?
Think what you may
but why are you
making us engage in this
unrighteous deed now?
We cannot accept the charity
being given by you.
I have merely
renounced my kingdom.
I have not yet
renounced my weapons.
I am still powerful.
I accept your charity,
Maharathi.
Please give me some.
Bless you!
Water stored only in a
baked pot is worth consuming.
An unbaked pot
renders even the water from the
Ganges unfit for consumption.
Similarly
blessings given out of the
fear of weapons is worthless.
And worthless
is the person
giving the blessings.
Revered 'Brahmins'
would you clarify
a doubt of mine?
Does a person lacking competence
not entitled to even
engage in religious deeds?
The deeds of one's past life
decide all this.
In his past life
he must have
hurt people immensely.
That is why, he is in pain
in his present life, child.
And after enduring great pain
in his present life
his next life will be
a blissful one.
But what about
the pain you are afflicting
Maharathi Karna in this life?
What will you get
in your next lives,
revered 'Brahmins?'
What will you get
in your next lives,
revered 'Brahmins?'
Brother Yudhishthir,
you are the King of Indraprastha
but we are being subjected
to injustice here!
You must uphold justice.
Why are you so agitated,
My Lord?
We just got the news
from Hastinapur
that no one is allowed to attend
the reverence of Indraprastha.
Not even the royal family.
Not even mother.
Hastinapur has
imprisoned mother.
The truth is, the entire
kingdom of Hastinapur
has now become a prison
for mother, Panchali.
Does mother-in-law require
permission to take part
in the reverence of our city?
The truth is
that even for the
reverence of a city
one requires
permission, friend.
Fortunately,
His Highness
has already taken that decision.
None of you
are independent to take
a decision on your own.
Obeying the orders of Hastinapur
is your duty.
I am not concerned
about the duties!
That rule applies only to
brother Yudhishthir.
All I know is that
if someone loves you
you must be ready
to die for them.
And the one who is your enemy
deserves to die at your hands!
That is why,
you are so dear to me
brother Bheem.
What do you suggest,
Govind?
It is true
that attacking Hastinapur
would be committing treason.
And it is also true
that this rule
applies only to the King
and
not to the sons of a mother.
Speak clearly,
Madhav.
How can I speak clearly, friend?
She is your mother
it is your kingdom
the weapons are yours
and the duty...
The duty belongs
to all of you as well.
What can we do in such a
situation, brother Yudhishthir?
I cannot order you to attack.
And neither can I lend you
the army of Indraprastha.
But
in order to build
a case for mother
if all of you go to Hastinapur
to request to His Highness
then I cannot stop you
from doing so either.
I cannot stop you
from carrying weapons and
if you have to take to arms
in your defense
then I cannot stop you
from doing so either.
But do remember
that if any of you
is the first one to attack
then I shall
renounce the kingdom.
Maharathi* Karna!
*Great charioteer, great hero/warrior, name of Shiva.
Maharathi Karna
can you ever pardon me?
Pardon you?
For what?
I spoke ill of you
and you renounced your kingdom.
The result was that the insult
you had left far behind
has caught up...
Has caught up to you.
You need not apologize,
Vrushali.
The dilemma is
that in order to be righteous,
I attained my competence
but my competence propelled me
towards unrighteousness.
The truth is
you have opened
my eyes, Vrushali.
How can someone else's behaviour
compel me to leave
my righteous ways?
I am indebted to you.
You are so benevolent
and forgiving,
Maharathi Karna.
I did not know that.
And that
at such a young age
you could have such a deep
understanding of life's truths
is something I was unaware of.
The path that I
was unable to see until now
has been shown to me
by you so effortlessly.
Whoever haves you in his life
would certainly
never lose his way.