Servant!
Bring that maid Draupadi
in this royal court.
Handmaid
what's the news?
It's a sad news, Your Highness.
For a lady divested
of the title of the empress
has no end to her
pain and insult.
What do you mean?
Your Highness
you've been ordered at once to
be present at the royal court.
Who the heck are you?
How dare you enter my room
without permission!
Fool!
Get out of here!
I am the charioteer
of Emperor Duryodhan.
Please come along to abide by
Emperor Duryodhan's order.
My husband has lost
merely the game of gambling
not his life!
I don't take anyone's orders
apart from my husbands.
But the slaves don't have rights
to order, Your Highness.
King Yudhishthira had lost
himself in the gambling
along with you.
Now you are
Emperor Duryodhan's maid.
Please come.
Go and tell Duryodhan
that Empress Draupadi refuses
to be lost by Yudhishthira
in the game of gambling.
The already cut down tree
can neither grow
new leaves in the spring
nor can lose them in the autumn.
If Yudhishthira
had already lost himself
in the gambling
he had no right to stake me!
Go
tell Duryodhan.
Go!
Draupadi is right,
Your Highness.
If Yudhishthira had already
lost himself in the gambling
he had no right
to stake his wife.
That means
when Yudhishthira lost himself
along with his property
he lost even his wife.
No.
It's the person
who has a right on the property
not vice versa.
The husband
as well as the wife
both have a right on each other.
A wife,
certified by the scriptures
and revered by the society
can never be taken
as her husband's property.
Therefore, the moment
Yudhishthira lost himself
he had not lost Draupadi.
That means, neither
Yudhishthira lost Draupadi
nor did he have a right
to lose her.
Is that what
all of you want to prove?
In that case, all of you let
an utmost inequity take place
in this royal court.
None of you has a right
to be in this royal court.
Karna... - Please calm down,
Master Drona.
You won't get answer to such a
difficult question like this.
We must ask
the most righteous person
for this answer.
Tell me, slave Yudhishthira.
Your silence
will be taken as falsity.
Tell me.
Was losing Draupadi right
or wrong?
Please remain mum, brother.
Please don't mind committing
such a petty inequity, today.
But please remain mum.
Speak up, slave Yudhishthira.
Was staking Draupadi right
or wrong?
If...
If losing my four brothers
was right
then losing Draupadi
wasn't wrong.
What have you done, brother!
Did you pay heed, Master Drona?
Dushasan
bring that handmaid
in the royal court.
If that egoistic lady
refuses to accept my order
hold her by her hair
and bring over here, dragging.
Dushasan!
If you even touch her
I would kill you!
Keep quiet!
Just keep quiet, slave!
You can't do anything.
You are bound by dharma.
I have attained
that slave Draupadi
as per the dharma.
To heck with your dharma!
Don't forget, Duryodhan
that God lies in 'Shivlinga'*
*Symbolic rock of Shiva.
but upon hitting with the stone
it yields the sparks!
I will burn you to ashes!
Stop yelling
slave Arjun.
If you want to commit
the wrong
go ahead.
Even we want to witness
how you insult
your elder brother Yudhishthira.
Tell Yudhishthira
that you don't accept
the limit set by him.
Tell him
that you have nothing
to do with his defeat.
Take your weapons
and leave this royal court!
We will set you free.
Go!
Dushasan, go.
Bring that handmaid
in this royal court.
Your Highness
Prince Dushasan
is entering your room.
Handmaid Draupadi
you were ordered to be present
in the royal court!
Don't cross your limit, Prince!
Even the entire farm
of dried straws
can't bind
even the smallest ember.
In the same way,
you hundred brothers
will burn to ashes!
Shut up, slave Draupadi!
Your five husbands
have already been shut up
by Emperor Duryodhan.
Come!
I warn you, Prince.
You will have to face the
consequences of this insolence.
'Consequences'!
It is the desire of bearing
the consequences
for which you're being
called to the court.
Wicked man!
How dare you insult me?
If you have the guts
then take the daughter-in-law
of the Kuru lineage
in the presence
of the empress.
You scoundrel!
My curse will destroy you.
No!
Come!
- You scoundrel!
Leave me!
Your freedom!
Your honour!
Yudhisthira lost everything.
Come!
Leave me, you wicked man...
Dushasana!
The hands that have dared
to touch Draupadi's pious hair...
I vow to rip those hands off!
Dushasana
when one's pride
is destroyed
it is the face that is
blackened first.
Let me see this
proud woman's face.