'Very soon, for the benefit
of his son, Lord Indra'
'will come to you to ask
for your ear-rings and armour.'
'As long as you bear your armour
and stand before me'
'it is impossible to kill me.'
'This armour of yours
makes you invincible, friend.'
'However,
it makes me immortal.'
'Your holy armour is'
'undoubtedly important to you.'
'However, it is'
'more important to me, friend.'
Greetings,
revered 'Brahmin'.
I am a requester.
I have been travelling to seek
something, King of Anga
which is both death
and ambrosia.
It is both living
and also the cause of life.
It is both visible
and invisible.
It is gentle
yet tough.
It is a part of the body
but also a means.
It is both pure and impure.
My armour and ear-rings.
As they are a blessing,
they are pure.
However, as they are joined
to my body, they are impure.
They are both
visible and invisible.
As long as they are
joined to my body
they act as ambrosia.
However, when they will be
separated from my body
they will become
the cause of my death.
Have you not come here
to ask for these
Lord Indra?
Your father must indeed
have told you, dear.
Tomorrow at dawn
I am going to ask you
for your ear-rings and armour.
Does your son
have no competence
to retaliate against me?
Is he scared of
my armour and ear-rings?
Looking for ways to ensure
the protection of one's son
is the right of every father.
My son's fear has got
nothing to do with this!
However
the apprehensions within
the heart of a father
are certainly
associated with it.
Despite being a God, how can
you be so partial, Lord Indra?
The enmity between people is
limited solely to their deaths.
If the immortal Gods
begin to act partially
it would be a disgrace to them.
Even the waves of the ocean
compete with each other.
However, the ocean does not
act partially towards any wave.
Do you not have faith
in your competence?
Or without your armour
will you not be able
to confront Arjun?
Is that what you fear?
I do not fear for myself,
Lord Indra.
I have firm faith
that I shall indeed slay Arjun.
Then the entire world will know
who the true brave one is.
But the question here is
not solely about my bravery.
It is about the trust
of my friend.
I have taken an oath
to protect him
and help him gain victory.
By taking my armour away
you are being
unjust to my friend.
I request you...
- The decision is yours!
If you do not wish to engage
in charity then just say so.
And if you do not have
the courage to refuse me
then offering Surya Dev
water at dawn is a right
you will no longer have.
You need to decide which oath
is more important to you
out of the two oaths of yours.
I shall wait at the river-bank
at dawn with the intent
of seeking charity from you.
'Very soon, for the benefit
of his son, Lord Indra'
'will come to you to ask
for your ear-rings and armour.'
'These make you immortal and
denote your divinity as well.'
'Without them,
the weapons of Arjun'
'will be able
to pierce your body.'
'Tomorrow at dawn'
'I am going to ask you
for your ear-rings and armour.'
'Your competence does not lie
in your armour'
'but in your armour
lies my protection.'
'If the Pandavas'
'attack me with a weapon'
'then this holy armour of yours'
'will protect me like a fort,
friend Karna.'
'I shall wait at the river-bank'
'at dawn with the intent'
'of seeking charity from you.'
It is almost time for dawn,
Madhav
but Surya Dev refuses
to grace us with His presence.
Wars do not exist
solely in battlefields.
Sometimes
a war can take place
within the heart, friend.
And then, the darkness of
the heart cannot be dispelled.
Even the darkness of Surya Dev
himself cannot be dispelled.
But why would
the heart of Surya Dev
be troubled with a war,
Madhav?
Where there is attachment
there is struggle.
And where there is struggle,
there is
the hope of victory.
There is the hope of success.
However,
be it life or a war
success can be had
only with the aid
of three weapons.
Righteousness,
patience
and courage.
The rest of the weapons
are merely means.
You forgot one more weapon,
Vasudev.
And that weapon
is opportunity.
Without opportunity
righteousness remains latent
so does courage
and patience does not exist.
Bless you, Arjun,
son of Pandu.
Vasudev Krishna
do accept my greetings.
Greetings.
In order to establish
righteousness on the earth
the great initiative you have
taken in the form of this war
just fills my heart
with great respect for you.
The human beings who will
fight from your side in this war
will be exceedingly fortunate.
But an old 'Brahmin' like me
does not have the strength
to bear any weapon.
However,
I wish to contribute
something precious
to this great undertaking.
You are too kind,
revered 'Brahmin.'
However,
a war
demands the shedding of blood.
Splendid.
Then that is how I shall
contribute, Arjun, son of Kunti.
But is blood not shed
in a battlefield?
It is not shed before a war.
By acquiring knowledge
man creates opportunities
for himself
for his success in the future.
In order to be able
to shed blood in a war
it is better to create
opportunities today itself
Vasudev.
And this would be
my contribution.
An opportunity to shed blood.
Surya Dev
it is time for you to rise.
The entire creation awaits you.
Everyone is your child.
For the benefit
of one son of yours
do not keep the other children
of yours from your light.
Once, the son of Pavan Dev* had hidden you in His mouth.
*Pavana (the Purifier), other name of Vayu, the god of the winds.
The entire creation was on
the verge of destruction then.
I request you,
father.
Please show yourself
and accept my offering.
In the dilemmas of life,
please allow your son
to take his own decisions,
father.
At some point of time in life
every person is robbed of
the protection of his father
and that is when his competence
is truly put to the test
father.
Even a tree
lets go of its fruits
in order to aid the creation
generate new life.
Allow the world to test
my competence, father
so that no one is able to say
that I gained victory
with your help.
If that happens
then my entire life
will be tainted.
I too am a part
of your light, father.
Instead of living in
the darkness of a tainted life
it would be better
if I die a death of glory.
I request you,
father.
Please show yourself
and accept my offering.
I am prepared
to give your son an opportunity
to win, Lord Indra.
Emitting light to the world
does not lessen the sun's power.
The son of Lord Surya
is still competent enough.
Tell me.
What is it that you
wish to seek from me?
But what will that
revered 'Brahmin' give me
that will become
an opportunity for me?
Call it deceit, treachery
or opportunity
but all the attempts
to allay an agitated mind
hold no value.
Where there is righteousness,
patience and courage
there is success.
And one is bound to find success
with their aid, friend.
Without opportunity,
righteousness remains latent
courage is dormant
and patience is lost...
This is what he had said.
Righteousness
is nothing but a lie
if it requires opportunity.
Courage is incomplete
if it lies dormant
until opportunity beckons.
Patience is worthless
if it is lost
before achieving success.
Then why did you
accept his aid, Madhav?
What he said was correct,
friend.
In this war of righteousness
every contribution is precious.
What can he gives me
that will become an opportunity
for victory for me?
Rendering the enemy
weak in a war
is also called an opportunity,
friend.
Guru Arjun
no armour is safe
from your arrows.
One would require
a holy armour for that.