Let me take your leave,
Highness.
Wait, Shakuni.
Wait!
Actually I'd need you
to give the right advise
to Duryodhan
at the right time, Shakuni.
I hereby revoke my order
for asking you to leave
Gandhar right now. Shakuni!
I'd send my confidante,
Sanjay with a peace treaty
to Pandavas.
- No, Highness.
No.
In fact Pandavas need to propose
the peace treaty.
That will make Duryodhan happy.
Hastinapur's throne
and you shall redeem
your lost respect.
I hope you don't have a problem
with this proposal.
- I don't.
I am for peace.
No matter which way
it comes from.
Perfect!
Absolutely perfect!
Then
their uncle
that is the Chief Minister,
Vidhur too could aptly
escort Sanjay.
He shall talk to Pandavas
about compassion.
Sanjay on the other hand
would talk to them
about politics.
Then
Vasudev Krishna shall be invited
to Hastinapur
with Pandava's proposal.
'Greetings!'
'I greet the warrior
a thousand times.'
'He feeds me.'
'Thanks to him, there's
abundance everywhere.'
'I greet the Pandavas
a thousand times.'
'He's mighty, magnanimous...'
'I greet you a thousand times.'
'A warfare wizard.'
'I greet all you citizens.
Greetings!'
'Greetings!
'Tomorrow Princess Uttara shall'
'Arjun's son Abhimanyu.'
'It will be all happy
an festive.'
'Singing and dancing.'
'A lavish feast shall
be organised.'
'There'll be charity.'
'How about we welcome
these happy times'
'with the tale
of an ideal personality?'
'On this evening,
prior to the wedding'
'in order to entertain you all'
'I've been invited to recite
one such tale.'
'So, people, which tale would
you like to listen to?'
Shiva's wedding!
- Ram's wedding.
Parashuram's tale.
- 'Calm down!'
'Why are you screaming?'
'Tell me, Yudhishtir. Which tale
would you like to listen to?'
Not me.
Today Vasudev himself is here.
Vasudev, which tale would
you like to listen to?
This lady here
would decide that.
Tell me. Which tale would
help you calm down?
I am fine now, Govind.
- No.
You seem fine but you
aren't at peace.
Brother, may I suggest?
Go aboard.
Dhundhumali
I would like to listen
to a tale
that I've heard
during childhood.
I haven't been
able to understand
it's importance until now.
Neither has my son, Abhmanyu's
been able to understand this
nor my sister's sons.
'Yes, people!'
'There's just one such tale'
'that I can think of.'
'People close to him
have never understood'
'his importance
and his sensibilities.'
'But an ordinary man like me'
'has not just observed him'
'but understood him as well.'
'No matter how much'
'I praise him'
'I never think it's enough.'
'The entire Aryan clan
is indebted to him.'
'He has helped
people get rid of agony.'
'He looks like a common man'
'but he's an ascetic.'
'He looks like a King'
'but he's a hermit.'
'He looks like a warrior'
'but is magnanimous.'
'He's knowledgeable,
a philosopher and generous'
'yet he is not proud!'
'People, there's just one
such man'
'It isn't a story of Lord Shiva'
'or Rama.'
'It's a tale of Lord Krishna.'
'It's not a warrior tale
of Kailash.'
'Not a tale of land of gold.'
'A tale about the banks
of the River Yamuna.'
'A tale about the village
Gokul.'
'Ugrasena, the King of Mathura* was held captive'
*Now a city in the North Indian state of Uttar Pradesh.
'by his own son, Kans
and he took over his throne.'
'Kans was the son-in-law of
Magadh King Jarasandha.'
'He possessed a dark demeanour.'
Stop!
'He was monstrous,
loathsome and sinful.'
'He gave Yadavas a tough time.'
'He troubled his subjects.'
'He had surpassed
all the limits.'
'Be it the art deceit,
treachery or betrayal!'
'He had mastered it all.'
You can't cross Mathura gate.
What's the trouble,
brother Kans?
The trouble is Devki.
The lady you're married
to, Vasudev.
Haven't you heard the prophecy
that Devki's eighth son shall
be responsible for my death?
And I shall kill Devki.
Comrade, pull Devki
down the chariot.
Wait.
Kans,
will you kill Devki
for a prophecy?
Vasudev!
Divine prophecies
never go wrong.
Prophecies are God sent
and they always come true.
That's a myth.
How can my son kill his uncle?
It's a myth.
I know everything, Devki.
Devak*, Sakroor...
*Devaka was Devaki's father, the younger brother of King Ugrasena of Mathura.
the old Somdutt...
They're all eager to see me die.
Before accusing us
take a good look
at yourself first.
Yadavas aren't your enemy.
You torment your clan
all the time.
You harass your subjects.
You've held your
own father captive.
An arrogant man
is hated by everyone.
Kans, you'll suffer for sure.
I!
I'll suffer!
I'll suffer.
Who'll make me suffer?
Who?
Him!
Or him!
Remember this!
I am your God.
If anyone goes against me
he shall be beheaded.
Kans, don't be foolish.
Don't forget who I am.
I am Shurasena's son
from Yadava clan.
My sister Briha
is King Kuntibhoj's
adopted daughter.
She's been married to
Hastinapur's ruler, Pandu.
If you harm me
then Pandu, King Shurasena
and Kuntibhoj's army
shall attack you.
You may die today.
Send for everyone.
I'll be killed
by Devki's eighth son
as per the divine prophecy.
No one else
can cause me any harm.
You can't harm me too.
No one can harm me.
Do you see my soldiers?
They can kill all
the Yadava men right here.
No brother.
Listen to me. It's a myth.
Brother, listen to me.
You'll not be harmed.
Brother, trust me.
Brother!
- Kans, wait!
If the prophecy's right
how will you stop it.
If it's true
what will killing
Devki fetch you.
I am Shurasena's son Vasudev.
If I want I can
kill you right away.
That would bring a stir
among Yadavas.
It won't do good to anyone.
Devki and me are ready
to sacrifice our lives.
We surrender, Kansa.
I promise, Kans
that neither Hastinapur,
nor Kuntibhoj
will make an effort
to rescue us.
I pardon you
and Devki.
My soldiers, arrive now
and put them behind the bars.
Vasudev!
Here's the infant.
It's time to sacrifice
your child, Devki.