Sister!
What are you doing?
I am bidding my sword goodbye.
Now, this sword will assume
the form of the Almighty
and help me reform my life.
I have failed the purpose
of my birth today.
No, sister.
Do not say that.
You do not know, Draupadi
but I was born
to deal with weapons.
Flowers not only emit fragrance
but also look beautiful
and provide seeds.
But a thorn...
A thorn is born
only to prick others.
What...
What do I now, Draupadi?
The people who do not
succeed in the battlefield
do they also not
succeed in life, sister?
I cannot be.
If ember loses its fire
it is nothing but coal.
Dark and ugly.
The person who touches it
becomes dirty.
If the fire within me dies out
I too shall become so!
The way
a serpent is born with
a poison pouch in its mouth
similarly, I was born
with anger and vengeance.
It is a tie of my
previous life, Draupadi.
If I do not hold a weapon
my entire being gets
filled with dejection.
To be the General of Panchal
is the basis of my life.
But
father snatched this basis
from me today.
He rendered all my efforts
fruitless today.
That can never happen, sister.
Father shall certainly
reappoint you as the General.
I shall talk to him.
You... You need
to come with me, sister.
You need to come with me.
Father will never listen
to you, Draupadi.
He shall indeed listen to me.
I was born from
a sacrificial fire.
I am a blessing of the Gods.
Did father not say so himself?
He shall certainly listen to me.
You need to come
with me, sister.
Come with me, sister.
Let's go, sister.
Greetings, father.
May you be invincible.
Father.
Father
sister deserves this respect.
Without any apparent reason
how can you take this right
away from sister?
How dare you question
your own father?
Only a father can answer
the questions of his children.
In order to question
one's father
a child only requires
a question.
One does not require
courage for it.
Quit with your rambling,
Draupadi!
Shikhandini has
murdered my trust.
She was supposed
to slay Bhishma
but was defeated
by the Kuru Princes!
How will she
defeat Bhishma then?!
She has proven the prediction
of the Gods to be false!
Even Dhrishtadyumna was given
to you by the Gods, father.
If you have faith
in Dhrishtadyumna
then why not in sister?
Because she is a woman!
Women can bear jewellery
but not swords!
Goddess Durga* is also a woman, father.
*Goddess of Victory of Good over Evil, "the invincible", the most popular incarnation of Devi/Goddess Shakti--the female aspect of the divine.
She bears not one
but ten weapons.
The way I am a blessing
of the Gods to you
similarly
sister is also
a gift of the Gods.
I do not require
any such gift or blessing.
You do not require it?
Father
why did you ask for me from Agni Dev* then?
*The god of fire and the acceptor of sacrifices.
I did not ask for you!
The Gods have sent you
because of their intransigence!
They have sent you
by defeating me!
The truth is that you are
a symbol of my weakness!
You and that Shikhandini!
The two of you remind me
of my defeat!
You cannot insult your children
in this manner, father.
One who does not get
respect from one's father
to that person, no respect
can ever make him happy.
I, your daughter, father
beg of you
to not commit injustice
by destroying
sister's self-confidence.
This is not injustice.
This is a punishment!
Punishment for being defeated!
Because I never accept defeat!
But in that battle
were you also
not defeated, father?
Then why punish only sister?
If you wish to stay alive
then go from here.
Otherwise, for committing the
crime of insulting your father
you shall be sent
to the gallows!
There is no place for you
in Kampilya any longer!
Go!
No, father!
Please pardon her.
Guard
this maiden has been banished
from the city of Kampilya!
Take her to the gates
of the city!
Right away!
Take her to the gates
of the city!
Right away!
If this is your order, father
then I shall certainly go away.
I am your daughter.
If I stay here after this insult
it will tarnish your reputation.
Draupadi, no.
Draupadi..
No, Draupadi.
Stop, Draupadi.
Stop!
Father, stop Draupadi.
Father, she has no
knowledge of the world.
Who will protect her?
Please do not banish
my sister, father.
Stop her.
Stop, Draupadi!
Father
I apologize on her behalf.
Please pardon us.
Draupadi, stop!
'I did not ask for you!'
'The Gods have sent you
because of their intransigence!'
'The truth is that you are
a symbol of my weakness!'
'They have sent you by defeating
me! You and that Shikhandini!'
'There is no place for you
in Kampilya any longer!'
'Go!'
'If you wish to stay alive'
'then go from here.'
'Otherwise, for committing the
crime of insulting your father'
'you shall be sent
to the gallows!'
'This maiden has been banished
from the city of Kampilya!'
'Take her to the gates
of the city!'
'Go!'