Lord Indra is your
biological father.
Will you be able to fight him?
The 'Vedas' say
that the might of Lord Indra
can be matched by only one God.
Agni Dev.
Agni Dev is termed as the
face of the Gods.
Today, I shall pray to Agni Dev
to have the love of my father.
And if I am unable
to have his love
then I would rather die!
But such an enormous forest
cannot be destroyed.
To chop down a tree
is far more grave a sin
than killing 100 humans.
Do not worry,
Panchali.
I shall pray to Agni Dev*
*God of fire and the acceptor of sacrifices.
to prey on only the illusions
of Mayasur.
I will ask him not to
harm the trees.
The illusion of Mayasur
is very powerful, Arjun.
Can it be destroyed?
Brother Bheem
Agni Dev is also called
the devourer.
Agni Dev can devour anything.
Even the illusion of Mayasur
will be devoured by him.
But ensure that he does not
devour the serpents, Arjun.
In order to save the humans
if we kill the serpents
then it would be unrighteous.
Lord of the Serpents,
there is still time.
Go and seek the refuge
of the Pandavas.
Mayasur, if you
had not transformed this forest
into an illusory one
and helped me
then I
would have bitten you
this instant.
And the one I bite
can not
be helped by anyone.
Son of Pandu,
Arjun.
Do not cross your limits.
I protect this forest.
Lord Indra
you protect
the entire world!
Yet, according to their needs,
competent warriors
make use of the earth.
Then why can we not,
Lord Indra?
Because I protect the serpents
of this forest!
These serpents have
committed the crime
of biting innocent people!
And protecting the culprits
does not befit the Gods,
Lord Indra!
Arjun!
Do not preach me
about righteousness.
When compared to me
you are only a child.
I am your child,
Lord Indra.
And the child sitting
on his father's shoulders
has a better vision
than his father!
Arjun!
Go away from here
otherwise you shall
meet your doom!
My life is a gift from you,
Lord Indra.
I would be blessed
if you gift me death as well!
But by laying down my weapons
I cannot tarnish
your reputation.
Arjun!
My foolish subjects!
Stop! Consuming
rodents as a meal
has left all of you
with a similar disposition!
Stop!
Who are you scared of?
No one can defeat us!
Stop!
Lord Indra
use your 'vajra!'*
*A club with a ribbed spherical head, symbolize both the properties of a diamond (indestructibility) and a thunderbolt (irresistible force).
You must keep
the promise you made!
Where are you going,
Mayasur?!
After spending
many joyful years in my refuge
you are abandoning me now?!
Dakshak
I had made a deal with you.
It was an exchange of benefits.
But this is a mortal trouble.
Neither can you protect me
nor can I protect you.
I am now going to seek
the refuge of the Pandavas.
Arjuna!
- Brother!
Lord Indra!
I am your son
and an ardent follower
of Lord Kartikeya*
*The god of war, the commander-in-chief of the army of the devas (gods) and the son of Shiva and Parvati.
who is the husband
of your daughter Devsena!
I will not get defeated
so easily.
I will not be defeated,
Lord Indra.
Lord Indra...
It's not a contest to test yours
and Arjuna's potential.
Arjuna is merely asking you
to spare our subjects' lives.
He is not trying to insult you.
Please do not show the Vajra
but clemency, My Lord.
O divine weapon Vajra!
Please accept my greetings.
Please show respect
to my divine weapon
and calm down.