Queen Kunti.
Upon your arrival in Hastinapur,
I wanted to be the first one
to welcome you
with these lotuses.
The truth is...
My heart never abandoned
that desire.
Whenever I see lotuses
I am reminded of your feet,
Queen.
If you stand silently like this
I shall consider that you have
not accepted this flower, Queen.
But
flowers are offered
only to sages
and at the feet of the Almighty.
I am not worthy of this.
But are mothers not another
form of the Almighty, Queen?
And my father had taught me
in my childhood
that the king and the queen
are the father and mother
of the subjects.
That is why, as a child,
I had the desire
to convey to Queen Kunti of
all the injustice done to me
so that she would help me
get justice as my mother.
When my own mother has forsaken
me for the fear of the society
then what can I expect
from anyone else?
What do you mean?
Just now, my mother
has refused to reside with me
in my palace, Queen.
Goodbye.
Son.
You...
You may think of me
as your mother.
I did not come to the palace
to look for a new mother, Queen.
My mother has forsaken me.
But I have not forsaken her.
This was just an old wish
that I fulfilled today.
Besides
by calling the mother
of my arch enemy
as my own, I do not wish to let
the fire of my enmity die out.
Why this enmity, son?
I...
I saw you in the arena.
You are a remarkable warrior.
You and Arjun are archers
of equal skills.
We are not equals.
I am a more superior archer
than your son.
And this enmity stems
from the fact
that the place Arjun
was given today in the arena
is mine.
And the place where
you are to be seated
I would never wish
to be seated there.
I have no place at
the feet of Prince Duryodhan.
In other words, you may
deem me as your competitor
but I do not deem you as mine.
Arjun.
Arrogance corrodes valour
as mercury corrodes gold.
Are you telling all this
to brother Arjun
or to the King of Anga Pradesh,
Karna?
What is the point of saying so
to King of Anga Pradesh, Nakul?
Mercury corrodes gold
and not iron.
And where valour is nothing
but a few fancy tricks
it is termed not as gold
but iron.
Iron.
Sahadev.
Do not use
such insulting language.
Karna...
King of Anga Pradesh, Karna,
is your
elder brother...
He is like your elder brother.
Indeed, mother.
He is just like our
elder brother Duryodhan.
King of Anga Pradesh
is just like him.
The same arrogance
and the same ignorance.
You are correct, mother.
He is just like him.
There is no difference, mother.
And our weapons
shall not differentiate either.
Arjun!
Stay within your limits.
King of Anga Pradesh,
you are welcome here.
Neither are we angry with you
nor do we bear
any feeling of competition.
But I do.
I have a reason to be both angry
and have the competitive spirit.
Oh Princes, who cherish
their birth as their ornaments
do remember
that in the actual battlefield
all will know the truth
about their valour and birth.
And Arjun.
If we ever cross paths
in the battlefield someday
then you will be destined
to die at my hands.
I give you my word.
If we ever cross paths
in the battlefield someday
then you will be destined
to die at my hands.
I give you my word.
Warriors are bound to cross each
other's paths in the battlefield
King of Anga Pradesh.
And not in a village fair.
And as for your promise
I shall remind you myself
about it.
Let's go, mother.
My son!
My son, Duryodhan.
Hearing of your prowess today
gave me great solace, son.
The earth was trembling today
with the sound of your feet.
The sound of your mace
felt as though
there were a battle
between the clouds, son.
Greetings.
After all, you have given
elder brother such a name.
He is Duryodhan!
Fighting him
will not be easy.
You are correct, Dusshasan.
Besides
the companionship and
protection of his 99 brothers
will always be with Duryodhan.
The truth is,
Duryodhan is invincible.
And your sons are inarguably
the most superior, father!
Go on, son.
Greetings, grandfather.
May you be prosperous, Prince.
Had there been a verdict
to today's competition
then the words of His Highness
would have seemed true.
There was no verdict?
I defeated four of the Pandavas
before everyone, grandfather.
The warrior left standing
at sundown
was not you.
It was not Prince Arjun either,
Your Excellency.
The King of Anga Pradesh,
Karna, was standing before him.
Undefeated.
- That is why, this competition
did not have any verdict.
- But grandfather
that undefeated warrior
is on my side now.
My friend and my associate.
In other words, my side
is more powerful right now.
And, Your Excellency
my beloved nephew has proved
that he is not only
a fine warrior
but also has the capacity
to become a fine prince.
By declaring Karna
as the King of Anga Pradesh
he brought governance
to the kingdom of Anga
he surrounded the enemy kingdom
of Magadha
and magnified his strength
and that of his kingdom greatly.
Alliance and sabotage
Duryodhan has knowledge
of both these concepts.
Your Excellency
even a prince is required
to perform these duties.
Physical might is not the only
requirement to rule a kingdom.
You are correct, uncle!
In order to protect themselves
from the lion
the small and weak animals
of the jungle
had made an army once.
Our teacher had narrated
such a tale to us.
The ones who do not have
strength in their limbs
only they speak of alliances,
uncle.
Greetings, your Majesty.
May you live long, son.
To know about the strength
of my limbs
you can inquire
the four brothers of yours
who got a taste of the ground
of the arena today.
You are right.
We did get just a taste of it.
Tomorrow, I will eat and digest
the whole of the arena.
And if you wish
to see it for yourself
then be present in the arena.
My name is Vrakodar.
Vrakodar.
Calm down, Bheem!
The competition
has now ended, son.
Now, expunge the thoughts of
the competition from your mind.
May all of you be prosperous!
Today's competition
was only about physical might.
No other capabilities
were being tested today.
That is why, this competition
did not have a verdict.
Today, the princes who
took part in this competition
and displayed their art
have brought contentment
to all of us.
If no verdict could be reached
then have the competition
held again tomorrow, father.
I am willing to participate.
Let it be, brother Duryodhan.
No verdict could be reached
for the competition today.
If the verdict for
the competition is out tomorrow
then you will be
defamed greatly.
Allow us to leave now, uncle.